<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>State-Policy Think-Tank Digest</title><link>https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml</link><description>Latest posts from free-market policy institutes across the U.S.</description><atom:link href="https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 07:06:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] Allen Mendenhall: API’s Christmas wish list</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/12/26/allen-mendenhall-apis-christmas-wish-list/</link><description>&lt;p&gt; The Alabama Policy Institute (API) has delivered its "Blueprint for 2026: Building a Stronger Alabama" with the seasonal timing of a policy wonk’s Christmas morning, complete with 30 wrapped proposals arranged beneath three conceptual ornaments: free markets, limited government, and strong families.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/12/26/allen-mendenhall-apis-christmas-wish-list/"&gt;Allen Mendenhall: API&amp;#8217;s Christmas wish list&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 18:50:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Libertas] A Year of Impact: 1.3+ Million Families</title><link>https://libertas.org/2025-report/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In early 2025 we set out an ambitious &amp;#8220;Vivid Vision&amp;#8221; for our team to grow our impact and scale up our work, and the end-of-year results demonstrate significant progress across all our initiatives. In total, we positively impacted more than 1.3 million families! Below, watch a 15-minute update sharing our 2025 impact, presented by our [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://libertas.org/2025-report/"&gt;A Year of Impact: 1.3+ Million Families&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://libertas.org"&gt;The Libertas Network: Changing Hearts, Minds, and Laws&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 01:49:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Rifreedom] Stenhouse Challenges Zurier’s Special Senate Energy Commission to “Act” on the Act On Climate</title><link>https://rifreedom.org/2026/01/stenhouse-challenges-zuriers-special-senate-energy-commission-to-act-on-the-act-on-climate/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;With "affordability" top of mind for Ocean State residents, the CEO of the RI Center for Freedom &amp;#038; Prosperity  today called upon  Senator  Sam Zurier  and all members of the special Senate Energy Commission he chairs to take a w holistic and realistic look at Rhode Island's net-zero policies and Act On Climate  mandates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org/2026/01/stenhouse-challenges-zuriers-special-senate-energy-commission-to-act-on-the-act-on-climate/"&gt;Stenhouse Challenges Zurier&amp;#8217;s Special Senate Energy Commission to &amp;#8220;Act&amp;#8221; on the Act On Climate&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org"&gt;RI Center for Freedom and Prosperity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 15:02:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Research Note: How Changes in AI Regulation Could Affect Nebraska</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/research-note-how-changes-in-ai-regulation-could-affect-nebraska/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of weeks before Christmas, following the President’s recent executive order on artificial intelligence (AI), the Nebraska Examiner published an article examining the potential implications for Nebraska. While the precise impact of the order remains uncertain, the state’s recent legislative activity related to AI suggests the possibility of conflict between state and federal approaches....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/research-note-how-changes-in-ai-regulation-could-affect-nebraska/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Research Note: How Changes in AI Regulation Could Affect Nebraska&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 15:05:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] NEW: Findings from IRG Listening Tour and new Poll— a ground-level look at the issues Wisconsinites care about most</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/new-findings-from-irg-listening-tour-and-new-poll-a-ground-level-look-at-the-issues-wisconsinites-care-about-most/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;NEW: Findings from IRG Listening Tour and New Poll— a ground-level look at the issues Wisconsinites care about most Key lessons and insights gathered from four months of listening across Wisconsin. Delafield, Wis. – What common challenges are on Wisconsinites’ minds heading into 2026? The Institute for Reforming Government released its newest community engagement report, Wisconsin [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/new-findings-from-irg-listening-tour-and-new-poll-a-ground-level-look-at-the-issues-wisconsinites-care-about-most/"&gt;NEW: Findings from IRG Listening Tour and new Poll— a ground-level look at the issues Wisconsinites care about most&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 22:25:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Happy New Year! A Blueprint for Mississippi in 2026!</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/happy-new-year-a-blueprint-for-mississippi-in-2026/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As we kick off 2026, the Mississippi Center for Public Policy is more energized than ever.&amp;#160;&amp;#160;We are excited about the successes our state has seen – and we have a plan to build on that momentum with further free market reform!&amp;#160;For decades, our state lagged behind.&amp;#160;&amp;#160;Growth was slow and too many young people left our [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/happy-new-year-a-blueprint-for-mississippi-in-2026/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Happy New Year! A Blueprint for Mississippi in 2026!&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 15:35:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] Center Square Covers IRG’s Wisconsin Speaks Report</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/center-square-covers-irgs-wisconsin-speaks-report/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;(The Center Square) – Voters in Wisconsin are worried about their wallets heading into the 2026 elections. The Institute for Reforming Government recently released the results of its listening session tour, and unsurprisingly “affordability” is the number one concern. “By far, the most significant issue discussed in every listening session was cost of living – rising [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/center-square-covers-irgs-wisconsin-speaks-report/"&gt;Center Square Covers IRG&amp;#8217;s Wisconsin Speaks Report&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 15:09:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Nebraska’s Tax Code Lets It Compete for Data Center Investment</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/nebraskas-tax-code-lets-it-compete-for-data-center-investment/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Midwest grows many things—including, increasingly, data centers. That’s good news, generating substantial local tax revenue, creating high-paying jobs, and expanding economic opportunities.  With 39 data centers (about 19 per 1 million people), Nebraska punches above its weight nationally, while trailing neighboring Iowa, which boasts the second-highest number of data centers per capita at 32...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/nebraskas-tax-code-lets-it-compete-for-data-center-investment/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Nebraska’s Tax Code Lets It Compete for Data Center Investment&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 17:26:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Shaping Georgia’s future: Opportunities for the year ahead</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/top-issues-shaping-georgia-future/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The well-being of many Georgians, their families, and their communities is at stake as pressing concerns like welfare reform, the cost of living, educational opportunities, and public safety take center stage in 2026. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/top-issues-shaping-georgia-future/"&gt;Shaping Georgia’s future: Opportunities for the year ahead&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 23:49:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] The importance of NH’s 1776 constitution</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2026/01/the-importance-of-nhs-1776-constitution/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On Jan. 5, 1776, New Hampshire became the first self-governing British colony in North America. That astonishing decision, made 250 years ago this week, deserved a bigger celebration than it received.  After a quarter of a millennium, Americans have become accustomed to thinking that self-government is normal. It isn’t. Achieving it in 1776 was extraordinary. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2026/01/the-importance-of-nhs-1776-constitution/"&gt;The importance of NH&amp;#8217;s 1776 constitution&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 20:34:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Short Session, Long Consequences: What Labor’s 2026 Agenda Would Mean for Connecticut</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/01/09/short-session-long-consequences-what-labors-2026-agenda-would-mean-for-connecticut/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connecticut lawmakers will return to Hartford on February 4 for the state’s so-called short session — a three-month legislative sprint intended primarily for technical fixes and budget adjustments.  In practice, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/01/09/short-session-long-consequences-what-labors-2026-agenda-would-mean-for-connecticut/"&gt;Short Session, Long Consequences: What Labor’s 2026 Agenda Would Mean for Connecticut &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 20:49:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] Franke: Edmund Burke</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2026/01/franke-edmund-burke/</link><description>by Mark Franke Edmund Burke was a philosophical hero for us Young Americans for Freedom undergraduates back in the Nixon administration. In large part this was due to Russell Kirk’s autobiography, “Edmund Burke: A Genius Reconsidered,” that had just been released.&amp;#160; In recent years Burke’s status has been brought into question by factions within the&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2026/01/franke-edmund-burke/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 14:03:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] State Report Card on Telehealth Reform: Incremental Progress in 2025 Leaves Many States Unprepared for Rural Health Transformation Funding</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/state-report-card-on-telehealth-reform-incremental-progress-in-2025-leaves-many-states-unprepared-for-rural-health-transformation-funding/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Boston, Mass – A new report from the Cicero Institute and Pioneer Institute finds that while state legislatures remained active on telehealth policy in 2025, most states made only incremental progress toward modern, patient-centered telehealth systems. With the passage of the One Big Beautiful Bill and its $50 billion Rural Health Transformation Program, states now face growing pressure to modernize outdated telehealth laws or risk falling behind in access, affordability, and federal funding competitiveness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/state-report-card-on-telehealth-reform-incremental-progress-in-2025-leaves-many-states-unprepared-for-rural-health-transformation-funding/"&gt;State Report Card on Telehealth Reform: Incremental Progress in 2025 Leaves Many States Unprepared for Rural Health Transformation Funding&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 15:22:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] HB2 – Mississippi’s School Choice Bill is Here!</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/hb2-mississippis-school-choice-bill-is-here/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Last week, House Speaker Jason White unveiled&amp;#160;HB2, the&amp;#160;Mississippi Education Freedom Act - the most exciting and ambitious advancement for school choice in our state in years, perhaps ever!&amp;#160;This comprehensive bill delivers everything supporters of parental power have long hoped for, and it aligns perfectly with President Trump’s strong commitment to education freedom.&amp;#160;This isn’t some minor [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/hb2-mississippis-school-choice-bill-is-here/" rel="nofollow"&gt;HB2 – Mississippi’s School Choice Bill is Here!&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 17:31:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] In Cambridge, New Lawsuit Challenges Constitutionality of Mandatory Set-Asides for Affordable Housing</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/in-cambridge-new-lawsuit-challenges-constitutionality-of-mandatory-set-asides-for-affordable-housing/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This edition of The House Call describes a legal complaint alleging that Cambridge&amp;#8217;s inclusionary zoning ordinance, which requires set-asides for below-market-rate housing in new development, is a regulatory taking under the Fifth Amendment to the Constitution. It also describes a number of actions the Commonwealth...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/in-cambridge-new-lawsuit-challenges-constitutionality-of-mandatory-set-asides-for-affordable-housing/"&gt;In Cambridge, New Lawsuit Challenges Constitutionality of Mandatory Set-Asides for Affordable Housing&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 19:18:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] ABQ Journal opinion piece: More investigative journalism is a must</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/abq-journal-opinion-piece-more-investigative-journalism-is-a-must/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following appeared in Albuquerque Journal on January 11, 2026. The Albuquerque Journal recently made appeals on its pages for donations to increase investigative journalism efforts. Even though the Rio Grande Foundation is in direct competition for limited donor dollars, we applaud the paper for focusing attention on investigative journalism currently. The issue of investigative journalism is [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/abq-journal-opinion-piece-more-investigative-journalism-is-a-must/"&gt;ABQ Journal opinion piece: More investigative journalism is a must&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 19:54:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Idaho GOP calls for an end to taxpayer support for teachers unions</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/teachers-unions/idaho-gop-calls-for-an-end-to-taxpayer-support-for-teachers-unions/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As the 2026 Idaho legislature convenes, the Idaho Republican Party has adopted a resolution calling for the “passage of legislation to prohibit taxpayer support for teachers’ unions in all forms, direct or indirect," a key Freedom Foundation initiative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/teachers-unions/idaho-gop-calls-for-an-end-to-taxpayer-support-for-teachers-unions/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Idaho GOP calls for an end to taxpayer support for teachers unions&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:39:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] PPS to Remove References to “Black Students” from Naming of “Center for Black Student Excellence” at Jan. 13 Board Meeting</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/global-news/pps-to-remove-references-to-black-students-from-naming-of-center-for-black-student-excellence-at-jan-13-board-meeting/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;January 12, 2026 FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE Cascade Policy Institute4850 SW Scholls Ferry Rd.,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/global-news/pps-to-remove-references-to-black-students-from-naming-of-center-for-black-student-excellence-at-jan-13-board-meeting/"&gt;PPS to Remove References to &amp;#8220;Black Students&amp;#8221; from Naming of &amp;#8220;Center for Black Student Excellence&amp;#8221; at Jan. 13 Board Meeting&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:41:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Alternatives to New England’s Energy Affordability Crisis</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/01/13/alternatives-to-new-englands-energy-affordability-crisis/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Energy-Paper-2026.png" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New Englanders would save hundreds of billions of dollars and avoid deadly power blackouts by replacing state-mandated renewable energy projects with nuclear and natural gas power, a study released today [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/01/13/alternatives-to-new-englands-energy-affordability-crisis/"&gt;Alternatives to New England’s Energy Affordability Crisis&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 12:00:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Utah Education Association sued over claims dues don’t fund politics</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/labor/utah-education-association-sued-over-claims-dues-dont-fund-politics/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Freedom Foundation, together with Utah public school teacher and member of the Utah State Board of Education Cole Kelley, has filed a lawsuit against the Utah Education Association for falsely claiming its members’ dues are not used to fund political activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/labor/utah-education-association-sued-over-claims-dues-dont-fund-politics/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Utah Education Association sued over claims dues don’t fund politics&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 12:01:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Rifreedom] NEW REPORT PROVIDES ALTERNATIVES TO RHODE ISLAND’S SUICIDAL ACT ON CLIMATE POLICIES</title><link>https://rifreedom.org/2026/01/new-report-provides-alternatives-to-rhode-islands-suicidal-act-on-climate-policies/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New Englanders would save hundreds of billions of dollars and avoid deadly power blackouts by replacing state-mandated renewable energy projects with nuclear and natural gas power, a study released today by a coalition of New England think tanks finds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alternatives to New England’s Energy Suicide, released by New England’s free-market think tanks along with Americans for Prosperity Foundation, estimated the effects of trying to meet the region’s energy needs through 2050 with nuclear and natural gas plants instead of wind and solar power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org/2026/01/new-report-provides-alternatives-to-rhode-islands-suicidal-act-on-climate-policies/"&gt;NEW REPORT PROVIDES ALTERNATIVES TO RHODE ISLAND&amp;#8217;S SUICIDAL ACT ON CLIMATE POLICIES&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org"&gt;RI Center for Freedom and Prosperity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 13:49:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2026/01/the-outstater-320/</link><description>Graduation for Graduation&amp;#8217;s Sake SOMETHING STRUCK ME&amp;#160;wrong about all the Indiana public school districts this week touting increases in their graduation rates. Shouldn’t we be worried about what is being graduated?&amp;#160; Civic&amp;#160;education, for instance.&amp;#160;Gallup tell us that only 41 percent of those born after 1997 are proud to be an American compared with 83 percent&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2026/01/the-outstater-320/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 14:11:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] New Englanders would save hundreds of billions of dollars by replacing mandated renewable energy with nuclear and natural gas</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2026/01/new-englanders-would-save-hundreds-of-billions-of-dollars-by-replacing-mandated-renewable-energy-with-nuclear-and-natural-gas/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New Englanders would save hundreds of billions of dollars and avoid deadly power blackouts by replacing state-mandated renewable energy projects with nuclear and natural gas power, a study released today by a coalition of New England think tanks finds. Alternatives to New England&amp;#8217;s Affordability Crisis, a new study released by a coalition of New England’s [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2026/01/new-englanders-would-save-hundreds-of-billions-of-dollars-by-replacing-mandated-renewable-energy-with-nuclear-and-natural-gas/"&gt;New Englanders would save hundreds of billions of dollars by replacing mandated renewable energy with nuclear and natural gas&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 17:26:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cardinalinstitute] A Conversation with Charles Mitchell</title><link>https://cardinalinstitute.com/a-conversation-with-charles-mitchell/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A Conversation with Charles Mitchell David and Laura Thayer Visiting Fellow, Cardinal Institute Editor’s Note: The Cardinal Institute is pleased to announce that Charles Mitchell, former CEO of the Commonwealth Foundation, has joined Cardinal as the David B. and Laura Thayer Visiting Fellow. Charles brings decades of national leadership experience in the conservative, free-market think [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com/a-conversation-with-charles-mitchell/"&gt;A Conversation with Charles Mitchell&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com"&gt;Cardinal Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 14:43:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] ABQ Ethics Board Dismisses frivolous “sweatshirt-gate” ethics complaint made by Keller campaign against RGF’s Paul Gessing</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/abq-ethics-board-dismisses-frivolous-sweatshirt-gate-ethics-complaint-made-by-keller-campaign-against-rgfs-paul-gessing/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This afternoon in a hearing, the Albuquerque Board of Ethics (BOE) unanimously dismissed a complaint filed by Daymon Ely for the Tim Keller campaign that was made against Rio Grande Foundation president Paul Gessing. The complaint arose out of the Foundation’s reporting over the purchase and delivery of yellow hoodie sweatshirts to members of Albuquerque’s [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/abq-ethics-board-dismisses-frivolous-sweatshirt-gate-ethics-complaint-made-by-keller-campaign-against-rgfs-paul-gessing/"&gt;ABQ Ethics Board Dismisses frivolous “sweatshirt-gate” ethics complaint made by Keller campaign against RGF’s Paul Gessing&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 22:08:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] The Denominators of our Prosperity – Energy and Water</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/the-denominators-of-our-prosperity-energy-and-water/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=the-denominators-of-our-prosperity-energy-and-water</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The premise of this newsletter is that abundant and affordable energy and water are prerequisites to solving every other challenge standing in the way of lowering California’s overall cost-of-living. Not only because the cost for energy and water directly impacts the cost to build homes, or pay household utility bills, or engage in industrial production,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/the-denominators-of-our-prosperity-energy-and-water/"&gt;The Denominators of our Prosperity – Energy and Water&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 22:23:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cardinalinstitute] 2026 State of the State Response</title><link>https://cardinalinstitute.com/2026-state-of-the-state-response/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;2026 State of the State Response On Wednesday evening, Governor Patrick Morrisey delivered his annual State of the State address, outlining his priorities for the year ahead and offering a window into his governing philosophy. As is customary, the speech functioned as both pep rally and agenda-setting exercise. State of the state addresses tend to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com/2026-state-of-the-state-response/"&gt;2026 State of the State Response&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com"&gt;Cardinal Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 15:07:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF opinion piece: Data centers are coming: How to handle them</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-opinion-piece-data-centers-are-coming-how-to-handle-them/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following appeared in the Santa Fe New Mexican on January 10, 2026. It has appeared in several other publications as well. &amp;#160; After years of failure to land a “big fish” business for New Mexico’s economy (or effectively use the oil and gas revenues to grow the economy) Gov. Michelle Lujan Grisham, with the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-opinion-piece-data-centers-are-coming-how-to-handle-them/"&gt;RGF opinion piece: Data centers are coming: How to handle them&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 15:48:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Empire Center Warns of Sharp Increase in New York Electricity Prices</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/empire-center-warns-of-sharp-increase-in-new-york-electricity-prices/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New York households pay some of the highest electricity prices in the nation, raising affordability concerns, according to the Empire....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/empire-center-warns-of-sharp-increase-in-new-york-electricity-prices/"&gt;Empire Center Warns of Sharp Increase in New York Electricity Prices&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 15:51:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] Passing a “Lottery Only” bill won’t limit Alabama to a Lottery</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2026/01/15/passing-a-lottery-only-bill-wont-limit-alabama-to-a-lottery/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Did you know passing a lottery without also allowing games, digital games, and sports betting is impossible?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2026/01/15/passing-a-lottery-only-bill-wont-limit-alabama-to-a-lottery/"&gt;Passing a &amp;#8220;Lottery Only&amp;#8221; bill won’t limit Alabama to a Lottery&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 16:21:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Pine Tree Pulse, Episode 77: Jonathan Bush</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/pine-tree-pulse-episode-77-jonathan-bush/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Jonathan Bush, Republican candidate for governor of Maine, recently sat down with Maine Policy CEO Matt Gagnon and Policy Analyst Harris Van Pate at MPI headquarters to discuss the 2026 gubernatorial campaign, and his story. Bush is a technology entrepreneur, best known as the cofounder and former chief executive officer of athenahealth, a healthcare technology [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/pine-tree-pulse-episode-77-jonathan-bush/"&gt;Pine Tree Pulse, Episode 77: Jonathan Bush&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 17:21:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Louisiana Economic Report – Winter 2026</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/tax-budget/louisiana-economic-report-winter-2026/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Download the Full Report Here&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/tax-budget/louisiana-economic-report-winter-2026/"&gt;Louisiana Economic Report – Winter 2026&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 22:59:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Helton expounds on expanding farmworker housing</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/01/helton-expounds-on-expanding-farmworker-housing/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Hawaii’s farmers and ranchers need easier pathways to build more employee housing on their land, according to policy analyst Jonathan Helton, author of a new policy brief released by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii.&amp;#160; Doing so, Helton said during a radio interview this past Sunday with host Johnny Miro of H. Hawaii Media, would take [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/01/helton-expounds-on-expanding-farmworker-housing/"&gt;Helton expounds on expanding farmworker housing&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 01:13:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] A state takeover of Education Freedom Account administration would increase program costs</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2026/01/a-state-takeover-of-education-freedom-accounts-would-increase-program-costs/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Opponents of New Hampshire’s Education Freedom Account (EFA) program have always claimed its administration costs were too high. Yet a proposal from EFA critics to fold the program into the Education Department would increase administrative costs and allow them to grow unchecked. Currently, the state contracts with a non-profit charity, the Children’s Scholarship Fund-New Hampshire [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2026/01/a-state-takeover-of-education-freedom-accounts-would-increase-program-costs/"&gt;A state takeover of Education Freedom Account administration would increase program costs&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 16:07:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Florida Politics: Florida’s AI Laws Are Stronger Than You Think</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/florida-politics-floridas-ai-laws-are-stronger-than-you-think/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As Florida’s 2026 Legislative Session approaches, artificial intelligence is expected to be a major focus among Tallahassee’s policymakers....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/florida-politics-floridas-ai-laws-are-stronger-than-you-think/"&gt;Florida Politics: Florida’s AI Laws Are Stronger Than You Think&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 16:13:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Under The Dome: House Passes the Education Freedom Act</title><link>https://empowerms.org/house-passes-the-education-freedom-act/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, the Mississippi House of Representatives passed House Bill 2, the Mississippi Education Freedom Act, one of the most comprehensive education reform bills our state has considered in years. Authored by House Speaker Jason White and Representative Jansen Owen, this bill puts families first by expanding school choice, increasing transparency, and giving parents and local communities more control over how&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/house-passes-the-education-freedom-act/"&gt;Under The Dome: House Passes the Education Freedom Act&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 18:27:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Alleged savings from the proposed Wichita sales tax are based on flawed assumptions and won’t materialize</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/savings-wichita-sales-tax-wont-materialize/</link><description>Believe it or not, Wichita voters are being told they will pay lower taxes overall if they vote for a new 1% sales tax. Yes, you read that correctly; the message is ‘Pay more taxes so you can pay less tax.’ That’s the essence of the pitch the City of Wichita is making to encourage [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 18:42:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] The SEBAC ‘Concessions’ Narrative Collapses Under Its Own Accounting</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/01/16/the-sebac-concessions-narrative-collapses-under-its-own-accounting/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For nearly a decade, Connecticut officials have pointed to the 2017 SEBAC agreement as evidence that fiscal responsibility and political compromise can coexist. The deal, negotiated by the Malloy administration [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/01/16/the-sebac-concessions-narrative-collapses-under-its-own-accounting/"&gt;The SEBAC ‘Concessions’ Narrative Collapses Under Its Own Accounting&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 19:02:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2026/01/the-outstater-321/</link><description>Childcare and Charitable Exhaustion THE PROPHETS WARN&amp;#160;that the devil loves an impossible task. A newsroom corollary is that corruption follows an inarguable good. Both apply to the challenge of caring for children in troubled homes due to poverty, emotional crisis or the myriad snares of modern society. Indiana spends $147 million a year in state&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2026/01/the-outstater-321/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 19:18:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Goldwater Fights CON Laws in the Mississippi Supreme Court</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/goldwater-fights-con-laws-in-the-mississippi-supreme-court/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Goldwater Institute today filed a brief in the Mississippi Supreme Court urging the justices not to allow existing businesses..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/goldwater-fights-con-laws-in-the-mississippi-supreme-court/"&gt;Goldwater Fights CON Laws in the Mississippi Supreme Court&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 20:04:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] 2026 Capitol Chat: Week 2</title><link>https://empowerms.org/2026-capitol-chat-week-2/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Capitol Chat: Week 2 A sweeping education bill, hours of debate, and a narrow House vote put school choice at the center of Week 2 action. In this edition of Capitol Chat, we unpack what happened with House Bill 2, take a quick look at early budget hearings, and highlight a few things to look&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/2026-capitol-chat-week-2/"&gt;2026 Capitol Chat: Week 2&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 20:37:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Bothfield v. WEC &amp; WBLD v WEC</title><link>https://will-law.org/bothfield-v-wec-wbld-v-wec/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On behalf of Wisconsin voters in all 8 of the state's congressional districts, WILL filed motions to intervene in two lawsuits seeking to overturn Wisconsin’s Congressional Maps. Seeking again to defend those maps on behalf of a group of Wisconsin voters, WILL argues that these new lawsuits are time-barred, the three-judge panel lacks authority to overrule the Wisconsin Supreme Court, and any attempt to impose new maps in this manner would violate federal law and the U.S. Constitution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/bothfield-v-wec-wbld-v-wec/"&gt;Bothfield v. WEC &amp;#038; WBLD v WEC&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 21:19:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Coming Soon: More LA GATOR Scholarship Applications, Decision Time for State Leaders</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/education/lagator-coming-soon/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Louisiana families should prepare now: applications for the LA GATOR Scholarship Program are expected to open soon for the 2026–27 school year. This innovative education scholarship account (ESA) program gives parents the power to tailor their children’s education by allowing funds to be used for private school tuition, tutoring, curricula, technology, courses, and other approved...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/education/lagator-coming-soon/"&gt;Coming Soon: More LA GATOR Scholarship Applications, Decision Time for State Leaders&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 21:33:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Subsidies Cost Kansans Even When Revenues Rise</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/subsidies-cost-kansans-even-when-revenues-rise/</link><description>Why the Chiefs deal hurts people today and tomorrow In a previous post, I explained why the now-approved deal to bring the Kansas City Chiefs to Kansas is bad economics—built on diverted taxes, weakened guardrails, and decades of fiscal risk. What’s become even clearer since then is an often-overlooked truth: even if a subsidy generates [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 16:00:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Alternatives to ‘pausing’ Hawaii’s income tax cuts</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/01/alternatives-to-pausing-hawaiis-income-tax-cuts/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Remember that historically big tax cut passed in 2024 that was supposed to save Hawaii taxpayers more than $7 billion through 2031? Well, I hope you didn&amp;#8217;t count your chickens before they hatched because now it appears those phased-in cuts are already in danger. I had been hearing rumblings that Gov. Josh Green was intending [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/01/alternatives-to-pausing-hawaiis-income-tax-cuts/"&gt;Alternatives to &amp;#8216;pausing&amp;#8217; Hawaii&amp;#8217;s income tax cuts&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 19:13:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Portland Ends School Choice Policy for Jefferson High School</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/education/portland-ends-school-choice-policy-for-jefferson-high-school/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By John A. Charles, Jr. Fifteen years ago, the Portland Public Schools (PPS)...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/education/portland-ends-school-choice-policy-for-jefferson-high-school/"&gt;Portland Ends School Choice Policy for Jefferson High School&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 23:36:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] Alabama Policy Celebrates Governor Kay Ivey Opting Alabama into the Federal Education Freedom Tax Credit Program</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2026/01/20/alabama-policy-celebrates-governor-kay-ivey-opting-alabama-into-the-federal-education-freedom-tax-credit-program/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Alabama Policy is once again celebrating Governor Kay Ivey's unwavering support for School Choice in Alabama! Today, Governor Ivey signed Executive Order No. 742, expanding school choice in the state of Alabama by officially opting into the newly-created Federal Education Freedom Tax Credit program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2026/01/20/alabama-policy-celebrates-governor-kay-ivey-opting-alabama-into-the-federal-education-freedom-tax-credit-program/"&gt;Alabama Policy Celebrates Governor Kay Ivey Opting Alabama into the Federal Education Freedom Tax Credit Program&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 03:41:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] We need real performance metrics for Michigan public universities</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2026/we-need-real-performance-metrics-for-michigan-public-universities</link><description>Public spending should produce better results for students and society</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 11:02:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Rifreedom] “Doc” Skoly Stepping Down as Center’s Chair to Pursue Congressional Seat</title><link>https://rifreedom.org/2026/01/doc-skoly-stepping-down-as-centers-chair-to-pursue-congressional-seat/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The  Rhode Island Center for Freedom &amp;#038; Prosperity announced today that Dr. Stephen "Doc" Skoly has stepped down as Chairman of its Board of Directors to pursue a run for the US House of Representatives in Rhode Island's second Congressional district.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org/2026/01/doc-skoly-stepping-down-as-centers-chair-to-pursue-congressional-seat/"&gt;&amp;#8220;Doc&amp;#8221; Skoly Stepping Down as Center&amp;#8217;s Chair to Pursue Congressional Seat&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org"&gt;RI Center for Freedom and Prosperity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 15:10:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Alternatives to New England’s Energy Affordability Crisis</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/alternatives-to-new-englands-energy-affordability-crisis/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In 2024 Maine Policy Institute, along with a coalition of New England’s free-market think tanks, released an energy report which modeled the economic and reliability impacts of the energy policies passed in the six New England states. Alternatives to New England&amp;#8217;s Energy Affordability Crisis, released earlier this month, is a direct sequel to that report. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/alternatives-to-new-englands-energy-affordability-crisis/"&gt;Alternatives to New England’s Energy Affordability Crisis&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 15:56:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] A New Chapter for New Jersey</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/01/a-new-chapter-for-new-jersey/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Today, New Jersey turns the page. With the inauguration of Mikie Sherrill as the state’s 57th governor, New Jersey begins [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/01/a-new-chapter-for-new-jersey/"&gt;A New Chapter for New Jersey&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 16:13:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] InsiderNJ: NJPI Statement on the Appointment of Dr. Lily Laux as Commissioner of Education</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/01/insidernj-njpi-statement-on-the-appointment-of-dr-lily-laux-as-commissioner-of-education/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The New Jersey Policy Institute (NJPI) congratulates Dr. Lily Laux on her nomination to serve as New Jersey’s next Commissioner of [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/01/insidernj-njpi-statement-on-the-appointment-of-dr-lily-laux-as-commissioner-of-education/"&gt;InsiderNJ: NJPI Statement on the Appointment of Dr. Lily Laux as Commissioner of Education&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 16:24:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Newsom Has His Own Massive State Fraud Problem</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/newsom-has-his-own-massive-state-fraud-problem/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=newsom-has-his-own-massive-state-fraud-problem</link><description>&lt;p&gt;California’s scandal dwarfs Minnesota’s. Tim Walz perp-walked himself out of the Minnesota governor’s race this past week, beset by evidence that fraudsters have plundered his state’s federally funded food, housing, daycare, and Medicaid programs. It’s “what has been described as the nation’s largest COVID-era scheme,” says Fox News, with the U.S. attorney in Minnesota estimating “the fraud...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/newsom-has-his-own-massive-state-fraud-problem/"&gt;Newsom Has His Own Massive State Fraud Problem&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 16:52:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Freedom Foundation Authors Amicus Brief in Support of Ohio Wage Theft Case</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/press-release/freedom-foundation-authors-amicus-brief-in-support-of-ohio-wage-theft-case/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Freedom Foundation attorney James Abernathy authored an amicus brief joined by other national workers’ rights protections groups to back The Buckeye Institute's appeal in asking the Ohio Supreme Court to hear their case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/press-release/freedom-foundation-authors-amicus-brief-in-support-of-ohio-wage-theft-case/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation Authors Amicus Brief in Support of Ohio Wage Theft Case&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 16:58:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Governor Tate Reeves: Momentum and Good Policy</title><link>https://empowerms.org/governor-tate-reeves-momentum-and-good-policy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Governor Tate Reeves: Momentum and Good Policy In this episode of the Empower Podcast, Grant Callen sits down with Governor Tate Reeves for a wide-ranging conversation about the state’s growing momentum and what comes next. Recorded from the Governor’s office overlooking the State Capitol, the discussion explores why Mississippi is climbing national rankings for wage&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/governor-tate-reeves-momentum-and-good-policy/"&gt;Governor Tate Reeves: Momentum and Good Policy&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 18:43:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Policy Pathway for Principled Tax Reform</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/policy-pathway-for-principled-tax-reform/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Policy Pathway for Principled Tax Reform outlines a framework for evaluating tax policy through the lens of sound tax principles including transparency, simplicity, stability, neutrality, and economic efficiency. The report examines Nebraska’s major tax types including property, income, and sales and offers practical, principle-based recommendations to improve affordability, competitiveness, and long-term fiscal sustainability. While designed...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/policy-pathway-for-principled-tax-reform/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Policy Pathway for Principled Tax Reform&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 19:40:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Florida Politics: Unused K-12 Scholarship Funds Are a Feature, Not a Bug</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/florida-politics-unused-k-12-scholarship-funds-are-a-feature-not-a-bug/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;If the&amp;#160;Florida Restaurant Association&amp;#160;ever detects a shortage of chefs in our state, the first place it should look...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/florida-politics-unused-k-12-scholarship-funds-are-a-feature-not-a-bug/"&gt;Florida Politics: Unused K-12 Scholarship Funds Are a Feature, Not a Bug&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 21:04:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] The Empire Center Reacts to Governor Hochul’s Budget Address</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/the-empire-center-reacts-to-governor-hochuls-budget-address/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In response to the release of Governor Hochul’s executive budget proposal for fiscal 2027, the Empire Center issued the following....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/the-empire-center-reacts-to-governor-hochuls-budget-address/"&gt;The Empire Center Reacts to Governor Hochul&amp;#8217;s Budget Address&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 21:32:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] New property tax assessed valuation limit legislation saves money, eliminates prior concerns</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/assessed-valuation-limit-saves-money/</link><description>New legislation to limit increases in taxable assessed valuation addresses two concerns opponents raised last year, with two major improvements. Some people last year feared that limiting appraised values would distort the property&amp;#8217;s market value. This year’s legislation, SCR 1616, doesn’t affect appraisals and instead limits the increase in the taxable assessed value of a [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 22:49:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] House Bill 493 — Commercial sexual activity, penalty (-1)</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/house-bill-493-commercial-sexual-activity-penalty/</link><description>Bill Description:&amp;#160;House Bill 493 would make the first offense of soliciting commercial sexual activity a felony rather than a misdemeanor and apply a mandatory minimum sentence of incarceration. NOTE: House Bill 493&amp;#160;is similar to House Bill 88, introduced in the 2025 Legislative Session. Rating: -1 Does it directly or indirectly create or increase penalties for [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 03:15:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Give credit where due on the roads deal</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2026/give-credit-where-due-on-the-roads-deal</link><description>Whitmer gets 20%</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Goldwater Asks Court for Transparency in Maricopa County Sheriff’s Case</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/goldwater-asks-court-for-transparency-in-maricopa-county-sheriffs-case/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Goldwater Institute on Tuesday filed a friend of the court brief in federal court asking the judge to allow..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/goldwater-asks-court-for-transparency-in-maricopa-county-sheriffs-case/"&gt;Goldwater Asks Court for Transparency in Maricopa County Sheriff’s Case&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 13:00:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Nuclear being considered to address rising grid demand in Washington</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/post/nuclear-being-considered-to-address-rising-grid-demand-in-washington</link><description>Washington needs to seriously consider additional nuclear power that can meet the rising grid demand for generations to come.</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 14:03:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cardinalinstitute] Healthcare in West Virginia</title><link>https://cardinalinstitute.com/healthcare-in-west-virginia/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Healthcare in West Virginia Healthcare policy is complicated. These resources make it understandable. If you are trying to make sense of West Virginia’s latest healthcare debates, you are not alone. PBM regulation, PEIA’s recurring funding crises, and Certificate of Need laws all affect what care costs, where it is available, and who has choices. We [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com/healthcare-in-west-virginia/"&gt;Healthcare in West Virginia&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com"&gt;Cardinal Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 15:44:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Reserves are a Cushion, Not a Strategy</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/reserves-are-a-cushion-not-a-strategy/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Reserves are a Cushion, Not a Strategy" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/iowa-us-flags.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iowa’s budget remains structurally sound, but spending is accelerating: The FY 2026 budget totals about $9.4 billion—up more than 5 percent year over year—raising sustainability concerns even as lawmakers face a $1 billion shortfall that is not a true deficit due to large reserve balances. Strong reserves and credit ratings provide a cushion, not a blank check: Iowa closed FY 2025 with nearly $1.9 billion in surplus, more than $900 million in reserves, and roughly $4 billion in the Taxpayer Relief Fund, helping maintain AAA credit ratings—but rating agencies warn disciplined spending must continue. Tax reform was planned and paid for by restraint, not federal windfalls: The full phase-in of the 3.8 percent flat tax reduced state revenues as expected, leaving more money with taxpayers; maintaining conservative budgeting—rather than using reserves to fuel faster spending growth—is essential to preserve fiscal stability and enable future reforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/reserves-are-a-cushion-not-a-strategy/"&gt;Reserves are a Cushion, Not a Strategy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 15:56:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Federal Tax Conformity for Tax Cuts Should Happen Now</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/federal-tax-conformity-for-tax-cuts-should-happen-now/</link><description>Why are Idahoans being told to wait for Trump’s tax cuts? At the beginning of each legislative session, the Joint Finance-Appropriations Committee (JFAC) adopts — or attempts to adopt — a three-year revenue estimate: the current fiscal year and the two upcoming — in this case, an update for Fiscal Year 2026 (FY26), FY27, and [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 17:19:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Wisconsin Senate Passes WILL-Backed ﻿Amendment to End Tax-Veto Loopholes</title><link>https://will-law.org/wisconsin-senate-passes-will-backed-amendment-to-end-tax-veto-loopholes/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL issued a statement applauding the Wisconsin State Senate for passing Senate Joint Resolution 116 (SJR 116). This proposed amendment to the Wisconsin Constitution curbs executive overreach by prohibiting the governor from using the partial veto to create or increase taxes or fees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/wisconsin-senate-passes-will-backed-amendment-to-end-tax-veto-loopholes/"&gt;Wisconsin Senate Passes WILL-Backed ﻿Amendment to End Tax-Veto Loopholes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 17:40:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] The Wisconsin Higher-Ed Reform Model</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/the-wisconsin-higher-ed-reform-model/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Republican lawmakers managed to pass a conservative-coded policy in a purple state with a Democratic governor. It’s all well and good to point to Florida or Texas and wish that every state could do likewise. Unfortunately, not every state capitol boasts a conservative governor ready to pick controversial fights backed up by a large Republican majority. Wisconsin demonstrates that even purple states can win meaningful, albeit limited, conservative victories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/the-wisconsin-higher-ed-reform-model/"&gt;The Wisconsin Higher-Ed Reform Model&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 17:42:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Why Fossil Fuel Use Must Increase: The Numerical Reality</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/why-fossil-fuel-use-must-increase-the-numerical-reality/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=why-fossil-fuel-use-must-increase-the-numerical-reality</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Statistical Review of Global Energy, has been published every year since 2023 by The Energy Institute. For nearly 75 years before that it was published by British Petroleum. It is one of the most authoritative sources available for energy statistics. It is a terrific place, if not the place, to develop a deeper understanding of our global...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/why-fossil-fuel-use-must-increase-the-numerical-reality/"&gt;Why Fossil Fuel Use Must Increase: The Numerical Reality&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 19:30:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Cured of Cancer—and Now Advocating for Others’ Right to Try</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/cured-of-cancer-and-now-advocating-for-others-right-to-try/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;“A little soreness is just a symptom of a dual sport athlete.” That was the thought that Diego Morris and..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/cured-of-cancer-and-now-advocating-for-others-right-to-try/"&gt;Cured of Cancer—and Now Advocating for Others’ Right to Try&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 19:47:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Governor Evers’ property tax relief plan fails to constrain property tax growth</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/governor-evers-property-tax-relief-plan-fails-to-constrain-property-tax-growth/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Policymakers are scrambling for solutions as Wisconsin property tax burdens continue to rise. As homeowners clamor for relief, Gov. Tony Evers (D) has proposed using $1.3 billion from the state’s surplus to buy down property tax bills. Unfortunately, the proposal does nothing to address the structural drivers of high (and rising) property taxes and, if anything, puts more pressure on them in the future. His proposal commits the state to subsidies that shift burdens rather than alleviate them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/governor-evers-property-tax-relief-plan-fails-to-constrain-property-tax-growth/"&gt;Governor Evers’ property tax relief plan fails to constrain property tax growth&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 19:58:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] How Iowa Can Defend Property Rights Through Property Tax Reform</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/how-iowa-can-defend-property-rights-through-property-tax-reform/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="How Iowa Can Defend Property Rights Through Property Tax Reform" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/national-review-1200x630-1.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“As the Founders saw it, the right to property was not simply an economic concept and was much more than owning a bit of land. It was a first principle of liberty,” Spalding argued. Property is not limited to land or a home; it also includes financial assets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/how-iowa-can-defend-property-rights-through-property-tax-reform/"&gt;How Iowa Can Defend Property Rights Through Property Tax Reform&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 20:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Idaho Freedom Foundation Calls for Investigation into University Defiance of Landmark DEI Ban</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/idaho-freedom-foundation-calls-for-investigation-into-university-defiance-of-landmark-dei-ban/</link><description>BOISE, ID — The Idaho Freedom Foundation (IFF), in partnership with the Goldwater Institute, is sounding the alarm on blatant attempts by Idaho’s higher education establishment to circumvent Senate Bill 1198 (S1198), or the Freedom from Indoctrination Act; the nation’s most comprehensive ban on mandatory Diversity, Equity, and Inclusion (DEI) instruction: In a formal letter [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 20:24:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] WILL-Backed Equality Amendment ﻿On November 2026 Ballot</title><link>https://will-law.org/will-backed-equality-amendment-on-november-2026-ballot/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The “Equality Amendment,” otherwise known as Assembly Joint Resolution 102 (AJR 102) will be on the November 2026 ballot after the Wisconsin State Senate voted in favor today. The Wisconsin State Assembly passed the amendment last week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/will-backed-equality-amendment-on-november-2026-ballot/"&gt;WILL-Backed Equality Amendment ﻿On November 2026 Ballot&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 20:58:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Parental choice surge in Idaho: Trends and projections on state's new tax credit program</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/post/parental-choice-surge-in-idaho-trends-and-projections-on-state-s-new-tax-credit-program</link><description>New figures from the Idaho State Tax Commission show Idaho families are moving quickly to take advantage of the state’s new parental choice tax credit — and early application volume suggests demand will be strong throughout the open enrollment period.</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 21:17:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Statement in Response to Transportation for Massachusetts Report and MassBudget and Policy Center</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/statement-in-response-to-transportation-for-massachusetts-report-and-massbudget-and-policy-center/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Massachusetts taxpayers were told in 2022 that raising taxes and directing billions in new tax revenues to transportation would dramatically improve quality and reliability. Voters were told the surtax would fix the system. Barely three years later—here we go again.   The...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/statement-in-response-to-transportation-for-massachusetts-report-and-massbudget-and-policy-center/"&gt;Statement in Response to Transportation for Massachusetts Report and MassBudget and Policy Center&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 21:22:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Competing ‘pressers’ expose a dangerous lack of coordination between local and federal law enforcement leaders in Operation Metro Surge</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/competing-pressers-illustrate-a-dangerous-lack-of-coordination-between-local-and-federal-law-enforcement-leaders-in-operation-metro-surge/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday morning a group of local law enforcement leaders gathered at the State Capitol for a press conference drawing attention to their concern that a small number of federal agents may be racially profiling as part of the immigration enforcement detail known as Operation Metro Surge. A short time later, at the Whipple Building in...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/competing-pressers-illustrate-a-dangerous-lack-of-coordination-between-local-and-federal-law-enforcement-leaders-in-operation-metro-surge/"&gt;Competing &amp;#8216;pressers&amp;#8217; expose a dangerous lack of coordination between local and federal law enforcement leaders in Operation Metro Surge&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 22:17:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Cascade Policy Institute is Hiring – Development Assistant</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/news/cascade-policy-institute-is-hiring-development-assistant/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;We are seeking a detail-oriented, organized, part-time Development Assistant to support Cascade Policy...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/news/cascade-policy-institute-is-hiring-development-assistant/"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute is Hiring &amp;#8211; Development Assistant&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 23:07:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Trim special funds before hitting pause on historic income tax cuts</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/01/trim-special-funds-before-hitting-pause-on-historic-income-tax-cuts/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following “Island Voices” commentary was first published on Jan. 20, 2026, in the Honolulu Star-Advertiser under the headline “Tamp down special funds, not tax cuts.”_____________ By Jonathan Helton and Ahryanna McGuirk The state Department of Budget and Finance recently confirmed that Gov. Josh Green’s proposed budget plan features a “pause” of at least part [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/01/trim-special-funds-before-hitting-pause-on-historic-income-tax-cuts/"&gt;Trim special funds before hitting pause on historic income tax cuts&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 04:26:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Federal auditors seek $1B from California for illegal benefits</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/federal-auditors-seek-1b-from-california-for-illegal-benefits/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Megan Barth writes for the California Globe about an interesting development in the Golden State. In a major escalation of federal oversight, audits by the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services (CMS) under the Trump administration have determined that California must repay more than $1 billion in improperly claimed federal Medicaid funds tied to healthcare...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/federal-auditors-seek-1b-from-california-for-illegal-benefits/"&gt;Federal auditors seek $1B from California for illegal benefits&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 10:42:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Want to boost Michigan? Stop punishing R&amp;D</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2026/want-to-boost-michigan-stop-punishing-r-d</link><description>Tax policies penalize companies that invest in innovation</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Chicago Public Schools students thrive through academic rigor</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/chicago-public-schools-students-thrive-through-academic-rigor/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Chicago Public Schools’ school choice experiment is working: students at the city’s selective enrollment schools are thriving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/chicago-public-schools-students-thrive-through-academic-rigor/"&gt;Chicago Public Schools students thrive through academic rigor&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 11:00:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Idaho joins the nation’s first federal education choice tax credit scholarship program</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/post/idaho-joins-the-nation-s-first-federal-education-choice-tax-credit-scholarship-program</link><description>Idaho has taken a significant step forward in expanding educational opportunity by joining the nation’s first federal education choice tax credit scholarship program.</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 13:18:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Offshore wind: known and speculative national security risks</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/offshore-wind-known-and-speculative-national-security-risks/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Citing national security risks, the U.S. Department of the Interior (DOI)&amp;#160;announced&amp;#160;on Dec. 22, 2025, that it was pausing the leases “for all large-scale offshore wind projects under construction in the United States.” Because the projects affected are already under construction, this halt is different from President Donald Trump’s&amp;#160;earlier directive&amp;#160;halting government leasing of offshore wind projects....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/offshore-wind-known-and-speculative-national-security-risks/"&gt;Offshore wind: known and speculative national security risks&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 14:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Three Plans, One Goal as Legislation is Introduced</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/three-plans-one-goal-as-legislation-is-introduced/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Three Plans, One Goal as Legislation is Introduced" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/AdobeStock_329581775-e1769093766888.jpeg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Property tax reform has moved quickly into action in 2026, with Republicans in both chambers and Governor Kim Reynolds advancing comprehensive proposals aimed at slowing property tax growth and addressing long-standing structural problems in Iowa’s system. The Senate, Governor, and House proposals share common goals but take different approaches, including caps on local government revenue growth, changes to assessment practices, shifts in school funding, limits on TIF, and varying mixes of exemptions, freezes, and tax base adjustments. The House proposal stands out by prioritizing transparency and structural restraint, improving property tax disclosure statements and avoiding targeted exemptions or freezes for specific groups, reflecting a broader debate over how to provide relief while minimizing unintended consequences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/three-plans-one-goal-as-legislation-is-introduced/"&gt;Three Plans, One Goal as Legislation is Introduced&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 14:54:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Assembly clears bill to tackle fears of data center spiking power rates</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/assembly-clears-bill-to-tackle-fears-of-data-center-spiking-power-rates/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The state Assembly this week passed a bill barring data centers from passing on any utility costs to other ratepayers in Wisconsin — targeting a key objection from Wisconsinites who oppose data center development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assembly Bill 840, passed 53-44 almost entirely along party lines, also requires new data centers to use water-conserving technology for cooling and to report annual water use to the Department of Natural Resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/assembly-clears-bill-to-tackle-fears-of-data-center-spiking-power-rates/"&gt;Assembly clears bill to tackle fears of data center spiking power rates&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 15:50:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Habeas Corpus floods the zone</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/habeas-corpus-floods-the-zone/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In classic Saul Alinsky/Cloward-Piven-style, immigration lawyers have overwhelmed the local federal district court with habeas corpus filings to bring normal court business to a halt. Habeas corpus (lit. produce the body) filings demand emergency relief to have a suspect released from custody by a judge&amp;#8217;s order. As of today (Thursday, Jan. 22), 319 habeas petitions...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/habeas-corpus-floods-the-zone/"&gt;Habeas Corpus floods the zone&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 17:05:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Paving the way for microschools in North Carolina</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/paving-the-way-for-microschools-in-north-carolina/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When I founded Burbrella Microschools, I never imagined that one of the biggest barriers to serving children — especially neurodivergent, gifted, and underserved learners — would come from something as basic as zoning. Yet that is exactly what I encountered when I purchased the property that became our new campus. Even after proving our impact...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/paving-the-way-for-microschools-in-north-carolina/"&gt;Paving the way for microschools in North Carolina&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 17:32:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Red tape is strangling rural health care. It’s time to cut it</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/red-tape-is-strangling-rural-health-care-its-time-to-cut-it/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Rural America is running out of doctors. According to a new report from the Commonwealth Fund, 43 million Americans now live in rural communities facing a shortage of primary care providers. This shortage isn&amp;#8217;t new. It&amp;#8217;s been reality for rural America for decades. And it helps explain why patients there experience higher rates of chronic [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/red-tape-is-strangling-rural-health-care-its-time-to-cut-it/"&gt;Red tape is strangling rural health care. It&amp;#8217;s time to cut it&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 18:17:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Brandeis Is Doing Something About Grade Inflation. Will Texas Be Next?</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/brandeis-is-doing-something-about-grade-inflation-will-texas-be-next/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This is a good-news, bad-news tale for American higher education. The good news: A top-tier university has finally taken serious aim at the epidemic of grade hyperinflation. The bad news: We have fallen so far that even elite institutions must now devise entirely new, parallel evaluation systems just to deliver what straightforward, principled grading should...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/brandeis-is-doing-something-about-grade-inflation-will-texas-be-next/"&gt;Brandeis Is Doing Something About Grade Inflation. Will Texas Be Next?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 18:31:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG Issues Demand Letter to DPI Over Year-Long Delay on Dairyland Sentinel’s Public Records Request</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-issues-demand-letter-to-dpi-over-year-long-delay-on-dairyland-sentinels-public-records-request/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;IRG Issues Demand Letter to DPI Over Year-Long Delay on Dairyland Sentinel&amp;#8217;s Public Records Request Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government (IRG) sent a formal demand letter to the Wisconsin Department of Public Instruction (DPI) on Thursday seeking the immediate release of public records that have been withheld for one year. The original [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-issues-demand-letter-to-dpi-over-year-long-delay-on-dairyland-sentinels-public-records-request/"&gt;IRG Issues Demand Letter to DPI Over Year-Long Delay on Dairyland Sentinel&amp;#8217;s Public Records Request&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 18:56:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Louisiana’s Legal Reforms: A Step Toward Fairer Courts and Lower Auto Insurance Rates</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/legal-regulatory/la_legal_reforms/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As 2026 gets underway, Louisiana residents finally have reason to celebrate real progress in our long fight against skyrocketing auto insurance rates. Governor Jeff Landry, Insurance Commissioner Tim Temple, and state lawmakers deserve credit for pushing through a series of reforms in 2025 that are now reshaping our legal system and helping to bring down...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/legal-regulatory/la_legal_reforms/"&gt;Louisiana’s Legal Reforms: A Step Toward Fairer Courts and Lower Auto Insurance Rates&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 19:01:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] New Jersey at a Crossroads: Looking back on Governor Murphy and Ahead to Mikie Sherrill</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/01/new-jersey-at-a-crossroads-looking-back-on-governor-murphy-and-ahead-to-mikie-sherrill/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;by Megan Whitman, NJPI Jr. Economy Fellow As Governor Phil Murphy officially left office this week after eight years, New [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/01/new-jersey-at-a-crossroads-looking-back-on-governor-murphy-and-ahead-to-mikie-sherrill/"&gt;New Jersey at a Crossroads: Looking back on Governor Murphy and Ahead to Mikie Sherrill&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 19:02:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Chicago Teachers Union releases ‘annual’ audits 5 years late</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/chicago-teachers-union-releases-annual-audits-5-years-late/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Chicago Teachers Union leaders fought members, a Congressional inquiry and a potential U.S. Department of Labor investigation over audits. Now we know why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/chicago-teachers-union-releases-annual-audits-5-years-late/"&gt;Chicago Teachers Union releases ‘annual’ audits 5 years late&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 19:19:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Florida Politics: Skip the lawsuits, teach the kids</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/edward-longe-skip-the-lawsuits-teach-the-kids/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Teaching kids digital literacy beats unconstitutional mandates and endless lawsuits. For parents navigating the rise of social media...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/edward-longe-skip-the-lawsuits-teach-the-kids/"&gt;Florida Politics: Skip the lawsuits, teach the kids&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 19:29:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] No Accountability as Insurers Profit From Public Programs</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/no-accountability-as-insurers-profit-from-public-programs/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Executives from the nation&amp;#8217;s largest health insurers are set to testify before Congress soon in a hearing on healthcare affordability. It&amp;#8217;s about time. From Medicare Advantage to Obamacare exchanges to prescription drug benefits, insurers have been extracting ever-greater amounts of public funds while passing costs and risk on to patients and taxpayers. Read the op-ed [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/no-accountability-as-insurers-profit-from-public-programs/"&gt;No Accountability as Insurers Profit From Public Programs&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 19:38:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Missouri Forms an Advanced Nuclear Task Force</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/article/economy/missouri-forms-an-advanced-nuclear-task-force/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Governor Kehoe recently signed an executive order establishing the “Missouri Advanced Nuclear Task Force” as part of an “all-in” commitment on nuclear energy in Missouri. The new task force is [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/article/economy/missouri-forms-an-advanced-nuclear-task-force/"&gt;Missouri Forms an Advanced Nuclear Task Force&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 20:30:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] The Budget Mirage Reappears</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/article/budget-and-spending/the-budget-mirage-reappears/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;To borrow from Yogi Berra, it is déjà vu all over again. For the past two years, I have warned that Missouri’s budget totals are likely misleading. Lawmakers are routinely [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/article/budget-and-spending/the-budget-mirage-reappears/"&gt;The Budget Mirage Reappears&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 20:51:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Greenland shows the limits and opportunities of Danish statecraft</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/greenland-shows-the-limits-and-opportunities-of-danish-statecraft/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;American interest in Greenland confronts Denmark with a choice it has faced before. With strategic imagination, it could engage the US to forge a mutually beneficial path for the island’s future. Denmark is well-practised in the relinquishment of its lands. The Danish kingdom was compelled by war to surrender Norway (to Sweden) and Schleswig-Holstein (to Prussia) in...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/greenland-shows-the-limits-and-opportunities-of-danish-statecraft/"&gt;Greenland shows the limits and opportunities of Danish statecraft&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 20:57:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Charter Schools Do Special Education Better</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/article/education/charter-schools-do-special-education-better/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A new study by Scott Imberman and Andrew Johnson shows that special education students benefit from attending charter schools. Using data from Michigan, the authors identify the effects of charter [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/article/education/charter-schools-do-special-education-better/"&gt;Charter Schools Do Special Education Better&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 21:01:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] The University of Austin Shows What Education Should Be</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/the-university-of-austin-shows-what-education-should-be/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The inaugural Austin Union event, back in March 2024, featured a debate on the question: Is the United States Constitution broken? Later that evening, University of Austin (UATX) hosted A Conversation on Free Speech, Civil Discourse &amp;#38; Debate in a Healthy Democracy, featuring former ACLU president Nadine Strossen and then-presidential candidate Robert F. Kennedy Jr....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/the-university-of-austin-shows-what-education-should-be/"&gt;The University of Austin Shows What Education Should Be&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 21:07:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] ‘A family’s worst nightmare’</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/a-familys-worst-nightmare/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The abduction The abduction of a seven-year-old girl in Zimmerman yesterday afternoon began what the Bureau of Criminal Apprehension’s Superintendent Drew Evans described as “a family’s worst nightmare.” It ended in the best possible way about nine hours later and 135 miles away, when Albert Lea police stopped and arrested the suspect as he drove...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/a-familys-worst-nightmare/"&gt;&amp;#8216;A family’s worst nightmare&amp;#8217;&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 21:08:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Is Hochul Really Going to Shut Down the Essential Plan?</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/is-hochul-really-going-to-shut-down-the-essential-plan/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Governor Hochul is hingeing a big chunk of her budget – and the state&amp;#8217;s health-care system – on a politically....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/is-hochul-really-going-to-shut-down-the-essential-plan/"&gt;Is Hochul Really Going to Shut Down the Essential Plan?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 21:41:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Facts Over Fear: What Mainers Should Know About ICE Enforcement</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/facts-over-fear-what-mainers-should-know-about-ice-enforcement/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Recent headlines have reignited debate in Maine over immigration enforcement and the authority of federal agents to operate within our communities. Immigration enforcement is a lawful federal responsibility. ICE operates under defined legal constraints, and claims that agents are “roaming without warrants” misrepresent how federal law enforcement works. Mischaracterizing immigration enforcement in Maine erodes trust [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/facts-over-fear-what-mainers-should-know-about-ice-enforcement/"&gt;Facts Over Fear: What Mainers Should Know About ICE Enforcement&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 21:42:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Census: 95% of Illinoisans moving out head to lower-tax states</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/census-95-of-illinoisans-moving-out-head-to-lower-tax-states/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;U.S. Census estimates showed Illinois lost residents to 32 states and Washington, D.C. – virtually all to lower-tax states.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/census-95-of-illinoisans-moving-out-head-to-lower-tax-states/"&gt;Census: 95% of Illinoisans moving out head to lower-tax states&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 23:15:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Newsom budget expands green subsidies taxpayers can’t afford</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/newsom-budget-expands-green-subsidies-taxpayers-cant-afford/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;California is staring at a $3 billion budget deficit, but Gov. Gavin Newsom still wants to spend $200 million on electric vehicle rebates. It’s both a foolish gesture and a graphic example of why Sacramento can’t get spending under control. The funds would replace the $7,500 federal EV tax credits for new cars that ended [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/newsom-budget-expands-green-subsidies-taxpayers-cant-afford/"&gt;Newsom budget expands green subsidies taxpayers can’t afford&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:05:32 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>