<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>State-Policy Think-Tank Digest</title><link>https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml</link><description>Latest posts from free-market policy institutes across the U.S.</description><atom:link href="https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 10:04:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>[Arkansaspolicyfoundation] ARKANSAS GOV. SARAH HUCKABEE SANDERS &amp; STATE INCOME TAX CUTS</title><link>https://arkansaspolicyfoundation.org/arkansas-gov-sarah-huckabee-sanders-state-income-tax-cuts/</link><description>(4Q-2025) Arkansas Gov. Sarah Huckabee Sanders is the Natural State’s first female governor. Since taking office in January 2023, Sanders has also distinguished herself by advancing three separate reductions in Arkansas’ top income tax rate from 4.9 to 3.9 percent. The income tax was reduced from 7.0% to 6.9% in 2013 under Democratic Gov. Mike [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 14:33:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Todd Schaible: The Importance of Career and Technical Education in Tennessee Schools</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/todd-schaible-the-importance-of-career-technical-education-in-tennessee-schools/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=todd-schaible-the-importance-of-career-technical-education-in-tennessee-schools</link><description>By elevating CTE in Tennessee schools, we can increase support for employers and improve workforce readiness for students across the state.</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 15:34:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Enrollment and Employment: Is Tennessee Preparing K-12 Students for Today’s Economy?</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/enrollment-and-employment-is-tennessee-preparing-k-12-students-for-todays-economy/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=enrollment-and-employment-is-tennessee-preparing-k-12-students-for-todays-economy</link><description>Tennessee is doing well in providing Career and Technical Education (CTE) opportunities to students, but policymakers should recognize that improvements can be made.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 02:17:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] U.S. House defangs federal protection of gray wolves in Wisconsin</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/us-house-defangs-federal-protection-of-gray-wolves-in-wisconsin/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The U.S. House of Representatives Thursday passed a bill that would remove the state’s rapidly expanding and aggressive gray wolf population from the endangered species list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/us-house-defangs-federal-protection-of-gray-wolves-in-wisconsin/"&gt;U.S. House defangs federal protection of gray wolves in Wisconsin&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 22:32:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Ugly Math for Taxpayers</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/ugly-math-for-taxpayers/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=ugly-math-for-taxpayers</link><description>Taxpayer-funded lobbying (TFL) is nothing new in Tennessee, but it is almost universally frowned upon.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 22:52:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Ninety New York Educators Receive $300k+ in Annual Pay</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/ninety-new-york-educators-receive-300k-in-annual-pay/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Ninety employees from New York’s school districts (outside New York City) received more than $300,000 during fiscal year 2025, according....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/ninety-new-york-educators-receive-300k-in-annual-pay/"&gt;Ninety New York Educators Receive $300k+ in Annual Pay&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 14:27:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] California Home Care Workers Take on Union Abuse in Court</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/litigation/california-home-care-workers-take-on-union-abuse-in-court/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, the Freedom Foundation filed a class-action lawsuit against United Domestic Workers of America, AFSCME Local 3930 (UDW) on behalf of in-home supportive services (IHSS) workers across California. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/litigation/california-home-care-workers-take-on-union-abuse-in-court/" rel="nofollow"&gt;California Home Care Workers Take on Union Abuse in Court&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 15:50:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] In Case You Missed It: WILL Raised Key Voter Roll Concerns Ahead of DOJ Lawsuit</title><link>https://will-law.org/in-case-you-missed-it-will-raised-key-voter-roll-concerns-ahead-of-doj-lawsuit/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Department of Justice has filed a lawsuit against the Wisconsin Election Commission’s (WEC) for refusing to comply with their investigation into the state’s voter rolls. The request from USDOJ was for a copy of Wisconsin’s computerized registration list including information necessary to audit the list for ineligible voters, including driver’s license number and/or the last 4 digits of the social security number. The lawsuit also comes after an investigation from our organization released earlier this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/in-case-you-missed-it-will-raised-key-voter-roll-concerns-ahead-of-doj-lawsuit/"&gt;In Case You Missed It: WILL Raised Key Voter Roll Concerns Ahead of DOJ Lawsuit&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 15:57:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] Civic Foundations: Are we Properly Preparing the Next Generation of Citizens?</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/12/civic-foundations-are-we-properly-preparing-the-next-generation-of-citizens/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;by Aiden DeMarsey – Evesham Twp. Board of Ed. Member &amp;#38; NJPI Junior Education Policy Fellow The state of New [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/12/civic-foundations-are-we-properly-preparing-the-next-generation-of-citizens/"&gt;Civic Foundations: Are we Properly Preparing the Next Generation of Citizens?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 18:30:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] The Economic and Legal Risks of New Jersey’s Proposed Climate Superfund Act</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/12/the-economic-and-legal-risks-of-new-jerseys-proposed-climate-superfund-act/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Sean Barry, NJPI Junior Energy Policy Fellow For the past several months, New Jersey lawmakers have been considering Assembly [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/12/the-economic-and-legal-risks-of-new-jerseys-proposed-climate-superfund-act/"&gt;The Economic and Legal Risks of New Jersey’s Proposed Climate Superfund Act&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 18:35:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF discusses MLG National Guard deployment as they depart</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-discusses-mlg-national-guard-deployment-as-they-depart/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In a unique example of the Rio Grande Foundation being more positive about the Gov.&amp;#8217;s policy than the Gov. herself, the Rio Grande Foundation was asked to comment on whether MLG&amp;#8217;s deployment of the National Guard to Albuquerque was &amp;#8220;a disappointment.&amp;#8221; On the one hand, while we 100% agree with the Gov. that &amp;#8220;lax engagement [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-discusses-mlg-national-guard-deployment-as-they-depart/"&gt;RGF discusses MLG National Guard deployment as they depart&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 18:49:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] From Magna Carta to Mass Arrests: Britain’s Warning to America</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/from-magna-carta-to-mass-arrests-britains-warning-to-america/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Imagine facing arrest simply for posting sharp or critical comments online. Picture police at your door for expressing opposition to mass immigration. Envision a country where you could be imprisoned for years without a jury ever deciding your guilt. This isn't dystopian fiction - it's the reality unfolding in Britain today, my former home and [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/from-magna-carta-to-mass-arrests-britains-warning-to-america/" rel="nofollow"&gt;From Magna Carta to Mass Arrests: Britain’s Warning to America&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 20:01:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Guest Editorial: The role of Credit Unions in Nebraska</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/guest-editorial-the-role-of-credit-unions-in-nebraska/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Credit unions have always stood apart from other financial services providers because of how and why they were first built starting in 1864. Credit Unions are formed by people — workers such as manufacturing employees, farmers, teachers,firefighters, church groups and more to pool their resources and provide low-cost credit to one another. That origin story...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/guest-editorial-the-role-of-credit-unions-in-nebraska/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Guest Editorial: The role of Credit Unions in Nebraska&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 16:46:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] New York’s Education Shows Improvement, but Questions Remain</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/new-yorks-education-shows-improvement-but-questions-remain/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In the effort to improve transparency and accountability of New York’s education system, the Empire Center has systematized and published....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/new-yorks-education-shows-improvement-but-questions-remain/"&gt;New York&amp;#8217;s Education Shows Improvement, but Questions Remain&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 14:15:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] Allen Mendenhall: API’s Christmas wish list</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/12/26/allen-mendenhall-apis-christmas-wish-list/</link><description>&lt;p&gt; The Alabama Policy Institute (API) has delivered its "Blueprint for 2026: Building a Stronger Alabama" with the seasonal timing of a policy wonk’s Christmas morning, complete with 30 wrapped proposals arranged beneath three conceptual ornaments: free markets, limited government, and strong families.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/12/26/allen-mendenhall-apis-christmas-wish-list/"&gt;Allen Mendenhall: API&amp;#8217;s Christmas wish list&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 18:50:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF president discusses massive cost of MLG’s “free” childcare plans on KOAT 7</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-president-discusses-massive-cost-of-mlgs-free-childcare-plans-on-koat-7/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;RGF has raised concerns about the impact of the Gov&amp;#8217;s plans to expand &amp;#8220;free&amp;#8221; child care to those New Mexico families who make MORE THAN 400% of the federal poverty level (about $128,000 for a family of four). Is the program financially sustainable at a time of moderating oil revenues? According to the Legislative Finance [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-president-discusses-massive-cost-of-mlgs-free-childcare-plans-on-koat-7/"&gt;RGF president discusses massive cost of MLG&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8220;free&amp;#8221; childcare plans on KOAT 7&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 16:18:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] $2 billion Chiefs stadium deal won’t fix the Kansas economy, but property tax relief would help</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/chiefs-stadium-deal-wont-fix-kansas-economy/</link><description>Kansas Governor Laura Kelly declared it a “once-in-a-generation opportunity” to transform the state’s economy by delivering thousands of new jobs and billions of dollars in new business activity. That was in 2022, when she announced the state would give Panasonic $829 million to build an electric battery plant in Johnson County. Her hoped-for economic transformation [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 17:03:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Libertas] A Year of Impact: 1.3+ Million Families</title><link>https://libertas.org/2025-report/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In early 2025 we set out an ambitious &amp;#8220;Vivid Vision&amp;#8221; for our team to grow our impact and scale up our work, and the end-of-year results demonstrate significant progress across all our initiatives. In total, we positively impacted more than 1.3 million families! Below, watch a 15-minute update sharing our 2025 impact, presented by our [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://libertas.org/2025-report/"&gt;A Year of Impact: 1.3+ Million Families&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://libertas.org"&gt;The Libertas Network: Changing Hearts, Minds, and Laws&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 01:49:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Shrinking 82nd Avenue: John Charles Responds to Tyler Frisbee</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/transportation/shrinking-82nd-avenue-john-charles-responds-to-tyler-frisbee/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By John A. Charles, Jr. At TriMet’s December 10 board meeting, director Tyler...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/transportation/shrinking-82nd-avenue-john-charles-responds-to-tyler-frisbee/"&gt;Shrinking 82nd Avenue: John Charles Responds to Tyler Frisbee&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 23:06:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Matt’s Top Stories of 2025</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/matts-top-stories-of-2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On Matt&amp;#8217;s last WGAN show of 2025, he reflects on significant events of the year: Listen here: Newsradio WGAN · Matt&amp;#x27;s Top Stories Of 2025 Listen to Matt discuss what to anticipate in 2026: Newsradio WGAN · Looking At 2026&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/matts-top-stories-of-2025/"&gt;Matt&amp;#8217;s Top Stories of 2025&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 18:08:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Questions Come as Twin Falls School District Protects Teacher’s Explicit Content Instead of Children</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/questions-come-as-twin-falls-school-district-protects-teachers-explicit-content-instead-of-children/</link><description>For any reasonable individual, protecting children from people who engage in sexual deviance and celebrate political violence should be a no-brainer. Yet the events that unfolded in Twin Falls, Idaho, involving one concerned mother and substitute teacher, leave us wondering.&amp;#160; On October 1, 2025, Cierra Clarke — a substitute teacher and parent of a 1st [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 23:25:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Rifreedom] Stenhouse Challenges Zurier’s Special Senate Energy Commission to “Act” on the Act On Climate</title><link>https://rifreedom.org/2026/01/stenhouse-challenges-zuriers-special-senate-energy-commission-to-act-on-the-act-on-climate/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;With "affordability" top of mind for Ocean State residents, the CEO of the RI Center for Freedom &amp;#038; Prosperity  today called upon  Senator  Sam Zurier  and all members of the special Senate Energy Commission he chairs to take a w holistic and realistic look at Rhode Island's net-zero policies and Act On Climate  mandates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org/2026/01/stenhouse-challenges-zuriers-special-senate-energy-commission-to-act-on-the-act-on-climate/"&gt;Stenhouse Challenges Zurier&amp;#8217;s Special Senate Energy Commission to &amp;#8220;Act&amp;#8221; on the Act On Climate&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org"&gt;RI Center for Freedom and Prosperity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 15:02:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] NJPI Urges Lawmakers Not to Advance Bill Targeting Homeschooling Families</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/01/njpi-urges-lawmakers-not-to-advance-bill-targeting-homeschooling-families/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;by Wells Winegar, NJPI Executive Director The New Jersey Policy Institute has formally urged members of the Assembly Health Committee [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/01/njpi-urges-lawmakers-not-to-advance-bill-targeting-homeschooling-families/"&gt;NJPI Urges Lawmakers Not to Advance Bill Targeting Homeschooling Families&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 15:07:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2026/01/the-outstater-318/</link><description>A Word for our Times solipsism &amp;#124; ˈsäləpˌsizəm &amp;#124; noun. The quality of being self-centered or selfish. In philosophy it is the view or theory that the self is all that can be known to exist. &amp;#8220;SOLIPSISM&amp;#8221; IS A GOOD WORD.&amp;#160;More use can be made of it.&amp;#160;The late Charles Krauthammer&amp;#160; used it to characterize persons&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2026/01/the-outstater-318/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 10:58:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Freedom Foundation Sues to Block Oregon Law Silencing Worker Rights Speech</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/press-release/freedom-foundation-sues-to-block-oregon-law-silencing-worker-rights-speech/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Freedom Foundation filed a federal lawsuit challenging Oregon House Bill 3789, a law that hands public-sector unions the power to sue the organization into oblivion for doing what it's done for years: informing public employees about their constitutional rights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/press-release/freedom-foundation-sues-to-block-oregon-law-silencing-worker-rights-speech/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation Sues to Block Oregon Law Silencing Worker Rights Speech &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 17:59:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Why the approved Chiefs deal is bad economics</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/why-the-approved-chiefs-deal-is-bad-economics/</link><description>In December 2025, the deal to bring the Kansas City Chiefs across the state line was agreed upon. Supporters called it a historic win. In reality, it locked Kansas into a multi-decade financial commitment that violates one of the most basic principles of good economics: government should not pick winners and losers. This deal is [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 21:43:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Research Note: How Changes in AI Regulation Could Affect Nebraska</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/research-note-how-changes-in-ai-regulation-could-affect-nebraska/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of weeks before Christmas, following the President’s recent executive order on artificial intelligence (AI), the Nebraska Examiner published an article examining the potential implications for Nebraska. While the precise impact of the order remains uncertain, the state’s recent legislative activity related to AI suggests the possibility of conflict between state and federal approaches....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/research-note-how-changes-in-ai-regulation-could-affect-nebraska/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Research Note: How Changes in AI Regulation Could Affect Nebraska&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 15:05:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Hartford Lawmakers Step Into a Local Labor Dispute — and Leave City Hall With the Bill</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/01/06/hartford-lawmakers-step-into-a-local-labor-dispute-and-leave-city-hall-with-the-bill/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="675" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/union_zoom_thumbnail_1200x675-1.png" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On December 23, the New Haven Federation of Teachers (NHFT) announced on social media that its bargaining team had met privately with members of New Haven’s delegation to the General [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/01/06/hartford-lawmakers-step-into-a-local-labor-dispute-and-leave-city-hall-with-the-bill/"&gt;Hartford Lawmakers Step Into a Local Labor Dispute — and Leave City Hall With the Bill &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 21:03:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] NEW: Findings from IRG Listening Tour and new Poll— a ground-level look at the issues Wisconsinites care about most</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/new-findings-from-irg-listening-tour-and-new-poll-a-ground-level-look-at-the-issues-wisconsinites-care-about-most/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;NEW: Findings from IRG Listening Tour and New Poll— a ground-level look at the issues Wisconsinites care about most Key lessons and insights gathered from four months of listening across Wisconsin. Delafield, Wis. – What common challenges are on Wisconsinites’ minds heading into 2026? The Institute for Reforming Government released its newest community engagement report, Wisconsin [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/new-findings-from-irg-listening-tour-and-new-poll-a-ground-level-look-at-the-issues-wisconsinites-care-about-most/"&gt;NEW: Findings from IRG Listening Tour and new Poll— a ground-level look at the issues Wisconsinites care about most&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 22:25:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Happy New Year! A Blueprint for Mississippi in 2026!</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/happy-new-year-a-blueprint-for-mississippi-in-2026/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As we kick off 2026, the Mississippi Center for Public Policy is more energized than ever.&amp;#160;&amp;#160;We are excited about the successes our state has seen – and we have a plan to build on that momentum with further free market reform!&amp;#160;For decades, our state lagged behind.&amp;#160;&amp;#160;Growth was slow and too many young people left our [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/happy-new-year-a-blueprint-for-mississippi-in-2026/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Happy New Year! A Blueprint for Mississippi in 2026!&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 15:35:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] House Bill 500 — Placeholder (0)</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/house-bill-500-placeholder-0/</link><description>Bill Description: House Bill 500 (2026) does not yet exist. This is a placeholder. Rating: 0 NOTE: House Bill 500 placeholder. Does it violate the spirit or the letter of either the U.S. Constitution or the Idaho Constitution? Examples include restrictions on speech, public assembly, the press, privacy, private property, or firearms. Conversely, does it restore or [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 17:35:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Proposed Ballot Questions for 2026: What Mainers Should Know</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/proposed-ballot-questions-for-2026-what-mainers-should-know/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Maine’s ballot initiative process is often described as a direct democratic safeguard, a way for citizens to place pressing policy questions before the voters when the Legislature declines to do so. But it also frequently functions as a pressure valve for interest groups attempting to bypass the scrutiny, hearings, fiscal analyses, and compromise that accompany [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/proposed-ballot-questions-for-2026-what-mainers-should-know/"&gt;Proposed Ballot Questions for 2026: What Mainers Should Know&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 17:47:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2026/01/the-outstater-319/</link><description>Creating a Homeless Magnet AGAIN, AS CITIES throughout the nation gear up to lure business away from New York City’s socialist mayor, my city is taking a different tact. We are striving to become as much like New York City as our meager resources permit — complete with a government grocery, a casino and upgraded homeless&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2026/01/the-outstater-319/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 14:59:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Crime and Public Safety in St. Louis: Upcoming Events</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/criminal-justice/crime-and-public-safety-in-st-louis-upcoming-events/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Please join us for an in-depth discussion on crime and public safety trends in St. Louis. Patrick Tuohey, Senior Fellow [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/criminal-justice/crime-and-public-safety-in-st-louis-upcoming-events/"&gt;Crime and Public Safety in St. Louis: Upcoming Events&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 15:50:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Statewide Coalition of Free Market Groups Calls for Action on “Red Tape Reset” Package</title><link>https://will-law.org/statewide-coalition-of-free-market-groups-calls-for-action-on-red-tape-reset-package/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A wide coalition of free market groups and associations representing Wisconsin’s largest job creators are calling on the Wisconsin Legislature to vote on a legislative package known as the “Red Tape Reset.”  The package was formally introduced last year and has advanced out of committee in both houses.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/statewide-coalition-of-free-market-groups-calls-for-action-on-red-tape-reset-package/"&gt;Statewide Coalition of Free Market Groups Calls for Action on “Red Tape Reset” Package&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 15:52:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Set the Floor, Not the Ceiling: Lessons From Florida’s AI Week</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/set-the-floor-not-the-ceiling-lessons-from-floridas-ai-week/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Florida House of Representatives&amp;#8217; final committee week featured their inaugural “AI week” following a directive from the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/set-the-floor-not-the-ceiling-lessons-from-floridas-ai-week/"&gt;Set the Floor, Not the Ceiling: Lessons From Florida’s AI Week&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 16:49:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Nebraska’s Tax Code Lets It Compete for Data Center Investment</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/nebraskas-tax-code-lets-it-compete-for-data-center-investment/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Midwest grows many things—including, increasingly, data centers. That’s good news, generating substantial local tax revenue, creating high-paying jobs, and expanding economic opportunities.  With 39 data centers (about 19 per 1 million people), Nebraska punches above its weight nationally, while trailing neighboring Iowa, which boasts the second-highest number of data centers per capita at 32...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/nebraskas-tax-code-lets-it-compete-for-data-center-investment/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Nebraska’s Tax Code Lets It Compete for Data Center Investment&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 17:26:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Pioneer Institute Statement on Mayor Wu’s Decision to Add $100 Million to the Cost of Building a New Madison Park Technical Vocational High School</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/pioneer-institute-statement-on-mayor-wus-decision-to-add-100-million-to-the-cost-of-building-a-new-madison-park-technical-vocational-high-school/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Mayor Wu continues to push her effort to further raise Boston’s commercial property tax rate, even though as of 2022 the city already had the&amp;#160;second highest ratio of commercial to residential effective tax rates&amp;#160;among the largest cities in each state.&amp;#160;&amp;#160;Wu claims&amp;#160;that&amp;#160;cutting&amp;#160;Boston’s budget&amp;#160;to...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/pioneer-institute-statement-on-mayor-wus-decision-to-add-100-million-to-the-cost-of-building-a-new-madison-park-technical-vocational-high-school/"&gt;Pioneer Institute Statement on Mayor Wu’s Decision to Add $100 Million to the Cost of Building a New Madison Park Technical Vocational High School   &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 17:41:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] “Oregon System” Sends Governor Back to Square One</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/tax-and-budget/oregon-system-sends-governor-back-to-square-one/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Naomi Inman The final signatures were plunked down on December 30—down on...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/tax-and-budget/oregon-system-sends-governor-back-to-square-one/"&gt;“Oregon System” Sends Governor Back to Square One&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 18:01:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] How the Left and Right Can Unite to Restore Opportunity in America</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/how-the-left-and-right-can-unite-to-restore-opportunity-in-america/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=how-the-left-and-right-can-unite-to-restore-opportunity-in-america</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The scandals erupting in Minnesota offer another example of how easy it is for generous U.S. welfare programs to squander billions of dollars. And while it’s important to hold accountable the individuals who figured out how to scam the system, until the system itself is changed, for every billion-dollar fraud that is uncovered, others will take...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/how-the-left-and-right-can-unite-to-restore-opportunity-in-america/"&gt;How the Left and Right Can Unite to Restore Opportunity in America&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 18:01:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Under The Dome: House Introduces the Education Freedom Act</title><link>https://empowerms.org/house-introduces-the-education-freedom-act/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, the Mississippi House of Representatives introduced House Bill 2, the Mississippi Education Freedom Act, one of the most comprehensive education reform bills our state has considered in years. Authored by House Speaker Jason White and Representative Jansen Owen, this bill puts families first by expanding school choice, increasing transparency, and giving parents and local communities&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/house-introduces-the-education-freedom-act/"&gt;Under The Dome: House Introduces the Education Freedom Act&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 18:27:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] School Choice for All Idaho Families</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/school-choice-for-all-idaho-families/</link><description>A local left-leaning podcast host had me on his show recently to talk about, among other things, Idaho’s new school choice opportunity — the Parental Choice Tax Credit (PCTC), which passed in 2025. He asked how in the world Idaho’s school choice could be “held accountable” if there were no mandatory testing or other state [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 19:58:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Matthew Gagnon on Gateway Fraud, Gubernatorial Race, Big Gov.</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/matthew-gagnon-on-gateway-fraud-gubernatorial-race-big-gov/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On his show on WGAN this week, Maine Policy Institute CEO Matthew Gagnon covered the Mills administration’s handling of the DHHS investigation into Gateway and fraud, highlighting the inadequacy of clawing back $1 million, and assails big government for its inevitable corruption. He goes on to address the Maine gubernatorial race, including Jonathan Bush&amp;#8217;s fundraising [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/matthew-gagnon-on-gateway-fraud-gubernatorial-race-big-gov/"&gt;Matthew Gagnon on Gateway Fraud, Gubernatorial Race, Big Gov.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 21:08:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Connecticut Declared a Housing Emergency. The Clock Started Ticking — and Nothing Happened</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/01/08/connecticut-declared-a-housing-emergency-the-clock-started-ticking-and-nothing-happened/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="1280" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/92098019-1920x1280-1.jpg" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;House Bill 8002 was enacted during a November special session after state leaders argued that Connecticut faced a housing emergency requiring immediate legislative action. The bill advanced without a public [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/01/08/connecticut-declared-a-housing-emergency-the-clock-started-ticking-and-nothing-happened/"&gt;Connecticut Declared a Housing Emergency. The Clock Started Ticking — and Nothing Happened&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 21:30:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Lead paint: The 50-year saga continues</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/lead-paint-the-50-year-saga-continues/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Nearly 50 years after the U.S. government banned lead-based paint, Milwaukee Public Schools officials have again been trying to cover up or remove the toxic substance that parents likely presume was dealt with long ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/lead-paint-the-50-year-saga-continues/"&gt;Lead paint: The 50-year saga continues&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 22:53:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Superior coal terminal is latest victim of declining Great Lakes shipments</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/superior-coal-terminal-is-latest-victim-of-declining-great-lakes-shipments/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A decline in cargo moving across the Great Lakes via United States-flagged “lakers” has led to widely felt impacts in port towns, including at a major Superior coal terminal now slated to shutter its operations by this upcoming summer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/superior-coal-terminal-is-latest-victim-of-declining-great-lakes-shipments/"&gt;Superior coal terminal is latest victim of declining Great Lakes shipments&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 22:54:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Shaping Georgia’s future: Opportunities for the year ahead</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/top-issues-shaping-georgia-future/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The well-being of many Georgians, their families, and their communities is at stake as pressing concerns like welfare reform, the cost of living, educational opportunities, and public safety take center stage in 2026. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/top-issues-shaping-georgia-future/"&gt;Shaping Georgia’s future: Opportunities for the year ahead&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 23:49:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] ‘People are very bad at managing their own finances’</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/podcasts/the-overton-window/chris-surprenant-talks-integrating-financial-literacy-at-the-high-school-level-to-improve-outcomes</link><description>Chris Surprenant talks integrating financial literacy at the high school level to improve outcomes</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Legislature Approved Zero New Business Subsidies in 2025</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/pressroom/2026/legislature-approved-zero-new-business-subsidies-in-2025</link><description>Mackinac Center applauds historic win for taxpayers</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 14:24:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Session Preview: Property Taxes</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/session-preview-property-taxes-2026/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Session Preview: Property Taxes" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/iowa-capitol-rotunda-1200x630-1.png" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Property tax reform is shaping up to be the defining issue of Iowa’s upcoming legislative session, with bipartisan attention and growing public pressure. Rising property taxes are driven by unchecked local government spending, not by isolated flaws in the tax system. A firm 2% cap on property tax growth is essential to delivering real, lasting relief, and must be central to any serious reform effort. As Iowa lawmakers return to the Capitol, one issue has emerged as the defining policy debate of the upcoming legislative session: property taxes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/session-preview-property-taxes-2026/"&gt;Session Preview: Property Taxes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 15:40:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Breaking the K-Shaped Divide in Texas Education: Time for Bold Accountability Reforms</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/breaking-the-k-shaped-divide-in-texas-education-time-for-bold-accountability-reforms/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When I entered the first grade, I was assigned to the lowest reading group. This came as a shock to my mom, as I had always loved books. Over the winter break, my mom and I read from “Fun with Zip and Zap,” a phonics chapter book. When I returned to school after the break,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/breaking-the-k-shaped-divide-in-texas-education-time-for-bold-accountability-reforms/"&gt;Breaking the K-Shaped Divide in Texas Education: Time for Bold Accountability Reforms&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 15:40:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Week in Review: Families, Not Bureaucrats</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-families-not-bureaucrats/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;From Fox News to the Maine Wire, news outlets across the country are taking notice of the Goldwater Institute’s petition..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-families-not-bureaucrats/"&gt;Week in Review: Families, Not Bureaucrats&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 16:44:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] State Delays Disclosing Emails About $1B Home Health Contract</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/state-delays-disclosing-emails-about-1b-home-health-contract/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For a third time the state Health Department has postponed releasing records related to a disputed $1 billion Medicaid contract,....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/state-delays-disclosing-emails-about-1b-home-health-contract/"&gt;State Delays Disclosing Emails About $1B Home Health Contract&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 18:25:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Fading Ripples from Gov. Newsom’s Last State of the State Address</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/newsoms-last-state-of-the-state/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=newsoms-last-state-of-the-state</link><description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been years since Gov. Gavin Newsom put on a tie and made his way to the Assembly Chambers to grace the legislature with his presence and share some witty lines his whip-smart crisis communications team put together for him. He is, afterall, preparing to storm the country with his not-yet-declared-but-super-obvious campaign for the presidency...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/newsoms-last-state-of-the-state/"&gt;Fading Ripples from Gov. Newsom’s Last State of the State Address&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 20:17:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] The importance of NH’s 1776 constitution</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2026/01/the-importance-of-nhs-1776-constitution/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On Jan. 5, 1776, New Hampshire became the first self-governing British colony in North America. That astonishing decision, made 250 years ago this week, deserved a bigger celebration than it received.  After a quarter of a millennium, Americans have become accustomed to thinking that self-government is normal. It isn’t. Achieving it in 1776 was extraordinary. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2026/01/the-importance-of-nhs-1776-constitution/"&gt;The importance of NH&amp;#8217;s 1776 constitution&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 20:34:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Short Session, Long Consequences: What Labor’s 2026 Agenda Would Mean for Connecticut</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/01/09/short-session-long-consequences-what-labors-2026-agenda-would-mean-for-connecticut/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connecticut lawmakers will return to Hartford on February 4 for the state’s so-called short session — a three-month legislative sprint intended primarily for technical fixes and budget adjustments.  In practice, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/01/09/short-session-long-consequences-what-labors-2026-agenda-would-mean-for-connecticut/"&gt;Short Session, Long Consequences: What Labor’s 2026 Agenda Would Mean for Connecticut &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 20:49:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] 2026 Capitol Chat: Week 1</title><link>https://empowerms.org/2026-capitol-chat-week-1/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Capitol Chat: Week 1 Capitol Chat is back for the 2026 legislative session, which is off to a quick start after only one week! Host Wil Ervin highlights early Senate action on teacher pay and public school choice, a sweeping House education bill, and a major Senate proposal to shore up PERS, setting the tone for a&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/2026-capitol-chat-week-1/"&gt;2026 Capitol Chat: Week 1&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 21:09:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] 2026 Legislative Sessions: What lawmakers should and shouldn't do</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/mspc-policy-recommendations-for-the-2026-legislative-sessions</link><description>We have dozens of policy recommendations for lawmakers to consider. These reforms can be acted on even with the challenging budget situations across the states. Here are a couple of our top recommendations for Idaho, Washington and Wyoming lawmakers</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 21:12:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Pelican Institute CEO Daniel Erspamer Available for Media Interviews on Louisiana Coastal Litigation &amp; U.S. Supreme Court Oral Arguments</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/press-release/media-interviews-la-coastal-litigation/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE Media Contact: sydney@pelicaninstitute.org January 9, 2026 &amp;#160; New Orleans, LA— As the U.S. Supreme Court prepares to hear oral arguments Monday in Chevron U.S.A. Inc. v. Plaquemines Parish, the Pelican Institute for Public Policy is making its CEO, Daniel Erspamer, and General Counsel, Sarah Harbison, available to reporters for on camera interviews,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/press-release/media-interviews-la-coastal-litigation/"&gt;Pelican Institute CEO Daniel Erspamer Available for Media Interviews on Louisiana Coastal Litigation &amp;#038; U.S. Supreme Court Oral Arguments &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 21:14:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] The Amazing Case of Steubenville, Ohio</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/performance/the-amazing-case-of-steubenville-ohio/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Over at The74, Chad Aldeman wrote an excellent article about the remarkable reading results in Steubenville, Ohio. He shows that [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/performance/the-amazing-case-of-steubenville-ohio/"&gt;The Amazing Case of Steubenville, Ohio&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 21:28:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Winners &amp; Losers: Maduro’s in Jail, Somali’s Steal Billions and Red Meat is Back on the Menu</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/winners-losers-maduros-in-jail-somalis-steal-billions-and-red-meat-is-back-on-the-menu/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Every Friday morning, I join the Cardle &amp;#38; Woolley Show on Talk 1370 Radio in Austin to announce the week’s Winners &amp;#38; Losers. The holidays are totally over now, and 2026 is up and running in earnest with big happenings all over the world—and in Texas. Here’s who made the list:   WINNER: Trump Takes...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/winners-losers-maduros-in-jail-somalis-steal-billions-and-red-meat-is-back-on-the-menu/"&gt;Winners &amp; Losers: Maduro’s in Jail, Somali’s Steal Billions and Red Meat is Back on the Menu&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 21:34:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Louisiana’s Energy Moment: Why Competition—Not Regulatory Shortcuts—Will Power Growth and Lower Costs</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/energy/louisianas-energy-moment/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As Louisiana enters 2026, energy and infrastructure policy remain front and center. Last month’s announcement of another major artificial intelligence data center project coming to the state underscores Louisiana’s economic potential—and the growing importance of getting our regulatory framework right. The challenge is immediate and significant. Electricity demand is rising rapidly, driven by aging generation...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/energy/louisianas-energy-moment/"&gt;Louisiana’s Energy Moment: Why Competition—Not Regulatory Shortcuts—Will Power Growth and Lower Costs&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 22:28:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Chicago gets lowest employment score since 2009</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/chicago-gets-lowest-employment-score-since-2009/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Chicago’s worst employment climate score since 2009 drove a 25th month of business decline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/chicago-gets-lowest-employment-score-since-2009/"&gt;Chicago gets lowest employment score since 2009&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 22:36:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Session Preview: Conservative Budgeting</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/session-preview-conservative-budgeting/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Session Preview: Conservative Budgeting" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/iowa-capitol-winter.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conservative budgeting is the foundation of fiscal conservatism and the key to sustaining Iowa’s tax reforms. Spending growth has accelerated in recent budgets, even as economic uncertainty and revenue pressures increase. As lawmakers craft the FY 2027 budget, spending discipline will be essential to protecting Iowa’s fiscal stability and future tax relief. As economist Art Laffer has observed, “government spending is taxation, pure and simple.” For that reason, the starting point for any sound tax policy discussion must be spending restraint. The state budget is the foundational product of each legislative session, shaping other policy debates and determining whether past tax reforms can be sustained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/session-preview-conservative-budgeting/"&gt;Session Preview: Conservative Budgeting&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 13:20:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] The Union that May Have Broken California</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/the-union-that-may-have-broken-california/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=the-union-that-may-have-broken-california</link><description>&lt;p&gt;2026 began with revelations that numerous billionaires owning upwards of $1 trillion in assets had cut ties with California just before the ball dropped on January 1. These well-heeled folks did not suddenly get tired of California’s weather, scenery, culture, or social scene. Instead, they were avoiding a potential wealth tax hatched by a group...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/the-union-that-may-have-broken-california/"&gt;The Union that May Have Broken California&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 22:43:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Three polls, same result: Idaho voters support ed choice tax credit</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/three-polls-same-result-idaho-voters-support-ed-choice-tax-credit</link><description>One poll might be a fluke. Two polls might be a coincidence. But three independent polls—conducted over more than a year, before and after passage—all landing in the mid-60s is not an accident. It’s a pattern. And that pattern reflects broad, durable public support.</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 04:19:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Spending Watch: California’s Budget Delusion</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/spending-watch-californias-budget-delusion/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Spending Watch: California’s Budget Delusion Tim Anaya January 2026 Governor Newsom has released his final state budget and for the fourth year in a row, the state is facing a large budget deficit that it must close. This prolonged period of persistent budget deficits was entirely predictable. For the upcoming FY2026-27 budget, that deficit is [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/spending-watch-californias-budget-delusion/"&gt;Spending Watch: California’s Budget Delusion&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 10:17:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Minnesota fraud should ‘wake up’ Democrats</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/minnesota-fraud-should-wake-up-democrats/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Ruy Teixeira hopes fellow Democrats learn a lesson from the Minnesota welfare fraud scandal. The specter of welfare fraud haunts the Democrats once again. Concerns about abuse of generous government programs helped power the rise of Reagan-era conservatism in the 1970s and ’80s. Could the criminal abuse of hundreds of millions of dollars in welfare...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/minnesota-fraud-should-wake-up-democrats/"&gt;Minnesota fraud should &amp;#8216;wake up&amp;#8217; Democrats&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 10:39:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Clintons could face contempt of Congress charges</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/clintons-could-face-contempt-of-congress-charges/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Emily Goodin writes for the New York Post about the latest bad news for a former American first couple. The federal government’s legislative branch wants the Clintons to provide information in the ongoing probe of Jeffrey Epstein’s misdeeds. To date, neither the former president nor the Democrats’ 2016 presidential nominee has been willing to participate...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/clintons-could-face-contempt-of-congress-charges/"&gt;Clintons could face contempt of Congress charges&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 10:42:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Chicago Public Schools spends a lot on empty desks</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/chicago-public-schools-spends-a-lot-on-empty-desks/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The emptiest Chicago Public Schools building held just 3% of its capacity and cost nearly $55,000 per student. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/chicago-public-schools-spends-a-lot-on-empty-desks/"&gt;Chicago Public Schools spends a lot on empty desks&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 11:00:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] What is the role of a think tank?</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2026/what-is-the-role-of-a-think-tank</link><description>A guest column from Donald Bryson, CEO and president, John Locke Foundation</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 12:01:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Left seeks martyrs to fuel anti-Trump uprising as ICE enforcement operations ramp up nationwide</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/left-seeks-martyrs-to-fuel-anti-trump-uprising-as-ice-enforcement-operations-ramp-up-nationwide/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Radical groups are causing confrontations with federal agents to spark nationwide unrest and undermine Republicans. As the Trump administration ramps up enforcement against illegal immigration and cracks down on welfare fraud, the radical left is escalating its tactics in a calculated bid to create martyrs. We’ve seen this before, but today’s ideological fervor, backed by deep-pocketed donors...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/left-seeks-martyrs-to-fuel-anti-trump-uprising-as-ice-enforcement-operations-ramp-up-nationwide/"&gt;Left seeks martyrs to fuel anti-Trump uprising as ICE enforcement operations ramp up nationwide&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 12:42:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Former Speaker Steve Crisafulli Joins JMI As Scholar in Residence</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/former-speaker-steve-crisafulli-joins-jmi-as-scholar-in-residence/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASEJanuary 12, 2026CONTACTLogan Elizabeth Padgett(850) 386-3131 Former Speaker Steve Crisafulli Joins JMI As Scholar in Residence...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/former-speaker-steve-crisafulli-joins-jmi-as-scholar-in-residence/"&gt;Former Speaker Steve Crisafulli Joins JMI As Scholar in Residence&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] Franke: Edmund Burke</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2026/01/franke-edmund-burke/</link><description>by Mark Franke Edmund Burke was a philosophical hero for us Young Americans for Freedom undergraduates back in the Nixon administration. In large part this was due to Russell Kirk’s autobiography, “Edmund Burke: A Genius Reconsidered,” that had just been released.&amp;#160; In recent years Burke’s status has been brought into question by factions within the&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2026/01/franke-edmund-burke/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 14:03:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Fact-checking a “fact check” on solar and wind energy</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/fact-checking-a-fact-check-on-solar-and-wind-energy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On Sept. 5, 2025, the U.S. Energy Department’s official X account posted an Aug. 23, 2025, Washington Examiner article featuring Energy Secretary Chris Wright. The accompanying text in the post stated, “Wind and solar energy infrastructure is essentially worthless when it is dark outside, and the wind is not blowing.” Three and a half months...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/fact-checking-a-fact-check-on-solar-and-wind-energy/"&gt;Fact-checking a “fact check” on solar and wind energy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 15:19:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Session Preview: No Shutdown Rule</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/session-preview-no-shutdown-rule/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Session Preview: No Shutdown Rule" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/capitol-at-night.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iowa currently lacks a clear process to prevent a state government shutdown if a budget is not passed on time, creating uncertainty for taxpayers and essential services. A budget-continuation, or “no shutdown,” rule would ensure government operations continue by temporarily extending the prior year’s budget during impasses or emergencies. Adopting such a rule would promote stability, limit political brinkmanship, and align Iowa with best practices already used in other states. Last year, Iowans once again watched Washington struggle through another federal government shutdown. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/session-preview-no-shutdown-rule/"&gt;Session Preview: No Shutdown Rule&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 15:20:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] State Report Card on Telehealth Reform: Incremental Progress in 2025 Leaves Many States Unprepared for Rural Health Transformation Funding</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/state-report-card-on-telehealth-reform-incremental-progress-in-2025-leaves-many-states-unprepared-for-rural-health-transformation-funding/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Boston, Mass – A new report from the Cicero Institute and Pioneer Institute finds that while state legislatures remained active on telehealth policy in 2025, most states made only incremental progress toward modern, patient-centered telehealth systems. With the passage of the One Big Beautiful Bill and its $50 billion Rural Health Transformation Program, states now face growing pressure to modernize outdated telehealth laws or risk falling behind in access, affordability, and federal funding competitiveness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/state-report-card-on-telehealth-reform-incremental-progress-in-2025-leaves-many-states-unprepared-for-rural-health-transformation-funding/"&gt;State Report Card on Telehealth Reform: Incremental Progress in 2025 Leaves Many States Unprepared for Rural Health Transformation Funding&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 15:22:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] How Does Kansas Rank in Economic Freedom?</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/how-does-kansas-rank-in-economic-freedom/</link><description>Kansas ranks 14th nationally, with an overall score of 7.12, in the Economic Freedom of North America report published by the Fraser Institute. The ranking, based on 2023 data, places Kansas just outside the top quartile of states. That position tells a precise economic story. Kansas has restored stability after years of fiscal turbulence from [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 16:00:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] MPS Wins Big In Property Tax Shift</title><link>https://will-law.org/mps-wins-big-in-property-tax-shift/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;MPS, a school district with declining enrollment and only 8.1% of Wisconsin's public school population, is getting over 50% of the property tax revenue shift. Why is that? We explain why. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/mps-wins-big-in-property-tax-shift/"&gt;MPS Wins Big In Property Tax Shift&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 16:22:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] No Adult Left Behind, How Politics Hijacks Education Policy with Vlad Kogan</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/education/no-adult-left-behind-how-politics-hijacks-education-policy-with-vlad-kogan/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Susan Pendergrass speaks with Vladimir Kogan, professor of political science at The Ohio State University, to discuss his new book, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/education/no-adult-left-behind-how-politics-hijacks-education-policy-with-vlad-kogan/"&gt;No Adult Left Behind, How Politics Hijacks Education Policy with Vlad Kogan&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 16:37:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] HB2 – Mississippi’s School Choice Bill is Here!</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/hb2-mississippis-school-choice-bill-is-here/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Last week, House Speaker Jason White unveiled&amp;#160;HB2, the&amp;#160;Mississippi Education Freedom Act - the most exciting and ambitious advancement for school choice in our state in years, perhaps ever!&amp;#160;This comprehensive bill delivers everything supporters of parental power have long hoped for, and it aligns perfectly with President Trump’s strong commitment to education freedom.&amp;#160;This isn’t some minor [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/hb2-mississippis-school-choice-bill-is-here/" rel="nofollow"&gt;HB2 – Mississippi’s School Choice Bill is Here!&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 17:31:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Does California Want To Be Part Of The Nuclear Renaissance?</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/does-california-want-to-be-part-of-the-nuclear-renaissance/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As the California Coastal Commission agreed this month to keep the state’s last nuclear energy plant open for at least five more years, the Trump administration announced federal funding for the development of small modular nuclear reactors. The Diablo Canyon Power Plant in San Luis Obispo Power Plant, the only remaining nuclear energy facility in a state, was [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/does-california-want-to-be-part-of-the-nuclear-renaissance/"&gt;Does California Want To Be Part Of The Nuclear Renaissance? &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 18:32:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] 2026 Idaho Poll: Voters want transparency, tax relief</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/2026-idaho-poll-voters-want-transparency-tax-relief</link><description>As Idaho lawmakers convene for the 2026 legislative session, a new statewide poll shows voters are generally optimistic about the state’s direction but want policymakers to focus on transparency, tax relief, and regulatory reform rather than expanding government.</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 18:32:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Accounting for Growth: Human capital per worker, 2024</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/accounting-for-growth-human-capital-per-worker-2024/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Back in October,&amp;#160;I wrote&amp;#160;about Minnesota’s relatively poor performance on Gross Domestic Product (GDP) per capita growth in the last decade. To investigate this, I wanted to do what economists call a &amp;#8220;growth accounting&amp;#8221; exercise for Minnesota, which breaks down the growth rate of per capita GDP into the portions arising from increases in human capital,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/accounting-for-growth-human-capital-per-worker-2024/"&gt;Accounting for Growth: Human capital per worker, 2024&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 18:32:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Pelican Institute Issues Statement in Response to Oral Arguments in Chevron v. Plaquemines</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/press-release/chevron-v-plaquemines/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE Media Contact: sydney@pelicaninstitute.org January 12, 2026 Washington, D.C.— Earlier today, the United States Supreme Court heard oral arguments in Chevron v. Plaquemines, a critical case arising from dozens of lawsuits filed by private trial lawyers on behalf of Louisiana coastal parishes against energy companies. The suits seek massive damages for alleged coastal erosion tied in...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/press-release/chevron-v-plaquemines/"&gt;Pelican Institute Issues Statement in Response to Oral Arguments in &amp;lt;i&amp;gt;Chevron v. Plaquemines&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt;&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 18:34:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] $1 million Ilhan Omar earmark yanked</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/1-million-ilhan-omar-earmark-yanked/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Lost in all of the news last week was this item involving local U.S. Congresswoman Ilhan Omar (D-Minneapolis), from The Hill newspaper, GOP backlash to Omar earmark slows government-funding bill. The legislation involved was part of one of the dozen or so annual budget bills that have to pass to keep the federal government operating...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/1-million-ilhan-omar-earmark-yanked/"&gt;$1 million Ilhan Omar earmark yanked&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 18:50:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] In Cambridge, New Lawsuit Challenges Constitutionality of Mandatory Set-Asides for Affordable Housing</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/in-cambridge-new-lawsuit-challenges-constitutionality-of-mandatory-set-asides-for-affordable-housing/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This edition of The House Call describes a legal complaint alleging that Cambridge&amp;#8217;s inclusionary zoning ordinance, which requires set-asides for below-market-rate housing in new development, is a regulatory taking under the Fifth Amendment to the Constitution. It also describes a number of actions the Commonwealth...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/in-cambridge-new-lawsuit-challenges-constitutionality-of-mandatory-set-asides-for-affordable-housing/"&gt;In Cambridge, New Lawsuit Challenges Constitutionality of Mandatory Set-Asides for Affordable Housing&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 19:18:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] UCSD’s Math Meltdown: The Cost of Prioritizing Identity Politics Over The Basics</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/ucsds-math-meltdown-the-cost-of-prioritizing-identity-politics-over-the-basics/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The University of California, San Diego is confronting an academic breakdown that would have been unthinkable a decade ago: a..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/ucsds-math-meltdown-the-cost-of-prioritizing-identity-politics-over-the-basics/"&gt;UCSD&amp;#8217;s Math Meltdown: The Cost of Prioritizing Identity Politics Over The Basics&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 19:47:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] ABQ Journal opinion piece: More investigative journalism is a must</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/abq-journal-opinion-piece-more-investigative-journalism-is-a-must/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following appeared in Albuquerque Journal on January 11, 2026. The Albuquerque Journal recently made appeals on its pages for donations to increase investigative journalism efforts. Even though the Rio Grande Foundation is in direct competition for limited donor dollars, we applaud the paper for focusing attention on investigative journalism currently. The issue of investigative journalism is [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/abq-journal-opinion-piece-more-investigative-journalism-is-a-must/"&gt;ABQ Journal opinion piece: More investigative journalism is a must&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 19:54:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Illinois county updates property tax sale rules after court warnings</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/illinois-county-updates-property-tax-sale-rules-after-court-warnings/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Rock Island County required tax buyers at its Dec. 30 sale to attest they would protect homeowners’ equity as judges warn Illinois counties may be liable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/illinois-county-updates-property-tax-sale-rules-after-court-warnings/"&gt;Illinois county updates property tax sale rules after court warnings&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 20:24:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Amend property tax-dedication guidelines for low-income rentals</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/01/amend-property-tax-dedication-guidelines-for-low-income-rentals/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Honolulu City Council Committee on Budget on Jan. 13, 2026._____________ Jan. 13, 2026, 9 a.m.Honolulu Hale To: Honolulu City Council Committee on Budget&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Val Okimoto, Chair&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; &amp;#160;Scott Nishimoto, Vice Chair From: Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Ted Kefalas, Director of Strategic [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/01/amend-property-tax-dedication-guidelines-for-low-income-rentals/"&gt;Amend property tax-dedication guidelines for low-income rentals&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 20:56:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Create commission with aim of reducing cost of city government</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/01/create-commission-with-aim-of-reducing-cost-of-city-government/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Honolulu Charter Commission on Jan. 12, 2026. _____________ Jan. 12, 2026, 2:30 p.m.Honolulu Hale To: Honolulu Charter Commission&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Dawn Szewczyk, Chair&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Sommerset Yamamoto, Vice Chair From: Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Ted Kefalas, Director of Strategic Campaigns RE: P065 — RELATING [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/01/create-commission-with-aim-of-reducing-cost-of-city-government/"&gt;Create commission with aim of reducing cost of city government&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 20:59:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Florida Politics: Why Orange County School Leaders Should Look to Wichita</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/florida-politics-why-orange-county-school-leaders-should-look-to-wichita/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;It may be a memorable line in the&amp;#160;White Stripes’&amp;#160;iconic anthem, “Seven Nation Army.” But the phrase “I’m goin’...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/florida-politics-why-orange-county-school-leaders-should-look-to-wichita/"&gt;Florida Politics: Why Orange County School Leaders Should Look to Wichita&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 21:05:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] How to achieve a policy trifecta</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/01/how-to-achieve-a-policy-trifecta/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;What if we could help farmers, ease the housing crisis and improve Hawaii’s economy all at the same time? A series of simple reforms could do that. The starting point would be to make it easier to build farmworker housing on agricultural land. That would enable farm and ranch workers to find housing closer to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/01/how-to-achieve-a-policy-trifecta/"&gt;How to achieve a policy trifecta&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 21:09:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Correcting faulty narratives in ICE shooting</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/correcting-faulty-narratives-in-ice-shooting/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Last week agents from Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) were conducting targeted immigration enforcement in South Minneapolis, when agent Jonathan Ross fatally shot an activist, Renee Good, who drove her car at Ross and struck his leg. In the days following the fatal shooting a great deal of misinformation has emerged in varying degrees of...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/correcting-faulty-narratives-in-ice-shooting/"&gt;Correcting faulty narratives in ICE shooting&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 21:37:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Gov. Hobbs’ False Attacks on ESAs – The 2026 Edition</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/gov-hobbs-false-attacks-on-esas-the-2026-edition/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Governor Katie Hobbs used her State of the State address to launch yet another attack on Arizona’s highly successful Empowerment..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/gov-hobbs-false-attacks-on-esas-the-2026-edition/"&gt;Gov. Hobbs’ False Attacks on ESAs – The 2026 Edition&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 22:06:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] HB 2: Mississippi Education Freedom Act</title><link>https://empowerms.org/hb-2-mississippi-education-freedom-act/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;House Bill 2, authored by House Speaker Jason White and Representative Jansen Owen, is a comprehensive education reform bill that expands opportunity by ensuring parents have access to a wider range of high-quality education options for their children, while also strengthening public schools through transparency, innovation, and local control.   Specifically, this bill:   Creates Magnolia Student Accounts, which allow eligible families to use a portion of&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/hb-2-mississippi-education-freedom-act/"&gt;HB 2: Mississippi Education Freedom Act&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 23:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Idaho GOP calls for an end to taxpayer support for teachers unions</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/teachers-unions/idaho-gop-calls-for-an-end-to-taxpayer-support-for-teachers-unions/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As the 2026 Idaho legislature convenes, the Idaho Republican Party has adopted a resolution calling for the “passage of legislation to prohibit taxpayer support for teachers’ unions in all forms, direct or indirect," a key Freedom Foundation initiative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/teachers-unions/idaho-gop-calls-for-an-end-to-taxpayer-support-for-teachers-unions/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Idaho GOP calls for an end to taxpayer support for teachers unions&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:39:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] PPS to Remove References to “Black Students” from Naming of “Center for Black Student Excellence” at Jan. 13 Board Meeting</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/global-news/pps-to-remove-references-to-black-students-from-naming-of-center-for-black-student-excellence-at-jan-13-board-meeting/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;January 12, 2026 FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE Cascade Policy Institute4850 SW Scholls Ferry Rd.,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/global-news/pps-to-remove-references-to-black-students-from-naming-of-center-for-black-student-excellence-at-jan-13-board-meeting/"&gt;PPS to Remove References to &amp;#8220;Black Students&amp;#8221; from Naming of &amp;#8220;Center for Black Student Excellence&amp;#8221; at Jan. 13 Board Meeting&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:41:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] PRI All Stars Analyze Governor Newsom’s 2026-27 Budget Plan</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/pri-all-stars-analyze-governor-newsoms-2026-27-budget-plan/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This week, PRI&amp;#8217;s team of policy experts &amp;#8211; Wayne Winegarden, Steve Smith, and Lance Izumi &amp;#8211; join Tim to analyze Gov. Newsom&amp;#8217;s budget priorities and explore whether his final state budget plan is sustainable or if it sets the state on a perilous fiscal course.  They also discuss whether Newsom is setting up his successor [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/pri-all-stars-analyze-governor-newsoms-2026-27-budget-plan/"&gt;PRI All Stars Analyze Governor Newsom&amp;#8217;s 2026-27 Budget Plan&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 05:41:56 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>