<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>State-Policy Think-Tank Digest</title><link>https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml</link><description>Latest posts from free-market policy institutes across the U.S.</description><atom:link href="https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 03:00:32 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>[Mspolicy] If You Want Parent Power, Only HB2 Will Do</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/if-you-want-parent-power-only-hb2-will-do/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past few years, Mississippi lawmakers have passed some critical conservative reforms.&amp;#160;Last year, Mississippi became the first state in America to legislate to eliminate the income tax in 40 years.&amp;#160; In 2022, we implemented flat tax reform.&amp;#160; A few years before that, we passed important labor market reforms.&amp;#160; In 2024, we reformed school funding [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/if-you-want-parent-power-only-hb2-will-do/" rel="nofollow"&gt;If You Want Parent Power, Only HB2 Will Do&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 16:09:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Rifreedom] MEDIA RELEASE: Center Launches Petition Calling for Affordable Energy Policies</title><link>https://rifreedom.org/2026/01/media-release-center-launches-petition-calling-for-affordable-energy-policies/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Rhode Island Center for Freedom &amp;#038; Prosperity today announced that it has launched an online petition drive calling for policymakers to support a fundamental pivot away from our state's current energy strategy, which will lead to staggeringly high electricity prices and potentially dangerous blackouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org/2026/01/media-release-center-launches-petition-calling-for-affordable-energy-policies/"&gt;MEDIA RELEASE: Center Launches Petition Calling for Affordable Energy Policies&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org"&gt;RI Center for Freedom and Prosperity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 14:19:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] A New Governor Takes Office. Will She Deliver on Education?</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/01/a-new-governor-takes-office-will-she-deliver-on-education/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;by Aiden DeMarsey, NJPI Jr. Fellow &amp;#160; Governor Mikie Sherrill, sworn into office last week, enters her term with a [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/01/a-new-governor-takes-office-will-she-deliver-on-education/"&gt;A New Governor Takes Office. Will She Deliver on Education?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 19:10:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] New housing permits are highest since 2006, but single-family homes lag</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2026/01/new-housing-permits-are-highest-since-2006-but-single-family-homes-lag/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New Hampshire towns and cities are permitting more residential housing units than they have in years, which is great news. But the new units are skewed heavily toward rentals, suggesting that local restrictions on small, single-family homes remain a significant barrier. Local governments issued permits for 5,822 new housing units in 2024, the highest number [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2026/01/new-housing-permits-are-highest-since-2006-but-single-family-homes-lag/"&gt;New housing permits are highest since 2006, but single-family homes lag&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:16:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] The Denial of Distinctions</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/the-denial-of-distinctions/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Denial of Distinctions By Abe Greenwald Yesterday, I wrote about the return of American disorder in the form of mobs that obstruct ICE raids. Part of what makes anti-ICE/open-border activism so strange is that it attacks the most fundamental aspect of what it means to be a country: its physical boundaries. When leftists repeat, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/the-denial-of-distinctions/"&gt;The Denial of Distinctions&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:37:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Crime is down, and it should end ‘root cause’ excuse-making for good</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/crime-is-down-and-it-should-end-root-cause-excuse-making-for-good/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/crime-is-down-and-it-should-end-root-cause-excuse-making-for-good/"&gt;Crime is down, and it should end ‘root cause’ excuse-making for good&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 22:13:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Introducing TennSight, Tennessee’s only hub for voter insights</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/introducing-tennsight-tennessees-only-hub-for-voter-insights/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=introducing-tennsight-tennessees-only-hub-for-voter-insights</link><description>We hope that TennSight will become the go-to source for you to learn what matters most to your fellow Tennesseans, why it matters, and what can be done about it.</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 13:08:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Beacon Poll: January 2026 Results</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/beacon-poll-january-2026-results/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=beacon-poll-january-2026-results</link><description>Today, we released the latest installment of the Beacon Poll, a statewide survey of 1,200 Tennessee voters featuring questions about voters’ views on property taxes, the federal school choice tax credit included in the One Big Beautiful Bill Act, and political approval ratings at the state and federal level, and more. Tennesseans continue to prioritize key...</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 19:35:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cardinalinstitute] Op-Ed: Hospitals Collect Tax Breaks. West Virginians Collect Medical Debt.</title><link>https://cardinalinstitute.com/op-ed-hospitals-collect-tax-breaks-west-virginians-collect-medical-debt/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;To many West Virginians, healthcare continues to be a burden more than a lifeline as roughly 180,000 residents, or 13.3% of adults, now facing some sort of  medical debt. This is well above the national average of 8.6% and, even worse, nearly one in four of these residents in rural Appalachia have medical debt in [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com/op-ed-hospitals-collect-tax-breaks-west-virginians-collect-medical-debt/"&gt;Op-Ed: Hospitals Collect Tax Breaks. West Virginians Collect Medical Debt.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com"&gt;Cardinal Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 15:16:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Why Portland’s Suggested Statewide Eviction Moratorium Would Hurt Maine’s Housing Market</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/why-portlands-suggested-statewide-eviction-moratorium-would-hurt-maines-housing-market/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Portland city officials are urging Gov. Janet Mills to impose a 60-day statewide eviction moratorium in response to “fear and instability” that they are linking to federal immigration enforcement. While the resolution is framed as an emergency measure that they are claiming is only meant to protect “vulnerable residents,” such a moratorium risks repeating a [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/why-portlands-suggested-statewide-eviction-moratorium-would-hurt-maines-housing-market/"&gt;Why Portland&amp;#8217;s Suggested Statewide Eviction Moratorium Would Hurt Maine’s Housing Market&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 16:38:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] Tim Pawlenty: The Crisis Will Subside in Minnesota, but Trust Will Need to be Rebuilt</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/tim-pawlenty-the-crisis-will-subside-in-minnesota-but-trust-will-need-to-be-rebuilt/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;We’ll all be part of that task. Here’s where efforts could be focused. By Tim Pawlenty For the Star Tribune It’s been said that trust is the glue that holds relationships together. That may well explain why recent events in Minnesota have stretched our relationship with government to the breaking point. Fraudsters stole a ton [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/tim-pawlenty-the-crisis-will-subside-in-minnesota-but-trust-will-need-to-be-rebuilt/"&gt;Tim Pawlenty: The Crisis Will Subside in Minnesota, but Trust Will Need to be Rebuilt&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 19:57:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] The Numbers Don’t Lie: The CHOOSE Act is Empowering Alabama’s Families</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2026/02/04/the-numbers-dont-lie-the-choose-act-is-empowering-alabamas-families/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For decades, the Alabama Policy Institute has championed a simple, powerful idea: every child in Alabama deserves a high-quality education, regardless of their zip code or their size of their parents’ bank account. With the passage and implementation of the CHOOSE Act, that vision is finally becoming a reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2026/02/04/the-numbers-dont-lie-the-choose-act-is-empowering-alabamas-families/"&gt;The Numbers Don’t Lie: The CHOOSE Act is Empowering Alabama’s Families&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 22:48:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] 312 Out of More than 3 Million Votes</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/312-out-of-more-than-3-million-votes/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Federal prosecutors are closing in on prosecuting more than 100 Minnesotans for rampant fraud in several social service programs designed to serve children and low-income residents. By the time the US Attorney’s office is done investigating, charging, convicting, and sentencing these felons, this unchecked fraud will significantly increase Minnesota’s prison population. But there’s one other [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/312-out-of-more-than-3-million-votes/"&gt;312 Out of More than 3 Million Votes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 13:58:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Rifreedom] TESTIMONY: Senate Commission to Study the Successful Implementation of the Act on Climate</title><link>https://rifreedom.org/2026/02/senate-commission-act-on-climate/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In this powerful testimony, Mike Stenhouse, CEO of the RI Center for Freedom &amp;#038; Prosperity, explains why energy policy—not taxes, not housing, not government services—is the single most important determinant of Rhode Island’s future prosperity or poverty. Whether one believes in climate change or not, the economic consequences of the Act on Climate are unavoidable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org/2026/02/senate-commission-act-on-climate/"&gt;TESTIMONY: Senate Commission to Study the Successful Implementation of the Act on Climate&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org"&gt;RI Center for Freedom and Prosperity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 21:12:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] BERGEN RECORD: NJ climate superfund is a blank check with no accountability | Opinion</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/02/bergen-record-nj-climate-superfund-is-a-blank-check-with-no-accountability-opinion/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;#160; New Jersey’s Climate Superfund Is a Blank Check With No Accountability by Rosemary Becchi New Jersey lawmakers are considering [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/02/bergen-record-nj-climate-superfund-is-a-blank-check-with-no-accountability-opinion/"&gt;BERGEN RECORD: NJ climate superfund is a blank check with no accountability | Opinion&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 13:58:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Governor Mills’ Supplemental Budget Abandons Fiscal Discipline, Sets Maine Up for Higher Costs</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/governor-millss-supplemental-budget-abandons-fiscal-discipline-sets-maine-up-for-higher-costs/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Governor Janet Mills’ FY 2026 supplemental budget marks a clear break from the fiscal restraint her administration often claimed to practice. Rather than using Maine’s strong revenue growth to stabilize taxpayers after years of tax increases and inflation, the proposal dramatically expands spending, broadens emergency powers, and doubles down on distortionary tax policy choices that [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/governor-millss-supplemental-budget-abandons-fiscal-discipline-sets-maine-up-for-higher-costs/"&gt;Governor Mills’ Supplemental Budget Abandons Fiscal Discipline, Sets Maine Up for Higher Costs&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 17:22:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Affordability tops the list of state priorities for 2026</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/affordability-tops-the-list-of-state-priorities-for-2026/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/affordability-tops-the-list-of-state-priorities-for-2026/"&gt;Affordability tops the list of state priorities for 2026&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 21:36:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Ayotte: Maximize economic freedom, and New Hampshire will thrive</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2026/02/ayotte-maximize-economic-freedom-and-new-hampshire-will-thrive/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Gov. Kelly Ayotte’s 2026 State of the State address can be summed up in seven words: New Hampshire wins by competing on freedom. Leading with a list of eight No. 1 national rankings for the state—including economic freedom, economic opportunity and taxpayer return on investment—Ayotte noted that, overall, “U.S. News ranks us the #2 state [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2026/02/ayotte-maximize-economic-freedom-and-new-hampshire-will-thrive/"&gt;Ayotte: Maximize economic freedom, and New Hampshire will thrive&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 14:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] Alabama Senate unanimously passes App Store Accountability Act</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2026/02/09/alabama-senate-unanimously-passes-app-store-accountability-act/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The App Store Accountability Act passed the Alabama Senate with a unanimous vote on Feb. 5. The bill is focused on online safety for children and teens by requiring parental approval for kids to download apps from the App Store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2026/02/09/alabama-senate-unanimously-passes-app-store-accountability-act/"&gt;Alabama Senate unanimously passes App Store Accountability Act&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 23:47:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] Alabama Senate passes App Store age verification requirement</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2026/02/10/alabama-senate-passes-app-store-age-verification-requirement/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Lawmakers spoke before the Senate in favor of shielding minors from inappropriate content, requiring parental permission for account creation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2026/02/10/alabama-senate-passes-app-store-age-verification-requirement/"&gt;Alabama Senate passes App Store age verification requirement&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 02:12:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Strengthening families for generational change: GCO welcomes Travis Thorne to the team</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/welcoming-travis-thorne/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/welcoming-travis-thorne/"&gt;Strengthening families for generational change: GCO welcomes Travis Thorne to the team&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 14:26:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Florida Politics: Florida’s A+ Plan To Help ‘Plan B’ Families</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/floridas-a-plan-to-help-plan-b-families/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;It was a curious finding that seemed to make no sense at all. Last year, more than 41,000...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/floridas-a-plan-to-help-plan-b-families/"&gt;Florida Politics: Florida’s A+ Plan To Help ‘Plan B’ Families&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 14:47:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF talks to KOAT TV about roads</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-talks-to-koat-tv-about-roads/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;SB 2 has passed which means that the road issue has been &amp;#8220;put to bed&amp;#8221; for the time being. The bill which has been signed by the Gov. includes: $1.5 billion in new road spending via a bond (debt) package. This also includes: A 35% increase in the weight-distance tax on trucks A 25% increase [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-talks-to-koat-tv-about-roads/"&gt;RGF talks to KOAT TV about roads&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 16:09:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Domestic Outmigration is Hollowing Out Massachusetts’ Workforce and Economy</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/domestic-outmigration-is-hollowing-out-massachusetts-workforce-and-economy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;From April 2020 through July 2025, Massachusetts experienced a net loss of approximately 182,000 residents to domestic outmigration — the equivalent of losing one-and-a-half Cambridges. While a recent surge in international immigration temporarily boosted labor force numbers, new research from Pioneer Institute shows that underlying demographic, workforce, and economic challenges continue to threaten the Commonwealth’s long-term competitiveness. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/domestic-outmigration-is-hollowing-out-massachusetts-workforce-and-economy/"&gt;Domestic Outmigration is Hollowing Out Massachusetts’ Workforce and Economy &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 14:37:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Bipartisan electoral politics stand in the way of property tax relief</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/electoral-politics-property-tax-relief/</link><description>Kansas homeowners aren’t just facing higher property taxes — they’re facing unaffordable assessed valuation increases that make it impossible to budget for life essentials or stay in their homes. Property tax is the #1 affordability issue facing many Kansans, but nothing may be done about it – again – because electoral politics is the #1 [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 15:59:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] An Open Letter to Maine’s Legislature: Stop Advancing a Bill You Know is Unconstitutional</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/an-open-letter-to-maines-legislature-stop-advancing-a-bill-you-know-is-unconstitutional/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Last June, Maine Policy Institute urged Governor Janet Mills to veto LD 1666, a bill expanding ranked-choice voting (RCV) to elections for governor, state senator, and state representative. That request was grounded in clear constitutional text, the Maine Supreme Judicial Court’s 2017 advisory opinion, and Governor Mills’ own legal analysis as Attorney General. Since then, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/an-open-letter-to-maines-legislature-stop-advancing-a-bill-you-know-is-unconstitutional/"&gt;An Open Letter to Maine’s Legislature: Stop Advancing a Bill You Know is Unconstitutional&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 16:39:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Texas Parents Break Records for School Choice Applications</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/education/texas-parents-break-records-for-school-choice-applications/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Kathryn Hickok At last count, more than one and a half million...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/education/texas-parents-break-records-for-school-choice-applications/"&gt;Texas Parents Break Records for School Choice Applications&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 19:45:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Metro’s Plan for Making Housing More Expensive</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/reports/metros-plan-for-making-housing-more-expensive/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Randal O’Toole High housing prices in the Portland area led to a&amp;#160;legislative...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/reports/metros-plan-for-making-housing-more-expensive/"&gt;Metro’s Plan for Making Housing More Expensive&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 20:18:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG urges Wisconsin lawmakers to question DPI secrecy</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-urges-wisconsin-lawmakers-to-question-dpi-secrecy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;IRG urges Wisconsin lawmakers to question DPI secrecy (The Center Square) – It’s not just the nearly $400,000 expense that has one watchdog group wanting more from Wisconsin’s public school managers. The Institute for Reforming Government on Thursday said lawmakers in Madison need to question the secrecy around the Department of Public Instruction&amp;#8217;s 2024 meeting to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-urges-wisconsin-lawmakers-to-question-dpi-secrecy/"&gt;IRG urges Wisconsin lawmakers to question DPI secrecy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 21:08:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Nebraska Shouldn’t Tax Social Media Accounts</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-shouldnt-tax-social-media-accounts/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Under LB 1025, Nebraska would implement a first-in-the-nation tax on social media accounts, at rates of up to $6 per account per year. Other states have considered similar taxes, but no state has adopted a social media tax to date, and with good reason. The proposed tax could deprive Nebraskans of free access to online...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-shouldnt-tax-social-media-accounts/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Nebraska Shouldn’t Tax Social Media Accounts&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 15:38:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] New York’s Electricity Prices Among the Highest in the Country</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/new-yorks-electricity-prices-among-the-highest-in-the-country/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Albany, NY — New York households continue to pay some of the highest electricity prices in the nation, according to data from....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/new-yorks-electricity-prices-among-the-highest-in-the-country/"&gt;New York’s Electricity Prices Among the Highest in the Country&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 16:54:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] 2026 Capitol Chat: Week 6</title><link>https://empowerms.org/2026-capitol-chat-week-6/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Capitol Chat: Week 6 From floor votes to a few “spirited” House measures, Week 6 had a little bit of everything. We break down the education bills still moving, the buzz around a recent voice vote, and what’s brewing as lawmakers eye the next big deadline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/2026-capitol-chat-week-6/"&gt;2026 Capitol Chat: Week 6&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 17:22:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Newsmax: CMS Should Be Embracing Fla.’s Medicaid Success Story</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/newsmax-cms-should-be-embracing-fla-s-medicaid-success-story/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A decade ago, as speaker of the Florida House of Representatives, I&amp;#160;led&amp;#160;the fight against Medicaid expansion under Obamacare....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/newsmax-cms-should-be-embracing-fla-s-medicaid-success-story/"&gt;Newsmax: CMS Should Be Embracing Fla.&amp;#8217;s Medicaid Success Story&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 17:33:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Portland’s “Affordable” Housing Averages $800 per Square Foot</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/land-use/portlands-affordable-housing-averages-800-per-square-foot/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Randal O’Toole Note: This post is a sequel to Metro’s Plan for...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/land-use/portlands-affordable-housing-averages-800-per-square-foot/"&gt;Portland’s “Affordable” Housing Averages $800 per Square Foot&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 17:46:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Freedom Foundation Files Unfair Labor Practice Complaint Against Ohio Union after Bus Drivers Blocked from Stopping Dues Deductions</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/litigation/freedom-foundation-files-unfair-labor-practice-complaint-against-ohio-union-after-bus-drivers-blocked-from-stopping-dues-deductions/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Freedom Foundation today announced it has filed an unfair labor practice complaint against the Ohio Association of Public School Employees (OAPSE) after the union refused to stop collecting dues from seven Symmes Valley school bus drivers who had properly resigned their membership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/litigation/freedom-foundation-files-unfair-labor-practice-complaint-against-ohio-union-after-bus-drivers-blocked-from-stopping-dues-deductions/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation Files Unfair Labor Practice Complaint Against Ohio Union after Bus Drivers Blocked from Stopping Dues Deductions&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 20:09:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] Franke: Daylight Saving Folly</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2026/02/franke-daylight-saving-folly/</link><description>by Mark Frank “Time is the only scarce commodity.”&amp;#160;I heard this on a Viking commercial from company chairman Torstein Hagen. His point, I assume, is don’t put off things you have always wanted to do. Since Viking’s clientele is largely aging retirees, his advice is certainly well given. The problem with time is that it&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2026/02/franke-daylight-saving-folly/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 13:41:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Statement of Jim Stergios, Executive Director of Pioneer Institute on Governor Healey’s Opposition to Lowering State Income Tax</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/statement-of-jim-stergios-executive-director-of-pioneer-institute-on-governor-healeys-opposition-to-lowering-state-income-tax/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On Friday, Governor Healey opposed a proposed cut in the personal income tax that would put an average of $1,300 back into people’s pockets. Her claim that it would devastate the budget and gut education is a wild distortion—and it ignores more...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/statement-of-jim-stergios-executive-director-of-pioneer-institute-on-governor-healeys-opposition-to-lowering-state-income-tax/"&gt;Statement of Jim Stergios, Executive Director of Pioneer Institute on Governor Healey’s Opposition to Lowering State Income Tax&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 14:12:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Rifreedom] Center Launches K-12 Student Video Contest to Celebrate America’s 250th Birthday #America250RI</title><link>https://rifreedom.org/2026/02/center-launches-k-12-student-video-contest-to-celebrate-americas-250th-birthday-america250ri/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In recognition of President's Day and George Washington's upcoming birthday, the  RI Center for Freedom &amp;#038; Prosperity today launched a video contest encouraging K-12 students to create a video about why they are proud to celebrate America's semiquincentennial, commemorating the 250th Anniversary of the US Declaration of Independence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org/2026/02/center-launches-k-12-student-video-contest-to-celebrate-americas-250th-birthday-america250ri/"&gt;Center Launches K-12 Student Video Contest to Celebrate America&amp;#8217;s 250th Birthday #America250RI&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org"&gt;RI Center for Freedom and Prosperity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 14:18:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Research Note: Updates in Regulatory Restraint</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/research-note-updates-in-regulatory-restraint/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In recent years, states across the country have taken renewed interest in reviewing longstanding and often outdated regulatory frameworks. Many legislatures are reassessing rules that may constrain economic growth, aiming to reduce regulatory accumulation and increase legislative oversight of unelected agencies. Although each state varies in its approach, a common goal has emerged: limiting high-cost...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/research-note-updates-in-regulatory-restraint/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Research Note: Updates in Regulatory Restraint&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 14:18:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Freedom Foundation Files Unfair Labor Practice Complaint Against AFSCME After Union Refuses to Stop Dues Deductions for Toledo School Secretary</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/press-release/freedom-foundation-files-unfair-labor-practice-complaint-against-afscme-after-union-refuses-to-stop-dues-deductions-for-toledo-school-secretary/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Freedom Foundation today announced it has filed an unfair labor practice complaint with the Ohio State Employment Relations Board (SERB) against AFSCME Ohio Council 8 after the union refused to stop collecting dues from Sandra Nelson, a Toledo Public Schools secretary who properly resigned her membership — twice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/press-release/freedom-foundation-files-unfair-labor-practice-complaint-against-afscme-after-union-refuses-to-stop-dues-deductions-for-toledo-school-secretary/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation Files Unfair Labor Practice Complaint Against AFSCME After Union Refuses to Stop Dues Deductions for Toledo School Secretary&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 16:45:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Economic Updates Suggest Kansas Can Lead</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/economic-updates-suggest-kansas-can-lead/</link><description>If you only look at Kansas’s unemployment rate, you might think everything is fine. That’s the political trap: point to a low number, declare victory, and move on.  But the latest state labor and economic output data show a more complicated truth. Kansas has real strengths, but it’s also leaving growth on the table because [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 19:15:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] A Roadmap for States to Build High-Quality Online Education</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/a-roadmap-for-states-to-build-high-quality-online-education/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;BOSTON – State policy is pivotal to the development and availability of online and virtual learning options, and Pioneer Institute’s new Virtual Schools Toolkit provides tactical guidance for developing such policies in the current educational landscape.   “Virtual learning began by serving students...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/a-roadmap-for-states-to-build-high-quality-online-education/"&gt;A Roadmap for States to Build High-Quality Online Education&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 13:32:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Florida Politics: Anastasios Kamoutsas Curbs Double Counting in K-12 Scholarships</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/florida-politics-anastasios-kamoutsas-curbs-double-counting-in-k-12-scholarships/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;February 16, 2026 Administrative fix delivers zero net cost to state Anastasios Kamoutsas&amp;#160;has been in his new job...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/florida-politics-anastasios-kamoutsas-curbs-double-counting-in-k-12-scholarships/"&gt;Florida Politics: Anastasios Kamoutsas Curbs Double Counting in K-12 Scholarships&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 15:26:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] WILL Supports Teacher Bill of Rights</title><link>https://will-law.org/will-supports-teacher-bill-of-rights/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;#038; Liberty (WILL) supports the Teacher Bill of Rights, AB 614 / SB 611, introduced by Representative Goeben and Senator Cabral-Guevara. The legislation clarifies and strengthens teachers’ authority to maintain order in the classroom, protects teachers from retaliation when they enforce classroom rules or respond to disruptive or violent behavior, and ensures transparency and accountability when serious behavior incidents occur at school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/will-supports-teacher-bill-of-rights/"&gt;WILL Supports Teacher Bill of Rights&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 15:48:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Legislators look at local zoning rules blocking education, child care &amp; home businesses</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2026/02/legislators-look-at-local-zoning-rules-blocking-education-child-care-home-businesses/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Local land use regulations do more than severely restrict the size, shape, design and placement of homes, creating scarcity and driving up prices. They also heavily regulate the activities that occur inside those homes. These regulations derive from legitimate local police powers. Local governments exist primarily for the purpose of keeping the peace, and Americans [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2026/02/legislators-look-at-local-zoning-rules-blocking-education-child-care-home-businesses/"&gt;Legislators look at local zoning rules blocking education, child care &amp;#038; home businesses&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 16:01:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cardinalinstitute] West Virginia’s hospital debate is missing a key piece of the financial picture</title><link>https://cardinalinstitute.com/west-virginias-hospital-debate-is-missing-a-key-piece-of-the-financial-picture/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;West Virginia’s hospital debate is missing a key piece of the financial picture Debates over hospital policy in West Virginia usually follow a familiar pattern. Hospital systems warn that their finances are weak. Industry groups say they have too many patients with government insurance. Certificate of Need (CON) rules are defended as needed to keep [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com/west-virginias-hospital-debate-is-missing-a-key-piece-of-the-financial-picture/"&gt;West Virginia’s hospital debate is missing a key piece of the financial picture&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com"&gt;Cardinal Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 16:10:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Testimony in Opposition to SB 151</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/02/17/testimony-in-opposition-to-sb-151/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="630" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Testimonies-2026.jpg" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Chairs Senator Marx and Representative Felipe, Ranking Members Senator Sampson, and Representative Scott, and distinguished members of the Housing Committee.   Thank you for the opportunity to provide testimony on SB 151, An Act Prohibiting Certain Land [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/02/17/testimony-in-opposition-to-sb-151/"&gt;Testimony in Opposition to SB 151&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 16:43:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] We Can’t Afford to Trim Your Trees, but We Can Hire Lobbyists</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/we-cant-afford-to-trim-your-trees-but-we-can-hire-lobbyists/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=we-cant-afford-to-trim-your-trees-but-we-can-hire-lobbyists</link><description>We’ve long called for reform to the practice of taxpayer-funded lobbying. But this NES response is probably the most glaring example of the need for reform.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 18:22:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Aaron Rice: Defending the Constitution in Uniform and in Court</title><link>https://empowerms.org/aaron-rice-defending-the-constitution-in-uniform-and-in-court/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Aaron Rice: Defending the Constitution in Uniform and in Court What does it look like to defend the Constitution with your life, and then keep defending it with your career? In this episode, Grant sits down with Aaron Rice, a Mississippi Marine and Purple Heart recipient who was wounded in Iraq and later became a&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/aaron-rice-defending-the-constitution-in-uniform-and-in-court/"&gt;Aaron Rice: Defending the Constitution in Uniform and in Court&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 19:52:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Mamdani Gets an Important Tax Fact Wrong</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/mamdani-gets-an-important-tax-fact-wrong/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;At a hearing in Albany last week, New York City Mayor Zohran Mamdani lobbied state lawmakers to help him balance....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/mamdani-gets-an-important-tax-fact-wrong/"&gt;Mamdani Gets an Important Tax Fact Wrong&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 20:58:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Reducing Red Tape: Advancing Economic Liberty and Accountability In Nebraska</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/reducing-red-tape-advancing-economic-liberty-and-accountability-in-nebraska/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The growing volume and complexity of government regulation at the state and local levels threaten economic freedom, entrepreneurial innovation, and democratic accountability. State regulations, often issued by unelected officials in executive agencies, accumulate over time, creating significant &amp;#8220;hidden taxes&amp;#8221; on small businesses and families within the state. This policy brief outlines a set of proven,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/reducing-red-tape-advancing-economic-liberty-and-accountability-in-nebraska/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Reducing Red Tape: Advancing Economic Liberty and Accountability In Nebraska&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 21:01:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Freedom Foundation Challenges Oregon’s Unconstitutional Speech Law in Federal Court</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/press-release/freedom-foundation-challenges-oregons-unconstitutional-speech-law-in-federal-court/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Freedom Foundation today presented oral arguments in federal court seeking a preliminary injunction against Oregon HB 3789, a law that threatens the organization with millions in penalties for informing public employees about their constitutional rights. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/press-release/freedom-foundation-challenges-oregons-unconstitutional-speech-law-in-federal-court/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation Challenges Oregon&amp;#8217;s Unconstitutional Speech Law in Federal Court  &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 22:26:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] 2025 data is in: Four straight years of unaffordable assessed valuation hikes. Where’s the relief?</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/four-straight-years-assessed-valuation-hikes/</link><description>Assessed valuation changes for 2025, released this morning, reiterate the need for a constitutional amendment to limit the increases. The average increase for existing residential property (not counting new construction) of 5.9% is more than double the inflation rate, and that’s not the worst of the story. Homeowners in a dozen counties had double-digit increases [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 22:51:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Trump Administration Sides with WILL, Federal Scholarships Now Open to All Students in Need Regardless of Race</title><link>https://will-law.org/trump-administration-sides-with-will-federal-scholarships-now-open-to-all-needy-students-regardless-of-race/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/trump-administration-sides-with-will-federal-scholarships-now-open-to-all-needy-students-regardless-of-race/"&gt;Trump Administration Sides with WILL, Federal Scholarships Now Open to All Students in Need Regardless of Race&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 13:29:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2026/02/the-outstater-328/</link><description>History Matters, Ms. Ocasio-Cortez IT IS EASY to make fun of Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez (AOC) and her flubs. It is clear she doesn&amp;#8217;t  understand the dynamics that created America or her own heritage. But she is not alone. It would be surprising if there are 20 Indiana legislators who would fare better. Surveys of how little this generation understands of Western Civilization are so discouraging that&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2026/02/the-outstater-328/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 15:34:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] Government in the Shadows: Gov. Evers, AG Kaul, DPI and Other Officials Failing to Comply with Public Records Law</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/government-in-the-shadows-gov-evers-ag-kaul-dpi-and-other-officials-failing-to-comply-with-public-records-law/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Government in the Shadows: Gov. Evers, AG Kaul, DPI and Other Officials Failing to Comply with Public Records Law IRG has several outstanding requests that have been pending for months  Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government (IRG) has waited over eight months for records on DOJ immigration enforcement and the Evers Administration’s Office [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/government-in-the-shadows-gov-evers-ag-kaul-dpi-and-other-officials-failing-to-comply-with-public-records-law/"&gt;Government in the Shadows: Gov. Evers, AG Kaul, DPI and Other Officials Failing to Comply with Public Records Law&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 17:45:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] New Certificate of Need Law – A Small Free Market Win</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/new-certificate-of-need-law-a-small-free-market-win/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A small win for freedom in Mississippi!&amp;#160; Governor Tate Reeves recently signed HB3, a law that reforms the state’s Certificate of Need (CON) rules.&amp;#160; CON is basically a government approval process healthcare providers (like hospitals) must go through before they can add certain services, build new facilities, buy expensive equipment, or make big expansions. HB3 [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/new-certificate-of-need-law-a-small-free-market-win/" rel="nofollow"&gt;New Certificate of Need Law – A Small Free Market Win&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 19:24:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] What Will California Gas Prices Do in 2026?</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/what-will-california-gas-prices-do-in-2026/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=what-will-california-gas-prices-do-in-2026</link><description>&lt;p&gt;About the time it became inevitable that California was going to lose two major refineries, in May of last year, an alarming study was released by Michael Mische, an economist and business professor at USC. In his analysis, “Ensuring California’s Gasoline Security for the 21st Century,” Mische made a prediction that was widely quoted: “Based on current...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/what-will-california-gas-prices-do-in-2026/"&gt;What Will California Gas Prices Do in 2026?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 19:43:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Connecticut’s Proposed Climate Superfund Would Centralize Authority — and Raise Cost Questions</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/02/18/connecticuts-proposed-climate-superfund-would-centralize-authority-and-raise-cost-questions/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="1024" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/ChatGPT-Image-Feb-18-2026-at-03_03_58-PM.png" width="1536" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Environment Committee will hold a public hearing on Feb. 20 regarding H.B. 5156, a proposal to create a new “climate superfund” requiring certain fossil-fuel companies to pay for climate-related [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/02/18/connecticuts-proposed-climate-superfund-would-centralize-authority-and-raise-cost-questions/"&gt;Connecticut’s Proposed Climate Superfund Would Centralize Authority — and Raise Cost Questions &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 20:06:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Legislature Grants Initial Approval for WILL-Backed Constitutional Amendment to Protect Legislative Oversight</title><link>https://will-law.org/legislature-grants-initial-approval-for-will-backed-constitutional-amendment-to-protect-legislative-oversight/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Wisconsin State Senate approved Assembly Joint Resolution 133 (AJR 133) on first consideration, a WILL-supported proposed amendment to the Wisconsin Constitution designed to restore legislative oversight of administrative rulemaking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/legislature-grants-initial-approval-for-will-backed-constitutional-amendment-to-protect-legislative-oversight/"&gt;Legislature Grants Initial Approval for WILL-Backed Constitutional Amendment to Protect Legislative Oversight&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 20:32:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Pritzker proposes record-setting $56 billion budget</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/pritzker-proposes-record-setting-56-billion-budget/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Spending proposal features $1 billion in updated revenue assumptions, $589 million in tax and fee hikes and $139 million in fund sweeps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/pritzker-proposes-record-setting-56-billion-budget/"&gt;Pritzker proposes record-setting $56 billion budget&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 23:29:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Your Electricity Bill is the General Assembly’s New Favorite Piggy Bank</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/your-electricity-bill-is-the-general-assemblys-new-favorite-piggy-bank/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="720" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/IMG_7623.jpeg" width="1280" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key energy legislation poised to pass the 2026 General Assembly will increase your future electricity bills, not lower them.&amp;#160;They will worsen price increases already caused by the Virginia Clean Economy Act, which passed the last time Virginia was under one party control. As the Assembly crosses its first deadline, with each chamber now able to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/your-electricity-bill-is-the-general-assemblys-new-favorite-piggy-bank/"&gt;Your Electricity Bill is the General Assembly&amp;#8217;s New Favorite Piggy Bank&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 00:44:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Make Michigan competitive again</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2026/make-michigan-competitive-again</link><description>Prosperous states keep taxes low and regulatory burdens light</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Credit Card Price Controls Aren’t a Shortcut to Affordability</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/credit-card-price-controls-arent-a-shortcut-to-affordability/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When costs rise and families feel squeezed, Washington’s reflex is always the same: cap prices, mandate terms, declare victory. It’s..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/credit-card-price-controls-arent-a-shortcut-to-affordability/"&gt;Credit Card Price Controls Aren’t a Shortcut to Affordability&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 13:00:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Why Montanans need a convention to update their constitution</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/post/why-montanans-need-a-convention-to-update-their-constitution</link><description>The only way the people of Montana can systematically update their constitution is to commission a state convention to propose a new one.</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 14:49:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Virginiainstitute] The Case Against SB 269</title><link>https://virginiainstitute.org/the-case-against-sb-269/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=the-case-against-sb-269</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In Virginia's 2026 legislative session, Senate Bill 269 (patroned by Senator Favola) is a flashpoint for debate regarding the role of technology in mental healthcare. While proponents argue it creates necessary guardrails, it is a solution in search of a problem that could stifle innovation and limit patient access to care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org/the-case-against-sb-269/"&gt;The Case Against SB 269&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org"&gt;Virginia Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 14:54:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Assessing Tax Trends in the City of Austin</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/assessing-tax-trends-in-the-city-of-austin/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Does history suggest that property taxes are too high in the city of Austin? And, if so, have local decision-makers actively helped or hurt the situation?   To help answer these questions, let’s review the city’s 2024 Annual Comprehensive Financial Report (ACFR) and gather four types of data—i.e., tax levies, local population, total tax rates, and taxable values—over a 10-year time horizon. Using these audited estimates, we can gauge the growth of government (i.e., tax levy trends), assess its reasonability...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/assessing-tax-trends-in-the-city-of-austin/"&gt;Assessing Tax Trends in the City of Austin&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 19:44:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Another Step for Improving Missouri’s Licensing Regime</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/article/economy/another-step-for-improving-missouris-licensing-regime/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In occupational licensing, Missouri has been ahead of the curve. In 2020, the state established a universal licensing reciprocity regime, allowing licensed professionals from other states to have Missouri requirements [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/article/economy/another-step-for-improving-missouris-licensing-regime/"&gt;Another Step for Improving Missouri’s Licensing Regime&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 20:15:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Missouri Doesn’t Have To Be Kansas</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/article/taxes/missouri-doesnt-have-to-be-kansas/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A version of the following commentary appeared in the St. Louis Post-Dispatch. In his January 30 op-ed for the Post-Dispatch, Kansas political scientist Michael Smith called Governor Mike Kehoe’s proposal [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/article/taxes/missouri-doesnt-have-to-be-kansas/"&gt;Missouri Doesn&amp;#8217;t Have To Be Kansas&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 20:28:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] California High-Speed Rail at a Crossroads</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/california-high-speed-rail-at-a-crossroads/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=california-high-speed-rail-at-a-crossroads</link><description>&lt;p&gt;California&amp;#8217;s high-speed rail project has never lacked for drama, but the challenges converging on the California High-Speed Rail Authority in early 2026 represent something qualitatively different from the delays, cost overruns, and political skirmishes that have defined the project for the better part of two decades. The Authority now faces a reckoning that is simultaneously...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/california-high-speed-rail-at-a-crossroads/"&gt;California High-Speed Rail at a Crossroads&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 20:50:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Lawmakers split on how to keep WisEye broadcasting</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/lawmakers-split-on-how-to-keep-wiseye-broadcasting/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Until last week, it appeared that legislators from both political parties were on a path to restoring WisconsinEye, an independent channel that has broadcast state government meetings and events since 2007.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/lawmakers-split-on-how-to-keep-wiseye-broadcasting/"&gt;Lawmakers split on how to keep WisEye broadcasting&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 21:01:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Early Literacy Reform Advances in the House</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/article/education/early-literacy-reform-advances-in-the-house/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Listen to this article Momentum for early literacy reform continues in Jefferson City, as House Bill (HB) 2872 recently passed out of committee. While this version removed several provisions from [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/article/education/early-literacy-reform-advances-in-the-house/"&gt;Early Literacy Reform Advances in the House&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 21:07:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Arizona Supreme Court Weighs Jury Rights in the Administrative State</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/arizona-supreme-court-weighs-jury-rights-in-the-administrative-state/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Arizona Supreme Court this morning heard arguments in a crucial case about whether bureaucratic agencies can disregard the constitutional..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/arizona-supreme-court-weighs-jury-rights-in-the-administrative-state/"&gt;Arizona Supreme Court Weighs Jury Rights in the Administrative State&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 21:08:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Waste watch: Illinois uses temporary federal aid to fund ongoing social programs</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/waste-watch-illinois-uses-temporary-federal-aid-to-fund-ongoing-social-programs/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Illinois lawmakers diverted at least $74 million in one-time pandemic relief funds to select social programs and nonprofits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/waste-watch-illinois-uses-temporary-federal-aid-to-fund-ongoing-social-programs/"&gt;Waste watch: Illinois uses temporary federal aid to fund ongoing social programs&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 21:46:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] School levy tax credits reward big spenders at the expense of frugal districts</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/school-levy-tax-credits-reward-big-spenders-at-the-expense-of-frugal-districts/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;You might be paying higher school property taxes this year because of a referendum to exceed a school district’s revenue cap — one that you did not get a vote on in a district your kids do not attend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/school-levy-tax-credits-reward-big-spenders-at-the-expense-of-frugal-districts/"&gt;School levy tax credits reward big spenders at the expense of frugal districts&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 22:01:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Virginiainstitute] The Pioneering Spirit of Microschools</title><link>https://virginiainstitute.org/the-pioneering-spirit-of-microschools/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=the-pioneering-spirit-of-microschools</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Pioneering Spirit of Microschools: Insights from the Latest National Education Survey In an era where traditional institutions are increasingly questioned, the release of the 50CAN Educational Opportunity Survey&amp;#8217;s second&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org/the-pioneering-spirit-of-microschools/"&gt;The Pioneering Spirit of Microschools&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org"&gt;Virginia Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 22:05:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Crucial Badger-supported housing bill passes through Senate</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/crucial-badger-supported-housing-bill-passes-through-senate/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A bill that will ultimately help increase housing supply, make homes more affordable and still allow local municipalities to control where and how fast they grow passed through the Wisconsin Senate this week and was expected to pass in the Assembly Thursday as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/crucial-badger-supported-housing-bill-passes-through-senate/"&gt;Crucial Badger-supported housing bill passes through Senate&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 22:08:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] House Bill 720 — City elections, districts (+1)</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/house-bill-720-city-elections-districts/</link><description>Bill Description:&amp;#160;House Bill 720 would lower the population threshold for which cities are required to hold city council elections by district. Rating: +1 NOTE: House Bill 720 is similar to Senate Bill 1075 (2025).&amp;#160; Does it in any way restrict public access to information related to government activity or otherwise compromise government transparency, accountability, or [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 04:48:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Virginia Democrats equate their gerrymandering with fairness</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/virginia-democrats-equate-their-gerrymandering-with-fairness/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Breccan Thies writes for the Federalist about the latest shenanigans from leading Virginia Democrats. Virginia Democrats are rigging the statewide vote on their gerrymandering scheme with proposed ballot language that euphemistically describes the lopsided redistricting map as a plan “to restore fairness.” “Should the Constitution of Virginia be amended to allow the General Assembly to...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/virginia-democrats-equate-their-gerrymandering-with-fairness/"&gt;Virginia Democrats equate their gerrymandering with fairness&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 10:39:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Trump administration cancels visas for 100K foreign nationals</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/trump-administration-cancels-visas-for-100k-foreign-nationals/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Samantha Chang writes for the Western Journal about a significant Trump administration action. The Department of State revoked the visas of a record 100,000 foreign nationals with criminal backgrounds during the first year of President Donald Trump’s second term, pursuant to the administration’s goal of enhancing national security and public safety. The figure is an...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/trump-administration-cancels-visas-for-100k-foreign-nationals/"&gt;Trump administration cancels visas for 100K foreign nationals&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 10:42:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] ‘We don't wear capes’</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/podcasts/the-overton-window/donald-bryson-demonstrates-how-think-tanks-help-shape-public-policy-for-the-better</link><description>Donald Bryson demonstrates how think tanks help shape public policy for the better</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 10:58:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] The Death of Fair Representation: Every Partisan-Drawn Map is an Insult, but Virginia’s is the Most Insulting</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/the-death-of-fair-representation-every-partisan-drawn-map-is-an-insult-but-virginias-is-the-most-insulting/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="559" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/rank-of-shame.png" width="1024" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a difference between redistricting and rigging. One is a constitutional necessity. The other is&amp;#160;political&amp;#160;temptation.&amp;#160;Right now, Virginia stands at the crossroads between the two.&amp;#160;On&amp;#160;April&amp;#160;21st&amp;#160;the&amp;#160;voters will&amp;#160;decide&amp;#160;which way&amp;#160;we turn.&amp;#160; Using current congressional delegation data and 2024 presidential vote totals, we can measure fairness in a straightforward way: compare a party’s statewide vote share&amp;#160;in the last Presidential [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/the-death-of-fair-representation-every-partisan-drawn-map-is-an-insult-but-virginias-is-the-most-insulting/"&gt;The Death of Fair Representation: Every Partisan-Drawn Map is an Insult, but Virginia’s is the Most Insulting&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] No, a win for socialism is not a win for ‘freedom’</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/no-a-win-for-socialism-is-not-a-win-for-freedom/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As we celebrate the 250th anniversary of our nation’s founding, socialists in America are cynically exploiting our country’s traditional value of freedom to gain support for their economic system. Recently elected New York City mayor and self-avowed socialist Zohran Mamdani promised city voters that his platform would “win freedom for all,” and as a candidate...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/no-a-win-for-socialism-is-not-a-win-for-freedom/"&gt;No, a win for socialism is not a win for &amp;#8216;freedom&amp;#8217;&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2026/02/the-outstater-329/</link><description>Reality Check: NFL Economics BACK WHEN INDIANAPOLIS&amp;#160;was selling its&amp;#160;grandchildren to bring the Colts to town, an economist friend estimated that the contribution to the local economy would be equivalent to only three Walmarts. He was way off base. When spread over 365 days, the daily economic &amp;#8220;foot traffic&amp;#8221; impact of an NFL stadium falls between&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2026/02/the-outstater-329/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 12:38:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] First in the nation: How Iowa can lead the country in welfare reform</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/first-in-the-nation-how-iowa-can-lead-the-country-in-welfare-reform/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="First in the nation: How Iowa can lead the country in welfare reform" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/sunrise-1200x630-1.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key takeaways: Download a PDF of the full report. Iowa’s welfare system is at a crossroads. What were once temporary safety-net programs designed to protect the truly vulnerable have steadily expanded into sprawling systems that now touch nearly every corner of state government—and consume an ever-growing share of taxpayer resources. Nowhere is this more evident than in Medicaid and food [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/first-in-the-nation-how-iowa-can-lead-the-country-in-welfare-reform/"&gt;First in the nation: How Iowa can lead the country in welfare reform&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 13:22:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Iowa’s Welfare System Is Broken—and Now There’s a Path to Fix It</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/iowas-welfare-system-is-broken-and-now-theres-a-path-to-fix-it/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Iowa’s Welfare System Is Broken—and Now There’s a Path to Fix It" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/welfare-reform.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Medicaid has become Iowa’s largest welfare program, enrolling nearly one in five residents and consuming about one-quarter of the state budget, with rapid growth since the 2014 expansion. Rising welfare costs are straining taxpayers and crowding out core priorities, while contributing to workforce challenges and long-term dependency. Federal reforms create an opportunity for Iowa to lead, by enforcing work requirements, tightening eligibility, limiting loopholes, and restoring accountability. To better understand the scope and trajectory of Iowa’s welfare system, ITR Foundation commissioned a comprehensive report outlining both the challenges and the path forward. This article offers the highlights of that analysis.  For readers seeking a deeper dive,  the full report is accessible in the links above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/iowas-welfare-system-is-broken-and-now-theres-a-path-to-fix-it/"&gt;Iowa’s Welfare System Is Broken—and Now There’s a Path to Fix It&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 13:36:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Iowa can do more to reduce workforce barriers</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/iowa-can-do-more-to-reduce-workforce-barriers/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Iowa can do more to reduce workforce barriers" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/iowa-capital-dispatch-1200x630-1.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The need for more qualified workers is a bipartisan issue in Iowa. Regardless of a rural or urban setting, workforce is still a concern for many employers and communities. State policymakers have been responsive to this concern, and they have actively been easing regulatory burdens in recent years. This includes reducing barriers to employment and ensuring that unnecessary roadblocks do not deter individuals from securing meaningful work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/iowa-can-do-more-to-reduce-workforce-barriers/"&gt;Iowa can do more to reduce workforce barriers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 13:36:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Virginiainstitute] Are Virginia’s Newest “Tax Cuts” Actually Tax Cuts?</title><link>https://virginiainstitute.org/are-virginias-newest-tax-cuts-actually-tax-cuts/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=are-virginias-newest-tax-cuts-actually-tax-cuts</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Campaign promises are easy to make, but often far harder to legislate. Last November, Virginia Democrats ran on what they called the “Affordable Virginia Plan,” promising to reduce the cost&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org/are-virginias-newest-tax-cuts-actually-tax-cuts/"&gt;Are Virginia’s Newest “Tax Cuts” Actually Tax Cuts?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org"&gt;Virginia Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 14:06:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] House Bill 673 — State legislators, qualifications (-1)</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/house-bill-673-state-legislators-qualifications/</link><description>Bill Description: House Bill 673 would require a legislative candidate to have maintained a home in the district for a year before filing, rather than a year before the general election.  Rating: -1 Does it in any way restrict public access to information related to government activity or otherwise compromise government transparency, accountability, or election integrity? [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 14:22:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Assessing Tax Trends in the City of Arlington</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/assessing-tax-trends-in-the-city-of-arlington/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Does history suggest that property taxes are too high in the city of Arlington? And, if so, have local decision-makers actively helped or hurt the situation?   To help answer these questions, let’s review the city’s 2024 Annual Comprehensive Financial Report (ACFR) and gather four types of data—i.e., tax levies, local population, total tax rates, and taxable values—over a 10-year time horizon. Using these audited estimates, we can gauge the growth of government (i.e., tax levy trends), assess its reasonability...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/assessing-tax-trends-in-the-city-of-arlington/"&gt;Assessing Tax Trends in the City of Arlington&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 15:45:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] As Other States Move Forward, Will New Jersey Leave Education Dollars Behind?</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/02/as-other-states-move-forward-will-new-jersey-leave-education-dollars-behind/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;#160; By Wells Winegar, Executive Director, New Jersey Policy Institute &amp;#160; As Governor Mikie Sherrill begins her term in office, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/02/as-other-states-move-forward-will-new-jersey-leave-education-dollars-behind/"&gt;As Other States Move Forward, Will New Jersey Leave Education Dollars Behind?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 16:04:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Affordable housing mandates drive up home prices, reduce inventory</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/02/affordable-housing-mandates-drive-up-home-prices-reduce-inventory/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the House Committee on Water and Land on Feb. 19, 2026._____________ Feb. 19, 2026, 9 a.m.Hawaii State CapitolConference Room 411 and Videoconference To: House Committee on Water and Land       Rep. Mark Hashem, Chair       Rep. Dee Morikawa, Vice Chair From: Grassroot Institute [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/02/affordable-housing-mandates-drive-up-home-prices-reduce-inventory/"&gt;Affordable housing mandates drive up home prices, reduce inventory&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 16:29:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Medicare’s ‘efficiency’ cut will reduce access, not costs</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/medicares-efficiency-cut-will-reduce-access-not-costs/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Many physicians received another pay cut this year, courtesy of Medicare. Under the program’s new physician fee schedule, Medicare reimbursement for the vast majority of physician-provided services will effectively decline by 2.5%. Medicare officials justify the change as an “efficiency adjustment.” The theory is that doctors have gotten more productive over time — and therefore [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/medicares-efficiency-cut-will-reduce-access-not-costs/"&gt;Medicare’s ‘efficiency’ cut will reduce access, not costs&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 16:29:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Establish regulations and permitting rules for mobile homes</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/02/establish-regulations-and-permitting-rules-for-mobile-homes/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the House Committee on Transportation on Feb. 19, 2026._____________ Feb. 19, 2026, 9 a.m.Hawaii State CapitolConference Room 430 and Videoconference To: House Committee on Transportation&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Rep. Darius K. Kila, Chair&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Rep. Tyson K. Miyake, Vice Chair From: Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/02/establish-regulations-and-permitting-rules-for-mobile-homes/"&gt;Establish regulations and permitting rules for mobile homes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 16:33:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Make it easier for ‘seagliders’ to operate in Hawaii</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/02/make-it-easier-for-seagliders-to-operate-in-hawaii/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the House Committee on Transportation on Feb. 19, 2026._____________ Feb. 19, 2026, 9 a.m.Hawaii State CapitolConference Room 430 and Videoconference To: House Committee on Transportation&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Rep. Darius K. Kila, Chair&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Rep. Tyson K. Miyake, Vice Chair From: Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/02/make-it-easier-for-seagliders-to-operate-in-hawaii/"&gt;Make it easier for &amp;#8216;seagliders&amp;#8217; to operate in Hawaii&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 16:36:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] U.S. Supreme Court upholds the exclusive taxing power of Congress</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/post/u-s-supreme-court-upholds-the-exclusive-taxing-power-of-congress</link><description>Whether tariff tax increases are good or bad economic policy, the fact remains that tax increases should be introduced, debated, and voted on by Congress. Major economic policies of any kind should not be imposed by one person unilaterally. This decision by the U.S. Supreme Court upholds and affirms that important check and balance of our republic.</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 17:10:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] The Wisconsin Administrative Reform Toolbox</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/the-wisconsin-administrative-reform-toolbox/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;AdministrativeReformToolbox&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/the-wisconsin-administrative-reform-toolbox/"&gt;The Wisconsin Administrative Reform Toolbox&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 17:40:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] 2026 Capitol Chat: Week 7</title><link>https://empowerms.org/2026-capitol-chat-week-7/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Capitol Chat: Week 7 It was a budget-heavy week under the Dome, with more than 100 appropriations bills clearing a critical hurdle. We unpack the latest on education funding, the lingering school choice conversation, and what to watch as the session heads toward its next deadline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/2026-capitol-chat-week-7/"&gt;2026 Capitol Chat: Week 7&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 18:06:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Why Michigan needs more housing, despite a flat population</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2026/michigan-needs-more-housing-despite-a-flat-population</link><description>What matters is the number of people who want to buy</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 18:47:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Governor Little makes a big commitment to expand educational opportunities for families</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/post/governor-little-makes-a-big-commitment-to-expand-educational-opportunities-for-families</link><description>By opting into the federal scholarship tax credit program, Idaho continues to reinforce its commitment to education freedom and parental choice, ensuring families have greater access to resources that help tailor education to each child’s unique needs.</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 18:52:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Trump Repeals EPA’s Endangerment Finding, Preserving Affordable Energy and Housing</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/trump-repeals-epas-endangerment/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=trump-repeals-epas-endangerment</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On February 12, the Trump Administration formally repealed the Environmental Protection Agency’s 2009 “endangerment finding” that gave the EPA authority to regulate greenhouse gas emissions from virtually anything that used energy, including vehicles, power plants, factories, dairy farms, landfills, fertilizer, rice paddies, tractors, air conditioners, refrigerators, etc. Reactions were swift. From CBS News, “an enormous blow to...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/trump-repeals-epas-endangerment/"&gt;Trump Repeals EPA’s Endangerment Finding, Preserving Affordable Energy and Housing&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 18:55:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Illinois job openings drop by 100,000 since September with 302,000 unemployed</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/illinois-job-openings-drop-by-100000-since-september-with-302000-unemployed/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Illinois job openings are down by more than 100,000 since September. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/illinois-job-openings-drop-by-100000-since-september-with-302000-unemployed/"&gt;Illinois job openings drop by 100,000 since September with 302,000 unemployed&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 18:57:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Connecticut’s Fiscal Guardrails Saved the State. Why Weaken Them Now?</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/02/20/connecticuts-fiscal-guardrails-saved-the-state-why-weaken-them-now/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connecticut lawmakers are once again eyeing the state’s fiscal guardrails — the bipartisan reforms widely credited with stabilizing the state’s finances less than a decade ago.  But many of the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/02/20/connecticuts-fiscal-guardrails-saved-the-state-why-weaken-them-now/"&gt;Connecticut’s Fiscal Guardrails Saved the State. Why Weaken Them Now? &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 19:18:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Week in Review: Underdogs No More</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-underdogs-no-more/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Going to court is hard enough without having the deck stacked against you from the start. In a major victory..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-underdogs-no-more/"&gt;Week in Review: Underdogs No More&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 19:31:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] An anti-science FDA is a threat to our health and prosperity</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/an-anti-science-fda-is-a-threat-to-our-health-and-prosperity/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Food and Drug Administration supposedly “implements gold standard science.” Yet the agency appears to relish obstructing scientific progress. Earlier this month, Vinay Prasad, the director of FDA’s vaccine division, rejected Moderna’s application for a new mRNA flu vaccine for adults 50 and older on dubious grounds. The FDA claimed that the application did [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/an-anti-science-fda-is-a-threat-to-our-health-and-prosperity/"&gt;An anti-science FDA is a threat to our health and prosperity&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 20:56:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Hochul continues to bribe Big Health with reckless Medicaid spending</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/hochul-continues-to-bribe-big-health-with-reckless-medicaid-spending/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For the fourth year in a row, Gov. Kathy Hochul has used the word “unsustainable” to describe her own Medicaid budget. Give her....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/hochul-continues-to-bribe-big-health-with-reckless-medicaid-spending/"&gt;Hochul continues to bribe Big Health with reckless Medicaid spending&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 20:57:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Winners &amp; Losers: The Fight for Western Civilization (and beating Canada)</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/winners-losers-the-fight-for-western-civilization-and-beating-canada/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Every Friday morning, I join the Cardle &amp;#38; Woolley Show on Talk 1370 Radio in Austin to announce the week’s Winners &amp;#38; Losers. Next week you can join us at the Texas Public Policy Foundation for Winners and Losers LIVE. Click here for more info.   See you there. Here’s who made this week’s list....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/winners-losers-the-fight-for-western-civilization-and-beating-canada/"&gt;Winners &amp; Losers: The Fight for Western Civilization (and beating Canada)&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 21:26:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Marxism and Western Tradition: Identifying the Proper Role of Government</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/marxism-and-western-tradition-identifying-the-proper-role-of-government/</link><description>The Idaho legislative session is in full swing, and as lawmakers debate particular issues like education, parental rights, bodily autonomy, judicial reform, regulations and licensure, and budgets, they are actually engaging — often implicitly — in the age-old philosophical dispute about the proper role of government. Lawmakers are daily confronting the question: who should shape [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 21:53:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Jason Lewis: ‘Doable’ health care reform can deliver money to consumers now</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/jason-lewis-doable-health-care-reform-can-deliver-money-to-consumers-now/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This week, Center of the American Experiment President John Hinderaker addressed approximately 250 attendees — mostly snowbirds — at the organization’s annual Naples, Florida meeting. Hinderaker delivered a comprehensive update on how American Experiment has worked to provide truthful, fact-based information about what is actually happening in Minnesota to assist journalists and lawmakers alike, amid...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/jason-lewis-doable-health-care-reform-can-deliver-money-to-consumers-now/"&gt;Jason Lewis: &amp;#8216;Doable&amp;#8217; health care reform can deliver money to consumers now&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 01:08:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] A Win for Louisiana: SCOTUS Limits Trump’s Tariffs</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/legal-regulatory/trumps-tarrifs/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Louisiana is one of the most trade-exposed states in America. That’s not a slogan, it’s our economic reality. So when Washington plays roulette with tariffs, Louisianans don’t just read about it, they feel it in port activity, energy exports, manufacturing costs, farm demand, and household budgets. That’s why today’s 6–3 Supreme Court decision limiting President...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/legal-regulatory/trumps-tarrifs/"&gt;A Win for Louisiana: SCOTUS Limits Trump’s Tariffs&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 03:43:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] 2026 Legislative Session Public Safety and Criminal Justice Overview</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/local-government/public-satefy-criminal-justice-overview/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;With just weeks until the legislative session begins, the nearly 200 prefiled bills and the spotlight of local journalism reflect the policy priorities that will dominate the legislature this year. On the public safety front, a growing concern over corrections costs and budgetary issues, a renewed attention to the value of reentry courts and prerelease...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/local-government/public-satefy-criminal-justice-overview/"&gt;2026 Legislative Session Public Safety and Criminal Justice Overview&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 04:05:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Minnesota’s Economic News — W/E 2/20/26</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/minnesotas-economic-news-w-e-2-20-26/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;State and local taxes and spending Mesabi Tribune: School officials beat the drum on seasonal recreation property taxes The Ely Echo: More lodging tax drama West Central Tribune: Minnesota Opinion: Don&amp;#8217;t forget, lawmakers, it&amp;#8217;s a bonding year KROC: Minnesota January Tax Revenue Beats Forecast by Nearly 17%&amp;#160; Grand Rapids Herald Review: As federal surge ends,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/minnesotas-economic-news-w-e-2-20-26/"&gt;Minnesota’s Economic News — W/E 2/20/26&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 06:01:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Arizona cities should be blocked from blocking short-term rentals</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/arizona-cities-should-be-blocked-from-blocking-short-term-rentals/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Ten years ago, then-Arizona Gov. Doug Ducey signed Senate Bill 1350 into law, preventing local governments from banning short-term rentals in their respective jurisdictions. “For thousands of hardworking citizens, opening up their home to out-of-state guests provides the financial breathing room they need to provide for their family or enjoy an extra expense that they [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/arizona-cities-should-be-blocked-from-blocking-short-term-rentals/"&gt;Arizona cities should be blocked from blocking short-term rentals&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 11:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Habeas Man</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/habeas-man/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Edgar Vinicio Pilamunga-Toalombo represents a rare cross-over case: an apparent illegal alien with one federal judge considering a habeas corpus petition for his release, with another federal judge having ordered his detention on federal criminal charges. Call him Habeas Man. At present Pilamunga is being held by the U.S. Marshals in the federal lockup at...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/habeas-man/"&gt;Habeas Man&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 16:59:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Interview with Louisiana Works Secretary Susie Schowen</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/education/secretary-susie-schowen/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Governor Landry recently issued an executive order &amp;#8220;Modernizing Louisiana&amp;#8217;s Workforce For A New Era.&amp;#8221; Louisiana Works Secretary Susie Schowen breaks down what this means for job seekers and Louisiana&amp;#8217;s growing economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/education/secretary-susie-schowen/"&gt;Interview with Louisiana Works Secretary Susie Schowen&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 17:04:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Supreme Court Restores the Rule of Law and, for a Moment, Increased Economic Freedom</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/supreme-court-restores-the-rule-of-law-and-for-a-moment-increased-economic-freedom/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="630" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/exec-tariffs-1.jpg" width="630" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Supreme Court’s decision in&amp;#160;Learning Resources v. Trump&amp;#160;is a landmark reaffirmation of one of the Constitution’s most fundamental principles: the power to tax belongs to Congress alone.&amp;#160;Article I, Section 8 of the Constitution&amp;#160;explicitly vests in the legislative branch the authority “to lay and collect Taxes, Duties, Imposts and Excises.” Tariffs are taxes, and the Court [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/supreme-court-restores-the-rule-of-law-and-for-a-moment-increased-economic-freedom/"&gt;Supreme Court Restores the Rule of Law and, for a Moment, Increased Economic Freedom&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 00:03:39 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>