<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>State-Policy Think-Tank Digest</title><link>https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml</link><description>Latest posts from free-market policy institutes across the U.S.</description><atom:link href="https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 13:30:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] ABQ Ethics Board Dismisses frivolous “sweatshirt-gate” ethics complaint made by Keller campaign against RGF’s Paul Gessing</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/abq-ethics-board-dismisses-frivolous-sweatshirt-gate-ethics-complaint-made-by-keller-campaign-against-rgfs-paul-gessing/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This afternoon in a hearing, the Albuquerque Board of Ethics (BOE) unanimously dismissed a complaint filed by Daymon Ely for the Tim Keller campaign that was made against Rio Grande Foundation president Paul Gessing. The complaint arose out of the Foundation’s reporting over the purchase and delivery of yellow hoodie sweatshirts to members of Albuquerque’s [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/abq-ethics-board-dismisses-frivolous-sweatshirt-gate-ethics-complaint-made-by-keller-campaign-against-rgfs-paul-gessing/"&gt;ABQ Ethics Board Dismisses frivolous “sweatshirt-gate” ethics complaint made by Keller campaign against RGF’s Paul Gessing&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 22:08:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cardinalinstitute] 2026 State of the State Response</title><link>https://cardinalinstitute.com/2026-state-of-the-state-response/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;2026 State of the State Response On Wednesday evening, Governor Patrick Morrisey delivered his annual State of the State address, outlining his priorities for the year ahead and offering a window into his governing philosophy. As is customary, the speech functioned as both pep rally and agenda-setting exercise. State of the state addresses tend to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com/2026-state-of-the-state-response/"&gt;2026 State of the State Response&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com"&gt;Cardinal Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 15:07:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF opinion piece: Data centers are coming: How to handle them</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-opinion-piece-data-centers-are-coming-how-to-handle-them/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following appeared in the Santa Fe New Mexican on January 10, 2026. It has appeared in several other publications as well. &amp;#160; After years of failure to land a “big fish” business for New Mexico’s economy (or effectively use the oil and gas revenues to grow the economy) Gov. Michelle Lujan Grisham, with the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-opinion-piece-data-centers-are-coming-how-to-handle-them/"&gt;RGF opinion piece: Data centers are coming: How to handle them&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 15:48:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Rifreedom] “Doc” Skoly Stepping Down as Center’s Chair to Pursue Congressional Seat</title><link>https://rifreedom.org/2026/01/doc-skoly-stepping-down-as-centers-chair-to-pursue-congressional-seat/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The  Rhode Island Center for Freedom &amp;#038; Prosperity announced today that Dr. Stephen "Doc" Skoly has stepped down as Chairman of its Board of Directors to pursue a run for the US House of Representatives in Rhode Island's second Congressional district.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org/2026/01/doc-skoly-stepping-down-as-centers-chair-to-pursue-congressional-seat/"&gt;&amp;#8220;Doc&amp;#8221; Skoly Stepping Down as Center&amp;#8217;s Chair to Pursue Congressional Seat&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org"&gt;RI Center for Freedom and Prosperity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 15:10:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Policy Pathway for Principled Tax Reform</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/policy-pathway-for-principled-tax-reform/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Policy Pathway for Principled Tax Reform outlines a framework for evaluating tax policy through the lens of sound tax principles including transparency, simplicity, stability, neutrality, and economic efficiency. The report examines Nebraska’s major tax types including property, income, and sales and offers practical, principle-based recommendations to improve affordability, competitiveness, and long-term fiscal sustainability. While designed...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/policy-pathway-for-principled-tax-reform/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Policy Pathway for Principled Tax Reform&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 19:40:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cardinalinstitute] Healthcare in West Virginia</title><link>https://cardinalinstitute.com/healthcare-in-west-virginia/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Healthcare in West Virginia Healthcare policy is complicated. These resources make it understandable. If you are trying to make sense of West Virginia’s latest healthcare debates, you are not alone. PBM regulation, PEIA’s recurring funding crises, and Certificate of Need laws all affect what care costs, where it is available, and who has choices. We [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com/healthcare-in-west-virginia/"&gt;Healthcare in West Virginia&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com"&gt;Cardinal Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 15:44:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Cascade Policy Institute is Hiring – Development Assistant</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/news/cascade-policy-institute-is-hiring-development-assistant/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;We are seeking a detail-oriented, organized, part-time Development Assistant to support Cascade Policy...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/news/cascade-policy-institute-is-hiring-development-assistant/"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute is Hiring &amp;#8211; Development Assistant&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 23:07:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] If You Want Parent Power, Only HB2 Will Do</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/if-you-want-parent-power-only-hb2-will-do/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past few years, Mississippi lawmakers have passed some critical conservative reforms.&amp;#160;Last year, Mississippi became the first state in America to legislate to eliminate the income tax in 40 years.&amp;#160; In 2022, we implemented flat tax reform.&amp;#160; A few years before that, we passed important labor market reforms.&amp;#160; In 2024, we reformed school funding [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/if-you-want-parent-power-only-hb2-will-do/" rel="nofollow"&gt;If You Want Parent Power, Only HB2 Will Do&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 16:09:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] A Trillion Dollar Energy Law – HB2021: Watch John Charles on PDX Real</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/environment/a-trillion-dollar-energy-law-hb2021-watch-john-charles-on-pdx-real/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;“All we want as consumers is reliable, affordable energy.” ~John A. Charles, Jr.,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/environment/a-trillion-dollar-energy-law-hb2021-watch-john-charles-on-pdx-real/"&gt;A Trillion Dollar Energy Law &amp;#8211; HB2021: Watch John Charles on PDX Real&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 00:12:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Rifreedom] MEDIA RELEASE: Center Launches Petition Calling for Affordable Energy Policies</title><link>https://rifreedom.org/2026/01/media-release-center-launches-petition-calling-for-affordable-energy-policies/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Rhode Island Center for Freedom &amp;#038; Prosperity today announced that it has launched an online petition drive calling for policymakers to support a fundamental pivot away from our state's current energy strategy, which will lead to staggeringly high electricity prices and potentially dangerous blackouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org/2026/01/media-release-center-launches-petition-calling-for-affordable-energy-policies/"&gt;MEDIA RELEASE: Center Launches Petition Calling for Affordable Energy Policies&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org"&gt;RI Center for Freedom and Prosperity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 14:19:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Open enrollment: Know the basics</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2026/01/open-enrollment-know-the-basics/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In 2025, New Hampshire legislators passed a law allowing students to enroll in any public school within their assigned district, as long as the school had room. This year, lawmakers might allow students to enroll in any New Hampshire public school that has room. This policy brief answers six core questions commonly raised about open [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2026/01/open-enrollment-know-the-basics/"&gt;Open enrollment: Know the basics&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 19:28:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] Day One, Energy First: Governor Mikie Sherrill’s Opening Strategy on Affordability</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/01/day-one-energy-first-governor-mikie-sherrills-opening-strategy-on-affordability/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Sean Barry, NJPI Jr. Fellow When Governor Mikie Sherrill was sworn in as New Jersey’s 57th governor, she did [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/01/day-one-energy-first-governor-mikie-sherrills-opening-strategy-on-affordability/"&gt;Day One, Energy First: Governor Mikie Sherrill’s Opening Strategy on Affordability&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 19:08:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] A New Governor Takes Office. Will She Deliver on Education?</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/01/a-new-governor-takes-office-will-she-deliver-on-education/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;by Aiden DeMarsey, NJPI Jr. Fellow &amp;#160; Governor Mikie Sherrill, sworn into office last week, enters her term with a [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/01/a-new-governor-takes-office-will-she-deliver-on-education/"&gt;A New Governor Takes Office. Will She Deliver on Education?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 19:10:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] A foolish law wages war against homemade shindigs</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/a-foolish-law-wages-war-against-homemade-shindigs/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The law, passed in 2023, decrees that venues rented for private events at which the people holding the party bring their own alcohol can host only six such events a year, and only one a month — unless they prohibit bring-your-own drinks and instead get a liquor license like a tavern. Those are subject to strict quotas. Town board can simply refuse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/a-foolish-law-wages-war-against-homemade-shindigs/"&gt;A foolish law wages war against homemade shindigs&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 19:33:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] New housing permits are highest since 2006, but single-family homes lag</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2026/01/new-housing-permits-are-highest-since-2006-but-single-family-homes-lag/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New Hampshire towns and cities are permitting more residential housing units than they have in years, which is great news. But the new units are skewed heavily toward rentals, suggesting that local restrictions on small, single-family homes remain a significant barrier. Local governments issued permits for 5,822 new housing units in 2024, the highest number [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2026/01/new-housing-permits-are-highest-since-2006-but-single-family-homes-lag/"&gt;New housing permits are highest since 2006, but single-family homes lag&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:16:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] The Denial of Distinctions</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/the-denial-of-distinctions/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Denial of Distinctions By Abe Greenwald Yesterday, I wrote about the return of American disorder in the form of mobs that obstruct ICE raids. Part of what makes anti-ICE/open-border activism so strange is that it attacks the most fundamental aspect of what it means to be a country: its physical boundaries. When leftists repeat, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/the-denial-of-distinctions/"&gt;The Denial of Distinctions&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:37:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Crime is down, and it should end ‘root cause’ excuse-making for good</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/crime-is-down-and-it-should-end-root-cause-excuse-making-for-good/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/crime-is-down-and-it-should-end-root-cause-excuse-making-for-good/"&gt;Crime is down, and it should end ‘root cause’ excuse-making for good&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 22:13:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Sedgwick County Commissioners use scare tactics and false claim to oppose property tax assessment limit</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/sedgwick-assessment-limit-scare-tactics/</link><description>Neutral testimony from the Kansas Association of Counties on the proposed 3% valuation assessment limit says, “The major benefit for taxpayers is predictability,” and notes that predictability could also help counties by having fewer disputes over valuations. Sedgwick County Commissioners, on the other hand, are taking a ‘sky is falling’ approach replete with scare tactics [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 16:56:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Introducing TennSight, Tennessee’s only hub for voter insights</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/introducing-tennsight-tennessees-only-hub-for-voter-insights/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=introducing-tennsight-tennessees-only-hub-for-voter-insights</link><description>We hope that TennSight will become the go-to source for you to learn what matters most to your fellow Tennesseans, why it matters, and what can be done about it.</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 13:08:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] A Steady-State Budget in a Moment of Crisis</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/a-steady-state-budget-in-a-moment-of-crisis/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Governor Maura Healey’s fiscal year 2027 budget totals $62.8 billion, a 3.8 percent year-over-year increase. The budget avoids sweeping new initiatives and largely preserves existing structures. That might be defensible in a period of stability. It is indefensible now. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/a-steady-state-budget-in-a-moment-of-crisis/"&gt;A Steady-State Budget in a Moment of Crisis &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 16:44:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Idaho schools paying $1.2 million per year for IEA/NEA dues</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/labor/idaho-schools-paying-1-2-million-per-year-for-iea-nea-dues/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;According to a new Freedom Foundation analysis, the Boise and Twin Falls School Districts are spending more than $1.2 million per year on programs to cover the cost of teachers union dues to the Idaho Education Association. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/labor/idaho-schools-paying-1-2-million-per-year-for-iea-nea-dues/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Idaho schools paying $1.2 million per year for IEA/NEA dues&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 17:33:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Beacon Poll: January 2026 Results</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/beacon-poll-january-2026-results/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=beacon-poll-january-2026-results</link><description>Today, we released the latest installment of the Beacon Poll, a statewide survey of 1,200 Tennessee voters featuring questions about voters’ views on property taxes, the federal school choice tax credit included in the One Big Beautiful Bill Act, and political approval ratings at the state and federal level, and more. Tennesseans continue to prioritize key...</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 19:35:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Johnson County superintendents fail 4th-grade math</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/johnson-county-supers-fail-4th-grade-math/</link><description>Today’s math riddle is brought to you by Johnson County school superintendents: How can taxpayers give school districts hundreds of millions of dollars more for special education without increasing total spending or cutting other state funding? The obvious answer is that it’s not possible, but that is what they tell taxpayers, and in their pitch [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 00:15:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Age Verification Isn’t Parenting</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/age-verification-isnt-parenting/</link><description>Kansas lawmakers are weighing a proposal that would require new age-verification measures for online platforms, part of a growing national effort to address concerns about children’s safety in digital spaces. The goal is understandable. Parents across Kansas want their kids protected online. The harder question is how far government should go—and whether mandates aimed at [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 16:00:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Dr. John Dixon: Charter Schools, Choice, and Accountability</title><link>https://empowerms.org/dr-john-dixon-charter-schools-choice-and-accountability/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Dr. John Dixon: Charter Schools, Choice, and Accountability As the 2026 legislative session moves forward, the conversation around school choice continues to intensify. While much of the focus has been on ESAs and public school transfers, one form of public school choice has quietly served thousands of Mississippi families for years: public charter schools. In&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/dr-john-dixon-charter-schools-choice-and-accountability/"&gt;Dr. John Dixon: Charter Schools, Choice, and Accountability&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 18:41:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] A State of the State Built on “You’re Welcome”</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/a-state-of-the-state-built-on-youre-welcome/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Last week Governor Janet Mills delivered her final State of the State address. The hour-long speech was heavy on reflection and self-congratulation. Again and again, the Governor reminded Mainers, sometimes explicitly, that we should be thanking her for her governance. But self gratitude is not a governing philosophy. And after seven years in office, Mainers [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/a-state-of-the-state-built-on-youre-welcome/"&gt;A State of the State Built on “You’re Welcome”&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 20:59:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cardinalinstitute] Op-Ed: Hospitals Collect Tax Breaks. West Virginians Collect Medical Debt.</title><link>https://cardinalinstitute.com/op-ed-hospitals-collect-tax-breaks-west-virginians-collect-medical-debt/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;To many West Virginians, healthcare continues to be a burden more than a lifeline as roughly 180,000 residents, or 13.3% of adults, now facing some sort of  medical debt. This is well above the national average of 8.6% and, even worse, nearly one in four of these residents in rural Appalachia have medical debt in [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com/op-ed-hospitals-collect-tax-breaks-west-virginians-collect-medical-debt/"&gt;Op-Ed: Hospitals Collect Tax Breaks. West Virginians Collect Medical Debt.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com"&gt;Cardinal Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 15:16:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Why Portland’s Suggested Statewide Eviction Moratorium Would Hurt Maine’s Housing Market</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/why-portlands-suggested-statewide-eviction-moratorium-would-hurt-maines-housing-market/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Portland city officials are urging Gov. Janet Mills to impose a 60-day statewide eviction moratorium in response to “fear and instability” that they are linking to federal immigration enforcement. While the resolution is framed as an emergency measure that they are claiming is only meant to protect “vulnerable residents,” such a moratorium risks repeating a [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/why-portlands-suggested-statewide-eviction-moratorium-would-hurt-maines-housing-market/"&gt;Why Portland&amp;#8217;s Suggested Statewide Eviction Moratorium Would Hurt Maine’s Housing Market&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 16:38:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] Tim Pawlenty: The Crisis Will Subside in Minnesota, but Trust Will Need to be Rebuilt</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/tim-pawlenty-the-crisis-will-subside-in-minnesota-but-trust-will-need-to-be-rebuilt/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;We’ll all be part of that task. Here’s where efforts could be focused. By Tim Pawlenty For the Star Tribune It’s been said that trust is the glue that holds relationships together. That may well explain why recent events in Minnesota have stretched our relationship with government to the breaking point. Fraudsters stole a ton [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/tim-pawlenty-the-crisis-will-subside-in-minnesota-but-trust-will-need-to-be-rebuilt/"&gt;Tim Pawlenty: The Crisis Will Subside in Minnesota, but Trust Will Need to be Rebuilt&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 19:57:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] The Numbers Don’t Lie: The CHOOSE Act is Empowering Alabama’s Families</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2026/02/04/the-numbers-dont-lie-the-choose-act-is-empowering-alabamas-families/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For decades, the Alabama Policy Institute has championed a simple, powerful idea: every child in Alabama deserves a high-quality education, regardless of their zip code or their size of their parents’ bank account. With the passage and implementation of the CHOOSE Act, that vision is finally becoming a reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2026/02/04/the-numbers-dont-lie-the-choose-act-is-empowering-alabamas-families/"&gt;The Numbers Don’t Lie: The CHOOSE Act is Empowering Alabama’s Families&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 22:48:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] 312 Out of More than 3 Million Votes</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/312-out-of-more-than-3-million-votes/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Federal prosecutors are closing in on prosecuting more than 100 Minnesotans for rampant fraud in several social service programs designed to serve children and low-income residents. By the time the US Attorney’s office is done investigating, charging, convicting, and sentencing these felons, this unchecked fraud will significantly increase Minnesota’s prison population. But there’s one other [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/312-out-of-more-than-3-million-votes/"&gt;312 Out of More than 3 Million Votes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 13:58:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Empire Center Report Makes the Case Against Further Tax Hikes</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/empire-center-report-makes-the-case-against-further-tax-hikes/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Adding to New York&amp;#8217;s already high tax burden would be both unnecessary and dangerous for the state&amp;#8217;s economy, according to....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/empire-center-report-makes-the-case-against-further-tax-hikes/"&gt;Empire Center Report Makes the Case Against Further Tax Hikes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 16:12:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Study Urges New K–12 Accountability Framework Following End of MCAS Graduation Requirement</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/study-urges-new-k-12-accountability-framework-following-end-of-mcas-graduation-requirement/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Calls for choices of high school pathways, early and end-of-course exams, and independent district accountability  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/study-urges-new-k-12-accountability-framework-following-end-of-mcas-graduation-requirement/"&gt;Study Urges New K–12 Accountability Framework Following End of MCAS Graduation Requirement&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 16:14:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Education Is Economic Development: Why Business Leaders Should Support House Bill</title><link>https://empowerms.org/education-is-economic-development-why-business-leaders-should-support-house-bill/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This article was originally published in the February 2026 edition of the Mississippi Business Journal. Mississippi’s business community understands a basic but often overlooked reality: economic development does not begin with tax incentives or site selectors. It begins with people. If we want our state to grow, we must be able to attract, retain, and&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/education-is-economic-development-why-business-leaders-should-support-house-bill/"&gt;Education Is Economic Development: Why Business Leaders Should Support House Bill&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 18:43:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Record-breaking start to 2026: 6,000 employees opt out</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/record-breaking-start-to-2026-6000-employees-opt-out/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Freedom Foundation set an all-time record in January with 6,000 public employees opting out—topping our previous record by nearly 3,000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/record-breaking-start-to-2026-6000-employees-opt-out/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Record-breaking start to 2026: 6,000 employees opt out&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 18:57:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Time for UW-Madison to do away with ethnic studies requirement</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/time-for-uw-madison-to-do-away-with-ethnic-studies-requirement/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Time can be better spent on other things like AI Here’s a question I hope somebody asks anyone who applies to be the next chancellor of the University of Wisconsin-Madison: Why in the world in 2026 should we continue to have an ethnic studies requirement for all undergrads? Here’s another one: Do you even know [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/time-for-uw-madison-to-do-away-with-ethnic-studies-requirement/"&gt;Time for UW-Madison to do away with ethnic studies requirement&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 20:05:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] A Badger Institute policy report: Character education and teacher retention</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/a-badger-institute-policy-report-character-education-and-teacher-retention/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Wisconsinites should be concerned the state's growing crisis of disappearing educators — a phenomenon the Badger Institute has been taking a closer look at. Multiple studies confirm that retaining good teachers is essential to school effectiveness and student achievement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/a-badger-institute-policy-report-character-education-and-teacher-retention/"&gt;A Badger Institute policy report: Character education and teacher retention&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 20:25:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Testimony: SB 1526 Creates State-Sponsored Nonprofit for Net Zero Projects</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/testimony/testimony-sb-1526-creates-state-sponsored-nonprofit-for-net-zero-projects/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By John A. Charles Jr. PORTLAND, OR – John Charles, President and CEO...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/testimony/testimony-sb-1526-creates-state-sponsored-nonprofit-for-net-zero-projects/"&gt;Testimony: SB 1526 Creates State-Sponsored Nonprofit for Net Zero Projects&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 20:40:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Rifreedom] TESTIMONY: Senate Commission to Study the Successful Implementation of the Act on Climate</title><link>https://rifreedom.org/2026/02/senate-commission-act-on-climate/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In this powerful testimony, Mike Stenhouse, CEO of the RI Center for Freedom &amp;#038; Prosperity, explains why energy policy—not taxes, not housing, not government services—is the single most important determinant of Rhode Island’s future prosperity or poverty. Whether one believes in climate change or not, the economic consequences of the Act on Climate are unavoidable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org/2026/02/senate-commission-act-on-climate/"&gt;TESTIMONY: Senate Commission to Study the Successful Implementation of the Act on Climate&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org"&gt;RI Center for Freedom and Prosperity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 21:12:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] What’s the Wisconsin Department of Public Instruction Hiding?</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/whats-the-wisconsin-department-of-public-instruction-hiding/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;What&amp;#8217;s the Wisconsin Department of Public Instruction Hiding? Things are rotten in the Wisconsin Department of Public Instruction (DPI). Late last year, a damning report showed hundreds of educational professionals, including aides and teachers, were investigated for sexual misconduct. Many of them were simply allowed to resign and kept their licenses. On top of that, educational standards [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/whats-the-wisconsin-department-of-public-instruction-hiding/"&gt;What&amp;#8217;s the Wisconsin Department of Public Instruction Hiding?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 22:49:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG’s Jake Curtis Joins the Vicki McKenna Show to talk about DPI Spending</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irgs-jake-curtis-joins-the-vicki-mckenna-show-to-talk-about-dpi-spending/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irgs-jake-curtis-joins-the-vicki-mckenna-show-to-talk-about-dpi-spending/"&gt;IRG&amp;#8217;s Jake Curtis Joins the Vicki McKenna Show to talk about DPI Spending&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 22:51:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] Republicans delay Wisconsin DPI funding over water park spending concerns</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/republicans-delay-wisconsin-dpi-funding-over-water-park-spending-concerns/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Republicans delay Wisconsin DPI funding over water park spending concerns The state Legislature&amp;#8217;s Joint Finance Committee delayed voting on the Department of Public Instruction&amp;#8217;s request to release operating funds Feb. 3, following a report from a conservative news outlet that criticized the agency for hosting a four-day event at a water park in Wisconsin Dells. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/republicans-delay-wisconsin-dpi-funding-over-water-park-spending-concerns/"&gt;Republicans delay Wisconsin DPI funding over water park spending concerns&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 23:01:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] BERGEN RECORD: NJ climate superfund is a blank check with no accountability | Opinion</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/02/bergen-record-nj-climate-superfund-is-a-blank-check-with-no-accountability-opinion/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;#160; New Jersey’s Climate Superfund Is a Blank Check With No Accountability by Rosemary Becchi New Jersey lawmakers are considering [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/02/bergen-record-nj-climate-superfund-is-a-blank-check-with-no-accountability-opinion/"&gt;BERGEN RECORD: NJ climate superfund is a blank check with no accountability | Opinion&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 13:58:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] The Virginian-Pilot: Federal Scholarship Tax Credits Should be a No-Brainer for Virginia</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/the-virginian-pilot-federal-scholarship-tax-credits-should-be-a-no-brainer-for-virginia/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/tax-credit-featured-image.jpg" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In today’s The Virginian-Pilot, Thomas Jefferson Institute Senior Advisor and Former President Chris Braunlich discusses Virginia’s participation in the new Federal Scholarship Tax Credit (FSTC) for K-12 students which, starting in 2027, will give taxpayers a dollar for dollar federal tax credit of up to $1,700 for donations to scholarship programs offering students in public [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/the-virginian-pilot-federal-scholarship-tax-credits-should-be-a-no-brainer-for-virginia/"&gt;The Virginian-Pilot: Federal Scholarship Tax Credits Should be a No-Brainer for Virginia&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 16:11:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Week in Review: Down with DEI Mandates</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-down-with-dei-mandates/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Despite the national backlash to diversity, equity, and inclusion (DEI), many universities across the country still require their employees to..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-down-with-dei-mandates/"&gt;Week in Review: Down with DEI Mandates&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 16:18:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Governor Mills’ Supplemental Budget Abandons Fiscal Discipline, Sets Maine Up for Higher Costs</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/governor-millss-supplemental-budget-abandons-fiscal-discipline-sets-maine-up-for-higher-costs/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Governor Janet Mills’ FY 2026 supplemental budget marks a clear break from the fiscal restraint her administration often claimed to practice. Rather than using Maine’s strong revenue growth to stabilize taxpayers after years of tax increases and inflation, the proposal dramatically expands spending, broadens emergency powers, and doubles down on distortionary tax policy choices that [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/governor-millss-supplemental-budget-abandons-fiscal-discipline-sets-maine-up-for-higher-costs/"&gt;Governor Mills’ Supplemental Budget Abandons Fiscal Discipline, Sets Maine Up for Higher Costs&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 17:22:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Stacked Local Taxes Are Making Virginia Less Affordable, Not More</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/stacked-local-taxes-are-making-virginia-less-affordable-not-more/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="630" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/virginia-local-taxes-v2.jpg" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Virginia’s restaurant and lodging sector is still in a fragile post-COVID recovery, yet local governments across the Commonwealth are piling on new and higher taxes that make affordability worse for families and survival harder for small businesses. A new statewide analysis of meals, lodging, and related sales taxes across all 133 Virginia localities by the&amp;#160;Virginia [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/stacked-local-taxes-are-making-virginia-less-affordable-not-more/"&gt;Stacked Local Taxes Are Making Virginia Less Affordable, Not More&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 17:43:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Courts vs. Communities: Should Judges Override Local Land-Use Decisions?</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/legal-regulatory/courts-vs-communities/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Can the courts substitute their judgment for the reasonable judgment of local governments when it comes to land use? That’s the question counsel for St. James Parish put to the Louisiana Supreme Court when it heard oral argument in Beverly Alexander, et al., v. St. James Parish on January 22, 2026. At issue is the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/legal-regulatory/courts-vs-communities/"&gt;Courts vs. Communities: Should Judges Override Local Land-Use Decisions?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 18:48:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Affordability tops the list of state priorities for 2026</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/affordability-tops-the-list-of-state-priorities-for-2026/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/affordability-tops-the-list-of-state-priorities-for-2026/"&gt;Affordability tops the list of state priorities for 2026&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 21:36:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] 2026 Capitol Chat: Week 5</title><link>https://empowerms.org/2026-capitol-chat-week-5/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Capitol Chat: Week 5 Week 5 at the Capitol featured some of the most consequential policy and political moves yet. In this episode, we walk through some of the biggest developments, including shifts in the education debate, major House action, an update on the ballot initiative, and another big deadline on the horizon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/2026-capitol-chat-week-5/"&gt;2026 Capitol Chat: Week 5&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 22:11:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2026/02/the-outstater-325/</link><description>Our &amp;#8216;Somali Mindset&amp;#8217; WHY, REALLY,&amp;#160;do the impoverished want to come to America? Is it the promises embedded in our Declaration of Independence? Perhaps a&amp;#160;legal system based on 800 years of Common Law and respect for private property? Liberty with responsibility? That would make us proud. But why is it,&amp;#160;to pick an example from the news,&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2026/02/the-outstater-325/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 14:59:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Union Activists Launch Full Scale Attack on Students, Families in AZ</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/union-activists-launch-full-scale-attack-on-students-families-in-az/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As students across the state continue to find new opportunity through Arizona’s Empowerment Scholarship Account (ESA) program, the total number..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/union-activists-launch-full-scale-attack-on-students-families-in-az/"&gt;Union Activists Launch Full Scale Attack on Students, Families in AZ&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 20:42:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2026/02/the-outstater-326/</link><description>Pimping for Data Centers &amp;#8220;The idea is to get back to a society where people can live together as neighbors and not just as wage slaves or bureaucratic cogs.” — G.K. Chesterton LOOK, I LIKE PROGRESS&amp;#160;as much as the next guy but sacrificing local autonomy is stupid. There are nine distinct regions of Indiana, each&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2026/02/the-outstater-326/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 13:21:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Mind the Body</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/mind-the-body/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;There are wars in the Middle East. Future battles with China. Covert missions in Latin America. And Elon Musk wants to build a Mars colony. All of these require one, simple biological necessity: human beings. Unfortunately, Americans are fat. And the obesity problem with our children has only ballooned. To protect our sovereignty, secure our...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/mind-the-body/"&gt;Mind the Body&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 14:16:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] The sun is stronger than our electric grid — and we are defenseless against it</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/the-sun-is-stronger-than-our-electric-grid-and-we-are-defenseless-against-it/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Carrington Event literally shocked telegraph operators. A repeat could shock an entire civilization into the pre-industrial age. Imagine being a telegraph operator in September 1859. You’re sitting at your station, using cutting-edge technology to tap out messages hundreds and thousands of miles away. Suddenly, brilliant auroras light up the night sky from the tropics...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/the-sun-is-stronger-than-our-electric-grid-and-we-are-defenseless-against-it/"&gt;The sun is stronger than our electric grid — and we are defenseless against it&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 14:25:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Ayotte: Maximize economic freedom, and New Hampshire will thrive</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2026/02/ayotte-maximize-economic-freedom-and-new-hampshire-will-thrive/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Gov. Kelly Ayotte’s 2026 State of the State address can be summed up in seven words: New Hampshire wins by competing on freedom. Leading with a list of eight No. 1 national rankings for the state—including economic freedom, economic opportunity and taxpayer return on investment—Ayotte noted that, overall, “U.S. News ranks us the #2 state [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2026/02/ayotte-maximize-economic-freedom-and-new-hampshire-will-thrive/"&gt;Ayotte: Maximize economic freedom, and New Hampshire will thrive&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 14:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] ITR Foundation Brings the Property Tax Conversation Directly to Iowans</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/itr-foundation-brings-the-property-tax-conversation-directly-to-iowans/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="ITR Foundation Brings the Property Tax Conversation Directly to Iowans" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/hendrickson-maga-nation.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ITR Foundation is taking the property tax conversation directly to Iowans, engaging grassroots audiences alongside elected officials and candidates to address the real-world impact of rising property taxes. The data show a clear problem: Iowa property taxes have grown by more than 100 percent over the past two decades, far outpacing population growth and inflation, driven primarily by sustained growth in local government spending rather than assessments alone. Meaningful property tax relief requires spending discipline, including reasonable caps on revenue growth, to complement Iowa’s recent income tax reforms and ensure taxpayers, homeowners, farmers, and small businesses are not squeezed by unchecked local spending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/itr-foundation-brings-the-property-tax-conversation-directly-to-iowans/"&gt;ITR Foundation Brings the Property Tax Conversation Directly to Iowans&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 15:07:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Wisconsin Is Ripping and Replacing What Already Works</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/wisconsin-is-ripping-and-replacing-what-already-works/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In response to repeated cyber espionage campaigns by foreign governments, the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) launched the “Secure...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/wisconsin-is-ripping-and-replacing-what-already-works/"&gt;Wisconsin Is Ripping and Replacing What Already Works&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 15:26:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Accountability? Oversight Requests Go Unanswered at the Capitol</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/02/09/accountability-oversight-requests-go-unanswered-at-the-capitol/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="1707" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/shutterstock_2496182785-scaled.jpg" width="2560" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;House Minority Leader Rep. Vincent Candelora (R-North Branford) and Appropriations Committee Ranking Member Rep. Tammy Nuccio (R-Tolland) are asking a straightforward question that Connecticut’s budget leadership seems has yet to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/02/09/accountability-oversight-requests-go-unanswered-at-the-capitol/"&gt;Accountability? Oversight Requests Go Unanswered at the Capitol &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 15:41:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Nine More Massachusetts Towns Subject of State Litigation over MBTA Communities Act Noncompliance</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/nine-more-massachusetts-towns-subject-of-state-litigation-over-mbta-communities-act-noncompliance/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;February's edition of The House Call discusses new legal action over Massachusetts' multifamily zoning mandate for transit-accessible communities. It also highlights a new federal data release that shows where many Massachusetts homeowners tend to overestimate - or underestimate - their property values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/nine-more-massachusetts-towns-subject-of-state-litigation-over-mbta-communities-act-noncompliance/"&gt;Nine More Massachusetts Towns Subject of State Litigation over MBTA Communities Act Noncompliance&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 16:58:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] When Political Rhetoric Goes Too Far</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/when-political-rhetoric-goes-too-far/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Empty phrases routinely populate our politics. But ever so often, there are irrefutable moments where rhetoric is wielded as a weapon to be used in animating hostility. “The day the Latino, African American, Asian and other communities realize that they share the same oppressor is the day we start winning because we are the majority...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/when-political-rhetoric-goes-too-far/"&gt;When Political Rhetoric Goes Too Far&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 17:23:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Keep an Eye on the DATA Act in Washington, D.C.</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/article/energy/keep-an-eye-on-the-data-act-in-washington-d-c/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Listen to this article As a writer, there are moments when someone else articulates an idea so well that rewriting it in my own words would be unnecessary. A recent [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/article/energy/keep-an-eye-on-the-data-act-in-washington-d-c/"&gt;Keep an Eye on the DATA Act in Washington, D.C.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 21:27:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] Alabama Senate unanimously passes App Store Accountability Act</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2026/02/09/alabama-senate-unanimously-passes-app-store-accountability-act/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The App Store Accountability Act passed the Alabama Senate with a unanimous vote on Feb. 5. The bill is focused on online safety for children and teens by requiring parental approval for kids to download apps from the App Store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2026/02/09/alabama-senate-unanimously-passes-app-store-accountability-act/"&gt;Alabama Senate unanimously passes App Store Accountability Act&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 23:47:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] Alabama Senate passes App Store age verification requirement</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2026/02/10/alabama-senate-passes-app-store-age-verification-requirement/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Lawmakers spoke before the Senate in favor of shielding minors from inappropriate content, requiring parental permission for account creation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2026/02/10/alabama-senate-passes-app-store-age-verification-requirement/"&gt;Alabama Senate passes App Store age verification requirement&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 02:12:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Legislators Not Curious About Cost, Safety or Efficiency As Massive Battery Mandate Rushes Toward Approval</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/legislators-not-curious-about-cost-safety-or-efficiency-as-massive-battery-mandate-rushes-toward-approval/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="720" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Virginia-green-battery-mandate.jpg" width="1280" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, a Senate committee is scheduled to take up the bill directing Virginia’s two investor-owned utilities to propose huge battery installations that will cover square miles of ground, cost ratepayers billions of dollars, and produce zero energy to power our homes and businesses. The bill has Governor Abigail Spanberger’s endorsement. So far, legislators have been in a “see, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/legislators-not-curious-about-cost-safety-or-efficiency-as-massive-battery-mandate-rushes-toward-approval/"&gt;Legislators Not Curious About Cost, Safety or Efficiency As Massive Battery Mandate Rushes Toward Approval&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 03:40:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Interest rates should be left to the private market</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2026/interest-rates-should-be-left-to-the-private-market</link><description>Why I signed onto a letter opposing price controls</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Testimony of Bill Hammond on the Health and Medicaid Budget for FY 2027</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/testimony-of-bill-hammond-on-the-health-and-medicaid-budget-for-fy-2027/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Testimony of Bill Hammond Senior Fellow, Empire Center for Public Policy Before the Joint Legislative Fiscal Committees February 10, 2026....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/testimony-of-bill-hammond-on-the-health-and-medicaid-budget-for-fy-2027/"&gt;Testimony of Bill Hammond on the Health and Medicaid Budget for FY 2027&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 13:36:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Hammond Calls for Restraint on Medicaid Spending</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/hammond-calls-for-restraint-on-medicaid-spending/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Albany, N.Y. — The state and its taxpayers cannot afford to allow Medicaid spending to keep growing at five times the....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/hammond-calls-for-restraint-on-medicaid-spending/"&gt;Hammond Calls for Restraint on Medicaid Spending&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 13:36:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Did Jefferson Raid Its Water Fund? Lawsuit Puts City Finances Under Scrutiny</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/did-jefferson-raid-its-water-fund-lawsuit-puts-city-finances-under-scrutiny/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Did Jefferson Raid Its Water Fund? Lawsuit Puts City Finances Under Scrutiny" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/jefferson-iowajpg.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lawsuit challenges Jefferson’s use of taxpayer dollars after the city transferred $800,000 from its Water Plant Construction Fund into economic development and TIF-related accounts. Plaintiffs argue the transfer violated Iowa law and public process, claiming the city neither demonstrated a lawful surplus nor created a binding repayment obligation, and failed to follow required budget amendment procedures. The case raises broader concerns about transparency and taxpayer trust, highlighting the risks of diverting funds and the potential for residents to pay twice through higher future rates or taxes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/did-jefferson-raid-its-water-fund-lawsuit-puts-city-finances-under-scrutiny/"&gt;Did Jefferson Raid Its Water Fund? Lawsuit Puts City Finances Under Scrutiny&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 14:09:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Connecticut’s “Emergency” Housing Law: Fair Share Returns, Deadlines Start Slipping</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/02/10/connecticuts-emergency-housing-law-fair-share-returns-deadlines-start-slipping/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="1024" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/ChatGPT-Image-Feb-10-2026-at-10_10_21-AM.png" width="1536" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Connecticut lawmakers rushed an omnibus housing bill through a November special session, they insisted the situation was dire enough to justify extraordinary measures. Public hearings were skipped. The normal [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/02/10/connecticuts-emergency-housing-law-fair-share-returns-deadlines-start-slipping/"&gt;Connecticut’s “Emergency” Housing Law: Fair Share Returns, Deadlines Start Slipping &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 15:15:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] On Lincoln’s Birthday, Remember the Right to Rise</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/principles-of-liberty/right-to-rise/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As Americans, we remember the great leaders of our country and reflect on their contributions to our present-day lives. February 12, 1809, marks the birthday of Abraham Lincoln—undoubtedly among the most famous and revered figures in our nation’s history, and with good reason. He was not only the Great Emancipator, but an exemplar of the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/principles-of-liberty/right-to-rise/"&gt;On Lincoln’s Birthday, Remember the Right to Rise&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 16:46:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Freedom Foundation Attorneys Secure Compensation from SEIU 099 for a Public-School Employee</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/litigation/freedom-foundation-attorneys-secure-compensation-from-seiu-099-for-a-public-school-employee/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Freedom Foundation attorneys have successfully freed California public school employee Keshawna Adams from SEIU 099’ unconstitutional dues deductions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/litigation/freedom-foundation-attorneys-secure-compensation-from-seiu-099-for-a-public-school-employee/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation Attorneys Secure Compensation from SEIU 099 for a Public-School Employee&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 17:52:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] It’s Time for Arizona’s Supreme Court to Protect ‘The Most Precious Liberty Man Possesses’</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/its-time-for-arizonas-supreme-court-to-protect-the-most-precious-liberty-man-possesses/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Goldwater Institute today filed a brief in the Arizona Supreme Court urging the justices to extend full constitutional protection..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/its-time-for-arizonas-supreme-court-to-protect-the-most-precious-liberty-man-possesses/"&gt;It’s Time for Arizona’s Supreme Court to Protect ‘The Most Precious Liberty Man Possesses’&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:33:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] WILL Releases New Model Policy Protecting Girls Privacy at School</title><link>https://will-law.org/will-releases-new-model-policy-protecting-girls-privacy-at-school/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL has released a new model school board policy outlining how and why sex-separated bathrooms are legal and critical to protecting girls at school. This policy release follows a national debate over sex-separated bathrooms and a controversy in the New Richmond, WI, school district over a policy allowing biological boys to use the girls’ bathrooms over the protest and concerns of parents and students alike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/will-releases-new-model-policy-protecting-girls-privacy-at-school/"&gt;WILL Releases New Model Policy Protecting Girls Privacy at School&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:54:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Florida Politics: Florida’s CHINA Prevention Unit Is a Needed Step To Safeguard Health Data</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/floridas-china-prevention-unit-is-a-needed-step-to-safeguard-health-data/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Once again, Florida is showing the rest of the country how to lead in protecting its citizens from...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/floridas-china-prevention-unit-is-a-needed-step-to-safeguard-health-data/"&gt;Florida Politics: Florida’s CHINA Prevention Unit Is a Needed Step To Safeguard Health Data&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 19:20:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Fraud tourists plead guilty</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/fraud-tourists-plead-guilty/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Anthony Waddell Jefferson and Lester Brown, both of Philadelphia, were in federal court in downtown Minneapolis to enter guilty pleas for their involvement in a fraud against the now-discontinued housing stabilization services (HSS) Medicaid program in Minnesota. Charges were filed against the two back in December. Perhaps what was most encouraging about yesterday&amp;#8217;s events was...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/fraud-tourists-plead-guilty/"&gt;Fraud tourists plead guilty&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 21:39:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] "May hurt somebody" - Lawmakers who opposed Idaho's parental choice tax credit advance new attack</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/post/may-hurt-somebody-lawmakers-who-opposed-idaho-s-parental-choice-tax-credit-advance-new-attack</link><description>Lawmakers who opposed the Parental Choice Tax Credit last year, advanced a new bill to cut it—by 4 percent immediately and another 5 percent in 2027—before the program has even fully begun.</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 07:04:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Pretty little income tax lies: Why Washington’s proposed "Millionaire Tax" is Olympia’s trojan horse</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/post/pretty-little-income-tax-lies-why-washington-s-proposed-millionaire-tax-is-olympia-s-trojan-horse</link><description>It’s the oldest trick in politics: sell a major policy shift by assuring voters it only targets someone else. Olympia is now running that play with the 9.9 percent “Millionaire Tax.” For those of us who have watched Washington’s spending habits for decades, the warning signs are obvious. The “fair share” narrative depends on intellectual dishonesty—and it’s being used to wedge open the door to a permanent state income tax.</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 07:05:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Illinois improves on one company’s list for people leaving</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/illinois-improves-on-one-companys-list-for-people-leaving/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Fewer Illinoisans moved out in 2025, according to United Van Lines. Illinois was No. 2 for departures in 2024 and No. 9 last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/illinois-improves-on-one-companys-list-for-people-leaving/"&gt;Illinois improves on one company’s list for people leaving&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 11:00:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] Book: ‘Decade of Disunion’</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2026/02/book-decade-of-disunion/</link><description>by Mark Franke I have a fondness for counter-factual history, perhaps too much so. This category of fiction begins with a what if question about some critical point in history and then hypothesizes a chain of events to follow. Some end up with a radically different ending while others argue that history would have worked&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2026/02/book-decade-of-disunion/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 12:09:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Senior discount won’t solve Michigan’s property tax problem</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2026/senior-discount-wont-solve-michigans-property-tax-problem</link><description>Reformers should aim to reduce overall rates</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Strengthening families for generational change: GCO welcomes Travis Thorne to the team</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/welcoming-travis-thorne/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/welcoming-travis-thorne/"&gt;Strengthening families for generational change: GCO welcomes Travis Thorne to the team&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 14:26:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Fox News: Gradually, Then Suddenly, Blue State America Is Heading for Financial Disaster</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/fox-news-gradually-then-suddenly-blue-state-america-is-heading-for-financial-disaster/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In his famous 20th century novel &amp;#8220;The Sun Also Rises,&amp;#8221; Ernest Hemingway’s character, Mike Campbell, was asked by...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/fox-news-gradually-then-suddenly-blue-state-america-is-heading-for-financial-disaster/"&gt;Fox News: Gradually, Then Suddenly, Blue State America Is Heading for Financial Disaster&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 14:34:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] YI President Carol Platt Liebau Featured in The Hartford Courant</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/02/11/yi-president-carol-platt-liebau-featured-in-the-hartford-courant/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="630" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/1.jpg" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yankee Institute President Carol Platt Liebau argues that affordability and opportunity should guide every proposal in Connecticut&amp;#8217;s 2026 legislative session — from protecting fiscal guardrails and reducing pension debt, to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/02/11/yi-president-carol-platt-liebau-featured-in-the-hartford-courant/"&gt;YI President Carol Platt Liebau Featured in The Hartford Courant&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 15:00:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] When a Landmark Trial Misses the Mark</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/misses-the-mark/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Social media use among young people is widespread, but so too are accounts of depression, anxiety, and exploitation. Because of this, families, mental health providers, advocates, and elected officials are operating under a sense of urgency. Some have turned to government to help keep kids safe online. Unfortunately, many of these efforts have resulted in...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/misses-the-mark/"&gt;When a Landmark Trial Misses the Mark &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 16:00:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Habeas and squatter’s rights</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/habeas-and-squatters-rights/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Democrat federal judges are inventing new legal doctrines to free illegal aliens from ICE detention. From Politico, Federal judges may have found a workaround to reject the Trump administration’s mass detention policy after an appeals court backed the approach. A three-judge panel of the 5th Circuit Court of Appeals on Friday blessed the administration’s interpretation...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/habeas-and-squatters-rights/"&gt;Habeas and squatter&amp;#8217;s rights&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 16:02:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF talks to KOAT TV about roads</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-talks-to-koat-tv-about-roads/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;SB 2 has passed which means that the road issue has been &amp;#8220;put to bed&amp;#8221; for the time being. The bill which has been signed by the Gov. includes: $1.5 billion in new road spending via a bond (debt) package. This also includes: A 35% increase in the weight-distance tax on trucks A 25% increase [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-talks-to-koat-tv-about-roads/"&gt;RGF talks to KOAT TV about roads&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 16:09:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] House Bill 602 — Idaho courts, foreign law (+1)</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/house-bill-602-idaho-courts-foreign-law-1/</link><description>Bill Description: House Bill 602 (H602) would require that any foreign law used in an Idaho court or adjudication must recognize and abide by certain fundamental liberties, rights, and privileges established in the Idaho and United States constitutions. Rating: (+1) Does it violate the spirit or the letter of either the United States Constitution or [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 18:29:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] House Bill 601 — Government unions (+3)</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/house-bill-601-government-unions-3/</link><description>Bill Description: House Bill 601 (H601) prohibits public officials from allowing school district funds, personnel, and other resources to be used in support of teachers’ unions and expands the list of “official actions” subject to the Ethics in Government Act. NOTE: House Bill 601 is similar to House Bill 98 from the 2025 legislative session [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 18:32:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] House Bill 588 — Virtual Public Education (0)</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/house-bill-588-virtual-public-education-0/</link><description>Bill Description: House Bill 588 (H588) revises various provisions regarding how school districts can conduct virtual education programs, including reporting requirements and teacher certification and curricula standards.&amp;#160; Rating: 0 Does it increase government spending (for objectionable purposes) or debt? Conversely, does it decrease government spending or debt? H588 would ensure that school districts are not [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 18:34:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Wolf plan needs to develop more quickly</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/wolf-plan-needs-to-develop-more-quickly/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;While wolves decide beef is what’s for dinner, the California Department of Fish and Wildlife is slow to address the urgent need for ranch rescue plans. A New Year’s Day wolf attack at a ranch in Lassen County highlights that, perhaps, the state is moving too slowly in its approach to wolf management. Read the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/wolf-plan-needs-to-develop-more-quickly/"&gt;Wolf plan needs to develop more quickly&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 18:41:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Arizona Republicans should stop trying to ban mRNA vaccines</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/arizona-republicans-should-stop-trying-to-ban-mrna-vaccines/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Despite Democratic Governor Hobbs&amp;#8217; past efforts to expand Arizonans&amp;#8217; access to cutting-edge medicines, the state Legislature continues to propose harmful anti-mRNA bills. The latest example is House Bill 2332, which, if enacted, would deny Arizonans access to promising technologies that could cure cancer and minimize the health consequences from deadly diseases. Lawmakers should reject this [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/arizona-republicans-should-stop-trying-to-ban-mrna-vaccines/"&gt;Arizona Republicans should stop trying to ban mRNA vaccines&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 19:04:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Wisconsin Senate Passes WILL-Backed ﻿“Red Tape Reset”</title><link>https://will-law.org/wisconsin-senate-passes-will-backed-red-tape-reset/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The WILL-backed “Red Tape Reset” is one step closer to becoming law after the Wisconsin State Senate voted in favor of the legislative package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/wisconsin-senate-passes-will-backed-red-tape-reset/"&gt;Wisconsin Senate Passes WILL-Backed ﻿“Red Tape Reset”&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 19:13:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Watch: The Public Safety Climate in the City of St Louis</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/article/state-and-local-government/watch-the-public-safety-climate-in-the-city-of-st-louis/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On January 21, 2026, the Show-Me Institute hosted an in-depth discussion on crime and public safety trends in the City of St. Louis at the Knight Center at Washington University. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/article/state-and-local-government/watch-the-public-safety-climate-in-the-city-of-st-louis/"&gt;Watch: The Public Safety Climate in the City of St Louis&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 19:57:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] CLIMBING: 215 families per day are signing up for Idaho parental choice tax credit</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/post/update-idaho-parental-choice-tax-credit-sign-ups</link><description>Since applications opened on January 15, a total of 6,030 families have applied, covering 10,105 students. That’s not a one-day surge. That’s nearly a month of steady participation.</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 20:17:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Join our team as an Energy Policy Fellow!</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/join-our-team-as-an-energy-policy-fellow/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Apply here: https://talentmarket.org/job-opening/cae-energy-policy-fellow/ Center of the American Experiment is hiring! Keep reading to learn about the position and how to apply. Position title: Energy Policy Fellow (Minnetonka, MN) About Center of the American Experiment: Center of the American Experiment is Minnesota’s leading policy organization. Its mission is to promote free-market, limited government policies. In addition...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/join-our-team-as-an-energy-policy-fellow/"&gt;Join our team as an Energy Policy Fellow!&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 20:52:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Emancipator and Economic Nationalist</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/emancipator-and-economic-nationalist/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Emancipator and Economic Nationalist" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/lincoln.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abraham Lincoln’s legacy is most often framed around the Civil War and slavery, but his economic philosophy—particularly his support for protectionism and economic nationalism—is frequently overlooked. Influenced by the Whig and Federalist traditions and leaders like Henry Clay, Lincoln championed the American System, which emphasized protective tariffs, a national bank, and internal improvements as essential to national prosperity and independence. Lincoln’s economic nationalism shaped Republican policy for generations, with tariffs and related reforms playing a central role in his administration and influencing American economic thought well into the 20th century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/emancipator-and-economic-nationalist/"&gt;Emancipator and Economic Nationalist&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 21:11:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] The $921M Special Interest Machine That Controls California</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/the-921m-special-interest-machine-that-controls-california/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=the-921m-special-interest-machine-that-controls-california</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Public sector unions collect nearly $1 billion a year to control Sacramento. Normal citizens? A trickle against a torrent. TL;DR California’s public sector unions rake in $921 million annually and spend hundreds of millions controlling elections—but there’s a legal pathway to break their grip. California’s public-sector unions are the Colorado River of political spending. Normal...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/the-921m-special-interest-machine-that-controls-california/"&gt;The $921M Special Interest Machine That Controls California&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 22:07:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] More Evidence on Grade Inflation in Our Schools</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/article/performance/more-evidence-on-grade-inflation-in-our-schools/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Listen to this article An article from QNS, a local news outlet covering Queens, New York, released an interesting article about a local high school under investigation by New York [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/article/performance/more-evidence-on-grade-inflation-in-our-schools/"&gt;More Evidence on Grade Inflation in Our Schools&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 22:10:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Illinois has 8th–largest racial wealth gap in the nation</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/illinois-has-8th-largest-racial-wealth-gap-in-the-nation/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Illinois in the top ten for largest racial wealth gaps. Disparities in income, education and poverty drive the state’s racial wealth gap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/illinois-has-8th-largest-racial-wealth-gap-in-the-nation/"&gt;Illinois has 8th–largest racial wealth gap in the nation&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 22:46:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Waste watch: Illinois gives $45M to select business groups</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/waste-watch-illinois-gives-45m-to-select-business-groups/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Some Illinois lawmakers handed money to their local business associations. Should everyone’s taxes subsidize certain groups because their lawmakers had clout?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/waste-watch-illinois-gives-45m-to-select-business-groups/"&gt;Waste watch: Illinois gives $45M to select business groups&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 22:48:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Governor Evers To Consider “Teacher Bill of Rights” Legislation</title><link>https://will-law.org/governor-evers-to-consider-teacher-bill-of-rights-legislation/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL applauds the Wisconsin State Assembly and State Senate for acting on AB 614 / SB 611, known as the Teacher Bill of Rights. The bill creates protections for teachers and students by strengthening teachers’ authority to manage their classrooms, requiring parental notification when serious incidents occur, and establishing clear accountability so teachers can focus on teaching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/governor-evers-to-consider-teacher-bill-of-rights-legislation/"&gt;Governor Evers To Consider “Teacher Bill of Rights” Legislation&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 23:36:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Governor Newsom: Turn Up the Delta Pumps!</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/turn-up-the-delta-pumps/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=turn-up-the-delta-pumps</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When it comes to the water supply in California for cities and farms, nothing matters more than how we manage the Sacramento-San Joaquin Delta. As of 2/09 we were 132 days into the 2025-26 rainfall season which began on 10/01/2025. That’s enough time to get an idea of how delta management is shaping up this...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/turn-up-the-delta-pumps/"&gt;Governor Newsom: Turn Up the Delta Pumps!&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 23:47:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Abolish state jobs after five years of vacancy to reallocate funds</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/02/abolish-state-jobs-after-five-years-of-vacancy-to-reallocate-funds/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Senate Committee on Labor and Technology on Feb. 11, 2026._____________ Feb. 11, 2026, 3 p.m.Hawaii State CapitolConference Room 225 and Videoconference To: Senate Committee on Labor and Technology&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Sen. Brandon J.C. Elefante, Chair&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Sen. Rachele Lamosao, Vice Chair From: Grassroot [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/02/abolish-state-jobs-after-five-years-of-vacancy-to-reallocate-funds/"&gt;Abolish state jobs after five years of vacancy to reallocate funds&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 00:47:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Automatically abolish state positions that remain vacant for 48 months</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/02/automatically-abolish-state-positions-that-remain-vacant-for-48-months/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii on Feb. 11, 2026, for consideration by the Senate Committees on Labor and Technology and Government Operations._____________ Feb. 11, 2026, 3 p.m.Hawaii State CapitolConference Room 225 and Videoconference To: Senate Committee on Labor and Technology       Sen. Brandon J.C. Elefante, Chair       Sen. Rachele Lamosao, Vice [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/02/automatically-abolish-state-positions-that-remain-vacant-for-48-months/"&gt;Automatically abolish state positions that remain vacant for 48 months&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 00:50:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Allow two ADUs per residential lot in all of Maui County</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/02/allow-two-adus-per-residential-lot-in-all-of-maui-county/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Moloka’i Planning Commission on Feb. 11, 2026.___________ Feb. 11, 2026, 11 a.m.Remote meeting To: Moloka&amp;#8217;i Planning Commission&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Zhantell Lindo, Chair&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Keolamaupono Sagario, Vice Chair From: Jonathan Helton, Policy Analyst&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Grassroot Institute of Hawaii RE: Item A(1) — ON ACCESSORY DWELLINGS [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/02/allow-two-adus-per-residential-lot-in-all-of-maui-county/"&gt;Allow two ADUs per residential lot in all of Maui County&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 00:55:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] California Forever Stagnating</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/california-forever-stagnating/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=california-forever-stagnating</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When Permission Replaces Property Rights, the California Dream Becomes a Dream Deferred For over a century, California stood as a frontier of first resort for the ambitious, attracting those eager to escape old-world constraints in exchange for a promise of radical autonomy. This California Dream was not a byproduct of luck; it was forged by...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/california-forever-stagnating/"&gt;California Forever Stagnating&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 01:05:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Dems’ demands could bring immigration enforcement to halt</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/dems-demands-could-bring-immigration-enforcement-to-halt/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Jessica Costescu of the Washington Free Beacon explores the potential impact of Democrats’ preferred approach to immigration enforcement. Democrats’ demand for the Department of Homeland Security to &amp;#8220;improve warrant procedures and standards&amp;#8221; when arresting illegal immigrants could grind ICE&amp;#8217;s enforcement and removal operations to a near halt, immigration experts told the Washington Free Beacon. The...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/dems-demands-could-bring-immigration-enforcement-to-halt/"&gt;Dems&amp;#8217; demands could bring immigration enforcement to halt&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 10:36:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Congress hears concerns about foreigners bankrolling left-wing groups</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/congress-hears-concerns-about-foreigners-bankrolling-left-wing-groups/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Shawn Fleetwood of the Federalist documents disturbing testimony on Capitol Hill this week. Foreign nationals are quietly bankrolling leftist causes throughout the United States, several witnesses told House lawmakers on Tuesday. The concerning news came during a House Ways and Means Committee hearing focused on noncitizens pouring foreign dollars into U.S.-based nonprofit organizations. These groups,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/congress-hears-concerns-about-foreigners-bankrolling-left-wing-groups/"&gt;Congress hears concerns about foreigners bankrolling left-wing groups&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 10:39:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Another sign that climate alarmism is winding down</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/another-sign-that-climate-alarmism-is-winding-down/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Editors at Issues and Insights probe the current state of climate alarmism within legacy media outlets. It’s not sad in the least that the Washington Post has cut its climate “reporting” team down to five lonely reporters. It is, in fact, encouraging that maybe we’re seeing the winding down of decades of political and scientific...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/another-sign-that-climate-alarmism-is-winding-down/"&gt;Another sign that climate alarmism is winding down&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 10:42:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Michigan only enacted 74 laws in 2025. So what?</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2026/michigan-only-enacted-74-laws-in-2025-so-what</link><description>It’s more important to kill bad bills than to pass good ones</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Lawsuit’s End Latest Sign of High Speed Rail’s Woes</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/lawsuits-end-latest-sign-of-high-speed-rails-woes/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;An HSRA official said the decision to pull the lawsuit was made because “the federal government is not a reliable, constructive, or trustworthy partner in advancing high-speed rail in California.” In reality, it’s a tacit admission from the HSRA that it doesn’t deserve the money. At this point, it’s become rather tedious to recite the high-speed rail’s catalog of troubles. The California [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/lawsuits-end-latest-sign-of-high-speed-rails-woes/"&gt;Lawsuit’s End Latest Sign of High Speed Rail’s Woes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 11:00:32 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>