<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>State-Policy Think-Tank Digest</title><link>https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml</link><description>Latest posts from free-market policy institutes across the U.S.</description><atom:link href="https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 02:56:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Research Note: How Changes in AI Regulation Could Affect Nebraska</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/research-note-how-changes-in-ai-regulation-could-affect-nebraska/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of weeks before Christmas, following the President’s recent executive order on artificial intelligence (AI), the Nebraska Examiner published an article examining the potential implications for Nebraska. While the precise impact of the order remains uncertain, the state’s recent legislative activity related to AI suggests the possibility of conflict between state and federal approaches....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/research-note-how-changes-in-ai-regulation-could-affect-nebraska/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Research Note: How Changes in AI Regulation Could Affect Nebraska&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 15:05:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Happy New Year! A Blueprint for Mississippi in 2026!</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/happy-new-year-a-blueprint-for-mississippi-in-2026/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As we kick off 2026, the Mississippi Center for Public Policy is more energized than ever.&amp;#160;&amp;#160;We are excited about the successes our state has seen – and we have a plan to build on that momentum with further free market reform!&amp;#160;For decades, our state lagged behind.&amp;#160;&amp;#160;Growth was slow and too many young people left our [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/happy-new-year-a-blueprint-for-mississippi-in-2026/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Happy New Year! A Blueprint for Mississippi in 2026!&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 15:35:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Nebraska’s Tax Code Lets It Compete for Data Center Investment</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/nebraskas-tax-code-lets-it-compete-for-data-center-investment/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Midwest grows many things—including, increasingly, data centers. That’s good news, generating substantial local tax revenue, creating high-paying jobs, and expanding economic opportunities.  With 39 data centers (about 19 per 1 million people), Nebraska punches above its weight nationally, while trailing neighboring Iowa, which boasts the second-highest number of data centers per capita at 32...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/nebraskas-tax-code-lets-it-compete-for-data-center-investment/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Nebraska’s Tax Code Lets It Compete for Data Center Investment&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 17:26:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Shaping Georgia’s future: Opportunities for the year ahead</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/top-issues-shaping-georgia-future/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The well-being of many Georgians, their families, and their communities is at stake as pressing concerns like welfare reform, the cost of living, educational opportunities, and public safety take center stage in 2026. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/top-issues-shaping-georgia-future/"&gt;Shaping Georgia’s future: Opportunities for the year ahead&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 23:49:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] HB2 – Mississippi’s School Choice Bill is Here!</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/hb2-mississippis-school-choice-bill-is-here/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Last week, House Speaker Jason White unveiled&amp;#160;HB2, the&amp;#160;Mississippi Education Freedom Act - the most exciting and ambitious advancement for school choice in our state in years, perhaps ever!&amp;#160;This comprehensive bill delivers everything supporters of parental power have long hoped for, and it aligns perfectly with President Trump’s strong commitment to education freedom.&amp;#160;This isn’t some minor [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/hb2-mississippis-school-choice-bill-is-here/" rel="nofollow"&gt;HB2 – Mississippi’s School Choice Bill is Here!&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 17:31:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] ABQ Journal opinion piece: More investigative journalism is a must</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/abq-journal-opinion-piece-more-investigative-journalism-is-a-must/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following appeared in Albuquerque Journal on January 11, 2026. The Albuquerque Journal recently made appeals on its pages for donations to increase investigative journalism efforts. Even though the Rio Grande Foundation is in direct competition for limited donor dollars, we applaud the paper for focusing attention on investigative journalism currently. The issue of investigative journalism is [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/abq-journal-opinion-piece-more-investigative-journalism-is-a-must/"&gt;ABQ Journal opinion piece: More investigative journalism is a must&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 19:54:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Rifreedom] NEW REPORT PROVIDES ALTERNATIVES TO RHODE ISLAND’S SUICIDAL ACT ON CLIMATE POLICIES</title><link>https://rifreedom.org/2026/01/new-report-provides-alternatives-to-rhode-islands-suicidal-act-on-climate-policies/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New Englanders would save hundreds of billions of dollars and avoid deadly power blackouts by replacing state-mandated renewable energy projects with nuclear and natural gas power, a study released today by a coalition of New England think tanks finds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alternatives to New England’s Energy Suicide, released by New England’s free-market think tanks along with Americans for Prosperity Foundation, estimated the effects of trying to meet the region’s energy needs through 2050 with nuclear and natural gas plants instead of wind and solar power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org/2026/01/new-report-provides-alternatives-to-rhode-islands-suicidal-act-on-climate-policies/"&gt;NEW REPORT PROVIDES ALTERNATIVES TO RHODE ISLAND&amp;#8217;S SUICIDAL ACT ON CLIMATE POLICIES&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org"&gt;RI Center for Freedom and Prosperity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 13:49:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cardinalinstitute] A Conversation with Charles Mitchell</title><link>https://cardinalinstitute.com/a-conversation-with-charles-mitchell/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A Conversation with Charles Mitchell David and Laura Thayer Visiting Fellow, Cardinal Institute Editor’s Note: The Cardinal Institute is pleased to announce that Charles Mitchell, former CEO of the Commonwealth Foundation, has joined Cardinal as the David B. and Laura Thayer Visiting Fellow. Charles brings decades of national leadership experience in the conservative, free-market think [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com/a-conversation-with-charles-mitchell/"&gt;A Conversation with Charles Mitchell&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com"&gt;Cardinal Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 14:43:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] ABQ Ethics Board Dismisses frivolous “sweatshirt-gate” ethics complaint made by Keller campaign against RGF’s Paul Gessing</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/abq-ethics-board-dismisses-frivolous-sweatshirt-gate-ethics-complaint-made-by-keller-campaign-against-rgfs-paul-gessing/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This afternoon in a hearing, the Albuquerque Board of Ethics (BOE) unanimously dismissed a complaint filed by Daymon Ely for the Tim Keller campaign that was made against Rio Grande Foundation president Paul Gessing. The complaint arose out of the Foundation’s reporting over the purchase and delivery of yellow hoodie sweatshirts to members of Albuquerque’s [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/abq-ethics-board-dismisses-frivolous-sweatshirt-gate-ethics-complaint-made-by-keller-campaign-against-rgfs-paul-gessing/"&gt;ABQ Ethics Board Dismisses frivolous “sweatshirt-gate” ethics complaint made by Keller campaign against RGF’s Paul Gessing&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 22:08:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cardinalinstitute] 2026 State of the State Response</title><link>https://cardinalinstitute.com/2026-state-of-the-state-response/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;2026 State of the State Response On Wednesday evening, Governor Patrick Morrisey delivered his annual State of the State address, outlining his priorities for the year ahead and offering a window into his governing philosophy. As is customary, the speech functioned as both pep rally and agenda-setting exercise. State of the state addresses tend to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com/2026-state-of-the-state-response/"&gt;2026 State of the State Response&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com"&gt;Cardinal Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 15:07:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF opinion piece: Data centers are coming: How to handle them</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-opinion-piece-data-centers-are-coming-how-to-handle-them/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following appeared in the Santa Fe New Mexican on January 10, 2026. It has appeared in several other publications as well. &amp;#160; After years of failure to land a “big fish” business for New Mexico’s economy (or effectively use the oil and gas revenues to grow the economy) Gov. Michelle Lujan Grisham, with the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-opinion-piece-data-centers-are-coming-how-to-handle-them/"&gt;RGF opinion piece: Data centers are coming: How to handle them&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 15:48:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Bothfield v. WEC &amp; WBLD v WEC</title><link>https://will-law.org/bothfield-v-wec-wbld-v-wec/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On behalf of Wisconsin voters in all 8 of the state's congressional districts, WILL filed motions to intervene in two lawsuits seeking to overturn Wisconsin’s Congressional Maps. Seeking again to defend those maps on behalf of a group of Wisconsin voters, WILL argues that these new lawsuits are time-barred, the three-judge panel lacks authority to overrule the Wisconsin Supreme Court, and any attempt to impose new maps in this manner would violate federal law and the U.S. Constitution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/bothfield-v-wec-wbld-v-wec/"&gt;Bothfield v. WEC &amp;#038; WBLD v WEC&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 21:19:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Portland Ends School Choice Policy for Jefferson High School</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/education/portland-ends-school-choice-policy-for-jefferson-high-school/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By John A. Charles, Jr. Fifteen years ago, the Portland Public Schools (PPS)...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/education/portland-ends-school-choice-policy-for-jefferson-high-school/"&gt;Portland Ends School Choice Policy for Jefferson High School&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 23:36:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Rifreedom] “Doc” Skoly Stepping Down as Center’s Chair to Pursue Congressional Seat</title><link>https://rifreedom.org/2026/01/doc-skoly-stepping-down-as-centers-chair-to-pursue-congressional-seat/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The  Rhode Island Center for Freedom &amp;#038; Prosperity announced today that Dr. Stephen "Doc" Skoly has stepped down as Chairman of its Board of Directors to pursue a run for the US House of Representatives in Rhode Island's second Congressional district.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org/2026/01/doc-skoly-stepping-down-as-centers-chair-to-pursue-congressional-seat/"&gt;&amp;#8220;Doc&amp;#8221; Skoly Stepping Down as Center&amp;#8217;s Chair to Pursue Congressional Seat&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org"&gt;RI Center for Freedom and Prosperity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 15:10:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Policy Pathway for Principled Tax Reform</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/policy-pathway-for-principled-tax-reform/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Policy Pathway for Principled Tax Reform outlines a framework for evaluating tax policy through the lens of sound tax principles including transparency, simplicity, stability, neutrality, and economic efficiency. The report examines Nebraska’s major tax types including property, income, and sales and offers practical, principle-based recommendations to improve affordability, competitiveness, and long-term fiscal sustainability. While designed...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/policy-pathway-for-principled-tax-reform/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Policy Pathway for Principled Tax Reform&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 19:40:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cardinalinstitute] Healthcare in West Virginia</title><link>https://cardinalinstitute.com/healthcare-in-west-virginia/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Healthcare in West Virginia Healthcare policy is complicated. These resources make it understandable. If you are trying to make sense of West Virginia’s latest healthcare debates, you are not alone. PBM regulation, PEIA’s recurring funding crises, and Certificate of Need laws all affect what care costs, where it is available, and who has choices. We [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com/healthcare-in-west-virginia/"&gt;Healthcare in West Virginia&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com"&gt;Cardinal Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 15:44:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Wisconsin Senate Passes WILL-Backed ﻿Amendment to End Tax-Veto Loopholes</title><link>https://will-law.org/wisconsin-senate-passes-will-backed-amendment-to-end-tax-veto-loopholes/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL issued a statement applauding the Wisconsin State Senate for passing Senate Joint Resolution 116 (SJR 116). This proposed amendment to the Wisconsin Constitution curbs executive overreach by prohibiting the governor from using the partial veto to create or increase taxes or fees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/wisconsin-senate-passes-will-backed-amendment-to-end-tax-veto-loopholes/"&gt;Wisconsin Senate Passes WILL-Backed ﻿Amendment to End Tax-Veto Loopholes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 17:40:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] WILL-Backed Equality Amendment ﻿On November 2026 Ballot</title><link>https://will-law.org/will-backed-equality-amendment-on-november-2026-ballot/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The “Equality Amendment,” otherwise known as Assembly Joint Resolution 102 (AJR 102) will be on the November 2026 ballot after the Wisconsin State Senate voted in favor today. The Wisconsin State Assembly passed the amendment last week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/will-backed-equality-amendment-on-november-2026-ballot/"&gt;WILL-Backed Equality Amendment ﻿On November 2026 Ballot&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 20:58:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Cascade Policy Institute is Hiring – Development Assistant</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/news/cascade-policy-institute-is-hiring-development-assistant/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;We are seeking a detail-oriented, organized, part-time Development Assistant to support Cascade Policy...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/news/cascade-policy-institute-is-hiring-development-assistant/"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute is Hiring &amp;#8211; Development Assistant&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 23:07:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Assembly clears bill to tackle fears of data center spiking power rates</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/assembly-clears-bill-to-tackle-fears-of-data-center-spiking-power-rates/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The state Assembly this week passed a bill barring data centers from passing on any utility costs to other ratepayers in Wisconsin — targeting a key objection from Wisconsinites who oppose data center development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assembly Bill 840, passed 53-44 almost entirely along party lines, also requires new data centers to use water-conserving technology for cooling and to report annual water use to the Department of Natural Resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/assembly-clears-bill-to-tackle-fears-of-data-center-spiking-power-rates/"&gt;Assembly clears bill to tackle fears of data center spiking power rates&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 15:50:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] New Jersey at a Crossroads: Looking back on Governor Murphy and Ahead to Mikie Sherrill</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/01/new-jersey-at-a-crossroads-looking-back-on-governor-murphy-and-ahead-to-mikie-sherrill/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;by Megan Whitman, NJPI Jr. Economy Fellow As Governor Phil Murphy officially left office this week after eight years, New [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/01/new-jersey-at-a-crossroads-looking-back-on-governor-murphy-and-ahead-to-mikie-sherrill/"&gt;New Jersey at a Crossroads: Looking back on Governor Murphy and Ahead to Mikie Sherrill&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 19:02:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Florida Politics: Skip the lawsuits, teach the kids</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/edward-longe-skip-the-lawsuits-teach-the-kids/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Teaching kids digital literacy beats unconstitutional mandates and endless lawsuits. For parents navigating the rise of social media...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/edward-longe-skip-the-lawsuits-teach-the-kids/"&gt;Florida Politics: Skip the lawsuits, teach the kids&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 19:29:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Is Hochul Really Going to Shut Down the Essential Plan?</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/is-hochul-really-going-to-shut-down-the-essential-plan/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Governor Hochul is hingeing a big chunk of her budget – and the state&amp;#8217;s health-care system – on a politically....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/is-hochul-really-going-to-shut-down-the-essential-plan/"&gt;Is Hochul Really Going to Shut Down the Essential Plan?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 21:41:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Facts Over Fear: What Mainers Should Know About ICE Enforcement</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/facts-over-fear-what-mainers-should-know-about-ice-enforcement/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Recent headlines have reignited debate in Maine over immigration enforcement and the authority of federal agents to operate within our communities. Immigration enforcement is a lawful federal responsibility. ICE operates under defined legal constraints, and claims that agents are “roaming without warrants” misrepresent how federal law enforcement works. Mischaracterizing immigration enforcement in Maine erodes trust [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/facts-over-fear-what-mainers-should-know-about-ice-enforcement/"&gt;Facts Over Fear: What Mainers Should Know About ICE Enforcement&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 21:42:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Understanding welfare work requirements: new eligibility rules for SNAP and Medicaid</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/understanding-snap-and-medicaid-work-requirements/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Big changes are in process for some recipients of Medicaid and Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP or food stamps) benefits and for the state governments that administer the programs. See a breakdown of the changes and who they will actually affect. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/understanding-snap-and-medicaid-work-requirements/"&gt;Understanding welfare work requirements: new eligibility rules for SNAP and Medicaid&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 18:53:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Prospect of open enrollment is already prompting talk of improving public schools’ appeal</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2026/01/prospect-of-open-enrollment-is-already-prompting-talk-of-improving-public-schools-appeal/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A bill to create universal open enrollment for New Hampshire public schools is already prompting school boards to consider marketing their districts to families. And the bill hasn&amp;#8217;t passed either chamber of the Legislature yet. Senate Bill 101, sponsored by Sen. Tim Lang, R-Sanbornton, would require all school districts to &amp;#8220;establish an open enrollment policy [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2026/01/prospect-of-open-enrollment-is-already-prompting-talk-of-improving-public-schools-appeal/"&gt;Prospect of open enrollment is already prompting talk of improving public schools&amp;#8217; appeal&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 20:45:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Revenue-Hungry Democrats Give Themselves a Buffet of Tax Increase Choices for 2026</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/revenue-hungry-democrats-give-themselves-a-buffet-of-tax-increase-choices-for-2026/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="630" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Tax-Buffet.jpg" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Governor Abigail Spanberger so far is no more clear on her tax and spending priorities than Candidate Spanberger was, but her fellow Democrats in the General Assembly are laying out a smorgasbord of tax increase options for her.    Would she like a major “tax the rich” approach? Start with Delegate Vivian Watt’s House Bill 979, pending in [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/revenue-hungry-democrats-give-themselves-a-buffet-of-tax-increase-choices-for-2026/"&gt;Revenue-Hungry Democrats Give Themselves a Buffet of Tax Increase Choices for 2026&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 12:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] If You Want Parent Power, Only HB2 Will Do</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/if-you-want-parent-power-only-hb2-will-do/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past few years, Mississippi lawmakers have passed some critical conservative reforms.&amp;#160;Last year, Mississippi became the first state in America to legislate to eliminate the income tax in 40 years.&amp;#160; In 2022, we implemented flat tax reform.&amp;#160; A few years before that, we passed important labor market reforms.&amp;#160; In 2024, we reformed school funding [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/if-you-want-parent-power-only-hb2-will-do/" rel="nofollow"&gt;If You Want Parent Power, Only HB2 Will Do&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 16:09:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] A Trillion Dollar Energy Law – HB2021: Watch John Charles on PDX Real</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/environment/a-trillion-dollar-energy-law-hb2021-watch-john-charles-on-pdx-real/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;“All we want as consumers is reliable, affordable energy.” ~John A. Charles, Jr.,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/environment/a-trillion-dollar-energy-law-hb2021-watch-john-charles-on-pdx-real/"&gt;A Trillion Dollar Energy Law &amp;#8211; HB2021: Watch John Charles on PDX Real&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 00:12:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Rifreedom] MEDIA RELEASE: Center Launches Petition Calling for Affordable Energy Policies</title><link>https://rifreedom.org/2026/01/media-release-center-launches-petition-calling-for-affordable-energy-policies/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Rhode Island Center for Freedom &amp;#038; Prosperity today announced that it has launched an online petition drive calling for policymakers to support a fundamental pivot away from our state's current energy strategy, which will lead to staggeringly high electricity prices and potentially dangerous blackouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org/2026/01/media-release-center-launches-petition-calling-for-affordable-energy-policies/"&gt;MEDIA RELEASE: Center Launches Petition Calling for Affordable Energy Policies&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org"&gt;RI Center for Freedom and Prosperity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 14:19:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Study Finds U.S. Drought Monitor Has Overstated Drought Conditions in California for 25 Years</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/usdm-study-pressrelease/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=usdm-study-pressrelease</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Study Finds U.S. Drought Monitor Has Overstated Drought Conditions in California for 25 Years IRVINE, CA — For 25 years, the U.S. Drought Monitor has significantly exaggerated drought conditions in California, providing state officials with the pretext for a range of climate-change policies that have crippled the state’s water infrastructure, devastated farming, and punished its 39...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/usdm-study-pressrelease/"&gt;Study Finds U.S. Drought Monitor Has Overstated Drought Conditions in California for 25 Years&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 15:58:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Millions Misspent: How Maine Lost Control of Autism Medicaid Spending</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/millions-misspent-how-maine-lost-control-of-autism-medicaid-spending/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Maine’s Medicaid-funded autism services are rooted in the goal of ensuring children with autism receive early, effective support. Few would dispute the importance of those services, but compassion without accountability isn’t compassion, it’s negligence. A newly released federal audit reveals that Maine’s autism services program has become a case study in how big government programs [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/millions-misspent-how-maine-lost-control-of-autism-medicaid-spending/"&gt;Millions Misspent: How Maine Lost Control of Autism Medicaid Spending&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 18:06:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] An estate tax would harm Wisconsin’s economy</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/an-estate-tax-would-harm-wisconsins-economy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Some lawmakers in Madison, however, led by members of the Assembly’s Socialist Caucus,  want to implement an estate tax with a top rate of 20 percent. Currently in draft form before being introduced, their legislation would propel Wisconsin to a tie with Hawaii for the second-highest state rate in the nation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/an-estate-tax-would-harm-wisconsins-economy/"&gt;An estate tax would harm Wisconsin’s economy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 17:04:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Orlando Sentinel: Will the Legislature Keep Its Eye on the Ball?</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/orlando-sentinel-will-the-legislature-keep-its-eye-on-the-ball/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As the curtain fell on 2025 and I looked at the coming legislative session with my team, a...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/orlando-sentinel-will-the-legislature-keep-its-eye-on-the-ball/"&gt;Orlando Sentinel: Will the Legislature Keep Its Eye on the Ball?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 17:43:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] California shatters another record, momentum keeps building</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/california-shatters-another-record-momentum-keeps-building/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;With nearly 24,500 opt-outs statewide, the Freedom Foundation didn’t just surpass last year’s total. We blew past it, representing a nearly 50 percent increase in opt-outs compared to 2024.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/california-shatters-another-record-momentum-keeps-building/" rel="nofollow"&gt;California shatters another record, momentum keeps building &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 18:21:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] California’s Drought is Over, But We Still Must Invest in Water Supply Projects</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/californias-drought-is-over-but-we-still-must-invest-in-water-supply-projects/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=californias-drought-is-over-but-we-still-must-invest-in-water-supply-projects</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For the last 25 years, the US Drought Monitor (USDM), a collaborative effort by the University of Nebraska, NOAA, the USDA, and other experts throughout the country, has released a weekly map that shows the location and intensity of drought across the United States. On January 8, for the first time ever, USDM’s weekly map showed the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/californias-drought-is-over-but-we-still-must-invest-in-water-supply-projects/"&gt;California’s Drought is Over, But We Still Must Invest in Water Supply Projects&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 19:25:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Open enrollment: Know the basics</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2026/01/open-enrollment-know-the-basics/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In 2025, New Hampshire legislators passed a law allowing students to enroll in any public school within their assigned district, as long as the school had room. This year, lawmakers might allow students to enroll in any New Hampshire public school that has room. This policy brief answers six core questions commonly raised about open [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2026/01/open-enrollment-know-the-basics/"&gt;Open enrollment: Know the basics&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 19:28:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] The Hill: School Choice in Florida Offers Wild and Imaginative Learning Options</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/the-hill-school-choice-in-florida-offers-wild-and-imaginative-learning-options/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Of the thousands of events commemorating this year’s National School Choice Week, the wildest and most imaginative may...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/the-hill-school-choice-in-florida-offers-wild-and-imaginative-learning-options/"&gt;The Hill: School Choice in Florida Offers Wild and Imaginative Learning Options&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 20:07:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] 10 Reasons to Discount ITEP’s Analysis of the Proposed Income Tax Cut</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/fact-check-10-reasons-to-discount-iteps-analysis-once-again/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Context Pioneer Institute has previously gone toe-to-toe with the Institute on Taxation and Economic Policy (ITEP) over flawed and misleading tax analyses—notably ITEP’s advocacy for the 2022 surtax on high earners as good for the Bay State economy. That argument that has proven to hold about...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/fact-check-10-reasons-to-discount-iteps-analysis-once-again/"&gt;10 Reasons to Discount ITEP’s Analysis of the Proposed Income Tax Cut&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 20:34:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] As Immigration Slowed, New York’s Population Hit a Wall in 2025</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/as-immigration-slowed-new-yorks-population-hit-a-wall-in-2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New York State added just 1,008 new residents last year as its post-pandemic recovery ground to a near standstill, newly....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/as-immigration-slowed-new-yorks-population-hit-a-wall-in-2025/"&gt;As Immigration Slowed, New York&amp;#8217;s Population Hit a Wall in 2025&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 21:41:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] Franke: Avoiding Another ‘Oil War’</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2026/01/franke-avoiding-another-oil-war/</link><description>by Mark Franke It seems that every time gas prices jump up at the pump, politicians are quick to find media microphones to blame Big Oil or the Arabs or the previous administration. That’s what we do best these days — find someone to blame. It saves mental energy otherwise wasted on research and analysis.&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2026/01/franke-avoiding-another-oil-war/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 12:15:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Poll Finds Massachusetts Residents Overwhelmingly Support Expanding Vocational Schools</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/poll-finds-massachusetts-residents-overwhelmingly-support-expanding-vocational-schools/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A new statewide poll finds overwhelming support among Massachusetts adults for expanding vocational-technical high school capacity, along with broad backing for school choice options, including the new Federal Tax Credit Scholarship Program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/poll-finds-massachusetts-residents-overwhelmingly-support-expanding-vocational-schools/"&gt;Poll Finds Massachusetts Residents Overwhelmingly Support Expanding Vocational Schools&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 14:37:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Liberty vs. the Leviathan: Price Controls Never Work, Even Ones Proposed by Conservatives</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/uncategorized/price-controls-never-work/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Credit card interest rates can feel punishing. When cash gets tight, many American families turn to credit cards to float expenses, often at interest rates that can be eye popping, especially for low-income families with less-than-stellar credit scores.  As a result, it&amp;#8217;s no surprise politicians are taking notice, and the idea of capping those rates...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/uncategorized/price-controls-never-work/"&gt;Liberty vs. the Leviathan: Price Controls Never Work, Even Ones Proposed by Conservatives&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 14:42:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Testimony on FY 2027 New York state executive budget Article VII legislation, parts N, O, P</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/60101/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Testimony of Zilvinas Silenas President, Empire Center for Public Policy   Before the Joint Legislative Committee on Environmental Conservation and....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/60101/"&gt;Testimony on FY 2027 New York state executive budget Article VII legislation, parts N, O, P&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 15:24:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] Day One, Energy First: Governor Mikie Sherrill’s Opening Strategy on Affordability</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/01/day-one-energy-first-governor-mikie-sherrills-opening-strategy-on-affordability/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Sean Barry, NJPI Jr. Fellow When Governor Mikie Sherrill was sworn in as New Jersey’s 57th governor, she did [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/01/day-one-energy-first-governor-mikie-sherrills-opening-strategy-on-affordability/"&gt;Day One, Energy First: Governor Mikie Sherrill’s Opening Strategy on Affordability&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 19:08:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] A New Governor Takes Office. Will She Deliver on Education?</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/01/a-new-governor-takes-office-will-she-deliver-on-education/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;by Aiden DeMarsey, NJPI Jr. Fellow &amp;#160; Governor Mikie Sherrill, sworn into office last week, enters her term with a [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/01/a-new-governor-takes-office-will-she-deliver-on-education/"&gt;A New Governor Takes Office. Will She Deliver on Education?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 19:10:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] A foolish law wages war against homemade shindigs</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/a-foolish-law-wages-war-against-homemade-shindigs/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The law, passed in 2023, decrees that venues rented for private events at which the people holding the party bring their own alcohol can host only six such events a year, and only one a month — unless they prohibit bring-your-own drinks and instead get a liquor license like a tavern. Those are subject to strict quotas. Town board can simply refuse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/a-foolish-law-wages-war-against-homemade-shindigs/"&gt;A foolish law wages war against homemade shindigs&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 19:33:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Will South Carolina Become the New Leader in State Tax Reform?</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/will-south-carolina-become-the-new-leader-in-state-tax-reform/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Will South Carolina Become the New Leader in State Tax Reform?" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/1769721825656-7ba70731-f62a-468e-aa5f-b9bb3afb3e30_1.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;States are choosing two very different paths. High-tax, high-spending states are running growing deficits, while reform-oriented states are cutting income taxes, controlling spending, and becoming more competitive. The push to eliminate income taxes is accelerating. States like Missouri, Louisiana, West Virginia, and especially South Carolina are using revenue triggers and disciplined budgeting to move toward flat—or zero—income taxes. Iowa can’t afford to get complacent. Iowa’s 3.8% flat tax and Taxpayer Relief Fund put it ahead today, but other states are catching up—continued spending restraint and long-term tax reform are essential to stay competitive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/will-south-carolina-become-the-new-leader-in-state-tax-reform/"&gt;Will South Carolina Become the New Leader in State Tax Reform?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 21:49:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Weingarten’s answer ignores her painful reality</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/teachers-unions/weingartens-answer-ignores-her-painful-reality/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Randi Weingarten didn’t ascend to the presidency of the powerful American Federation of Teachers (AFT) without learning how to mask lies in half-truth. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/teachers-unions/weingartens-answer-ignores-her-painful-reality/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Weingarten’s answer ignores her painful reality&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 22:32:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Virginia’s Paid Family Medical Leave Act Would be Among the Most Expansive and Expensive in the Country</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/virginias-paid-family-medical-leave-act-would-be-among-the-most-expansive-and-expensive-in-the-country/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="630" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/stop-sb2.jpg" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Governor Abigail Spanberger campaigned on a promise to sign “paid family and medical leave” when it reaches her desk. But popular vote-getting concepts often ignore the damaging impact such policies have once they are implemented. Virginia’s proposed paid family and medical leave program (SB2)/(HB1207) is a case study in how expansive design choices can turn a popular benefit idea [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/virginias-paid-family-medical-leave-act-would-be-among-the-most-expansive-and-expensive-in-the-country/"&gt;Virginia’s Paid Family Medical Leave Act Would be Among the Most Expansive and Expensive in the Country &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2026/01/the-outstater-324/</link><description>Return of the 1-Room Schoolhouse SCHOOL CHOICE,&amp;#160;an issue championed by the Indiana Policy Review Foundation since its beginning, has taken root. Thirty-four states&amp;#160;including Indiana have adopted some form of school choice, with 1.5 million students participating. Now another of the foundation’s early recommendations, micro schools, is gaining attention&amp;#160;as well — a high-tech version of the&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2026/01/the-outstater-324/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 13:14:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] What “Affordability” Really Means—and Why Louisiana Is at a Turning Point</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/tax-budget/louisiana-turning-point/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;“Affordability” has become one of the most talked-about issues in politics—and for good reason. Families feel squeezed. Groceries cost more. Housing is harder to find. Insurance and interest rates take a bigger bite out of every paycheck. But affordability isn’t a slogan or a buzzword. It’s a basic economic outcome: can people buy what they...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/tax-budget/louisiana-turning-point/"&gt;What “Affordability” Really Means—and Why Louisiana Is at a Turning Point&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 14:19:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Setting the Tone: Fiscal Restraint in Louisiana’s FY 2027 Executive Budget</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/tax-budget/fiscial-restraint-la/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The new year is well underway, which means a new budget for the upcoming fiscal year must be proposed for Louisiana. Governor Jeff Landry’s executive budget for fiscal year (FY) 2027 (July 1, 2026-June 30, 2027) was unveiled at the latest Joint Legislative Committee on the Budget (JLCB) meeting. As the first step in the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/tax-budget/fiscial-restraint-la/"&gt;Setting the Tone: Fiscal Restraint in Louisiana’s FY 2027 Executive Budget&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 15:23:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] As lawmakers consider new short-term rental bills, new MSPC study warns bans won’t fix housing affordability</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/post/as-lawmakers-consider-new-short-term-rental-bills-new-mspc-study-warns-bans-won-t-fix-housing-affor</link><description>This research piece is one of the most extensive reviews to date of short-term rental regulation, synthesizing academic research, economic data, and real-world case studies from major cities and resort communities.</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 18:30:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] HB 1736, HB 1735, SB 2041: MDOC Dyslexia Study</title><link>https://empowerms.org/hb-1736-hb-1735-sb-2041-mdoc-dyslexia-study/</link><description>&lt;p&gt; House Bill 1736, authored by Representative Roberson, House Bill 1735, authored by Rep. Larry Byrd, and Senate Bill 2041, authored by Senator Rod Hickman, direct the Mississippi Department of Corrections to study the prevalence of dyslexia among incarcerated individuals.  The bill’s requirement for a comprehensive, evidence-based study will provide valuable insight into how undiagnosed dyslexia may relate to education outcomes, crime, and recidivism. Better data on&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/hb-1736-hb-1735-sb-2041-mdoc-dyslexia-study/"&gt;HB 1736, HB 1735, SB 2041: MDOC Dyslexia Study&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 18:50:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] New housing permits are highest since 2006, but single-family homes lag</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2026/01/new-housing-permits-are-highest-since-2006-but-single-family-homes-lag/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New Hampshire towns and cities are permitting more residential housing units than they have in years, which is great news. But the new units are skewed heavily toward rentals, suggesting that local restrictions on small, single-family homes remain a significant barrier. Local governments issued permits for 5,822 new housing units in 2024, the highest number [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2026/01/new-housing-permits-are-highest-since-2006-but-single-family-homes-lag/"&gt;New housing permits are highest since 2006, but single-family homes lag&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:16:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Week in Review: Data Center Facts vs. Fiction</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-data-center-facts-vs-fiction/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;It’s an undeniable fact—data centers are now economic engines and indispensable infrastructure that power the digital world. And it’s no..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-data-center-facts-vs-fiction/"&gt;Week in Review: Data Center Facts vs. Fiction&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:55:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Crime is down, and it should end ‘root cause’ excuse-making for good</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/crime-is-down-and-it-should-end-root-cause-excuse-making-for-good/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/crime-is-down-and-it-should-end-root-cause-excuse-making-for-good/"&gt;Crime is down, and it should end ‘root cause’ excuse-making for good&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 22:13:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Federal Investigation Finds California Department of Education Violated FERPA by Keeping Secrets from Parents</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/federal-investigation-finds-california-department-of-education-violated-ferpa-by-keeping-secrets-from-parents/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=federal-investigation-finds-california-department-of-education-violated-ferpa-by-keeping-secrets-from-parents</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Department of Education announced this week that its investigation into the California Department of Education found that state policies that pressure schools to keep secrets from parents violate federal law. Specifically, the DOE said the “California Department of Education (CDE) is in continued violation of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA)—a federal law...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/federal-investigation-finds-california-department-of-education-violated-ferpa-by-keeping-secrets-from-parents/"&gt;Federal Investigation Finds California Department of Education Violated FERPA by Keeping Secrets from Parents&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 23:34:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] From a Mother’s Struggle to a Thriving Academy: The Story of Knox Academy</title><link>https://empowerms.org/from-a-mothers-struggle-to-a-thriving-academy-the-story-of-knox-academy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When Julie Gilliland first sat in doctors’ offices years ago, hearing predictions about her son John Knox, the words felt heavy and discouraging. Again and again, she was told that his autism was severe and that traditional paths might not offer him the support he would need to thrive in school or everyday settings.  But Julie refused to&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/from-a-mothers-struggle-to-a-thriving-academy-the-story-of-knox-academy/"&gt;From a Mother’s Struggle to a Thriving Academy: The Story of Knox Academy&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 14:50:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Sedgwick County Commissioners use scare tactics and false claim to oppose property tax assessment limit</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/sedgwick-assessment-limit-scare-tactics/</link><description>Neutral testimony from the Kansas Association of Counties on the proposed 3% valuation assessment limit says, “The major benefit for taxpayers is predictability,” and notes that predictability could also help counties by having fewer disputes over valuations. Sedgwick County Commissioners, on the other hand, are taking a ‘sky is falling’ approach replete with scare tactics [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 16:56:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Utah’s “bull manure” plan to increase gas prices in Idaho not well received - likely unconstitutional</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/post/utah-s-bull-manure-plan-to-increase-gas-prices-in-idaho-not-well-received-likely-unconstitutiona</link><description>"This is taxation without representation- something we fought a war over 250 years ago. I hope that Utah’s leaders realize that these dependencies run both ways, and as dependent as Idaho is on Utah for motor fuels, Utah is dependent on Idaho for water. I hope we don’t have to enter a cycle of mutual exploitation. I hope we can remain good friends and partners.”</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 23:13:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] The meaning of America, 250 years later</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2026/the-meaning-of-america-250-years-later</link><description>How do we recommit to the things that made us a shining city on a hill?</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Governor Spanberger, Winter Storm Fern Showed Us Wind and Solar Are Inadequate</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/governor-spanberger-winter-storm-fern-showed-us-wind-and-solar-are-inadequate/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Frozen-Solar-Panels.jpg" width="1080" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Governor Abigail Spanberger’s major campaign pledges to lower electricity bills have already been crushed by the harsh reality of last week’s Winter Storm&amp;#160;Fern.&amp;#160;Virginians everywhere are about to see their highest energy bills ever, and the energy sources Spanberger wants us to adopt were all but useless during the crisis.&amp;#160; Day after day, if you checked [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/governor-spanberger-winter-storm-fern-showed-us-wind-and-solar-are-inadequate/"&gt;Governor Spanberger, Winter Storm Fern Showed Us Wind and Solar Are Inadequate&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] Keating: Drama at the Federal Reserve</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2026/02/keating-drama-at-the-federal-reserve/</link><description>by Maryann O. Keating, Ph.D. The Trump-Powell feud over the interest rate is Shakespearean. Who knew that monetary policy could be so riveting? At this point, Kevin Warsh has emerged from a list of pretenders as President Trump’s nominee for the next Chairman of the Federal Reserve (Fed), replacing Jerome Powell. &amp;#160; The big question&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2026/02/keating-drama-at-the-federal-reserve/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 12:53:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Introducing TennSight, Tennessee’s only hub for voter insights</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/introducing-tennsight-tennessees-only-hub-for-voter-insights/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=introducing-tennsight-tennessees-only-hub-for-voter-insights</link><description>We hope that TennSight will become the go-to source for you to learn what matters most to your fellow Tennesseans, why it matters, and what can be done about it.</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 13:08:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Tax Relief, Spending Growth, and Restraint</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/tax-relief-spending-growth-and-restraint/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Tax Relief, Spending Growth, and Restraint" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/reynolds-2026-condition-of-the-state.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Governor Reynolds has proposed a $9.6 billion FY27 budget that modestly increases spending while education and health services, driven primarily by K-12 funding and Medicaid, continue to dominate state expenditures, consuming roughly 84 percent of the General Fund. Although Iowa is projecting a $1.2 billion revenue shortfall due to the fully phased-in 3.8 percent flat tax, this reflects a planned transition rather than a structural deficit, with the Taxpayer Relief Fund intentionally built to cushion revenues during tax reform. Iowa’s fiscal position remains strong with substantial reserves, but continued growth in major spending programs and federal uncertainty underscore the need for spending restraint and conservative budgeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/tax-relief-spending-growth-and-restraint/"&gt;Tax Relief, Spending Growth, and Restraint&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 13:38:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Professor Illegally Forced into DEI Training Deserves His Day in Court</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/professor-illegally-forced-into-dei-training-deserves-his-day-in-court/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When Arizona State University professor Owen Anderson was illegally forced to take a diversity, equity, and inclusion (DEI) training to..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/professor-illegally-forced-into-dei-training-deserves-his-day-in-court/"&gt;Professor Illegally Forced into DEI Training Deserves His Day in Court&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 14:57:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] A Steady-State Budget in a Moment of Crisis</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/a-steady-state-budget-in-a-moment-of-crisis/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Governor Maura Healey’s fiscal year 2027 budget totals $62.8 billion, a 3.8 percent year-over-year increase. The budget avoids sweeping new initiatives and largely preserves existing structures. That might be defensible in a period of stability. It is indefensible now. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/a-steady-state-budget-in-a-moment-of-crisis/"&gt;A Steady-State Budget in a Moment of Crisis &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 16:44:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Idaho schools paying $1.2 million per year for IEA/NEA dues</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/labor/idaho-schools-paying-1-2-million-per-year-for-iea-nea-dues/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;According to a new Freedom Foundation analysis, the Boise and Twin Falls School Districts are spending more than $1.2 million per year on programs to cover the cost of teachers union dues to the Idaho Education Association. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/labor/idaho-schools-paying-1-2-million-per-year-for-iea-nea-dues/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Idaho schools paying $1.2 million per year for IEA/NEA dues&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 17:33:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Beacon Poll: January 2026 Results</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/beacon-poll-january-2026-results/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=beacon-poll-january-2026-results</link><description>Today, we released the latest installment of the Beacon Poll, a statewide survey of 1,200 Tennessee voters featuring questions about voters’ views on property taxes, the federal school choice tax credit included in the One Big Beautiful Bill Act, and political approval ratings at the state and federal level, and more. Tennesseans continue to prioritize key...</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 19:35:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Students Used as Collateral in Adult Political Fights</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/students-used-as-collateral-in-adult-political-fights/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On Friday, Austin ISD officials permitted hundreds of students across 14 campuses to leave school during school hours to participate in anti–Immigration and Customs Enforcement demonstrations around the city. I personally observed several hundred students—some of them very young—marching up Congress Avenue toward the Texas Capitol. Many carried signs bearing vulgar slogans, including messages such...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/students-used-as-collateral-in-adult-political-fights/"&gt;Students Used as Collateral in Adult Political Fights&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 21:18:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Most states already say ‘yes’ to donations for students</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/most-states-already-say-yes-to-donations-for-students/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;At least 28 states have already said they plan to opt into the Federal Scholarship Tax Credit program to let donors provide extra academic help to their students. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/most-states-already-say-yes-to-donations-for-students/"&gt;Most states already say ‘yes’ to donations for students&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 22:09:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Johnson County superintendents fail 4th-grade math</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/johnson-county-supers-fail-4th-grade-math/</link><description>Today’s math riddle is brought to you by Johnson County school superintendents: How can taxpayers give school districts hundreds of millions of dollars more for special education without increasing total spending or cutting other state funding? The obvious answer is that it’s not possible, but that is what they tell taxpayers, and in their pitch [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 00:15:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] EDUCATION FREEDOM DAY – 2026</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2026/02/03/education-freedom-day-2026/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Americans for Prosperity–Alabama and the Alabama Policy Institute hosted Education Freedom Day on Wednesday, January 28, 2026, in Montgomery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2026/02/03/education-freedom-day-2026/"&gt;EDUCATION FREEDOM DAY &amp;#8211; 2026&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 00:26:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] Education Freedom Day held outside Alabama State House</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2026/02/03/education-freedom-day-held-outside-alabama-state-house/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Education Freedom Day was celebrated on the front steps of the Alabama State House to highlight the different school choice options available to Alabamians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2026/02/03/education-freedom-day-held-outside-alabama-state-house/"&gt;Education Freedom Day held outside Alabama State House&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 09:15:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Tech company bolts California for Florida</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/tech-company-bolts-california-for-florida/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Bianca Heyward writes for the New York Post about another bit of bad news for the Golden State’s economy. The state of California is losing yet another tech company to Florida. In a dramatic sign of the rising allure of low-tax, pro-business states, quantum computing firm D-Wave Quantum Inc. announced it is relocating its corporate...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/tech-company-bolts-california-for-florida/"&gt;Tech company bolts California for Florida&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 10:39:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Car companies have lost $114B on EVs</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/car-companies-have-lost-114b-on-evs/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Robert Bryce writes for the New York Post about a conflict between ideology and economics. Just two years ago, Mary Barra, chief executive of General Motors, declared: “We believe in an all-electric future.” She went on to claim that the challenges her company was facing in the EV market were merely temporary bumps on the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/car-companies-have-lost-114b-on-evs/"&gt;Car companies have lost $114B on EVs&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 10:42:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Indiana chokes with new cigarette taxes</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2026/indiana-chokes-with-new-cigarette-taxes</link><description>High excise tax rates drive smuggling, violence, theft and corruption</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Healthcare Reform Should Take Aim at Hidden Prices</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/healthcare-reform-should-take-aim-at-hidden-prices/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Effective healthcare reform should address the persistent problem of a system that hides prices, shields middlemen like pharmacy benefit managers and insurers from accountability, and leaves patients with little real leverage. Reforms can lower healthcare costs by increasing transparency, expanding competition, and reducing the influence of middlemen whose practices operate largely out of public view. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/healthcare-reform-should-take-aim-at-hidden-prices/"&gt;Healthcare Reform Should Take Aim at Hidden Prices&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 11:00:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Trucking industry vet calls Illinois toll hike needless punishment</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/trucking-industry-vet-calls-illinois-toll-hike-needless-punishment/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Illinois toll rates are about to increase as a political favor to construction unions. That’s despite a $3 billion surplus in the road fund. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/trucking-industry-vet-calls-illinois-toll-hike-needless-punishment/"&gt;Trucking industry vet calls Illinois toll hike needless punishment&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 11:00:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Illinois politicians still want boosted tax power</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/illinois-politicians-still-want-boosted-tax-power/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Illinois Constitution stops politicians from imposing progressive taxation, which would give them power to progressively tax everyone more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/illinois-politicians-still-want-boosted-tax-power/"&gt;Illinois politicians still want boosted tax power&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 11:00:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] How accountable are North Carolina public schools, really — Part 2</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/how-accountable-are-north-carolina-public-schools-really-part-2/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This series tests North Carolina public schools using education scholar Mike McShane’s three-pronged approach to accountability: financial, democratic, and educational. The first part found that North Carolina public schools lacked financial accountability. This part finds that public schools also lack democratic and educational accountability. What keeps public schools from being democratically accountable McShane explains that...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/how-accountable-are-north-carolina-public-schools-really-part-2/"&gt;How accountable are North Carolina public schools, really — Part 2&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Rochester Schools Trustee Sues to Protect Her Right to Speak with Constituents</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/pressroom/2026/rochester-schools-trustee-sues-to-protect-her-right-to-speak-with-constituents</link><description>Mackinac Center files legal challenge targeting secrecy policies</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 13:42:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Property Taxes at a Breaking Point as New Revolt Takes Shape</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/property-taxes-at-a-breaking-point-as-new-revolt-takes-shape/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Property Taxes at a Breaking Point as New Revolt Takes Shape" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/american-revolution-drummers.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tax revolts are a recurring feature of American history, from the founding era through Proposition 13 in the 1970s, and the Tea Party movement, each reshaping tax policy and political priorities in its time. Today, property taxes are again reaching a breaking point, with taxpayers nationwide demanding relief and states pursuing widely different strategies—from caps and assessment limits to outright elimination proposals. The most durable reforms focus on limiting government spending, recognizing that rising property taxes are driven less by valuations than by local spending growth, and that lasting relief requires rethinking the size and scope of government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/property-taxes-at-a-breaking-point-as-new-revolt-takes-shape/"&gt;Property Taxes at a Breaking Point as New Revolt Takes Shape&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 13:46:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Wyoming can lead on portable benefits — A new path for workers and businesses</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/post/wyoming-can-lead-on-portable-benefits-a-new-path-for-workers-and-businesses</link><description>Wyoming just took an important step toward modernizing how work and benefits fit together. Lawmakers have introduced Senate File 41, a bill that would authorize the creation and use of portable benefit accounts for independent contractors—accounts that can pay for benefits like health insurance and retirement, without affecting a worker’s classification.</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 14:51:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Arizona Moves to Permanently End DEI Through Constitutional Reform</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/arizona-moves-to-permanently-end-dei-through-constitutional-reform/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Arizona lawmakers are advancing what will be the strongest state-level safeguard in the country against race-based “diversity, equity, and inclusion”..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/arizona-moves-to-permanently-end-dei-through-constitutional-reform/"&gt;Arizona Moves to Permanently End DEI Through Constitutional Reform&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 15:53:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Age Verification Isn’t Parenting</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/age-verification-isnt-parenting/</link><description>Kansas lawmakers are weighing a proposal that would require new age-verification measures for online platforms, part of a growing national effort to address concerns about children’s safety in digital spaces. The goal is understandable. Parents across Kansas want their kids protected online. The harder question is how far government should go—and whether mandates aimed at [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 16:00:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Mass resignations from U.S. Attorney’s Office will hinder the fight against fraud in Minnesota</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/mass-resignations-from-u-s-attorneys-office-will-hinder-the-fight-against-fraud-in-minnesota/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In mid-January, U.S. Attorney Joe Thompson, who had been leading the legal fight against fraud in Minnesota, resigned along with a number of his colleagues. This was a hard blow to Minnesota&amp;#8217;s taxpayers, who have been fleeced of billions of dollars under an administration which is, at beast, uninterested in the issue. Sadly, in a...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/mass-resignations-from-u-s-attorneys-office-will-hinder-the-fight-against-fraud-in-minnesota/"&gt;Mass resignations from U.S. Attorney&amp;#8217;s Office will hinder the fight against fraud in Minnesota&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 16:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] What’s the Deal with the Tax Subsidies for Youth Sports Centers?</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/article/corporate-welfare/whats-the-deal-with-the-tax-subsidies-for-youth-sports-centers/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Yes, you are supposed to read the title like Jerry Seinfeld doing a bit. (I met Keith Hernandez at an event in St. Louis recently, so obviously Seinfeld is on [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/article/corporate-welfare/whats-the-deal-with-the-tax-subsidies-for-youth-sports-centers/"&gt;What’s the Deal with the Tax Subsidies for Youth Sports Centers?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 17:33:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Online databse would give public access to budget expenditures</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/02/online-databse-would-give-public-access-to-budget-expenditures/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Honolulu City Council Committee on Budget on Feb. 3, 2026._____________ Feb. 3, 2026, 9 a.m.Honolulu Hale To: Honolulu City Council Committee on Budget&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Val Okimoto, Chair&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Scott Nishimoto, Vice Chair From: Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Ted Kefalas, Director of Strategic [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/02/online-databse-would-give-public-access-to-budget-expenditures/"&gt;Online databse would give public access to budget expenditures&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 17:46:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Texas A&amp;M is Right to End Women and Gender Studies</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/texas-am-is-right-to-end-women-and-gender-studies/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Some professors at Texas A&amp;#38;M have issued a letter expressing outrage over the recent decision to eliminate the women’s and gender studies degree programs. Revving up the dramatics, faculty who run the program warn that the university is dismantling this degree track at a “moment of incendiary dispute across cultural, social, and political difference on...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/texas-am-is-right-to-end-women-and-gender-studies/"&gt;Texas A&amp;amp;M is Right to End Women and Gender Studies&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 17:51:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] To the Missouri House Elementary and Secondary Education Committee: We Have a Problem</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/article/education/to-the-missouri-house-elementary-and-secondary-education-committee-we-have-a-problem/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I attended the Missouri House Elementary and Secondary Education Committee hearing on Wednesday, January 28. The hearing covered two bills under current consideration—one on A–F letter grades for schools, and [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/article/education/to-the-missouri-house-elementary-and-secondary-education-committee-we-have-a-problem/"&gt;To the Missouri House Elementary and Secondary Education Committee: We Have a Problem&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 17:54:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] A new administrative hurdle for school districts: Paid Family and Medical Leave</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/a-new-administrative-hurdle-for-school-districts-paid-medical-and-family-leave/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As school districts across Minnesota continue to grapple with the logistic and financial challenges of the state government&amp;#8217;s many (80+) unfunded mandates, a new hurdle has arisen for districts: navigating Minnesota&amp;#8217;s new paid medical and family leave policy. The policy, passed in 2023 and effective this January, mandates that employers provide employees with up to...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/a-new-administrative-hurdle-for-school-districts-paid-medical-and-family-leave/"&gt;A new administrative hurdle for school districts: Paid Family and Medical Leave&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 17:58:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Dr. John Dixon: Charter Schools, Choice, and Accountability</title><link>https://empowerms.org/dr-john-dixon-charter-schools-choice-and-accountability/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Dr. John Dixon: Charter Schools, Choice, and Accountability As the 2026 legislative session moves forward, the conversation around school choice continues to intensify. While much of the focus has been on ESAs and public school transfers, one form of public school choice has quietly served thousands of Mississippi families for years: public charter schools. In&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/dr-john-dixon-charter-schools-choice-and-accountability/"&gt;Dr. John Dixon: Charter Schools, Choice, and Accountability&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 18:41:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] In the rush to hold insurers to account, don’t forget about hospitals</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/in-the-rush-to-hold-insurers-to-account-dont-forget-about-hospitals/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When asked to account for the skyrocketing cost of health coverage before two House committees last Thursday, the chief executives of five of America’s largest health insurance companies pointed fingers. Don’t look at us, they said. Look at hospitals and drugmakers. Read the op-ed here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/in-the-rush-to-hold-insurers-to-account-dont-forget-about-hospitals/"&gt;In the rush to hold insurers to account, don’t forget about hospitals&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 19:10:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] The TIF that Keeps Taking</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/article/corporate-welfare/the-tif-that-keeps-taking/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Thomas Friestad at the Kansas City Business Journal wrote recently that an engineering firm (Gannett Fleming TranSystems, formerly GFT) is moving its offices to the H&amp;#38;R Block building in downtown [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/article/corporate-welfare/the-tif-that-keeps-taking/"&gt;The TIF that Keeps Taking&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 19:16:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Apply sunshine law to government contractors</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/02/apply-sunshine-law-to-government-contractors/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Senate Committee on Government Operations on Feb. 3, 2026._____________ Feb. 3, 2026, 3 p.m.Hawaii State CapitolConference Room 225 and Videoconference To: Senate Committee on Government Operations&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Sen. Angus L.K. McKelvey, Chair&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Sen. Mike Gabbard, Vice-Chair From: Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/02/apply-sunshine-law-to-government-contractors/"&gt;Apply sunshine law to government contractors&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 19:21:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Prohibit nepotism regarding state contracts</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/02/prohibit-nepotism-regarding-state-contracts/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the House Committee on Judiciary &amp;#38; Hawaiian Affairs on Feb. 3, 2026._____________ Feb. 3, 2026, 2 p.m.Hawaii State CapitolConference Room 325 and Videoconference To: House Committee on Judiciary &amp;#38; Hawaiian Affairs       Rep. David A. Tarnas, Chair       Rep. Mahina Poepoe, Vice-Chair From: [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/02/prohibit-nepotism-regarding-state-contracts/"&gt;Prohibit nepotism regarding state contracts&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 19:24:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Dr. Oz Pulls Back the Curtain on MN Fraud</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/dr-oz-pulls-back-the-curtain-on-mn-fraud/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Grace and Kathryn sit down to catch you up on all the latest legal drama here in Minnesota. First, a judge orders the release of an illegal immigrant, and his 5-year-old son, after the man abandoned the child while fleeing from ICE. And, Keith Ellison suffers a loss in court as he attempts to block...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/dr-oz-pulls-back-the-curtain-on-mn-fraud/"&gt;Dr. Oz Pulls Back the Curtain on MN Fraud&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 20:03:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] A State of the State Built on “You’re Welcome”</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/a-state-of-the-state-built-on-youre-welcome/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Last week Governor Janet Mills delivered her final State of the State address. The hour-long speech was heavy on reflection and self-congratulation. Again and again, the Governor reminded Mainers, sometimes explicitly, that we should be thanking her for her governance. But self gratitude is not a governing philosophy. And after seven years in office, Mainers [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/a-state-of-the-state-built-on-youre-welcome/"&gt;A State of the State Built on “You’re Welcome”&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 20:59:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] Report: DPI spent $369K on standard-setting event at Wisconsin Dells resort</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/report-dpi-spent-369k-on-standard-setting-event-at-wisconsin-dells-resort/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Report: DPI spent $369K on stardard-setting event at Wisconsin Dells resort (The Center Square) – Wisconsin’s Department of Public Instruction spent $368,885 to hold a four-day standard setting event in June 2024 at a Wisconsin Dells waterpark, according to a new report. The event included 88 expert educators who were subject to non-disclosure agreements related [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/report-dpi-spent-369k-on-standard-setting-event-at-wisconsin-dells-resort/"&gt;Report: DPI spent $369K on standard-setting event at Wisconsin Dells resort&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 22:08:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] Delayed DPI Records Reveal Taxpayers Soaked with $368K Water Park Resort Bill to Weaken State Exam Standards</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/delayed-dpi-records-reveal-taxpayers-soaked-with-368k-water-park-resort-bill-to-weaken-state-exam-standards/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Delayed DPI Records Reveal Taxpayers Soaked with $368K Water Park Resort Bill to Weaken State Exam Standards By Brian Fraley, Dairyland Sentinel Publisher More than a year after the Dairyland Sentinel first sought public records regarding the overhaul of Wisconsin’s student performance benchmarks, the Department of Public Instruction has finally released another handful of internal documents. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/delayed-dpi-records-reveal-taxpayers-soaked-with-368k-water-park-resort-bill-to-weaken-state-exam-standards/"&gt;Delayed DPI Records Reveal Taxpayers Soaked with $368K Water Park Resort Bill to Weaken State Exam Standards&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 22:11:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Supermajority Solutions for Texas Taxpayers</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/supermajority-solutions-for-texas-taxpayers/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Texas bond elections often pass with low voter turnout and simple majorities, driving up local debt as a result. Raising voter approval thresholds could protect taxpayers and ensure a stronger consensus for public spending. Key points: Even though tax relief has been funded at the state level, increased debt at the local level has led...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/supermajority-solutions-for-texas-taxpayers/"&gt;Supermajority Solutions for Texas Taxpayers&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 22:52:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] Alabama school choice debate collides with football: How popular is the CHOOSE Act?</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2026/02/04/alabama-school-choice-debate-collides-with-football-how-popular-is-the-choose-act/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Alabama leaders spent the last week showcasing students who use publicly-funded vouchers to attend private schools and urging lawmakers to pour millions more into the program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2026/02/04/alabama-school-choice-debate-collides-with-football-how-popular-is-the-choose-act/"&gt;Alabama school choice debate collides with football: How popular is the CHOOSE Act?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 00:18:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Conservatism Past, Present and Future with Charles Kesler, Matt Continetti and Steven Hayward</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/conservatism-past-present-and-future-with-charles-kesler-matt-continetti-and-steven-hayward/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This week, we present a special recording of PRI&amp;#8217;s recent America 250 kickoff event in Los Angeles featuring a discussion of conservatism past, present, and future as we mark the semiquincentennial of the United States.  Offering perspective are Claremont Review of Books editor Charles Kesler, Matt Continetti of the American Enterprise Institute, and PRI senior fellow [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/conservatism-past-present-and-future-with-charles-kesler-matt-continetti-and-steven-hayward/"&gt;Conservatism Past, Present and Future with Charles Kesler, Matt Continetti and Steven Hayward&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 01:04:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] House Bill 563 — Certified public accountants (+1)</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/house-bill-563-certified-public-accountants/</link><description>Bill Description:&amp;#160;House Bill 563 would recognize more education pathways to become a Certified Public Accountant and make it simpler for accountants to work across state lines.&amp;#160; Rating: +1 Does it increase barriers to entry into the market? Examples include occupational licensure, the minimum wage, and restrictions on home businesses. Conversely, does it remove barriers to [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 01:04:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] House Bill 569 — Water skiing, towing (0)</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/house-bill-569-water-skiing-towing/</link><description>Bill Description:&amp;#160;House Bill 569 would amend and add to the state’s regulation of water skiing.&amp;#160; Rating: 0 Does it give government any new, additional, or expanded power to prohibit, restrict, or regulate activities in the free market? Conversely, does it eliminate or reduce government intervention in the market? Idaho law imposes a number of regulations [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 01:06:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Senate Bill 1241 — Protection of working animals (+1)</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/senate-bill-1241-protection-of-working-animals/</link><description>Bill Description:&amp;#160;Senate Bill 1241 would create a state preemption statute to protect the use of working animals from local regulation.&amp;#160; Rating: +1 Does it give government any new, additional, or expanded power to prohibit, restrict, or regulate activities in the free market? Conversely, does it eliminate or reduce government intervention in the market? Senate Bill [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 01:10:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG Oversight Leads to Lawmakers Pausing $1,000,000 for DPI</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-oversight-leads-to-lawmakers-pausing-1000000-for-dpi/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For Immediate Release:  February 3, 2026 Contact: Press@ReformingGoverment.org &amp;#160; IRG Oversight Leads to Lawmakers Pausing $1,000,000 for DPI  &amp;#160; Delafield, Wis. – Last week, the Institute for Reforming Government sent a demand letter to help the Dairyland Sentinel seek closure on a year-old public records request filed with the Department of Public Instruction.  Monday, DPI [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-oversight-leads-to-lawmakers-pausing-1000000-for-dpi/"&gt;IRG Oversight Leads to Lawmakers Pausing $1,000,000 for DPI&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 02:14:38 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>