<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>State-Policy Think-Tank Digest</title><link>https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml</link><description>Latest posts from free-market policy institutes across the U.S.</description><atom:link href="https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 01:31:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] WATCH: Megan Martin on PCN Discussing State Budget, Mass Transit Bail-out, and More</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/07/01/watch-megan-martin-on-pcn-discussing-state-budget-mass-transit-bail-out-and-more/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Megan Martin, Commonwealth Foundation&amp;#8217;s Chief Operating Officer and General Counsel, joins PCN&amp;#8217;s Capitol Preview to talk all things state budget. From public transit to Lifeline Scholarships, Martin outlines what good looks like in this year&amp;#8217;s budget, and which proposals will damage Pennsylvania&amp;#8217;s economic future. Watch below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/07/01/watch-megan-martin-on-pcn-discussing-state-budget-mass-transit-bail-out-and-more/"&gt;WATCH: Megan Martin on PCN Discussing State Budget, Mass Transit Bail-out, and More&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 13:27:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Welfare stands in the way of the American dream</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/welfare-stands-in-the-way-of-the-american-dream/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Meaningful relationships and a strong sense of community are as much a part of the American dream as any economic measure. What’s rarely discussed is how systemic obstacles are undermining these important aspects of a flourishing life. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/welfare-stands-in-the-way-of-the-american-dream/"&gt;Welfare stands in the way of the American dream&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 18:55:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] OBBB Delivers Historic Expansion of Educational Choice, Sweeping Reforms</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/07/03/obbb-delivers-historic-expansion-of-educational-choice-sweeping-reforms/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Harrisburg, Pa., July 3, 2025 —&amp;#160;After much anticipation and debate, the One Big, Beautiful Bill (OBBB) is now passed and set to be enacted—delivering policy accomplishments that Pennsylvanians can celebrate: Protecting Taxpayers: Preventing an average $2,500 tax hike per Pennsylvania taxpayer. Nearly every Pennsylvanian has benefited from the 2017 Tax Cuts and Job Act, which [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/07/03/obbb-delivers-historic-expansion-of-educational-choice-sweeping-reforms/"&gt;OBBB Delivers Historic Expansion of Educational Choice, Sweeping Reforms&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 19:17:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Are we witnessing a Baltimore Miracle in the fight against crime?</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/baltimore-miracle-in-fight-against-crime/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Baltimore has struggled with crime, especially drugs and violent crime, in both reality and in the imaginations of the American people for decades. That is, until recently. What changed and what can other high-crime cities learn from Baltimore's approach? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/baltimore-miracle-in-fight-against-crime/"&gt;Are we witnessing a Baltimore Miracle in the fight against crime?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 19:33:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] 97 NYSLRS Retirees Eligible for Pensions Over $200K in FY2025</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/97-nyslrs-retirees-eligible-for-pensions-over-200k-in-fy2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A total of 97 retirees from the New York State and Local Retirement System (NYSLRS) were eligible for pensions of....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/97-nyslrs-retirees-eligible-for-pensions-over-200k-in-fy2025/"&gt;97 NYSLRS Retirees Eligible for Pensions Over $200K in FY2025&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 13:50:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Frontierinstitute] Montana Leading with Free Market Healthcare</title><link>https://frontierinstitute.org/montana-leading-with-free-market-healthcare/</link><description>By eliminating the middlemen and bureaucracy involved in billing third parties, DPC providers are able to save patients money and focus on their health while also being radically transparent with their prices – a breath of fresh air in today’s modern healthcare world.</description><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 18:26:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Dr. Keri Ingraham: Industry-Specific High Schools</title><link>https://empowerms.org/dr-keri-ingraham-industry-specific-high-schools/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Dr. Keri Ingraham: Industry-Specific High Schools Join us on the Empower Podcast as we dive into the transformative world of industry-specific high schools with Dr. Keri Ingraham, whose recent policy brief at the American Enterprise Institute, “The Case for Industry-Specific High Schools,” is sparking conversation. In this episode, Dr. Ingraham explains why these specialized schools&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/dr-keri-ingraham-industry-specific-high-schools/"&gt;Dr. Keri Ingraham: Industry-Specific High Schools&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 01:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] Tim Walz Leaves Minnesotans on the Hook for a $430,000 Legal Bill</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/tim-walz-leaves-minnesotans-on-the-hook-for-a-430000-legal-bill/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Minnesota Gov. Tim Walz already has taxpayer-funded legal counsel. Additionally, he has access to the Attorney General&amp;#8217;s office. Yet, Minnesota taxpayers are now left to foot a $430,000 legal bill from outside lawyers that Walz racked up trying to prepare for a congressional hearing where he provided testimony on his Sanctuary City illegal immigration policies. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/tim-walz-leaves-minnesotans-on-the-hook-for-a-430000-legal-bill/"&gt;Tim Walz Leaves Minnesotans on the Hook for a $430,000 Legal Bill&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 19:22:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] What the “One Big Beautiful Bill Act” Means for School Choice in Mississippi</title><link>https://empowerms.org/what-the-one-big-beautiful-bill-act-means-for-school-choice-in-mississippi/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;There are two aspects to the school choice provisions in the OBBB: a tax credit for contributions to organizations that provide scholarships to students in public or private schools, and rules those organizations have to follow in granting scholarships (including eligibility of scholarship students).  Tax Credit for Contributions  Starting in 2027, an individual taxpayer (not&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/what-the-one-big-beautiful-bill-act-means-for-school-choice-in-mississippi/"&gt;What the “One Big Beautiful Bill Act” Means for School Choice in Mississippi&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 21:47:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] NJ SPOTLIGHT: Marathon school segregation case goes to appeals court</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/07/nj-spotlight-marathon-school-segregation-case-goes-to-appeals-court/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In this NJ Spotlight News piece, the long-running New Jersey school segregation case moves to the Appellate Division. As the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/07/nj-spotlight-marathon-school-segregation-case-goes-to-appeals-court/"&gt;NJ SPOTLIGHT: Marathon school segregation case goes to appeals court&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 15:56:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] NORTHJERSEY.COM: Appeals court to hear arguments in NJ school segregation lawsuit</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/07/northjersey-com-appeals-court-to-hear-arguments-in-nj-school-segregation-lawsuit/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In this NorthJersey.com article, the New Jersey appellate court prepares to hear arguments in the high‑profile school segregation lawsuit filed [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/07/northjersey-com-appeals-court-to-hear-arguments-in-nj-school-segregation-lawsuit/"&gt;NORTHJERSEY.COM: Appeals court to hear arguments in NJ school segregation lawsuit&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 16:00:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] Congressional Republicans Call Out Walz’s ‘Wasted Taxpayer Money’</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/congressional-republicans-call-out-walzs-wasted-taxpayer-money/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Minnesota Republicans criticized the use of taxpayer funds for the legal counsel, with U.S. House Majority Whip Tom Emmer calling the governor a “scam artist” and Rep. Pete Stauber saying, “more wasted taxpayer money by the ‘knucklehead.’” It&amp;#8217;s extremely disappointing that the governor felt the need to burn nearly half a million dollars of taxpayer [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/congressional-republicans-call-out-walzs-wasted-taxpayer-money/"&gt;Congressional Republicans Call Out Walz&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8216;Wasted Taxpayer Money&amp;#8217;&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 18:39:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] Albuquerque Mayoral Candidate Eddie Varela completes RGF candidate survey</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/albuquerque-mayoral-candidate-eddie-varela-completes-rgf-candidate-survey/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In its ongoing efforts to ensure that voters are fully informed about the views and plans of the various candidates for Albuquerque Mayor. The latest candidate to respond is Eddie Varela. His survey can be found here. Varela&amp;#8217;s campaign website can be accessed here. You can also see images of Varela&amp;#8217;s survey answers below: &amp;#160; [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/albuquerque-mayoral-candidate-eddie-varela-completes-rgf-candidate-survey/"&gt;Albuquerque Mayoral Candidate Eddie Varela completes RGF candidate survey&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 22:32:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] Sec. Simon Should Hop Off the Ranked-Choice Voting Train</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/sec-simon-should-hop-off-the-ranked-choice-voting-train/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Ranked-Choice Voting must be rejected when it presents itself in Minnesota. Our republic deserves no less than our willingness to educate voters about this failed voting system and to resist misguided efforts like Sec. Simons who wants to expand this radical scheme to all Minnesota cities and counties. &amp;#8212; Secretary of State backs legislation to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/sec-simon-should-hop-off-the-ranked-choice-voting-train/"&gt;Sec. Simon Should Hop Off the Ranked-Choice Voting Train&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 13:13:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Average Pay at Port Authority Surges as 11 Employees Collect $400k+</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/average-pay-at-panynj-surges-as-11-employees-collect-400k/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Eleven Port Authority of New York and New Jersey (PANYNJ) employees collected more than $400,000 each in total pay last....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/average-pay-at-panynj-surges-as-11-employees-collect-400k/"&gt;Average Pay at Port Authority Surges as 11 Employees Collect $400k+&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 15:40:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Frontierinstitute] Mike Mansfield and the Japanese</title><link>https://frontierinstitute.org/mike-mansfield-and-the-japanese/</link><description>"In 1988, on behalf of America and with Mike Mansfield’s support, President Ronald Reagan formally apologized for the internments and publicly admitted they were not justified."</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 17:43:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Mississippi’s Moment: Bold Reforms to Drive Growth</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/mississippis-moment-bold-reforms-to-drive-growth/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Mississippi is shedding its image as an economic laggard. Over the past five years, the state’s economic output has grown more than it did over the previous fifteen years combined. According to the U.S. Bureau of Economic Analysis, Mississippi posted the second-fastest per capita GDP growth and fifth-fastest personal income growth among all states in [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/mississippis-moment-bold-reforms-to-drive-growth/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi’s Moment: Bold Reforms to Drive Growth&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 17:49:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] PA House Democrats Pass Unbalanced, Reckless Spending Bill</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/07/14/pa-house-democrats-pass-unbalanced-reckless-spending-bill/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Harrisburg, Pa., July 14, 2025 — Today, Pennsylvania House Democrats passed the General Appropriations Act (HB 1330), their version of a budget bill, which includes a $2.9 billion spending increase. The bill would increase general fund spending to $50.6 billion—exacerbating Pennsylvania’s structural deficit, by spending $5.3 billion more than revenue. Lawmakers would need to drain [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/07/14/pa-house-democrats-pass-unbalanced-reckless-spending-bill/"&gt;PA House Democrats Pass Unbalanced, Reckless Spending Bill&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 21:52:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Kansas Taxpayers Still Waiting: Budget Bloat Blocks Relief Despite Strong Revenues</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/kansas-budget-bloat-despite-strong-revenues/</link><description>Kansas recently reported better-than-expected tax receipts—$248 million above projections—for the fiscal year ending June 30, 2025. Yet despite this encouraging news, Kansans won’t be seeing tax cuts anytime soon. Why? Because government spending continues to outpace sustainable levels, and the state’s new automatic tax reduction law has built-in roadblocks that delay relief even when taxpayers [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 14:00:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/07/the-outstater-278/</link><description>Islamists, Welcome? &amp;#8220;Islamism is a totalitarian ideology that seeks to impose a rigid, theocratic order, incompatible with the pluralistic values of Western civilization.” — Ayaan Hirsi Ali, Somali-born author and activist for women’s rights.&amp;#160; THE DEGRADING&amp;#160;EFFECTS&amp;#160;are&amp;#160;inarguable in&amp;#160;a half dozen U.S. cities, not to mention in the great cultural centers&amp;#160;of&amp;#160;Great Britain and Europe. So why are&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/07/the-outstater-278/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 17:10:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] NJ ED REPORT: Is Murphy Stalling the Segregation Lawsuit? What Would His Successor Do?</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/07/nj-ed-report-is-murphy-stalling-the-segregation-lawsuit-what-would-his-successor-do/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A new NJ Education Report article covers a high-stakes lawsuit accusing the Murphy administration of stalling efforts to fix New [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/07/nj-ed-report-is-murphy-stalling-the-segregation-lawsuit-what-would-his-successor-do/"&gt;NJ ED REPORT: Is Murphy Stalling the Segregation Lawsuit? What Would His Successor Do?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 18:36:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] One Big Beautiful Bill and Nebraska’s Fiscal Response</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/one-big-beautiful-bill-and-nebraskas-fiscal-response/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The One Big Beautiful Bill introduces sweeping changes to federal fiscal policy that will have tangible impacts on the state of Nebraska. Policymakers must choose which provisions to adopt of the federal law and which to defer. These decisions will have significant budgetary and growth implications for Nebraska.   On the tax side, the OBBB makes...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/one-big-beautiful-bill-and-nebraskas-fiscal-response/" rel="nofollow"&gt;One Big Beautiful Bill and Nebraska’s Fiscal Response&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 13:58:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] TriMet’s Plan for 82nd Avenue “Road Diet” Looms in Metro Decision</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/transportation/trimets-plan-for-82nd-avenue-road-diet-looms-in-metro-decision/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Maxwell Powers TriMet has a new “road diet” planned for Portland, this...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/transportation/trimets-plan-for-82nd-avenue-road-diet-looms-in-metro-decision/"&gt;TriMet’s Plan for 82nd Avenue “Road Diet” Looms in Metro Decision&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 14:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG Announces Chief Operating Officer</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-announces-chief-operating-officer/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;THE NEWS The Institute for Reforming Government (IRG) has promoted Chris Reader to Chief Operating Officer. In this expanded role, Chris will manage the day-to-day operations of IRG, overseeing its team and project portfolio. Reader has also been named the Executive Director of IRG Action Fund, IRG’s 501(C)(4) advocacy partner.   THE QUOTE CJ Szafir, IRG, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-announces-chief-operating-officer/"&gt;IRG Announces Chief Operating Officer&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 15:54:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] NEW: “School Dashboard” Provides Comprehensive District Data to Wisconsin Families</title><link>https://will-law.org/new-school-dashboard-provides-comprehensive-district-data-to-wisconsin-families/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL released its 2025 School Scorecard Dashboard with new features and data sets to better equip parents, education stakeholders, and taxpayers with insight on how school districts across the state are performing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/new-school-dashboard-provides-comprehensive-district-data-to-wisconsin-families/"&gt;NEW: “School Dashboard” Provides Comprehensive District Data to Wisconsin Families&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 14:28:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] Albuquerque Mayoral Candidate Darren White completes RGF Mayoral candidate survey</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/albuquerque-mayoral-candidate-darren-white-completes-rgf-mayoral-candidate-survey/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce that Albuquerque mayoral candidate (former Bernalillo County Sheriff and former Secretary of the New Mexico Department of Public Safety) Darren White, has completed and submitted the Rio Grande Foundation&amp;#8217;s mayoral candidate survey. You can find that survey embedded below and linked to here.  You can also find White&amp;#8217;s campaign website here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/albuquerque-mayoral-candidate-darren-white-completes-rgf-mayoral-candidate-survey/"&gt;Albuquerque Mayoral Candidate Darren White completes RGF Mayoral candidate survey&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 16:16:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Wisconsin Bar Association Eliminates Race-Based DEI in Settlement with WILL</title><link>https://will-law.org/wisconsin-bar-association-eliminates-race-based-dei-in-settlement-with-will/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The State Bar of Wisconsin has agreed to settle a federal lawsuit and remove harmful and discriminatory “diversity, equity, and inclusion,” or DEI, from its program. The Bar also agreed to change its definition of diversity and will no longer consider race, religion, sex, or other characteristics when determining eligibility for its programs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/wisconsin-bar-association-eliminates-race-based-dei-in-settlement-with-will/"&gt;Wisconsin Bar Association Eliminates Race-Based DEI in Settlement with WILL&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 16:55:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] A Warning for New York’s Energy Policy</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/a-warning-for-new-yorks-energy-policy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On June 24th New York’s electricity grid nearly blew a fuse. That day was extremely hot, and air conditioning was....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/a-warning-for-new-yorks-energy-policy/"&gt;A Warning for New York’s Energy Policy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 17:50:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Supreme Court gives governor’s bureaucrats free rein</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/supreme-court-gives-governors-bureaucrats-free-rein/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A state Supreme Court decision wresting rulemaking authority from elected state representatives has opened the door to a barrage of new regulations and fees in Wisconsin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/supreme-court-gives-governors-bureaucrats-free-rein/"&gt;Supreme Court gives governor’s bureaucrats free rein&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 21:38:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Job Licensing Reviews: Education Committee</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/job-licensing-reviews-education-committee/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Occupational Board Reform Act (OBRA) was passed in 2018 and became effective in 2019. It requires legislative committees of jurisdiction to review all occupational licenses in the state, roughly 20% per year, on a five-year rotation. These reviews examine whether the licensing requirements are adequate or excessive by current standards. The committees then submit...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/job-licensing-reviews-education-committee/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Job Licensing Reviews: Education Committee&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 16:59:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] Parents: Ask Your District How They Will Comply</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/07/18/parents-ask-your-district-how-they-will-comply/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A momentous parental rights victory was handed down by the United States Supreme Court on Friday, June 27, 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/07/18/parents-ask-your-district-how-they-will-comply/"&gt;Parents: Ask Your District How They Will Comply&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 17:45:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Boise’s FY26 Budget: A Betrayal of Taxpayer Trust</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/boises-fy26-budget-a-betrayal-of-taxpayer-trust/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/boises-fy26-budget-a-betrayal-of-taxpayer-trust/" rel="nofollow" title="Boise’s FY26 Budget: A Betrayal of Taxpayer Trust"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Cream-Neutral-Minimalist-New-Business-Pitch-Deck-Presentation-1.jpg" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;On July 15, 2025, the Boise City Council approved the FY26 budget, which included a 7.6% property tax increase — ignoring the financial strain on residents. As one of the few voices opposing this budget, I’m dismayed by the council’s disregard for taxpayers and the chorus of speakers who showered praise on the council, mayor, [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 19:19:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Do advocates for total government dependency have any limiting principles?</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/07/do-advocates-for-total-government-dependency-have-any-limiting-principles/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;“I find more and more that dependency from [upon] the will of others is always some diminution of human happiness, principally to a man accustom’d to follow his own will uncontrolled.”  &amp;#8211; Jan Ingenhousz to Ben Franklin, 1777 &amp;#160; During the two weeks since Americans celebrated the 249th anniversary of the Declaration of Independence, political [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/07/do-advocates-for-total-government-dependency-have-any-limiting-principles/"&gt;Do advocates for total government dependency have any limiting principles?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 19:45:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Ed Feulner (1941-2025): A National Leader with a Virginian Heart</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/ed-feulner-1941-2025-a-national-leader-with-a-virginian-heart/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="450" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Ed-Feulner-white.jpg" width="900" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the spring of 1971, the U.S. Senate was set to debate and vote on continued government support of the supersonic transport (SST), with most conservatives opposing taxpayer funding in favor of private sector support. A few days after the vote, a well-researched study from an old-line “think tank” landed in Senators’ offices. Why hadn’t it [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/ed-feulner-1941-2025-a-national-leader-with-a-virginian-heart/"&gt;Ed Feulner (1941-2025): A National Leader with a Virginian Heart&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 16:16:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Panasonic’s EV Gamble Isn’t Capitalism—It’s Corporate Welfare</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/panasonics-ev-gamble-is-corporate-welfare/</link><description>Kansas just got played. Again. Panasonic’s $4 billion EV battery plant in De Soto—touted as the state’s biggest economic development deal ever—is now delayed. Why? Because the federal government finally decided to stop propping up the electric vehicle market with taxpayer cash. President Trump’s “Big, Beautiful Bill” kills the $7,500 new EV tax credit and [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 16:56:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] 10 Best Things About Mississippi</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/10-best-things-about-mississippi/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Speaking to my friends at Smith County Republicans the other day, someone asked me what I most loved about moving to Mississippi from London. There are so many things I love about the Magnolia state, the more I thought about it, the longer my answer grew.&amp;#160;&amp;#160;I thought I’d list a few of my favorite things [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/10-best-things-about-mississippi/" rel="nofollow"&gt;10 Best Things About Mississippi&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 17:38:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG Court Watch Report: Wisconsin Supreme Court Term in Review</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-court-watch-report-wisconsin-supreme-court-term-in-review/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;IRG Court Watch Report: Wisconsin Supreme Court Term in Review Court Delivers Progressive Wins in Wisconsin for the First Time in Over a Decade Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government’s (IRG) Court Watch released a report detailing the Wisconsin Supreme Court’s 2024-2025 term on Tuesday, analyzing the new path taken by the Court’s [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-court-watch-report-wisconsin-supreme-court-term-in-review/"&gt;IRG Court Watch Report: Wisconsin Supreme Court Term in Review&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 12:56:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] Franke: Hagiography or Iconoclasm?</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/07/franke-hagiography-or-iconoclasm/</link><description>by Mark Franke Someone, and I wish I could remember who, said culture was the telling to ourselves stories about ourselves. OK, but what if we have conflicting stories to tell? The assumption behind all this is that the stories are at least partially true, if not in every detail then at least in the&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/07/franke-hagiography-or-iconoclasm/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 13:01:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] BBB Is Not The Tragedy Our Politicians Portray</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/bbb-is-not-the-tragedy-our-politicians-portray/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following appeared in Eastern New Mexico News and other outlets throughout July of 2025. If you haven’t heard already, over the 4th of July weekend, President Trump signed the so-called “Big Beautiful Bill” (BBB) into law. Setting aside the merits and demerits of the legislation, you have to hand it to President Trump and Speaker Mike [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/bbb-is-not-the-tragedy-our-politicians-portray/"&gt;BBB Is Not The Tragedy Our Politicians Portray&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 17:29:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Broadband revolution: What the new federal guidelines mean for Montana and beyond</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/broadband-revolution-what-the-new-federal-guidelines-mean-for-montana-and-beyond</link><description>Public dollars should always be spent wisely and efficiently, especially on infrastructure that touches nearly every home, school, and...</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 17:51:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Lawsuit Against United Teachers of Los Angeles Dismissed, Freedom Foundation to Appeal to Ninth Circuit</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/press-release/lawsuit-against-united-teachers-of-los-angeles-dismissed-freedom-foundation-to-appeal-to-ninth-circuit/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Today, the U.S. District Court for the Central District of California ruled against the lawsuit filed by seven Jewish teachers against United Teachers of Los Angeles (UTLA). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/press-release/lawsuit-against-united-teachers-of-los-angeles-dismissed-freedom-foundation-to-appeal-to-ninth-circuit/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Lawsuit Against United Teachers of Los Angeles Dismissed, Freedom Foundation to Appeal to Ninth Circuit&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 17:58:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Research Note: Use of the Nebraska Livestock Matrix</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/research-note-use-of-the-nebraska-livestock-matrix/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Introduced in 2015, the Nebraska Livestock Matrix is a tool designed to help counties evaluate proposed livestock operations seeking conditional use or special exception permits. Created to promote consistency across county lines in the permitting process, the committee tasked with developing the matrix faced two significant challenges in aligning its objectives. First, the tool needed...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/research-note-use-of-the-nebraska-livestock-matrix/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Research Note: Use of the Nebraska Livestock Matrix&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 19:58:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] VICTORY! Court Affirms that Public School DEI Indoctrination Isn’t a Trade Secret</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/victory-court-affirms-that-public-school-dei-indoctrination-isnt-a-trade-secret/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A Pennsylvania mother won a major victory for parental rights and government transparency last week when her local school district..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/victory-court-affirms-that-public-school-dei-indoctrination-isnt-a-trade-secret/"&gt;VICTORY! Court Affirms that Public School DEI Indoctrination Isn’t a Trade Secret&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 20:01:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Former Speaker Philip Gunn: Faith, Resilience, and Leadership</title><link>https://empowerms.org/former-speaker-philip-gunn-faith-resilience-and-leadership/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;﻿ Former Speaker Philip Gunn: Faith, Resilience, and Leadership In this episode, host Grant Callen sits down with former Mississippi House Speaker Philip Gunn to trace his journey from Clinton’s small-town roots to state leadership. Gunn shares how a personal tragedy at Ole Miss Law upended his life, yet God’s faithfulness sustained him, strengthened his faith,&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/former-speaker-philip-gunn-faith-resilience-and-leadership/"&gt;Former Speaker Philip Gunn: Faith, Resilience, and Leadership&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 00:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Federal School Choice Is A Double-Edged Sword for Educational Freedom</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/education/federal-school-choice-is-a-double-edged-sword-for-educational-freedom/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The passage of the One Big Beautiful Bill and President Trump’s signature on the legislation represent a watershed moment for American education policy. Embedded within this massive tax reform package is the Educational Choice for Children Act, creating a first-of-its-kind, nationwide tax credit scholarship program that could fundamentally reshape how families access educational options across...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/education/federal-school-choice-is-a-double-edged-sword-for-educational-freedom/"&gt;Federal School Choice Is A Double-Edged Sword for Educational Freedom&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 00:27:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Union Rules: Welcome to the Hotel California</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/union-rules-welcome-to-the-hotel-california/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="630" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Unions-and-Hotel-California.jpg" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most treasured rights in America is the right to a secret ballot – the opportunity to vote in privacy, free from harassment. It’s what separates democratic societies and is a right that filters down to even our local Rotary Clubs and Chambers of Commerce. It is a right that should be guaranteed for [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/union-rules-welcome-to-the-hotel-california/"&gt;Union Rules: Welcome to the Hotel California&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 12:45:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Metro Should Reject the Burnside Bridge Road Diet</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/transportation/metro-should-reject-the-burnside-bridge-road-diet/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Connor Roberts The new “Earthquake Ready Burnside Bridge” lane designs, backed with...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/transportation/metro-should-reject-the-burnside-bridge-road-diet/"&gt;Metro Should Reject the Burnside Bridge Road Diet&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 14:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Fixing Maine’s broken budget process begins with defining ‘extraordinary occasion’</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/fixing-maines-broken-budget-process-begins-with-defining-extraordinary-occasion/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Special legislative sessions in Maine have been used to create budgets using a simple majority dating back to 2005. However, they’ve become a more apparent issue in recent sessions given that Gov. Janet Mills has declared a special session every budget cycle since 2021. With this becoming a greater problem (and occurrence) during biennial budget [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/fixing-maines-broken-budget-process-begins-with-defining-extraordinary-occasion/"&gt;Fixing Maine&amp;#8217;s broken budget process begins with defining &amp;#8216;extraordinary occasion&amp;#8217;&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 14:09:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] DFI’s Jim Blew on Federal Education Tax Credit Program</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/dfis-jim-blew-on-federal-education-tax-credit-program/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In this week’s episode of The Learning Curve, co-hosts Alisha Searcy and Dr. Cara Candal of ExcelinEd interview former assistant secretary at the U.S. Department of Education and co-founder of the Defense of Freedom Institute (DFI), Jim Blew. Mr. Blew reflects on his tenure in federal education leadership and his motivation for establishing DFI. He discusses the decades of rising federal K-12 spending through initiatives like RTTT, ESSA, and ESSER funds, instead calling for devolving federal authority out of the U.S. Department of Education, and more private school choice and charter public school innovation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/dfis-jim-blew-on-federal-education-tax-credit-program/"&gt;DFI&amp;#8217;s Jim Blew on Federal Education Tax Credit Program&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 16:00:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Frontierinstitute] Written Public Comment to SFIC 7.23.25</title><link>https://frontierinstitute.org/written-public-comment-to-sfic-7-23-25/</link><description>We believe it is a constitutional and policy imperative for Montana to implement a statewide student-centered funding formula design as the primary way to fund public education.</description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 17:29:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Federal Courts Strike Down Maine’s Unconstitutional Campaign Finance Laws</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/federal-courts-strike-down-maines-unconstitutional-campaign-finance-laws/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Two rulings were handed down against different Maine ballot initiatives in recent weeks, with federal courts finding that they both violated the First Amendment by restricting political speech. The rulings are a win for freedom of speech in Maine, as they each reaffirmed that political contributions to political action committees (PACs) cannot be hindered. Notably, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/federal-courts-strike-down-maines-unconstitutional-campaign-finance-laws/"&gt;Federal Courts Strike Down Maine’s Unconstitutional Campaign Finance Laws&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 18:11:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Missouri’s Squandered Opportunity</title><link>https://www.showmeinstitute.org/blog/budget-and-spending/missouris-squandered-opportunity/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The first step toward finding a solution is admitting there’s a problem. It’s been obvious to anyone who’s been paying [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.showmeinstitute.org/blog/budget-and-spending/missouris-squandered-opportunity/"&gt;Missouri’s Squandered Opportunity&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 18:20:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] 10/17: You’re Invited to the Goldwater Institute’s 2025 Freedom Gala</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/2025-freedom-gala/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;You’re invited to the Goldwater Institute’s 2025 Freedom Gala on October 17 at the Arizona Biltmore. This year’s Freedom Gala..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/2025-freedom-gala/"&gt;10/17: You&amp;#8217;re Invited to the Goldwater Institute&amp;#8217;s 2025 Freedom Gala&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 19:36:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Layoffs at Bloated Federal Agencies Versus the Impact of Private Sector Layoffs Caused by the Federal Government</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/layoffs-at-bloated-federal-agencies-versus-the-impact-of-private-sector-layoffs-caused-by-the-federal-government/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Layoffs.jpg" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Secretary of State Marco Rubio recently laid off 1,350 employees as part of a broader restructuring effort, the media response was swift and emotional. Stories of tearful farewells, union outrage, and dramatic claims of “fascism” filled the airwaves. One would think these federal employees had lifetime appointments and that accountability or right-sizing government were foreign [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/layoffs-at-bloated-federal-agencies-versus-the-impact-of-private-sector-layoffs-caused-by-the-federal-government/"&gt;Layoffs at Bloated Federal Agencies Versus the Impact of Private Sector Layoffs Caused by the Federal Government&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 21:03:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Statement From The James Madison Institute on the Release of the Trump Administration’s AI Action Plan</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/statement-from-the-james-madison-institute-on-the-release-of-the-trump-administrations-ai-action-plan/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE July 23, 2025 CONTACT Emma Rose Graddy 850-386-3131 Statement From The James Madison Institute on...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/statement-from-the-james-madison-institute-on-the-release-of-the-trump-administrations-ai-action-plan/"&gt;Statement From The James Madison Institute on the Release of the Trump Administration’s AI Action Plan&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 21:11:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Idaho DOGE: Misses it by That Much</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/idaho-doge-misses-it-by-that-much/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/idaho-doge-misses-it-by-that-much/" rel="nofollow" title="Idaho DOGE: Misses it by That Much"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1396" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Gemini_Generated_Image_ku2awsku2awsku2a-scaled.jpg" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="2560" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Ask any good conservative in Idaho politics, and they’ll tell you Idaho’s budgets and government growth are out of control. They’re right. Now, throw in the biggest buzzword in politics for the last six months (the start of President Trump’s return to power), “DOGE.” Of course, that’s shorthand for the Department of Government Efficiency (headed [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 22:28:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] MSPC launches the Bill &amp;#38; Milly Kay Baldwin Center for Education</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/mspc-launches-the-bill-milly-kay-baldwin-center-for-education</link><description>Mountain States Policy Center (MSPC) is proud to announce the official launch of the Bill &amp;#38; Milly Kay Baldwin Center for Education, a new research and advocacy hub focused on expanding educational opportunity and defending student-centered policy reforms throughout the Mountain West.</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 07:15:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Fitzgerald, Lummis Introduce STUDENT Act to Curb Out-of-Control NEA</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/labor/fitzgerald-lummis-introduce-student-act-to-curb-out-of-control-nea/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This week, U.S. Rep. Scott Fitzgerald (R-WI) and U.S. Sen. Cynthia Lummis (R-WY) introduced legislation to overhaul the federal charter of the National Education Association (NEA), the largest teachers union in the country, to make it more accountable and less partisan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/labor/fitzgerald-lummis-introduce-student-act-to-curb-out-of-control-nea/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Fitzgerald, Lummis Introduce STUDENT Act to Curb Out-of-Control NEA&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Over 150,000 Kansas students may be functionally illiterate, yet the adults in charge won’t take action</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/150k-kansas-students-functionally-illiterate/</link><description>The 2024 state assessment indicates that more than 150,000 Kansas students suffer from what is officially described as having a “limited ability to understand and use English language arts skills and knowledge to be academically successful for postsecondary success.”  This closely aligns with what is commonly referred to as being ‘functionally illiterate’, which  Dictionary.com defines [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 14:08:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG Announces New Leadership</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-announces-new-leadership/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;IRG Announces New Leadership Alison Prange to serve as the next Chair of the Board of Directors  THE NEWS The Board of Directors for the Institute for Reforming Government has elected Alison Prange to serve as the next Chair of the Board. Alison Prange was appointed to IRG’s Board in 2022. THE QUOTES Alison Prange, IRG [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-announces-new-leadership/"&gt;IRG Announces New Leadership&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 15:54:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] “Just Let Me Write the Definitions”</title><link>https://www.showmeinstitute.org/blog/state-and-local-government/just-let-me-write-the-definitions/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In The Power Broker, Robert Caro’s legendary biography of Robert Moses, Caro describes how Moses was fully capable of getting [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.showmeinstitute.org/blog/state-and-local-government/just-let-me-write-the-definitions/"&gt;“Just Let Me Write the Definitions”&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 17:06:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Maine Must Act to Lift Students Under New Federal Education Tax Credit Program</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/maine-must-act-to-lift-students-under-new-federal-education-tax-credit-program/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In 2025, Congress enacted the first-ever federal 1-to-1 tax credit for donations to K–12 education scholarships. While championed by President Trump, the program reflects a broader bipartisan vision: empowering families, driving educational innovation, and keeping funding decisions closer to home. But unless Maine lawmakers act swiftly, Maine families and students will miss out on the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/maine-must-act-to-lift-students-under-new-federal-education-tax-credit-program/"&gt;Maine Must Act to Lift Students Under New Federal Education Tax Credit Program&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 17:20:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Teacher Freedom Summit brings together educators anxious to cut ties with their union</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/teacher-conference/teacher-freedom-summit-brings-together-educators-anxious-to-cut-ties-with-their-union/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Despite the shocking news headlines from big unions like the American Federation of Teachers (AFT) and the National Education Association (NEA), 2025 has been a year of success and hope for America’s education system and educators alike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/teacher-conference/teacher-freedom-summit-brings-together-educators-anxious-to-cut-ties-with-their-union/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Teacher Freedom Summit brings together educators anxious to cut ties with their union&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 18:16:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] In St. Louis County, Who Will Audit the Auditors?</title><link>https://www.showmeinstitute.org/blog/transparency/in-st-louis-county-who-will-audit-the-auditors/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A version of this commentary appeared in the St. Louis Post-Dispatch. When one thinks of no-show political jobs in Missouri government, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.showmeinstitute.org/blog/transparency/in-st-louis-county-who-will-audit-the-auditors/"&gt;In St. Louis County, Who Will Audit the Auditors?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 19:34:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Housing Affordability &amp; Property Rights Webinar</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/housing-affordability-property-rights-webinar/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=housing-affordability-property-rights-webinar</link><description>Whether you're a homeowner, renter, developer, or simply concerned about rising costs, this conversation is for you.</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 20:00:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Spending drives property tax increases. A cap is the only way to stop it.</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/spending-drives-property-tax-increases-a-cap-is-the-only-way-to-stop-it/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/spending-drives-property-tax-increases-a-cap-is-the-only-way-to-stop-it/"&gt;Spending drives property tax increases. A cap is the only way to stop it.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 21:23:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] “What Does It Cost?” Film by Discovery Institute Exposes the West Coast Climate Agenda</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/economic-opportunity/what-does-it-cost-film-by-discovery-institute-exposes-the-west-coast-climate-agenda/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This summer, Cascade’s summer Research Associates reviewed a film produced by the Discovery...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/economic-opportunity/what-does-it-cost-film-by-discovery-institute-exposes-the-west-coast-climate-agenda/"&gt;“What Does It Cost?” Film by Discovery Institute Exposes the West Coast Climate Agenda&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 21:57:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Tony Evers and why voters are going to be skeptical of what comes next</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/tony-evers-and-why-voters-are-going-to-be-skeptical-of-what-comes-next/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Tony Evers has had enough and that’s not a good thing for Democrats. More Wisconsinites (48%) approve of the way he handles his job than disapprove (46%), according to the June Marquette Law School poll of registered voters. Asked if they have a favorable or unfavorable opinion of the current governor, the numbers are just [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/tony-evers-and-why-voters-are-going-to-be-skeptical-of-what-comes-next/"&gt;Tony Evers and why voters are going to be skeptical of what comes next&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 22:15:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] How the pandemic is now used to make politicians look wonderful</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/how-the-pandemic-is-now-used-to-make-politicians-look-wonderful/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Wisconsin’s tourism resurgence has been built, at least in part, by more than $160 million in federal bailout money and a record doubling of the tourism department’s budget.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/how-the-pandemic-is-now-used-to-make-politicians-look-wonderful/"&gt;How the pandemic is now used to make politicians look wonderful&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 22:16:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] California’s Experience With Compulsory Education</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/compulsory-education/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=compulsory-education</link><description>&lt;p&gt;It’s time to review our collective fascination with perpetuating mandatory government school attendance. Since the beginning of statehood, Californians have pursued education at a steep cost to produce a free society in the frontier along the Pacific Ocean. During the height of the Mexican–American War, women like Olive Mann Isbell established the first school in...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/compulsory-education/"&gt;California’s Experience With Compulsory Education&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 22:24:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Three issues Georgia parents are most concerned about</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/georgia-parent-top-concerns/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A new report on child well-being from Emory University reveals the issues that Georgia parents say are impacting kids—and their futures—most. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/georgia-parent-top-concerns/"&gt;Three issues Georgia parents are most concerned about&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 22:42:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Virginiainstitute] The State of Educational Opportunity in Virginia – A Survey of Virginia Parents</title><link>https://virginiainstitute.org/the-state-of-educational-opportunity-in-virginia-a-survey-of-virginia-parents/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=the-state-of-educational-opportunity-in-virginia-a-survey-of-virginia-parents</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 11:07:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Manchester mayoral race creates test for media</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/07/manchester-mayoral-race-creates-test-for-media/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Manchester Mayor Jay Ruais was about to become the city’s first incumbent mayor to run for reelection unopposed in 150 years when Board of School Committee member Jessica Spillers announced her candidacy on Thursday.  Spillers’ entry creates a campaign custom-made to test the credibility of New Hampshire’s media.  In her announcement, Spillers said she decided [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/07/manchester-mayoral-race-creates-test-for-media/"&gt;Manchester mayoral race creates test for media&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 11:33:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Iowa’s Back-to-School Sales Tax Holiday: A Missed Opportunity?</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/iowas-back-to-school-sales-tax-holiday-a-welcome-break-or-missed-opportunity/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Limited Scope, Misplaced Focus: Iowa’s sales tax holiday offers short-term savings on clothing but excludes essential school supplies like backpacks, notebooks, and calculators—items families actually need for back-to-school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inconsistent with Regional Trends: While Iowa clings to its sales tax holiday, most neighboring states have eliminated theirs, signaling a broader shift away from such exemptions in favor of more stable, broad-based tax systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weakens Tax Reform Efforts: The holiday erodes Iowa’s sales tax base at a time when the state is pursuing a simpler, flatter tax code on other fronts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outdated and Ineffective: Policy experts across the spectrum agree tax holidays are politically popular but economically unsound, offering more optics than impact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/iowas-back-to-school-sales-tax-holiday-a-welcome-break-or-missed-opportunity/"&gt;Iowa’s Back-to-School Sales Tax Holiday: A Missed Opportunity?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 12:42:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] As Goes AI, So Goes the Nation</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/as-goes-ai-so-goes-the-nation/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The artificial intelligence (AI) of a country, including its capabilities, growth, and the culture surrounding it, is a powerful indicator of a nation’s global standing. The technology is interwoven into all industries, from medicine to education and defense, and is a major economic driver with billions of dollars pouring into the global AI marketplace. Despite...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/as-goes-ai-so-goes-the-nation/"&gt;As Goes AI, So Goes the Nation&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 17:48:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] How strict zoning can delay development even in housing-friendly towns</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/07/how-strict-zoning-can-delay-development-even-in-housing-friendly-towns/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For a great example of the delays local land use regulations can cause for housing construction in New Hampshire, you don’t have to look to the towns where building is made the most difficult. Even in housing-friendly towns, strict regulations delay and often prevent projects. Merrimack is one of the more housing-friendly communities in the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/07/how-strict-zoning-can-delay-development-even-in-housing-friendly-towns/"&gt;How strict zoning can delay development even in housing-friendly towns&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 18:34:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Week in Review: It’s Not a Secret.</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-its-not-a-secret/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In a major win for parental rights and government transparency, the Pennsylvania Supreme Court delivered a final blow to a..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-its-not-a-secret/"&gt;Week in Review: It’s Not a Secret.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 20:16:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] A Budget at Risk: How Office Market Decline Could Undercut Boston’s Public Services</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/blog/usdatalabs/a-budget-at-risk-how-office-market-decline-could-undercut-bostons-public-services/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Researchers are predicting revenue shortfalls for the City of Boston due to the collapse in office values. Boston’s budget continues to grow, making it crucial to understand how revenue will keep up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/blog/usdatalabs/a-budget-at-risk-how-office-market-decline-could-undercut-bostons-public-services/"&gt;A Budget at Risk: How Office Market Decline Could Undercut Boston&amp;#8217;s Public Services&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 20:45:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Changes in wording would improve Maui agritourism bill</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/07/changes-in-wording-would-improve-maui-agritourism-bill/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Maui County Council on July 25, 2025._____________ July 25, 2025, 9 a.m.Kalana O Maui Building To: Maui County Council&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Alice Lee, Chair&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Yuki Lei Sugimura, Vice Chair From: Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Jonathan Helton, Policy Analyst Re: Bill 75 (2025), [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/07/changes-in-wording-would-improve-maui-agritourism-bill/"&gt;Changes in wording would improve Maui agritourism bill&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 21:05:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Hill happy governor changed mind about bills on veto list</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/07/hill-happy-governor-changed-mind-about-bills-on-veto-list/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, Hawaii benefits when the governor changes his mind. This is one of those times, according to Grassroot Institute of Hawaii’s Policy Director Malia Hill, who spoke recently with host Johnny Miro during his Sunday morning public access program on H. Hawaii Media. Specifically, Gov. Josh Green altered course when he signed a handful of [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/07/hill-happy-governor-changed-mind-about-bills-on-veto-list/"&gt;Hill happy governor changed mind about bills on veto list&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 02:57:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Tallahassee Democrat: K-12 Scholarship Students Can Help Solve Public School Budget Woes | Opinion</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/tallahassee-democrat-k-12-scholarship-students-can-help-solve-public-school-budget-woes-opinion/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;July 26, 2025 Like many public-school officials around the country, Leon County Schools Superintendent Rocky Hanna is feeling...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/tallahassee-democrat-k-12-scholarship-students-can-help-solve-public-school-budget-woes-opinion/"&gt;Tallahassee Democrat: K-12 Scholarship Students Can Help Solve Public School Budget Woes | Opinion&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 13:13:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Michigan schools should go back to basics</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/michigan-schools-should-go-back-to-basics</link><description>Fancy innovations have failed to improve student performance</description><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Illinois revenue $717M more than expected, but politicians still raise taxes</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/illinois-revenue-717m-more-than-expected-but-politicians-still-raise-taxes/</link><description>Despite record revenues, Gov. J.B. Pritzker’s 2026 budget hikes taxes by another $482 million. Illinoisans are paying 44% more than six years ago and getting higher tax burdens as thanks.</description><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 10:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Wyoming parents shouldn’t lose hope about paused education choice funds</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/wyoming-parents-shouldn-t-lose-hope-about-paused-education-choice-funds</link><description>While funds may be temporarily paused for the nearly 4,000 families approved to receive education savings account funding in Wyoming...</description><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 14:15:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Mississippi or Milei?  America’s Magnolia state is a better example of what the free market can do</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/mississippi-or-milei-americas-magnolia-state-is-a-better-example-of-what-the-free-market-can-do/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When Javier Milei burst onto the scene as a presidential candidate in Argentina in 2023, brandishing a chainsaw, many dismissed him as unhinged.&amp;#160; His radical libertarian platform was presented by the media as evidence of Argentina’s tragicomic decline. Argentina was poorer in 2023 than it had been two decades earlier. That year, the economy contracted [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/mississippi-or-milei-americas-magnolia-state-is-a-better-example-of-what-the-free-market-can-do/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi or Milei?  America’s Magnolia state is a better example of what the free market can do&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 14:52:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Will the end of the Sandisk deal bring Michigan back to basics?</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/will-the-end-of-the-sandisk-deal-bring-michigan-back-to-basics</link><description>Twelve reasons corporate welfare doesn’t lead to prosperity</description><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 18:37:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] First Principles: When the Government Takes Your Land</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/first-principles-when-the-government-takes-your-land/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=first-principles-when-the-government-takes-your-land</link><description>"They didn’t ask. They just took." Travis Lewis details the emotional toll of eminent domain and reminds us why property rights still matter.</description><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 19:32:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] The Cost to Build</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/the-cost-to-build/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The City of Austin recently released its 2025-26 Proposed Budget, which contains a, “host of questionable projects and programs,” however, an overlooked issue within the budget is the increasing in fees relating to construction permits. Some permitting fees are increasing by over 200%, while others are astronomical raises. Most notably, a 9077.2% raise on utility...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/the-cost-to-build/"&gt;The Cost to Build&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 21:18:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Baked to order: new cottage food rules</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/07/baked-to-order-new-cottage-food-rules/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Hawaii Island farmer Rourk Reagan of Pukana Lā Farms in Waiohinu wants to more easily produce and sell jams, relishes and sauces made with local ingredients. Sally Stewart of Sally Jane’s Sweets and Savories, based in Kailua-Kona on Hawaii Island, would like to expand the sales of her homemade baked goods. Mark Suiso of Makaha [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/07/baked-to-order-new-cottage-food-rules/"&gt;Baked to order: new cottage food rules&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 00:49:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] WSJ leads Hezbollah coverage with anti-Israel reporter</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/wsj-leads-hezbollah-coverage-with-anti-israel-reporter/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Chuck Ross of the Washington Free Beacon documents another instance of media malpractice. A freelance reporter who plays a leading role in the Wall Street Journal&amp;#8216;s coverage of Hezbollah has repeatedly praised the terrorist group while condemning &amp;#8220;the Israeli enemy,&amp;#8221; a Washington Free Beacon analysis has found. Adam Chamseddine, a Beirut-based reporter, has written or...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/wsj-leads-hezbollah-coverage-with-anti-israel-reporter/"&gt;WSJ leads Hezbollah coverage with anti-Israel reporter&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 09:36:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Unclassified docs show Obama’s role in Russia hoax</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/unclassified-docs-show-obamas-role-in-russia-hoax/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Margot Cleveland of the Federalist highlights the latest bad news for the 44th president. Documents released over the last month have exposed a post-election plot designed to derail President Donald Trump’s first term. The recently declassified material reveals former President Barack Obama sought to continue the Russia-collusion hoax Hillary Clinton had launched during the presidential...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/unclassified-docs-show-obamas-role-in-russia-hoax/"&gt;Unclassified docs show Obama’s role in Russia hoax&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 09:39:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Democrats, media deserve poor reviews</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/democrats-media-deserve-poor-reviews/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;David Catron writes for the American Spectator about dissatisfaction with a major political party and its chief enabler. Anyone old enough to have watched the original Star Wars film on the big screen will clearly remember the scene in which Obi-Wan Kenobi advises Luke Skywalker that the Mos Eisley settlement is “a wretched hive of...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/democrats-media-deserve-poor-reviews/"&gt;Democrats, media deserve poor reviews&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 09:42:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] 7 questions to ask about any policy proposal</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/7-questions-to-ask-about-any-policy-proposal</link><description>Every policy idea has tradeoffs</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Congress wants largest teachers union to pick kids over politics</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/congress-wants-largest-teachers-union-to-pick-kids-over-politics/</link><description>A bill in Congress would hold the National Education Association accountable, forcing it to once more put students and educators first or risk losing its special status as a chartered organization.</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 10:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] The Sirens Never Came: Rebuilding the Texas State Guard for Readiness</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/the-sirens-never-came-rebuilding-the-texas-state-guard-for-readiness/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;At 4:03 a.m. on July 4, the Guadalupe River breached its banks in Kerr County. The flood came fast and silent—crashing through windows, sweeping entire homes off their foundations, ripping families from their beds. At least 132 people are confirmed dead. Nearly 100 remain missing. The Hill Country has become a graveyard of wreckage and...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/the-sirens-never-came-rebuilding-the-texas-state-guard-for-readiness/"&gt;The Sirens Never Came: Rebuilding the Texas State Guard for Readiness&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 11:41:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Is Government Truly Limited in Louisiana?</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/legal-regulatory/is-government-truly-limited-in-louisiana/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In Louisiana and across the country, there’s a growing hunger for limited government, driven by the recognition that more government doesn’t always correlate with heightened responsiveness or better outcomes. Time and again, we’ve seen how top-down policies, bloated bureaucracy, and ever-expanding regulations stand in the way of innovation, economic opportunity, and personal freedom. Louisiana’s continued...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/legal-regulatory/is-government-truly-limited-in-louisiana/"&gt;Is Government Truly Limited in Louisiana?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 12:13:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Coalition of WI Parents Encourage Court of Appeals to Protect Young Girls at School</title><link>https://will-law.org/coalition-of-wi-parents-encourage-court-of-appeals-to-protect-young-girls-at-school/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The News: WILL filed an amicus brief in the Seventh Circuit Court of Appeals, urging it to overrule two prior cases that require schools to allow biological males who identify as transgender to access girls’ restrooms and locker rooms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/coalition-of-wi-parents-encourage-court-of-appeals-to-protect-young-girls-at-school/"&gt;Coalition of WI Parents Encourage Court of Appeals to Protect Young Girls at School&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 14:25:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Lessons from Military-Run Schools: America’s Secret Weapon in Education</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/academic-standards/lessons-from-military-run-schools-americas-secret-weapon-in-education/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Military-run schools lead every U.S. state in NAEP scores and even outperform educational juggernauts abroad—despite half of their students living at the poverty line. “Lessons from Military-Run Schools: America’s Secret Weapon in Education” argues that, rather than embracing new fads and experimental programs, American public schools ought to be studying the DoDEA playbook. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/academic-standards/lessons-from-military-run-schools-americas-secret-weapon-in-education/"&gt;Lessons from Military-Run Schools: America’s Secret Weapon in Education&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 16:26:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Governor Newsom’s Redistricting Plan Would Not Be Cheap</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/governor-newsoms-redistricting-plan-would-not-be-cheap/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=governor-newsoms-redistricting-plan-would-not-be-cheap</link><description>&lt;p&gt;redistricting will cost California about a quarter of a billion dollars at a time of budgetary stress. The bulk of the cost will come from holding a special election. This is necessary because voters previously amended the state constitution to require district lines be drawn each decade by a non-partisan commission. Newsom would need a...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/governor-newsoms-redistricting-plan-would-not-be-cheap/"&gt;Governor Newsom’s Redistricting Plan Would Not Be Cheap&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 17:58:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Texas Calls Special Session for Property Tax Relief</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/texas-calls-special-session-for-property-tax-relief/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Spending Restraint Is Key to Real Tax Relief: Both the Chicago Tribune and Texas Governor Greg Abbott agree that meaningful property tax reform must be rooted in limiting local government spending, a lesson Iowa should heed.&lt;br /&gt;
Weak Caps Undermine Reform: Iowa’s recent attempts at a 2% property tax cap were diluted by exemptions, echoing similar challenges in Texas where loopholes have allowed spending and tax burdens to keep growing.&lt;br /&gt;
Iowa Must Push Through Resistance: Unlike Illinois, Iowa is taking steps toward property tax reform, but local government resistance and prolonged stakeholder discussions continue to stall bold action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/texas-calls-special-session-for-property-tax-relief/"&gt;Texas Calls Special Session for Property Tax Relief&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 18:30:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] First Principles Series: Protecting Property Rights</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/first-principle-series-protecting-property-rights/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=first-principle-series-protecting-property-rights</link><description>The Founders understood that protections for private property must exist if the nation was to remain free.</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 18:39:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Can San Francisco Be Saved From Itself?</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/can-san-francisco-be-saved-from-itself/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=can-san-francisco-be-saved-from-itself</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Daniel Lurie’s moderate promises clash with a city drowning in ideological dysfunction. Can he deliver, or will the status quo swallow him up? A City Choking on Its Own Excess San Francisco has always fancied itself a laboratory for progressive ideas. This is a place where progressive theory gets its field test, often with little...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/can-san-francisco-be-saved-from-itself/"&gt;Can San Francisco Be Saved From Itself?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 19:20:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Vallas: Hunger strike saved school, but academic neglect starves students</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/vallas-hunger-strike-saved-school-but-academic-neglect-starves-students/</link><description>The Chicago Teachers Union’s refusal to close near-empty schools and push for more “sustainable community schools” is hurting student achievement. CTU is about adding members and escaping accountability, not about what’s best for Chicago students.</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 19:46:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] IFF Spending Index: Unmasking Idaho's Overgrown Government</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/iff-spending-index-unmasking-idahos-overgrown-government/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/iff-spending-index-unmasking-idahos-overgrown-government/" rel="nofollow" title="IFF Spending Index: Unmasking Idaho&amp;#039;s Overgrown Government"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Article-Headers-2025-07-28T181001.712.png" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Last week’s kickoff of the Idaho DOGE Task Force highlights the need to rein in Idaho’s spending growth. It’s a tall order. Since 2019, the Idaho Freedom Foundation’s Spending Index has been the only yardstick for measuring the impacts of individual agency appropriations bills. And necessarily, the votes on these bills by legislators provide the [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 19:50:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Minnesota’s Tim Walz mulls a third term while Wisconsin’s Tony Evers says “no thanks”</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/minnesotas-tim-walz-mulls-a-third-term-while-wisconsins-tony-evers-says-no-thanks/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;If he wins, Tim Walz will be the first Minnesota governor elected to a third four-year term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/minnesotas-tim-walz-mulls-a-third-term-while-wisconsins-tony-evers-says-no-thanks/"&gt;Minnesota&amp;#8217;s Tim Walz mulls a third term while Wisconsin&amp;#8217;s Tony Evers says &amp;#8220;no thanks&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 20:10:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] The Messenger Spring 2025</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/the-messenger-spring-2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;President&amp;#8217;s Message Dear Friends, What an extraordinary year it’s been for liberty in the Sunshine State. This past...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/the-messenger-spring-2025/"&gt;The Messenger Spring 2025&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 20:45:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] EPA won’t regulate GHG for vehicles and engines anymore</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/epa-wont-regulate-ghg-for-vehicles-and-engines-anymore/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The EPA announced today that it would rescind a 2009 rule that the EPA uses to justify regulating greenhouse gas emissions. If finalized, all greenhouse gas emissions regulations for motor vehicles and engines would be nullified. EPA’s proposed rule, if finalized, would repeal all greenhouse gas emissions regulations for motor vehicles and engines, including the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/epa-wont-regulate-ghg-for-vehicles-and-engines-anymore/"&gt;EPA won&amp;#8217;t regulate GHG for vehicles and engines anymore&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 21:27:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] To Mexico, via Atlanta</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/to-mexico-via-atlanta/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Ley Enrique Ortiz-Calleja, age 29, was arguing his case this morning at the Federal Courthouse in downtown St. Paul. Your correspondent was there. Mr. Ortiz is an early frontrunner for Minnesota Dad of the Week. His story will be difficult to top. He has been indicted on two felony counts out of the federal Northern...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/to-mexico-via-atlanta/"&gt;To Mexico, via Atlanta&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 21:47:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] I Spoke with Three Health Care Experts About the One Big Beautiful Bill, Here’s What They Said</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/i-spoke-with-three-health-care-experts-about-the-one-big-beautiful-bill-heres-what-they-said/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;President Donald Trump’s One, Big, Beautiful Bill (OBBB) is packed full of policy changes—changes we’ll be feeling for years to come. To help break down what President Trump’s OBBB means for health care in Texas and the rest of America, I sat down with three health care experts and asked them what they thought the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/i-spoke-with-three-health-care-experts-about-the-one-big-beautiful-bill-heres-what-they-said/"&gt;I Spoke with Three Health Care Experts About the One Big Beautiful Bill, Here’s What They Said&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 22:26:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Medicare Turns 60 This Month: It’s Time for an Intervention</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/medicare-turns-60-this-month-its-time-for-an-intervention/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On July 30, Medicare will mark its 60th birthday. Like many 60-year-olds, it&amp;#8217;s in the throes of a midlife crisis. But unlike a harmless convertible purchase or spontaneous trip to Paris, this one midlife crisis threatens the nation&amp;#8217;s fiscal health &amp;#8212; and the well-being of future retirees. Read the entire RealClearHealth op-ed here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/medicare-turns-60-this-month-its-time-for-an-intervention/"&gt;Medicare Turns 60 This Month: It&amp;#8217;s Time for an Intervention&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 22:31:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] How Price Controls Make a Healthy Drug Market Sick</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/how-price-controls-make-a-healthy-drug-market-sick/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The unspoken assumption behind the prescription drug price controls at the heart of the Democrats&amp;#8217; August 2022 Inflation Reduction Act (IRA) is that the pharmaceutical market is broken. According to this view, drugmakers have the power to charge whatever they want. Only a sweeping system of government price-setting can put the average patient on equal [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/how-price-controls-make-a-healthy-drug-market-sick/"&gt;How Price Controls Make a Healthy Drug Market Sick&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 23:06:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] America Doesn’t Have Enough Doctors. Medicare Is Making That Worse.</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/america-doesnt-have-enough-doctors-medicare-is-making-that-worse/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The United States is facing a shortage of 37,000 physicians, according to the latest research from the Association of American Medical Colleges. That deficit will more than double to 86,000 doctors by 2036. Medicare&amp;#8217;s chronically low reimbursement rates deserve at least part of the blame. According to the American Medical Association, this is the fifth [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/america-doesnt-have-enough-doctors-medicare-is-making-that-worse/"&gt;America Doesn&amp;#8217;t Have Enough Doctors. Medicare Is Making That Worse.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 23:16:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/07/outstater-2/</link><description>Because We Live Here . . . INDEPENDENTLY, a friend and I like to design thought experiments to test public-policy&amp;#160;conception. He, an economist with a construction background, is working on one that challenges the “affordable” housing narrative. I’m working on a model for crime-plagued retail. The friend’s idea is that affordable housing is what you&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/07/outstater-2/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 23:24:45 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>