<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>State-Policy Think-Tank Digest</title><link>https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml</link><description>Latest posts from free-market policy institutes across the U.S.</description><atom:link href="https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 00:15:11 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>[Rifreedom] After Federal Action, Rhode Island Desperately Needs a Realistic Energy Strategy</title><link>https://rifreedom.org/2025/08/after-federal-action-rhode-island-desperately-needs-a-realistic-energy-strategy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Cranston, RI – The Rhode Island Center for Freedom &amp;#38; Prosperity advises state policymakers to immediately begin work to construct a new and realistic energy strategy that will put the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org/2025/08/after-federal-action-rhode-island-desperately-needs-a-realistic-energy-strategy/"&gt;After Federal Action, Rhode Island Desperately Needs a Realistic Energy Strategy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org"&gt;RI Center for Freedom and Prosperity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 15:41:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Mississippi's Progress and the Push for School Choice</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/mississippis-progress-and-the-push-for-school-choice/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This week, I’ll be traveling to Washington, D.C. talking about Mississippi’s remarkable progress, including our elimination of the income tax and how we might best advance school choice in our state. Mississippi is gaining national attention for our transformative public policies. Once seen as a perennial underdog, our state is now recognized as a leader in free-market [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/mississippis-progress-and-the-push-for-school-choice/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi&amp;#039;s Progress and the Push for School Choice&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 17:09:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Non-working adults concentrated in Georgia’s distressed communities</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/adults-not-working-in-georgia/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Many Georgia counties face high rates of non-working adults, fueling distress and limiting opportunities in struggling communities. See the percentages for your county. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/adults-not-working-in-georgia/"&gt;Non-working adults concentrated in Georgia’s distressed communities&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 18:51:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] New Poll: Inflation, Economy, Taxes, and Crime Top Voter Concerns, Pennsylvanians Hold Shapiro Responsible for Budget Impasse</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/09/03/new-poll-inflation-economy-taxes-and-crime-top-voter-concerns-pennsylvanians-hold-shapiro-responsible-for-budget-impasse/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Harrisburg, Pa., September 3, 2025 — Fewer than 4-in-10 Pennsylvania voters believe the state is on the right track, according to new polling released today by the Commonwealth Foundation. Inflation, the economy, taxes, and crime top their list of concerns facing the state, with nearly two-thirds of Pennsylvanians saying economic conditions are worsening for them [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/09/03/new-poll-inflation-economy-taxes-and-crime-top-voter-concerns-pennsylvanians-hold-shapiro-responsible-for-budget-impasse/"&gt;New Poll: Inflation, Economy, Taxes, and Crime Top Voter Concerns, Pennsylvanians Hold Shapiro Responsible for Budget Impasse &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 15:24:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] A conversation on New Mexico’s health care provider shortage w/ RGF’s Paul Gessing &amp; Think New Mexico’s Fred Nathan</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/a-conversation-on-new-mexicos-health-care-provider-shortage-w-rgfs-paul-gessing-think-new-mexicos-fred-nathan/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Most New Mexicans are abundantly aware of the dire medical provider shortage facing our state. The Rio Grande Foundation has been researching and discussing solutions to this problem for several years. The same is true for Think New Mexico which is led by Fred Nathan. While we don&amp;#8217;t always agree with the approach of Think [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/a-conversation-on-new-mexicos-health-care-provider-shortage-w-rgfs-paul-gessing-think-new-mexicos-fred-nathan/"&gt;A conversation on New Mexico&amp;#8217;s health care provider shortage w/ RGF&amp;#8217;s Paul Gessing &amp;#038; Think New Mexico&amp;#8217;s Fred Nathan&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 15:42:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Fact Checking Claims on Enrollment Declines</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/fact-checking-claims-on-enrollment-declines/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=fact-checking-claims-on-enrollment-declines</link><description>Despite declining enrollment occurring all across the nation, recent news reports have claimed that the problem is specific to Tennessee because of the state's new Education Freedom Scholarships (EFS) program. Not only do these accusations wrongly place blame, many critics simply get the basics of the EFS program wrong. Let’s set the record straight.</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 16:04:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] New Hampshire rated the least corrupt state</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/09/new-hampshire-rated-the-least-corrupt-state/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;America’s freest state has just been rated its least corrupt too. Using U.S. Department of Justice data on corruption convictions in all 94 federal judicial districts from 2003-2024, the Cato Institute calculated the rate of corruption convictions per 10,000 government employees, then recently ranked states by their conviction rates. New Hampshire ranked dead last, with [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/09/new-hampshire-rated-the-least-corrupt-state/"&gt;New Hampshire rated the least corrupt state&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 00:17:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] School Choice Improves Public School Performance</title><link>https://empowerms.org/school-choice-improves-public-school-performance/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#8217;s an argument going around that deserves a response: The Parents’ Campaign has repeatedly claimed that Mississippi is gaining academically while the &amp;#8220;top choice states&amp;#8221; plummeted. This is naive, lacking any academic rigor, and a dishonest interpretation of the data.   First, the phrase &amp;#8220;top choice states&amp;#8221; is misleading. Half the states in their top 10&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/school-choice-improves-public-school-performance/"&gt;School Choice Improves Public School Performance&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 15:41:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] First Principles Series: The Plight of Property Taxes</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/first-principles-series-the-plight-of-property-taxes/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=first-principles-series-the-plight-of-property-taxes</link><description>Tennessee joins Hawaii, Vermont, and New Hampshire as the outliers where property taxes can go up without limit.</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 16:02:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] Commonwealth Foundation Urges Legal Protection of State’s Rainy Day Fund</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/09/08/commonwealth-foundation-urges-legal-protection-of-states-rainy-day-fund/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Letter calls on Treasurer Garrity to withhold any transfer from the budget stabilization reserve fund, pending legal adjudication. Harrisburg, Pa., September 8, 2025 — Today, the Commonwealth Foundation sent a letter to leaders of the General Assembly and Pennsylvania State Treasurer Stacy Garrity, urging the legal protection of the commonwealth’s Rainy Day Fund. Gov. Josh [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/09/08/commonwealth-foundation-urges-legal-protection-of-states-rainy-day-fund/"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation Urges Legal Protection of State&amp;#8217;s Rainy Day Fund&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 15:28:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] How Much Does Private School Really Cost in Mississippi?</title><link>https://empowerms.org/how-much-does-private-school-really-cost-in-mississippi/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For many Mississippi families, private school feels financially out of reach. However new research shows that private education may be more affordable than most people think—and that smart policy could make it accessible to thousands more students.  Research conducted by Empower Mississippi reveals that the average tuition for private schools varies from approximately $6,710 for&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/how-much-does-private-school-really-cost-in-mississippi/"&gt;How Much Does Private School Really Cost in Mississippi?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 21:15:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] National Poverty Rate Fails to Capture the Problem of Poverty Concentration in Georgia and Beyond</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/press-release-poverty-rate-2024/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/press-release-poverty-rate-2024/"&gt;National Poverty Rate Fails to Capture the Problem of Poverty Concentration in Georgia and Beyond&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 18:26:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] WILL &amp; IRG File Suit to Allow IRG to Disclose Request for Investigation Brought Against Judge</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/will-irg-file-suit-to-allow-irg-to-disclose-request-for-investigation-brought-against-judge/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL &amp;#38; IRG File Suit to Allow IRG to Disclose Request for Investigation Brought Against Judge Wisconsin Law Bars Release of Denied Requests, Violates First Amendment The News: The Institute for Reforming Government, represented by the Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;#38; Liberty, filed a lawsuit against the Wisconsin Judicial Commission challenging a statute that prohibits [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/will-irg-file-suit-to-allow-irg-to-disclose-request-for-investigation-brought-against-judge/"&gt;WILL &amp;#038; IRG File Suit to Allow IRG to Disclose Request for Investigation Brought Against Judge&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 13:05:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Tightening Nebraska’s Property Tax Caps for Real Relief</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/tightening-nebraskas-property-tax-caps-for-real-relief/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Nebraska lawmakers can deliver stronger transparency and greater tax relief by consolidating and tightening Nebraska’s property tax caps. Nebraska has both a Truth-In-Taxation (TNT) transparency law and property tax caps for K-12 school districts and then separate caps for all other local governments.  By comparison, several less-fiscally-responsible states impose more strict property tax caps. Nebraska...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/tightening-nebraskas-property-tax-caps-for-real-relief/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Tightening Nebraska’s Property Tax Caps for Real Relief&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 13:43:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] As an LIRR Strike Looms, the Empire Center Publishes the Disputed Contracts</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/as-an-lirr-strike-looms-the-empire-center-publishes-the-disputed-contracts/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;With Long Island Rail Road workers threatening a strike that could strand hundreds of thousands of commuters, the Empire Center....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/as-an-lirr-strike-looms-the-empire-center-publishes-the-disputed-contracts/"&gt;As an LIRR Strike Looms, the Empire Center Publishes the Disputed Contracts&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 13:59:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Student Excellence for Every Portland Public School</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/education/student-excellence-for-every-portland-public-school/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By John Charles On September 9th, the Portland Public School (PPS) board was...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/education/student-excellence-for-every-portland-public-school/"&gt;Student Excellence for Every Portland Public School&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 17:49:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] KASB tries to whitewash new lower proficiency standards with deception and false claims</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/kasb-tries-to-whitewash-new-lower-proficiency-standards-with-deception-and-false-claims/</link><description>When something sounds too good to be true, it often is…like the State School Board and the Kansas Department of Education claiming that skyrocketing proficiency levels are not related to the state dumbing down proficiency standards. Now, the Kansas Association of School Boards (KASB) is joining the chorus with a new video denying that proficiency [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 19:45:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Virginiainstitute] In memory of Charlie Kirk (1993-2025)</title><link>https://virginiainstitute.org/in-memory-of-charlie-kirk-1993-2025/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=in-memory-of-charlie-kirk-1993-2025</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Virginia Institute for Public Policy tonight remembers Charlie Kirk, his beautiful wife Erika, and his young daughter and son who will grow up without a father&amp;#8217;s loving care and&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org/in-memory-of-charlie-kirk-1993-2025/"&gt;In memory of Charlie Kirk (1993-2025)&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org"&gt;Virginia Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 02:59:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] John Charles’ Sept. 9 Testimony for PPS Board Meeting Re: Purchase Agreement for Center for Black Student Excellence</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/education/john-charles-sept-9-testimony-for-pps-board-meeting-re-purchase-agreement-for-center-for-black-student-excellence/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Executive Summary: On September 9th, the Portland Public School (PPS) board met to...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/education/john-charles-sept-9-testimony-for-pps-board-meeting-re-purchase-agreement-for-center-for-black-student-excellence/"&gt;John Charles’ Sept. 9 Testimony for PPS Board Meeting Re: Purchase Agreement for Center for Black Student Excellence&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 14:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] In Memory of Charlie Kirk: Why Political Violence Demands A Better Response</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/in-memory-of-charlie-kirk-why-political-violence-demands-a-better-response/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The staff at Maine Policy Institute joins millions across the country in mourning the tragic and senseless killing of Charlie Kirk, founder of Turning Point USA. We offer our heartfelt condolences to his wife, children, and colleagues, and we stand in solidarity with those across the political spectrum who are grieving this immense loss. No [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/in-memory-of-charlie-kirk-why-political-violence-demands-a-better-response/"&gt;In Memory of Charlie Kirk: Why Political Violence Demands A Better Response&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 19:05:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] How Immigrants Became a Cash Cow for New York’s Essential Plan</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/how-immigrants-became-a-cash-cow-for-new-yorks-essential-plan/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Hochul administration&amp;#8217;s move to shrink the Essential Plan in response to federal budget cuts has exposed a surprising reality:....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/how-immigrants-became-a-cash-cow-for-new-yorks-essential-plan/"&gt;How Immigrants Became a Cash Cow for New York&amp;#8217;s Essential Plan&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 19:38:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Job Licensing Reviews: Judiciary, Natural Resources and Urban Affairs Committees</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/job-licensing-reviews-judiciary-natural-resources-and-urban-affairs-committees/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Occupational Board Reform Act (OBRA) was passed in 2018 and became effective in 2019. It requires legislative committees of jurisdiction to review all occupational licenses in the state, roughly 20% per year, on a five-year rotation. These reviews examine whether the licensing requirements are adequate or excessive by current standards. The committees then submit...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/job-licensing-reviews-judiciary-natural-resources-and-urban-affairs-committees/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Job Licensing Reviews: Judiciary, Natural Resources and Urban Affairs Committees&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 21:18:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Evers administration pigs out on livestock fees</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/wi-evers-administration-pigs-out-on-livestock-fees/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;State agencies have begun their rush through a regulatory back door that will almost certainly cost owners of businesses large and small in Wisconsin tens of millions of dollars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/wi-evers-administration-pigs-out-on-livestock-fees/"&gt;Evers administration pigs out on livestock fees&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 22:26:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Listen: Charlie Kirk’s Death and Political Violence on WGAN</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/listen-charlie-kirks-death-and-political-violence-on-wgan/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Policy analyst, Harris Van Pate, joined the WGAN Morning News to discuss the political response to the assassination of Charlie Kirk, including what lawmakers on both sides of the aisle have shared in response and what the political temperature in Augusta feels like. Listen to the full segment below. Newsradio WGAN · Maine Policy Institute&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/listen-charlie-kirks-death-and-political-violence-on-wgan/"&gt;Listen: Charlie Kirk&amp;#8217;s Death and Political Violence on WGAN&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 12:27:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] The Court and the Computer: When a Judge Underestimated Technological Innovation</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/the-court-and-the-computer-when-a-judge-underestimated-technological-innovation/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The antitrust case against Google was filed in 2020 and did not conclude until the beginning of this month. The last five years have been a case study in the differing paces of the judiciary and technological progress. Judge Mehta, who presided over the case, ruled on the remedies last week and his decision acknowledges...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/the-court-and-the-computer-when-a-judge-underestimated-technological-innovation/"&gt;The Court and the Computer: When a Judge Underestimated Technological Innovation&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 16:15:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Virginiainstitute] Press Release – Coalition Applauds Executive Order 53</title><link>https://virginiainstitute.org/press-release-coalition-applauds-executive-order-53/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=press-release-coalition-applauds-executive-order-53</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Summary Virginia Fair Elections (VFE), a coalition committed to ensuring transparent and secure elections in Virginia, has publicly praised Governor Glenn Youngkin’s Executive Order 53, issued on September 12, 2025.&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org/press-release-coalition-applauds-executive-order-53/"&gt;Press Release – Coalition Applauds Executive Order 53&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org"&gt;Virginia Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 16:17:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Join us in reviving the free exchange of ideas in New Hampshire</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/09/join-us-in-reviving-the-free-exchange-of-ideas-in-new-hampshire/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On September 9, the Foundation for Individual Rights and Expression (FIRE) released its 2026 campus free speech rankings, concluding that “America’s colleges get an ‘F’ for poor free speech climate.”  “More students than ever think violence and chaos are acceptable alternatives to peaceful protest,” FIRE Chief Research Advisor Sean Stevens said on the report’s release. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/09/join-us-in-reviving-the-free-exchange-of-ideas-in-new-hampshire/"&gt;Join us in reviving the free exchange of ideas in New Hampshire&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 20:08:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Mahomes Can’t Evade New York’s Licensing Blitz</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/mahomes-cant-evade-new-yorks-licensing-blitz/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The National Football League kicked off its new season this month and fans tuning in to television broadcasts this fall....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/mahomes-cant-evade-new-yorks-licensing-blitz/"&gt;Mahomes Can&amp;#8217;t Evade New York&amp;#8217;s Licensing Blitz&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 11:56:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/09/the-outstater-288/</link><description>Let&amp;#8217;s Fire Them for Cause GOOD JUDGMENT&amp;#160;like common sense is a trait considered too banal for this generation of human resource managers. Rather, decisions such as firing someone for justifying the assassination of a man for his opinion must involve an exercise in pearl-clutching and legalese. Thus, Ball State University&amp;#8217;s carefully worded response to a&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/09/the-outstater-288/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 13:48:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF opinion piece: Progressive policies are killing Albuquerque</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-opinion-piece-progressive-policies-are-killing-albuquerque/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following appeared on September 14, 2025 in the Albuquerque Journal: This fall’s city elections are critical for the future of Albuquerque. A further shift to the left could do great harm to our city. Polling indicates that a majority of voters in Albuquerque want change, but it is critical that voters turn out not [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-opinion-piece-progressive-policies-are-killing-albuquerque/"&gt;RGF opinion piece: Progressive policies are killing Albuquerque&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 17:06:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Pioneer Institute Joins Pew Charitable Trusts in Call to Expand Housing Affordability</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/pioneer-institute-joins-pew-charitable-trusts-in-call-to-expand-housing-affordability/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Pioneer Institute is pleased to join a statement of shared principles organized by the Pew Charitable Trusts in Washington, D.C., aimed at enhancing housing availability and affordability nationwide. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/pioneer-institute-joins-pew-charitable-trusts-in-call-to-expand-housing-affordability/"&gt;Pioneer Institute Joins Pew Charitable Trusts in Call to Expand Housing Affordability&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 17:56:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Reflecting on a Grim Week</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/reflecting-on-a-grim-week/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The past few days have been deeply unsettling. &amp;#160;The assassination of Charlie Kirk, gunned down while addressing young Americans on a Utah college campus, was horrifying. It seems clear that Charlie was targeted for his beliefs, which he expressed with remarkable clarity and conviction. Over the past decade, Charlie Kirk emerged as one of a [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/reflecting-on-a-grim-week/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Reflecting on a Grim Week&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 21:18:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Debunking ‘holding the line’ and other property tax myths</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/property-tax-myths/</link><description>Contrary to claims by some local elected officials, appraisers aren’t to blame for property tax increases. Elected officials set mill rates that determine property tax revenue for cities, counties, school districts, and other taxing authorities, and they alone are responsible for property tax hikes. Elected officials overseeing 62% of all local taxing authorities dropped mill [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 21:38:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] What the Old Right Teaches us on Constitution Day</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/what-the-old-right-teaches-us-on-constitution-day/</link><description>&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1700" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/AdobeStock_2098174-scaled.jpeg" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;" width="2560" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="What the Old Right Teaches us on Constitution Day  " src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/AdobeStock_2098174-500x332.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conservatives of the 1920s viewed the Constitution as the enduring foundation of American liberty, emphasizing limited government, federalism, and the need to preserve timeless principles rather than treat the document as obsolete. They rejected the progressive notion of a “living Constitution,” instead describing it as an anchor—flexible through amendment, but grounded in unchanging truths and rooted in prudence. These conservatives believed Americans have a duty to safeguard the Constitution. Through education, civic responsibility, and vigilance against drift, liberty can be protected for future generations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/what-the-old-right-teaches-us-on-constitution-day/"&gt;What the Old Right Teaches us on Constitution Day  &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 12:58:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] What is the Instructional Support Levy (ISL)?</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/what-is-the-instructional-support-levy-isl/</link><description>&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="630" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/wilton-csd.jpg" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="What is the Instructional Support Levy (ISL)?" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/wilton-csd-600x315.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Instructional Support Levy (ISL) is one of the main tools available to Iowa school districts to supplement state funding for educational programs. While the state sets limits on how much can be spent per student, the ISL provides districts with a way to go beyond that cap—funding additional staff, classroom resources, and other instructional needs. Because the levy can significantly affect local property taxes and school budgets, it is important for school board members, parents, and community members to understand how it works and how it is implemented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/what-is-the-instructional-support-levy-isl/"&gt;What is the Instructional Support Levy (ISL)?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 14:15:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] AI bills in Michigan House follow heavy-handed and punitive regulatory approach</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/ai-bills-in-michigan-house-follow-heavy-handed-and-punitive-regulatory-approach</link><description>‘Regulations born of fear threaten to derail beneficial innovation’</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 15:16:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] The Erosion of Parental Trust and Responsibility in America</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/education/the-erosion-of-parental-trust-and-responsibility-in-america/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In an era where parenting is more scrutinized than ever, the United States appears to be undergoing a subtle yet profound shift: diminishing confidence in parents’ ability to raise their children effectively. This erosion manifests across key domains—education, online safety in the digital age, and juvenile crime—where state legislatures are increasingly intervening with laws that...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/education/the-erosion-of-parental-trust-and-responsibility-in-america/"&gt;The Erosion of Parental Trust and Responsibility in America&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 17:03:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] SCOTUS Appeal Challenges Union Efforts to Stifle Opt-outs</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/press-release/scotus-appeal-challenges-union-efforts-to-stifle-opt-outs/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Freedom Foundation has filed its most recent petition for certiorari review at the United States Supreme Court, asking the justices to answer a critical First Amendment question: Do public employees have the right to leave their union?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/press-release/scotus-appeal-challenges-union-efforts-to-stifle-opt-outs/" rel="nofollow"&gt;SCOTUS Appeal Challenges Union Efforts to Stifle Opt-outs&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 18:41:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] How Nebraska Can Improve Truth-in-Taxation: Lessons from Utah’s Property Tax Reform</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/how-nebraska-can-improve-truth-in-taxation-lessons-from-utahs-property-tax-reform/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Utah passed the nation’s first Truth-in-Taxation (TNT) law in 1985, giving the Beehive State 40 years to refine and finesse their property tax program.   Nebraska has adopted a similar law which can be improved by adjusting the schedule for when Truth-in-Taxation hearings occur so that the TNT process precedes budget adoption.  Utah’s tax transparency procedure...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/how-nebraska-can-improve-truth-in-taxation-lessons-from-utahs-property-tax-reform/" rel="nofollow"&gt;How Nebraska Can Improve Truth-in-Taxation: Lessons from Utah’s Property Tax Reform&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 19:55:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] First Principles Series: Worker Freedom</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/first-principles-series-worker-freedom/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=first-principles-series-worker-freedom</link><description>More and more people are relocating to Tennessee to live and work and fleeing states that refuse to protect their freedoms, like California, Illinois, and New York.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 20:31:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] OHIO: 610 opt-outs in July and August</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/ohio-610-opt-outs-in-july-and-august/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In July and August alone, 610 Ohio public employees made the bold choice to walk away from union control — reclaiming their paychecks, their rights and their freedom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/ohio-610-opt-outs-in-july-and-august/" rel="nofollow"&gt;OHIO: 610 opt-outs in July and August&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 20:56:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Rebekah Staples: Work Work Work</title><link>https://empowerms.org/rebekah-staples-work-work-work/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Rebekah Staples: Work Work Work More than just a paycheck, work is the foundation of prosperity and the pathway to earned success. This week, host Grant Callen sits down with Rebekah Staples President &amp;#38; Founder of Free State Strategies and a Contributing Fellow at Empower Mississippi. Hailing from The Free State of Jones (County), Rebekah&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/rebekah-staples-work-work-work/"&gt;Rebekah Staples: Work Work Work&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 23:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] The Political Bait and Switch: When Promises Become Propaganda</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/the-political-bait-and-switch-when-promises-become-propaganda/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/the-political-bait-and-switch-when-promises-become-propaganda/" rel="nofollow" title="The Political Bait and Switch: When Promises Become Propaganda   "&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Article-Headers-2025-09-16T164920.750.png" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Imagine there’s a business you are looking to invest in. The businessman pitches you a compelling plan, explains how your money will be used, and promises long-term returns. You cut them a check and leave them to their work, excited for the future. A month later, you check in — only to find the original [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 23:12:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/09/the-outstater-289/</link><description>Rep. Carson&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8216;Racism&amp;#8217; Falls Flat WELL, IF ALL YOU HAVE&amp;#160;is a hammer everything looks like a nail. And so goes U.S. Rep. Andre Carson’s recent depiction of Indiana Republicans&amp;#160;as&amp;#160; “racist.” Last month he posted this on&amp;#160;X:&amp;#160;”We must stand united against extremism that endangers our community and democracy — including against racist redistricting that threatens to&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/09/the-outstater-289/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 13:20:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Dr. Gil Troy on Theodor Herzl – Father of Zionism &amp; Combating Antisemitism</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/dr-gil-troy-on-theodor-herzl-father-of-zionism-combating-antisemitism/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In this week’s episode of The Learning Curve, co-hosts U-Arkansas Prof. Albert Cheng and Eos Foundation’s Andrea Silbert interview Dr. Gil Troy, senior fellow at the Jewish People Policy Institute, Distinguished Scholar in North American History at McGill University, and editor of Theodor Herzl: The Collected Zionist Writings and Addresses of Israel's Founder. He offers an overview of Herzl’s upbringing in 19th-century Vienna, the antisemitic events that shaped his worldview, and how the infamous Dreyfus Affair spurred his determination to establish a Jewish State.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/dr-gil-troy-on-theodor-herzl-father-of-zionism-combating-antisemitism/"&gt;Dr. Gil Troy on Theodor Herzl &amp;#8211; Father of Zionism &amp;#038; Combating Antisemitism&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 13:56:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Property Tax Pain Index Shows Rising Burdens Across Iowa</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/property-tax-pain-index-shows-rising-burdens-across-iowa/</link><description>&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1396" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/yqHcs-property-tax-pain-index-city-.png" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;" width="2440" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Property Tax Pain Index Shows Rising Burdens Across Iowa" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/yqHcs-property-tax-pain-index-city--600x343.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the newest round of property tax payments due this month, too many Iowans are staring at their bills and wondering how long they can keep up with the rising costs. While most of us can feel the strain year after year, once factors like valuations, rollbacks, and “growth” are considered, it can be difficult to know exactly how much property tax pain we’re experiencing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/property-tax-pain-index-shows-rising-burdens-across-iowa/"&gt;Property Tax Pain Index Shows Rising Burdens Across Iowa&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 14:23:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Solving the Math Crisis: Get Wisconsin Kids Counting Again</title><link>https://will-law.org/solving-the-math-crisis-get-wisconsin-kids-counting-again/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL has unveiled a new policy report, “Closing Wisconsin’s Math Gap: A Call for Early Numeracy Reform,” sounding the alarm on declining math achievement and offering solutions to reverse the crisis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/solving-the-math-crisis-get-wisconsin-kids-counting-again/"&gt;Solving the Math Crisis: Get Wisconsin Kids Counting Again&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 14:25:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] The Hill: From Hanging Chads to the Gold Standard: Florida Is the Nation’s Leader on Elections</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/the-hill-from-hanging-chads-to-the-gold-standard-florida-is-the-nations-leader-on-elections/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When Florida’s 2000 presidential election descended into the now-historic Bush v. Gore&amp;#160;legal battle, its name became synonymous with...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/the-hill-from-hanging-chads-to-the-gold-standard-florida-is-the-nations-leader-on-elections/"&gt;The Hill: From Hanging Chads to the Gold Standard: Florida Is the Nation’s Leader on Elections&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 14:42:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Honoring Our Constitution</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/honoring-our-constitution/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/honoring-our-constitution/" rel="nofollow" title="Honoring Our Constitution"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/25-181-IFF-Constitution-Day-1920x1080-1.png" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Happy Constitution Day! Today, we honor the signing of the foundational charter of our Republic — the U.S. Constitution. Signed on September 17, 1787, the Constitution remains a beacon of liberty and justice, outlining the principles and rule of law by which we govern. The Framers of the Constitution were ordinary men who accomplished an [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Putting Our AI Regulations to the Test</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/putting-our-ai-regulations-to-the-test/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;American technology faces a regulatory framework that was built for a bygone era. As Artificial Intelligence (AI) systems...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/putting-our-ai-regulations-to-the-test/"&gt;Putting Our AI Regulations to the Test&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 15:38:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] CMP’s proposed rate hike sparks outrage, yet solar handouts cost Mainers more</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/cmps-proposed-rate-hike-sparks-outrage-yet-solar-handouts-cost-mainers-more/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday, Governor Janet Mills publicly rebuked Central Maine Power’s (CMP) newly proposed five-year spending plan, which would raise the average household’s electricity bill by up to $35 per month. Mills called the proposal “massive and unacceptable,” citing concerns about affordability for rural residents, seniors, and small businesses. While no one celebrates higher utility bills, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/cmps-proposed-rate-hike-sparks-outrage-yet-solar-handouts-cost-mainers-more/"&gt;CMP&amp;#8217;s proposed rate hike sparks outrage, yet solar handouts cost Mainers more&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 16:33:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Moscow school district uses taxpayer money... to sue taxpayers</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/moscow-school-district-uses-taxpayer-money-to-sue-taxpayers</link><description>Moscow’s school board isn’t standing up for students. Instead, it's standing in the way of parents, punishing taxpayers, and trying to take choices away from Idaho families who need them most.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 16:34:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Cashing In On University Patents Means Giving Up On Our Innovation Future</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/cashing-in-on-university-patents-means-giving-up-on-our-innovation-future/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Washington is addicted to taxing success. Now, Commerce Secretary Howard Lutnick is floating a plan to skim half the patent earnings from inventions developed at universities with federal funding. It’s being sold as a way to shore up programs like Social Security. In reality, it’s a raid on American innovation that would deliver pennies to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/cashing-in-on-university-patents-means-giving-up-on-our-innovation-future/"&gt;Cashing In On University Patents Means Giving Up On Our Innovation Future&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 16:42:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG Court Watch Celebrates Constitution Day</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-court-watch-celebrates-constitution-day/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government (IRG) released the following statement honoring Constitution Day and the document that has guided our nation with the principles of limited government, individual liberty, and personal responsibility for more than two centuries. &amp;#160; THE QUOTE:  “Our Constitution was designed to protect the people by restraining government and [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-court-watch-celebrates-constitution-day/"&gt;IRG Court Watch Celebrates Constitution Day&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 17:38:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Policy Errors at the Root of California Community College Enrollment Fraud</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/policy-errors-at-the-root-of-california-community-college-enrollment-fraud/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=policy-errors-at-the-root-of-california-community-college-enrollment-fraud</link><description>&lt;p&gt;California&amp;#8217;s community college system continues to struggle with massive enrollment fraud, costing taxpayers millions in improper financial aid payments and raising hurdles to real students trying to complete their programs. California community colleges are especially vulnerable to fraud because of two progressive policy imperatives: tuition-free education and protecting undocumented immigrants. While providing free education without...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/policy-errors-at-the-root-of-california-community-college-enrollment-fraud/"&gt;Policy Errors at the Root of California Community College Enrollment Fraud&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 17:52:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] GCO welcomes new team members to grow our BETTER WORK initiative</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/gco-welcomes-new-team-members/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/gco-welcomes-new-team-members/"&gt;GCO welcomes new team members to grow our BETTER WORK initiative&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 17:55:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Charters Have Outperformed Traditional Public Schools Post-Pandemic</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/performance/charters-have-outperformed-traditional-public-schools-post-pandemic/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Charter schools are public schools that operate with greater flexibility than traditional public schools, as they are exempt from many [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/performance/charters-have-outperformed-traditional-public-schools-post-pandemic/"&gt;Charters Have Outperformed Traditional Public Schools Post-Pandemic&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 18:50:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] Charlie Kirk wasn’t killed for his politics – he was martyred for the Gospel</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/09/17/charlie-kirk-wasnt-killed-for-his-politics-he-was-martyred-for-the-gospel/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The alarming responses to the cold-blooded assassination of Charlie Kirk from both sides of the political aisle are derived from the same source: false worldview.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/09/17/charlie-kirk-wasnt-killed-for-his-politics-he-was-martyred-for-the-gospel/"&gt;Charlie Kirk wasn’t killed for his politics – he was martyred for the Gospel&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 18:51:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] In defense of murder</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/09/17/in-defense-of-murder/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The alarming responses to the cold-blooded assassination of Charlie Kirk from both sides of the political aisle are derived from the same source: false worldview.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/09/17/in-defense-of-murder/"&gt;In defense of murder&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 18:52:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Oregon’s Electric Vehicle Policy Fail</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/transportation/oregons-electric-vehicle-policy-fail/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By John Charles On September 15, the Oregon Department of Energy (ODOE) released...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/transportation/oregons-electric-vehicle-policy-fail/"&gt;Oregon’s Electric Vehicle Policy Fail&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 19:01:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] How the Federal Government Can Massively Fund Water Supply Infrastructure</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/how-the-federal-government-can-massively-fund-water-supply-infrastructure/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=how-the-federal-government-can-massively-fund-water-supply-infrastructure</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A few months ago I had the privilege of speaking directly with some of the top executives at one of California’s largest water agencies. Their primary question for me was explicit, and my attempts to answer were inadequate. They contend, accurately, that during the last century there were periods when massive federal funding to pay...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/how-the-federal-government-can-massively-fund-water-supply-infrastructure/"&gt;How the Federal Government Can Massively Fund Water Supply Infrastructure&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 19:51:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Paid in Full, Required to Do Nothing: Connecticut’s Higher Ed Scandal</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/09/17/paid-in-full-required-to-do-nothing-connecticuts-higher-ed-scandal/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="1024" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/ChatGPT-Image-Sep-17-2025-at-05_29_52-PM.png" width="1024" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connecticut taxpayers are footing a nearly half a million dollar bill for former Connecticut State Colleges and Universities (CSCU) Chancellor Terrence Cheng — who will continue to “advise” the system [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/09/17/paid-in-full-required-to-do-nothing-connecticuts-higher-ed-scandal/"&gt;Paid in Full, Required to Do Nothing: Connecticut’s Higher Ed Scandal&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 21:30:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Michigan’s environmental department cries wolf over budget</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/michigans-environmental-department-cries-wolf-over-budget</link><description>EGLE seeks to feather its own nest</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] YIMBYs win political victories, but where are the new houses?</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/yimbys-win-political-victories-but-where-are-the-new-houses/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Gov. Gavin Newsom even held up passage of the state budget until lawmakers approved two reforms to the California Environmental Quality Act (CEQA). Assembly Bill 130 exempts a broader number of environmentally friendly infill housing projects from CEQA. Senate Bill 131 exempts nine types of projects from CEQA. These include health centers, advanced manufacturing facilities, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/yimbys-win-political-victories-but-where-are-the-new-houses/"&gt;YIMBYs win political victories, but where are the new houses?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 10:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Recent AI Legislation Roundup: The Good, the Bad, the Ugly</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/recent-ai-legislation-roundup-the-good-the-bad-the-ugly/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;With its ever-evolving capabilities and multitude of uses, it should be no surprise that artificial intelligence (AI) is seemingly everywhere. From kitchen appliances to military operations, the technology has been rapidly incorporated into daily life and industry. The legislatures of this country are no exception, and AI bills have multiplied rapidly over recent years. The...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/recent-ai-legislation-roundup-the-good-the-bad-the-ugly/"&gt;Recent AI Legislation Roundup: The Good, the Bad, the Ugly&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 12:00:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Connecticut at the Battle of Antietam</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/09/18/connecticut-at-the-battle-of-antietam/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="404" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/service-pnp-cph-3b00000-3b00000-3b00400-3b00418r-e1758199164774.jpg" width="612" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Awful carnage” was the Hartford Courant’s description of the Battle of Antietam, fought between Union and Confederate forces — led by Gens. George McClellan and Robert E. Lee, respectively — [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/09/18/connecticut-at-the-battle-of-antietam/"&gt;Connecticut at the Battle of Antietam&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 12:39:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG: The Real State of Education</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-the-real-state-of-education/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;IRG: The Real State of Education Wisconsin Students are Left Behind Despite Record Investment in Schools Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government (IRG) released the following statement outlining the real State of Education in Wisconsin ahead of Superintendent of Public Instruction Jill Underly’s annual State of Education Address. &amp;#160; THE REAL STATE OF [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-the-real-state-of-education/"&gt;IRG: The Real State of Education&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 13:25:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Massachusetts’ Changing Demographic Landscape</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/economic_opportunity/massachusetts-changing-demographic-landscape/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This edition of Mapping Mass Migration features an analysis of recently released demographic estimates from the Census Bureau. Our analysis covers how Massachusetts' population has changed since the pandemic by race and age, discussing the state's shrinking youth population, its flat growth among prime-aged working demographics, its growing racial and ethnic diversity, and how it compares to other states. The newsletter concludes with a brief discussion of what implications these trends may have for the Bay State's future population growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/economic_opportunity/massachusetts-changing-demographic-landscape/"&gt;Massachusetts&amp;#8217; Changing Demographic Landscape&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 13:29:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Dismantling DEI – Goldwater Launches Podcast Series</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/dismantling-dei-goldwater-launches-podcast-series/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WATCH ON YOUTUBE. LISTEN ON APPLE PODCASTS AND SPOTIFY. Is DEI in America finally defeated? Not even close. Dismantling DEI,..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/dismantling-dei-goldwater-launches-podcast-series/"&gt;Dismantling DEI – Goldwater Launches Podcast Series&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 16:26:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Federal government shutdown brinkmanship has got to go</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/federal-government-shutdown-brinkmanship-has-got-to-go</link><description>The phrase ‘government shutdown’ is younger than most members of Congress. Fifty years ago, government shutdowns didn’t exist. But now,...</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 16:53:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] The Taxman Cometh: City of DeSoto</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/the-taxman-cometh-city-of-desoto/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Most city, county, and school district officials are right now in the process of adopting budgets and determining tax rates for the next fiscal year. In some cases, these local decisions will increase the cost of government and put upward pressure on property tax bills. In a few cases, local government action will cause tax...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/the-taxman-cometh-city-of-desoto/"&gt;The Taxman Cometh: City of DeSoto&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 17:21:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] The Taxman Cometh: City of Marble Falls</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/the-taxman-cometh-city-of-marble-falls/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Most city, county, and school district officials are right now in the process of adopting budgets and determining tax rates for the next fiscal year. In some cases, these local decisions will increase the cost of government and put upward pressure on property tax bills. In a few cases, local government action will cause tax...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/the-taxman-cometh-city-of-marble-falls/"&gt;The Taxman Cometh: City of Marble Falls&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 17:23:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] The James Madison Institute Joins the America 250 Civics Education Coalition in Partnership With U.S. Department of Education and Over 40 National and State Organizations</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/the-james-madison-institute-joins-the-america-250-civics-education-coalition-in-partnership-with-u-s-department-of-education-and-over-40-national-and-state-organizations/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;JMI&amp;#8217;s William Mattox joined U.S. Secretary of Education Linda McMahon and the U.S. Department of Education in partnership...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/the-james-madison-institute-joins-the-america-250-civics-education-coalition-in-partnership-with-u-s-department-of-education-and-over-40-national-and-state-organizations/"&gt;The James Madison Institute Joins the America 250 Civics Education Coalition in Partnership With U.S. Department of Education and Over 40 National and State Organizations&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 17:41:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Hugh Hewitt to headline Libertas Award Dinner; Frank Edelblut to receive 2025 Libertas Award</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/09/hugh-hewitt-to-headline-libertas-award-dinner-frank-edelblut-to-receive-2025-libertas-award/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Josiah Bartlett Center for Public Policy is proud to announce our 2025 Libertas Award Dinner on Monday, Nov. 10, featuring special guest Hugh Hewitt and recognizing Frank Edelblut with our 2025 Libertas Award.  “At a time when fair, honest, and open discourse is so important for New Hampshire and the nation, we’re thrilled to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/09/hugh-hewitt-to-headline-libertas-award-dinner-frank-edelblut-to-receive-2025-libertas-award/"&gt;Hugh Hewitt to headline Libertas Award Dinner; Frank Edelblut to receive 2025 Libertas Award&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 18:31:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Correction: PortKC Ignoring Its Own Audits for Five Years, Not Four</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/transparency/correction-portkc-ignoring-its-own-audits-for-five-years-not-four/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In a recent column for The Kansas City Star, I pointed out that the port authority of Kansas City, PortKC, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/transparency/correction-portkc-ignoring-its-own-audits-for-five-years-not-four/"&gt;Correction: PortKC Ignoring Its Own Audits for Five Years, Not Four&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 18:40:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] WILL Uncovers Multi-Million Dollar Race-Based School Funding Scheme</title><link>https://will-law.org/will-uncovers-multi-million-dollar-race-based-school-funding-scheme/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL filed a new federal complaint against the Jefferson County Public School District (JCPS) in Louisville, Kentucky, after discovering a race-based funding scheme that allocates funds to students based on the color of their skin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/will-uncovers-multi-million-dollar-race-based-school-funding-scheme/"&gt;WILL Uncovers Multi-Million Dollar Race-Based School Funding Scheme&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 19:00:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Congressional Democratic leader wants Illinois to super-gerrymander maps</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/congressional-democratic-leader-wants-illinois-to-super-gerrymander-maps/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;U.S. House Minority Leader Hakeem Jeffries wants Illinois state lawmakers to redraw congressional district maps to offset Republican gains from mid-decade remapping in Texas. Illinois lawmakers aren’t eager to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/congressional-democratic-leader-wants-illinois-to-super-gerrymander-maps/"&gt;Congressional Democratic leader wants Illinois to super-gerrymander maps&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 20:42:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Wisconsin can learn from neighbors’ disappearing-passenger blues</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/wisconsin-can-learn-from-neighbors-disappearing-passenger-blues/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;One wonders what revolution in Wisconsinites’ preferences for where to live and to work will make commuter trains feasible in Milwaukee where they weren’t in Minneapolis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/wisconsin-can-learn-from-neighbors-disappearing-passenger-blues/"&gt;Wisconsin can learn from neighbors’ disappearing-passenger blues&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 21:26:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Kids who kill and maim</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/milwaukee-kids-who-kill-and-maim/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;And what adults who’ve lost control need to do about it Sometimes they get lucky, the many kids in Milwaukee who shoot people, and they sidestep homicide charges because their victims happen not to die. Removing luck and counting up the number of child-shooters who either killed or just wounded a victim, the numbers are [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/milwaukee-kids-who-kill-and-maim/"&gt;Kids who kill and maim&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 21:33:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] Sec. McMahon, TPUSA, AFPI, API, and Partners Launch National Civics Coalition</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/09/18/sec-mcmahon-tpusa-afpi-api-and-partners-launch-national-civics-coalition/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Department of Education (the Department), in partnership the America First Policy Institute (AFPI), Turning Point USA, Hillsdale College and more than 40 leading national and state-based organizations, today announced the launch of the America 250 Civics Education Coalition. This landmark initiative is dedicated to renewing patriotism, strengthening civic knowledge, and advancing a shared understanding of America’s founding principles in schools across the nation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/09/18/sec-mcmahon-tpusa-afpi-api-and-partners-launch-national-civics-coalition/"&gt;Sec. McMahon, TPUSA, AFPI, API, and Partners Launch National Civics Coalition&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 23:19:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] 2025 Bills CPC Is Watching on the Governor’s Desk September 15, 2025</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/2025-bills-cpc-is-watching/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=2025-bills-cpc-is-watching</link><description>&lt;p&gt;California Policy Center has been tracking the following bills that passed off the floors of both the Assembly and Senate last week and are headed to (or on) Gov. Gavin Newsom’s desk. The governor has until October 13th to sign or veto these bills. AB 715 (Zbur) – At a time of increased hostility and...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/2025-bills-cpc-is-watching/"&gt;2025 Bills CPC Is Watching on the Governor’s Desk September 15, 2025&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 23:59:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Idaho activists sue taxpayers and target children: Six takeaways</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/idaho-activists-sue-taxpayers-and-target-children-six-takeaways</link><description>There is no mention of improving outcomes for Idaho children.
Instead, petitioners spend nearly nine pages of the legal filing arguing they have standing and another nine pages begging the court to require taxpayers reimburse their attorney fees.</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 05:53:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Legislators Did Not Relieve California’s Energy Poverty Problem</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/legislators-did-not-relieve-californias-energy-poverty-problem/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Legislators Did Not Relieve California’s Energy Poverty Problem Wayne Winegarden September 2025 The legislative year is over and there is lots to be concerned about. Paramount among these concerns, the legislature passed several bills that will worsen the state’s energy affordability problems. Perhaps most disappointing, though not unexpected, legislators passed SB 840 and AB 1207. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/legislators-did-not-relieve-californias-energy-poverty-problem/"&gt;Legislators Did Not Relieve California’s Energy Poverty Problem&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 09:30:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Trump treats Antifa as terrorist group</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/trump-treats-antifa-as-terrorist-group/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Brianna Lyman writes for the Federalist about a significant development in the fight against left-wing violence. President Donald Trump announced Wednesday that he would be designating the radical far-left group Antifa as a terrorist organization. “I am pleased to inform our many U.S.A Patriots that I am designating ANTIFA, A SICK, DANGEROUS, RADICAL LEFT DISASTER,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/trump-treats-antifa-as-terrorist-group/"&gt;Trump treats Antifa as terrorist group&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 09:39:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Patel highlights Biden-era FBI failures</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/patel-highlights-biden-era-fbi-failures/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Katie Jerkovich writes for RedState.com about the FBI director’s latest work. FBI Director Kash Patel recounted the numerous accomplishments the agency has had in the last seven months as he shone a glaring light on the epic failures of former President Joe Biden&amp;#8217;s FBI to keep Americans safe, and it&amp;#8217;s so much worse than we...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/patel-highlights-biden-era-fbi-failures/"&gt;Patel highlights Biden-era FBI failures&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 09:42:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Federal scholarship could help rural Illinois students find education options</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/federal-scholarship-could-help-rural-illinois-students-find-education-options/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A new federal scholarship tax credit program could be a lifeline to students in rural Illinois. They may have limited educational options, but the federal money could boost those options through tutoring or other services if Gov. J.B. Pritzker allows it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/federal-scholarship-could-help-rural-illinois-students-find-education-options/"&gt;Federal scholarship could help rural Illinois students find education options&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 10:00:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] ‘What constitutes separation?’</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/podcasts/the-overton-window/glenn-moots-discusses-the-evolution-of-church-and-state-in-america</link><description>Glenn Moots discusses the evolution of church and state in America</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 10:55:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] Schansberg: Gerrymandering</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/09/schansberg-gerrymandering/</link><description>by Eric Schansberg, Ph.D. &amp;#8220;Gerrymandering&amp;#8221; is always a possibility in a republic, but sometimes the topic moves to the front burner. We&amp;#8217;re in one of those moments now. Last month, the Texas GOP stirred the pot with its efforts to &amp;#8220;redistrict&amp;#8221; and some Democrat leaders responded with angry rhetoric and promises to retaliate. (Indiana Republicans&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/09/schansberg-gerrymandering/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 12:44:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Kansas Needs More Capitalism, Not Cronyism or Socialism</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/kansas-needs-more-capitalism/</link><description>Gallup recently found that just 54% of Americans now view capitalism positively, the lowest share since they began asking the question in 2010. That’s down from 60% in 2021, which is about where it has been since at least 2010. Meanwhile, 39% still view socialism positively, a number that hasn’t changed much overall but masks [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 14:00:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Coalition of Students and Parents Urge SCOTUS to Protect Girls’ Privacy</title><link>https://will-law.org/coalition-of-students-and-parents-urge-scotus-to-protect-girls-privacy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On behalf of three high school students and a coalition of Wisconsin parents, WILL filed an amicus brief in West Virginia v. B.P.J, a case currently before the Supreme Court of the United States. WILL argues that laws limiting girls’ sports to biological girls do not violate Title IX.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/coalition-of-students-and-parents-urge-scotus-to-protect-girls-privacy/"&gt;Coalition of Students and Parents Urge SCOTUS to Protect Girls’ Privacy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 14:07:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] SCOTUS Requests Responses in Freedom Foundation Case Challenging California Laws Surrounding Public Employee Orientations</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/press-release/scotus-requests-responses-in-freedom-foundation-case-challenging-california-laws-surrounding-public-employee-orientations/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The United States Supreme Court has taken the next step in Freedom Foundation v. Rita Gail Turner, et al., requesting responses from the defendants after the Freedom Foundation filed a petition for certiorari challenging California’s secrecy laws surrounding new public employee orientations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/press-release/scotus-requests-responses-in-freedom-foundation-case-challenging-california-laws-surrounding-public-employee-orientations/" rel="nofollow"&gt;SCOTUS Requests Responses in Freedom Foundation Case Challenging California Laws Surrounding Public Employee Orientations&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 15:08:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Access Denied: Why the FDA Is Failing Patients</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/access-denied-why-the-fda-is-failing-patients/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In an age of accelerating medical innovation, the U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA) is facing renewed scrutiny for policies..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/access-denied-why-the-fda-is-failing-patients/"&gt;Access Denied: Why the FDA Is Failing Patients&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 16:41:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Week in Review: Dismantling DEI Podcast Launched! Listen Now!</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-dismantling-dei-podcast-launched-listen-now/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Think DEI is finished? Think again. One of the most toxic and divisive ideologies of recent times, so-called diversity, equity,..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-dismantling-dei-podcast-launched-listen-now/"&gt;Week in Review: Dismantling DEI Podcast Launched! Listen Now!&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 17:08:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Teacher Unions: Blocking Opportunity to Keep Their Monopoly Alive</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/09/19/teacher-unions-blocking-opportunity-to-keep-their-monopoly-alive/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connecticut’s education leaders often speak about “equity,” but recent testimony suggests that rhetoric stops when equity means giving families more options. At a Sept. 12 Education Committee Informational Forum on [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/09/19/teacher-unions-blocking-opportunity-to-keep-their-monopoly-alive/"&gt;Teacher Unions: Blocking Opportunity to Keep Their Monopoly Alive&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 19:17:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Wildwood’s Big Mistake</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/subsidies/wildwoods-big-mistake/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;During my time at the Show-Me Institute, I have regularly cited Wildwood as an example of a city that exercised [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/subsidies/wildwoods-big-mistake/"&gt;Wildwood’s Big Mistake&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 19:33:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Information sector bright spot as Illinois job market remains sluggish</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/information-sector-bright-spot-as-illinois-job-market-remains-sluggish/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Illinois showed slow job growth as the state trailed national trends. Unemployment was at 4.4% in August, slightly above the national rate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/information-sector-bright-spot-as-illinois-job-market-remains-sluggish/"&gt;Information sector bright spot as Illinois job market remains sluggish&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 19:45:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF president discusses elimination of federal Rail Trail Funding w/ KOAT Channel 7</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-president-discusses-elimination-of-federal-rail-trail-funding-w-koat-channel-7/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Rio Grande Foundation president Paul Gessing had a chance to sit down with KOAT to discuss the fact that the Trump Administration has eliminated $11.5 million in federal funds for the wildly overpriced Albuquerque rail trail being built in Albuquerque at the behest of the Tim Keller Administration. The canceled $11.5 million was allocated under [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-president-discusses-elimination-of-federal-rail-trail-funding-w-koat-channel-7/"&gt;RGF president discusses elimination of federal Rail Trail Funding w/ KOAT Channel 7&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 19:55:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] WCPSS tries to do tutoring on the cheap — and fails</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/wcpss-tries-to-do-tutoring-on-the-cheap-and-fails/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A recent&amp;#160;article&amp;#160;in the&amp;#160;News &amp;#38; Observer&amp;#160;said that officials from the Wake County Public School System (WCPSS) are blaming the federal funding freeze for delaying the return of a tutoring program that helps students improve their reading skills. A little digging revealed that last year, WCPSS paid nonprofits approximately $339,000 to operate and recruit teachers for an...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/wcpss-tries-to-do-tutoring-on-the-cheap-and-fails/"&gt;WCPSS tries to do tutoring on the cheap — and fails&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 20:14:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Winners &amp; Losers: Aftershocks</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/winners-losers-aftershocks/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Every Friday morning, I join the Cardle &amp;#38; Woolley Show on 1370 Talk Radio in Austin to announce the week’s Winners &amp;#38; Losers. Charlie Kirk’s horrific assassination continues to produce aftershocks in Texas, America and the world. It was a week where many moved forward, finding strength, meaning and purpose in these dark times while...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/winners-losers-aftershocks/"&gt;Winners &amp; Losers: Aftershocks&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 22:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Weight Loss Drugs Pack on the Fat to State Spending</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/weight-loss-drugs-pack-on-the-fat-to-state-spending/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/weight-loss-drugs-pack-on-the-fat-to-state-spending/" rel="nofollow" title="Weight Loss Drugs Pack on the Fat to State Spending"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Article-Headers-2025-09-19T163637.101.png" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Well, isn’t that generous? The Group Insurance Advisory Committee (GIAC), under the Office of Group Insurance (OGI) within the Department of Administration — ever the example of fiscal responsibility — unilaterally decided to extend the GLP-1 weight-loss drugs to the employee health benefits plan for the previous few years. But don’t worry, when it was [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 23:51:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Maui’s property tax system should focus on relief and transparency</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/09/mauis-property-tax-system-should-focus-on-relief-and-transparency/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Maui County Council Special Committee on Real Property Tax Reform on Sept. 16, 2025._____________ Sept. 16, 2025, 1:30 p.m.Kalana O Maui Building To: Maui County Council, Special Committee on Real Property Tax Reform Alice Lee, Chair Keani Rawlins-Fernandez, Vice Chair [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/09/mauis-property-tax-system-should-focus-on-relief-and-transparency/"&gt;Maui&amp;#8217;s property tax system should focus on relief and transparency&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 00:10:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Increase allowable ADU area to create more housing options</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/09/increase-allowable-adu-area-to-create-more-housing-options/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Lāna’i Planning Commission on Sept. 17, 2025. _____________ Sept. 17, 2025, 5 p.m.Remote meeting To: Lāna&amp;#8217;i Planning Commission&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Reynold Gima, Chair&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Nicole Alboro, Vice Chair From: Jonathan Helton, Policy Analyst&amp;#160;&amp;#160; &amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii RE: Item A(2) — A BILL [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/09/increase-allowable-adu-area-to-create-more-housing-options/"&gt;Increase allowable ADU area to create more housing options&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 00:12:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Completion of Lanai projects threatened by added permit approval</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/09/completion-of-lanai-projects-threatened-by-added-permit-approval/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Lāna’i Planning Commission on Sept. 17, 2025_____________ Sept. 17, 2025, 5 p.m.Remote meeting To: Lāna&amp;#8217;i Planning Commission       Reynold Gima, Chair       Nicole Alboro, Vice Chair From: Jonathan Helton, Policy Analyst            Grassroot Institute of Hawaii RE: Item A(1) — A PROPOSED AMENDMENT [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/09/completion-of-lanai-projects-threatened-by-added-permit-approval/"&gt;Completion of Lanai projects threatened by added permit approval&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 00:15:22 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>