<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>State-Policy Think-Tank Digest</title><link>https://&lt;replace-with-your-domain&gt;/rss.xml</link><description>Latest posts from free-market policy institutes across the U.S.</description><atom:link href="https://&lt;replace-with-your-domain&gt;/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 17:11:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>[Georgiapolicy] Protected: Fiscal savings for public school districts from school choice programs</title><link>https://www.georgiapolicy.org/2023/03/fiscal-savings-for-public-school-districts-from-school-choice-programs/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=fiscal-savings-for-public-school-districts-from-school-choice-programs</link><description>&lt;p&gt;There is no excerpt because this is a protected post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.georgiapolicy.org/2023/03/fiscal-savings-for-public-school-districts-from-school-choice-programs/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Protected: Fiscal savings for public school districts from school choice programs&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.georgiapolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Georgia Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 14:49:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Gardenstateinitiative] 2024 Intern Spotlight</title><link>https://www.gardenstateinitiative.org/2024-intern-spotlight/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New Jersey Needs More Budget Transparency Ahana Dasgupta, George Washington University For state government to truly serve the people, there must be more transparency in New Jersey’s budget process. More than $600 million worth of last minute budget amendments and their sponsors were finally disclosed weeks after the budget was passed in late June. &amp;#160; [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.gardenstateinitiative.org/2024-intern-spotlight/"&gt;2024 Intern Spotlight&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.gardenstateinitiative.org"&gt;Garden State Initiative&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 19:00:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Libertas] Announcing the Creation of Overton Insights: Polling for a Freer Future</title><link>https://libertas.org/announcing-the-creation-of-overton-insights-polling-for-a-freer-future/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Today, we’re excited to launch Overton Insights—a new public polling company owned by Libertas Network. At Libertas, our mission is to change hearts, minds, and laws for a freer society. Overton Insights brings us closer to that goal by delivering data-driven clarity on what people think and where we—and our partner organizations across the country—can [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://libertas.org/announcing-the-creation-of-overton-insights-polling-for-a-freer-future/"&gt;Announcing the Creation of Overton Insights: Polling for a Freer Future&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://libertas.org"&gt;The Libertas Network: Changing Hearts, Minds, and Laws&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2025 14:55:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] Microschooling Spreads In Choice-Friendly States</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/06/11/microschooling-spreads-in-choice-friendly-states/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Since 2020, microschools have spread rapidly all across the U.S., but they are particularly popular in states with expansive school-choice programs. These choice-friendly states have passed legislation that enables families to use a portion of state-allocated education funding toward their preferred learning environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/06/11/microschooling-spreads-in-choice-friendly-states/"&gt;Microschooling Spreads In Choice-Friendly States&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 02:16:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Rep. Lee Yancey: Kratom, Underground Markets, and the Demon Chipmunk</title><link>https://empowerms.org/rep-lee-yancey-kratom-underground-markets-and-the-demon-chipmunk/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;﻿ Rep. Lee Yancey: Kratom, Underground Markets, and the Demon Chipmunk In this episode, host, Grant Callen sits down with State Representative Lee Yancey, a seasoned lawmaker with 11 years of service in the Mississippi Legislature. A one-time Senator, Rep. Yancey now chairs the House Business and Commerce Committee and serves on eight other committees&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/rep-lee-yancey-kratom-underground-markets-and-the-demon-chipmunk/"&gt;Rep. Lee Yancey: Kratom, Underground Markets, and the Demon Chipmunk&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 01:00:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Rifreedom] Center CEO Mike Stenhouse To Be Inducted Into College Baseball Hall Of Fame</title><link>https://rifreedom.org/2025/06/center-ceo-mike-stenhouse-to-be-inducted-into-college-baseball-hall-of-fame/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;?The Rhode Island Center for Freedom &amp;#38; Prosperity Congratulates CEO Mike Stenhouse on Induction into College Baseball Hall of Fame Providence, RI &amp;#8211; The Rhode Island Center for Freedom &amp;#38; [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org/2025/06/center-ceo-mike-stenhouse-to-be-inducted-into-college-baseball-hall-of-fame/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Center CEO Mike Stenhouse To Be Inducted Into College Baseball Hall Of Fame&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;RI Center for Freedom and Prosperity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 18:23:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alaskapolicyforum] Alaska’s schools are rolling in cash, so why aren’t the results better?</title><link>https://alaskapolicyforum.org/2025/06/alaskas-schools-are-rolling-in-cash-so-why-arent-the-results-better/#utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=alaskas-schools-are-rolling-in-cash-so-why-arent-the-results-better</link><description>&lt;div style="margin: 5px 5% 10px 5%;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" height="1707" src="https://alaskapolicyforum.org/wp-content/uploads/Money-scaled.jpg" title="" width="2560" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alaska was ranked the second most adequately funded school system in the US by a 2024 study from Rutgers University. The rest of the story — the study actually understates how well neighborhood schoolsRead More&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alaskapolicyforum.org/2025/06/alaskas-schools-are-rolling-in-cash-so-why-arent-the-results-better/"&gt;Alaska’s schools are rolling in cash, so why aren’t the results better?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://alaskapolicyforum.org"&gt;Alaska Policy Forum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 02:25:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Virginiainstitute] Press Release – VIPP Champions AI Moratorium, Invokes Commerce Clause</title><link>https://virginiainstitute.org/5850-2/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=5850-2</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Virginia Institute for Public Policy’s statement for memorandum highlights the urgent need for a coordinated federal approach to AI regulation, leveraging constitutional authority to avoid a fragmented and counterproductive patchwork of state laws. The proposed moratorium offers a pragmatic pathway to safeguard innovation, support small businesses, and ensure U.S. leadership in the rapidly evolving global AI landscape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org/5850-2/"&gt;Press Release – VIPP Champions AI Moratorium, Invokes Commerce Clause&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org"&gt;Virginia Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 14:10:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Kathy Hochul’s ambition cancels out claims of coming ‘climate disaster’</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/kathy-hochuls-ambition-cancels-out-claims-of-coming-climate-disaster/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New York politicians are extremely worried about the threat of global climate change. Their only bigger worry is that the....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/kathy-hochuls-ambition-cancels-out-claims-of-coming-climate-disaster/"&gt;Kathy Hochul’s ambition cancels out claims of coming ‘climate disaster’&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 18:51:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Unions and General Assembly Allies Throw a Fit Over Lamont’s Veto</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/06/25/unions-and-general-assembly-allies-throw-a-fit-over-lamonts-veto/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gov. Ned Lamont followed through this week on a promise that sent shockwaves through his party: he vetoed S.B. 8, a bill that would have offered unemployment benefits to workers [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/06/25/unions-and-general-assembly-allies-throw-a-fit-over-lamonts-veto/"&gt;Unions and General Assembly Allies Throw a Fit Over Lamont’s Veto&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 20:49:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cardinalinstitute] Colleges Must Educate for Freedom</title><link>https://cardinalinstitute.com/colleges-must-educate-for-freedom/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Colleges Must Educate for Freedom A great American college or university will prepare students for self-governance as both a wise human being and a prudent, productive citizen. Rightly understood, the liberal arts are the intellectual potentials shared by the leaders of a free people. That is, education policy should consider, first of all, how to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com/colleges-must-educate-for-freedom/"&gt;Colleges Must Educate for Freedom&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com"&gt;Cardinal Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 16:31:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Taxpayers getting jobbed</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/taxpayers-getting-jobbed-northern-wisconsin-job-corps/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A federal judge’s injunction is blocking the closing down Job Corps centers — including two in Wisconsin — that have an expensive and dismal record ostensibly training the young and disadvantaged for work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/taxpayers-getting-jobbed-northern-wisconsin-job-corps/"&gt;Taxpayers getting jobbed&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 20:21:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] The Maine House Restored Rep. Libby’s Rights. What now?</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/the-maine-house-restored-rep-libbys-rights-what-now/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On the final day of the 2025 legislative session, the Maine House of Representatives voted to reinstate Rep. Laurel Libby’s right to speak and vote on the House floor, formally lifting the limits imposed on her earlier this year by her censure.&amp;#160; While the Legislature offered no explicit justification for this reversal, it was clearly [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/the-maine-house-restored-rep-libbys-rights-what-now/"&gt;The Maine House Restored Rep. Libby&amp;#8217;s Rights. What now?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 23:51:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Arkansaspolicyfoundation] MEDICAL CARE IDEAS ADVANCE</title><link>https://arkansaspolicyfoundation.org/medical-care-ideas-advance/</link><description>(2025-2Q) The Arkansas Policy Foundation was founded by business leaders to serve the community and advance ideas to create more prosperity for Arkansans. The Policy Foundation was founded 30 years ago as a 501(c)(3) nonprofit, nonpartisan think tank that publishes credible research, hosts forums to encourage citizenship and is cited in national and state news [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 06:09:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] Paul sits down with Vance Ginn for “Let People Prosper” podcast</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/paul-sits-down-with-vance-ginn-for-let-people-prosper-podcast/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Why does New Mexico, rich in resources and culture, remain poor in economic freedom? That’s the question I explore in this week’s Let People Prosper Show with Paul Gessing, president of the Rio Grande Foundation. Paul brings nearly two decades of insight into New Mexico’s political and economic trends, offering a sobering look at why the state is falling behind and [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/paul-sits-down-with-vance-ginn-for-let-people-prosper-podcast/"&gt;Paul sits down with Vance Ginn for &amp;#8220;Let People Prosper&amp;#8221; podcast&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 17:59:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Frontierinstitute] Recent Permitting Reforms Are Protecting Property Rights</title><link>https://frontierinstitute.org/recent-permitting-reforms-are-protecting-property-rights/</link><description>"What property rights are unequivocally not, however, is a license to control what others do with their own property."</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 18:27:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] WILL Reacts to SCOTUS Parental Rights Ruling</title><link>https://will-law.org/will-reacts-to-scotus-parental-rights-ruling/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL released a statement praising the U.S. Supreme Court’s (SCOTUS) 6–3 ruling in Mahmoud v. Taylor—a landmark parental rights case that confirms parents’ ability to challenge school curricula and potentially other school policies and practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/will-reacts-to-scotus-parental-rights-ruling/"&gt;WILL Reacts to SCOTUS Parental Rights Ruling&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 21:56:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Hill hails interstate telehealth as easy way to boost local medical care</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/06/hill-hails-interstate-telehealth-as-easy-way-to-boost-local-medical-care/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;One easy, virtually cost-free way to improve healthcare access and quality in Hawaii would be to remove the state’s regulations on interstate telehealth, according to Malia Hill, Grassroot Institute of Hawaii’s policy director and author of a new white paper on the subject. Speaking on Sunday, June 22, with host Johnny Miro on the H. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/06/hill-hails-interstate-telehealth-as-easy-way-to-boost-local-medical-care/"&gt;Hill hails interstate telehealth as easy way to boost local medical care&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 22:10:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Jennifer Sey’s HR rebellion is just what America needs</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/jennifer-seys-hr-rebellion-is-just-what-america-needs/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;She said what we’ve all known deep down: The best workplaces run on trust and clarity, not surveillance and seminars. Jennifer Sey struck a nerve when she declared that her company, XX-XY Athletics, operates without an HR department. “They produce nothing,” Sey said at Freedom Fest earlier this month. “They monitor our words. They tell...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/jennifer-seys-hr-rebellion-is-just-what-america-needs/"&gt;Jennifer Sey’s HR rebellion is just what America needs&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 11:47:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] What Georgia Can Learn from Other States About Fixing Welfare</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/what-georgia-can-learn-from-other-states-about-fixing-welfare/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Like most states, Georgia's welfare system is a maze of complex rules and disconnected programs that trap people in a cycle of frustration and dependence. A few states are beginning to rethink how welfare operates and are making changes that could also work in Georgia. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/what-georgia-can-learn-from-other-states-about-fixing-welfare/"&gt;What Georgia Can Learn from Other States About Fixing Welfare&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 13:05:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Job Licensing Reviews: Business and Labor Committee and General Affairs Committee</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/job-licensing-reviews-business-general-affairs-and-labor-committee-and-general-affairs-committee/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;[Note: This is the second in a group of articles reviewing occupational licensing reviews for the first five-plus years of the Occupational Board Reform Act. For more context, see this post.] The Business and Labor Committee has reviewed a number of licenses from 2019 to 2024. Their areas of review included: Boiler Safety/Pressure Vessel Inspectors...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/job-licensing-reviews-business-general-affairs-and-labor-committee-and-general-affairs-committee/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Job Licensing Reviews: Business and Labor Committee and General Affairs Committee&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 13:19:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG’s Work Bridging the Political Divide and Digging into the Impact of the Immigration Crisis in Wisconsin Named as Finalists for National Awards</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irgs-work-bridging-the-political-divide-and-digging-into-the-impact-of-the-immigration-crisis-in-wisconsin-named-as-finalists-for-national-awards/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;IRG’s Work Bridging the Political Divide and Digging into the Impact of the Immigration Crisis in Wisconsin Named as Finalists for National Awards  State Policy Network Recognizes IRG as a finalist for the Bob Williams Award for Most Influential Research and Innovation in Marketing Delafield, Wis. – The State Policy Network (SPN) nominated the Institute [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irgs-work-bridging-the-political-divide-and-digging-into-the-impact-of-the-immigration-crisis-in-wisconsin-named-as-finalists-for-national-awards/"&gt;IRG’s Work Bridging the Political Divide and Digging into the Impact of the Immigration Crisis in Wisconsin Named as Finalists for National Awards&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 17:41:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/06/the-outstater-276/</link><description>Meet the New IEDC Board (Yawn) A FRIEND, a former submarine commander now a troubleshooter for a regional manufacturer, shared a management technique: Cancel the company picnic. Please, stick with me; this will explain why Gov. Mike Braun missed a golden eco-devo opportunity. My friend’s experience told him that nobody coming&amp;#160;to his office to complain would be&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/06/the-outstater-276/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 18:22:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] 2025 City Freedom Index: How Free is Your City?</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/2025-city-freedom-index/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=2025-city-freedom-index</link><description>In 2020, Beacon released its first-ever City Freedom Index to shed light on the ways taxpayers are impacted by local government policies. Five years and many changed local policies later, the time has come for an update.</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 11:30:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] Thousands of Arkansas Kids Now Eligible to Receive a Better Education</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/thousands-of-arkansas-kids-now-eligible-to-receive-a-better-education/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;While Minnesota policymakers continue to throw gobs and gobs more taxpayer funds toward our sub-standard public schools while expecting better outcomes, other states are moving ahead, including Arkansas. Created by the LEARNS Act, a “2023 law that made sweeping changes to the state’s K-12 education system,” Arkansas school children are now eligible to participate in [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/thousands-of-arkansas-kids-now-eligible-to-receive-a-better-education/"&gt;Thousands of Arkansas Kids Now Eligible to Receive a Better Education&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 12:39:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Louisiana’s public schools are improving. Do families still need choice?</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/education/louisianas-public-schools-are-improving-do-families-still-need-choice/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For the past several months, state K-12 education officials have touted Louisiana’s climb to 32nd in the nation, as measured by the National Assessment of Educational Progress (NAEP). And rightly so—let’s give credit where credit is due. For the past decade, the Louisiana Department of Education (LDOE) and the State Board of Elementary and Secondary...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/education/louisianas-public-schools-are-improving-do-families-still-need-choice/"&gt;Louisiana’s public schools are improving. Do families still need choice?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 13:22:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] WATCH: Megan Martin on PCN Discussing State Budget, Mass Transit Bail-out, and More</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/07/01/watch-megan-martin-on-pcn-discussing-state-budget-mass-transit-bail-out-and-more/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Megan Martin, Commonwealth Foundation&amp;#8217;s Chief Operating Officer and General Counsel, joins PCN&amp;#8217;s Capitol Preview to talk all things state budget. From public transit to Lifeline Scholarships, Martin outlines what good looks like in this year&amp;#8217;s budget, and which proposals will damage Pennsylvania&amp;#8217;s economic future. Watch below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/07/01/watch-megan-martin-on-pcn-discussing-state-budget-mass-transit-bail-out-and-more/"&gt;WATCH: Megan Martin on PCN Discussing State Budget, Mass Transit Bail-out, and More&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 13:27:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Kelo v. New London Twenty Years Later</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/kelo-v-new-london-twenty-years-later/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Amazingly, it’s been two decades since the U.S. Supreme Court issued one of the most egregiously wrong decisions in constitutional..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/kelo-v-new-london-twenty-years-later/"&gt;Kelo v. New London Twenty Years Later&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 17:21:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] BINJE: Energy Matters with Jeanette Hoffman launches today on ONNJ</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/07/binje-energy-matters-with-jeanette-hoffman-launches-today-on-onnj/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 17:56:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] How both sides lost the ConVal school funding case</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/07/how-both-sides-lost-the-conval-school-funding-case/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday morning, the New Hampshire Supreme Court for the first time ordered the state to spend a minimum amount of money—$7.356.01 per pupil—to educate public school students.  The state therefore lost this landmark school funding case, Contoocook Valley School District v. State, as it had tried to avoid such a decree. But a closer [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/07/how-both-sides-lost-the-conval-school-funding-case/"&gt;How both sides lost the ConVal school funding case&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 17:57:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Why Is PortKC Keeping Secrets?</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/transparency/why-is-portkc-keeping-secrets/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;PortKC has become Kansas City’s go-to agency for economic development incentives—but with a troubling condition. Applicants must sign a non-disclosure [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/transparency/why-is-portkc-keeping-secrets/"&gt;Why Is PortKC Keeping Secrets?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 18:40:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Uncle Sam’s Wallet: An Update on Federal Funds in Iowa</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/uncle-sams-wallet-an-update-on-federal-funds-in-iowa/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Iowa’s reliance on federal funds flowing through our state—which cumulatively exceed the $9.4 billion state General Fund—reveals a growing imbalance that puts Iowa at risk. With Congress considering ways to rein in federal deficits by cutting spending on programs like Medicaid or food assistance (SNAP), Iowa’s General Fund might be forced to make up the difference. This would give Iowa taxpayers serious pain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/uncle-sams-wallet-an-update-on-federal-funds-in-iowa/"&gt;Uncle Sam’s Wallet: An Update on Federal Funds in Iowa&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 20:20:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Blistering opt-out pace continues</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/blistering-opt-out-pace-continues/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Freedom Foundation is proud to report back-to-back record-breaking months in May and June, each surpassing 5,000 union opt-outs. That’s more than just a milestone. It’s a momentum shift.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/blistering-opt-out-pace-continues/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Blistering opt-out pace continues&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 22:18:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] James Armistead Lafayette</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/james-armistead-lafayette/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/james-armistead-lafayette/" rel="nofollow" title="James Armistead Lafayette"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="580" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Prop-1-Exposed-2-23.png" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;In celebration of our national heritage, we continue our Pride in America series by honoring one of the unsung heroes of the American Revolution, James Armistead Lafayette.&amp;#160; James Armistead was born into slavery in c. 1748 and spent the early years of his life working on a plantation in Virginia. He was owned by William [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:10:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Democrats driving party to self-destruction?</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/democrats-driving-party-to-self-destruction/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Conrad Black writes for Real Clear Politics about trouble for national Democrats. The Democrats are now implacably self-destructive. They resemble nothing so much as a slowly capsizing ship, but show by their frenzied skullduggery that America is not in decline — the opposition is rotten and hopeless but it still fights savagely. I hope readers...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/democrats-driving-party-to-self-destruction/"&gt;Democrats driving party to self-destruction?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 09:42:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Schools need accountability, not a blank check</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/schools-need-accountability-not-a-blank-check</link><description>A new coalition seeks massive tax hike for failing Michigan education system</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] The Heart Of American Entrepreneurship Has Grown Cold</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/the-heart-of-american-entrepreneurship-has-grown-cold/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Silicon Valley has long been considered the white-hot destination for entrepreneurs. “The area is extremely start-up friendly,” says the University of Silicon Valley. The University of San Francisco’s Center for Research, Artistic and Scholarly Excellence tell us “Silicon Valley has a long history of creating and nurturing an ecosystem of entrepreneurs, startups, investors, and academics.” This is [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/the-heart-of-american-entrepreneurship-has-grown-cold/"&gt;The Heart Of American Entrepreneurship Has Grown Cold&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 10:00:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Mac Hoffmann: former Statehouse staffer turns Madigan downfall into folk music</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/mac-hoffmann-former-statehouse-staffer-turns-madigan-downfall-into-folk-music/</link><description>Former Illinois House Speaker Mike Madigan may be heading for a 7.5-year stint in the federal pen, but his corrupt legend lives on thanks to a folk song by a former staffer.</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 10:00:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] ‘If you build it, they will come’: Analysis shows passing education choice policy brings more options</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/if-you-build-it-they-will-come-analysis-shows-passing-education-choice-policy-brings-more-options/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;One argument against education choice programs is that expanding parental freedom to access alternative learning environments doesn&amp;#8217;t mean much in areas with limited options. But a recent study of universal school choice programs found there&amp;#8217;s a positive shift in the supply of education vendors after a choice program becomes available. In her report, &amp;#8220;The Supply...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/if-you-build-it-they-will-come-analysis-shows-passing-education-choice-policy-brings-more-options/"&gt;&amp;#8216;If you build it, they will come&amp;#8217;: Analysis shows passing education choice policy brings more options&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 12:01:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Sutherlandinstitute] We need a “PostBS” civics – starting in elementary and middle school</title><link>https://s35049.pcdn.co/we-need-a-postbs-civics/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;To build lasting democratic habits, we must begin teaching civics in elementary school – through age-appropriate lessons, daily modeling, and real-life engagement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://sutherlandinstitute.org/we-need-a-postbs-civics/"&gt;We need a “PostBS” civics – starting in elementary and middle school&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://sutherlandinstitute.org"&gt;Sutherland Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 12:48:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Education officials top the 2024 KPERS ‘millionaires’ list</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/2024-kpers-millionaires/</link><description>Data provided by the Kansas Public Employees Retirement System shows that Kansas has 4,758 KPERS ‘millionaires’—state and local government retirees who will collect at least $1 million in pension benefits over their first 20 years of retirement. That is an increase of 380 over last year. The complete list of KPERS ‘millionaires’ can be found at KansasOpenGov.org. [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 13:25:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Restoring the Citizens’ Voice in Florida’s Citizen’s Initiative Process</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/restoring-the-citizens-voice-in-floridas-citizens-initiative-process/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As a lifelong Floridian who cares deeply about the future of our state, I was pleased to see...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/restoring-the-citizens-voice-in-floridas-citizens-initiative-process/"&gt;Restoring the Citizens’ Voice in Florida’s Citizen’s Initiative Process&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 13:47:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] MSPC joins policy leaders at national tech summit</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/mspc-joins-policy-leaders-at-jmi-tech-summit-2025</link><description>I was proud and honored to represent Mountain States Policy Center at the James Madison Institute’s annual Tech and Innovation Summit in...</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 14:03:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Voters Aren’t Interested in New Transportation Taxes</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/transportation/voters-arent-interested-in-new-transportation-taxes/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By John A. Charles, Jr. The Oregon legislature ended on June 27 without...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/transportation/voters-arent-interested-in-new-transportation-taxes/"&gt;Voters Aren’t Interested in New Transportation Taxes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 14:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Press Release: Mississippi Center for Public Policy Named Finalist for National Bob Williams Award</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/press-release-mississippi-center-for-public-policy-named-finalist-for-national-bob-williams-award/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE (Jackson, MS) Mississippi Center for Public Policy Named Finalist for National Bob Williams Award The Mississippi Center for Public Policy (MCPP) has been selected as a finalist for the prestigious Bob Williams Award for Outstanding Policy Achievement in the “Biggest Home State Win” category. This national recognition, awarded by the State Policy [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/press-release-mississippi-center-for-public-policy-named-finalist-for-national-bob-williams-award/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Press Release: Mississippi Center for Public Policy Named Finalist for National Bob Williams Award&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 15:02:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Stanford’s Pulitzer Winner Jack Rakove on American Independence</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/stanfords-pulitzer-winner-jack-rakove-on-american-independence/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In this week’s episode of The Learning Curve, co-hosts Alisha Searcy and Massachusetts civics teacher Kelley Brown interview Pulitzer Prize-winning historian Jack Rakove, Coe Professor Emeritus at Stanford University. Prof. Rakove explores the origins of the American Revolution and U.S. Constitution through the lives of the nation’s Founding Era figures. Reflecting on young John Adams’ vivid depiction of his schoolhouse in colonial Massachusetts, Rakove offers context for the political and social landscape of the 18th-century America.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/stanfords-pulitzer-winner-jack-rakove-on-american-independence/"&gt;Stanford&amp;#8217;s Pulitzer Winner Jack Rakove on American Independence&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 15:25:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Another Union Takeover – This Time Buried In Housing Bills</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/another-union-takeover-this-time-buried-in-housing-bills/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=another-union-takeover-this-time-buried-in-housing-bills</link><description>&lt;p&gt;You would have to dig into the fine print of legislation signed yesterday to see how non-union business owners and workers got screwed, again. If A Tree Falls In The Forest And No One Hears It &amp;#8211; Did It Make A Noise? What we witnessed yesterday afternoon should alarm every Californian who values free enterprise...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/another-union-takeover-this-time-buried-in-housing-bills/"&gt;Another Union Takeover – This Time Buried In Housing Bills&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 16:52:45 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>