<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>State-Policy Think-Tank Digest</title><link>https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml</link><description>Latest posts from free-market policy institutes across the U.S.</description><atom:link href="https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 23:06:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Policy Pathway for Principled Tax Reform</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/policy-pathway-for-principled-tax-reform/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Policy Pathway for Principled Tax Reform outlines a framework for evaluating tax policy through the lens of sound tax principles including transparency, simplicity, stability, neutrality, and economic efficiency. The report examines Nebraska’s major tax types including property, income, and sales and offers practical, principle-based recommendations to improve affordability, competitiveness, and long-term fiscal sustainability. While designed...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/policy-pathway-for-principled-tax-reform/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Policy Pathway for Principled Tax Reform&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 19:40:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cardinalinstitute] Healthcare in West Virginia</title><link>https://cardinalinstitute.com/healthcare-in-west-virginia/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Healthcare in West Virginia Healthcare policy is complicated. These resources make it understandable. If you are trying to make sense of West Virginia’s latest healthcare debates, you are not alone. PBM regulation, PEIA’s recurring funding crises, and Certificate of Need laws all affect what care costs, where it is available, and who has choices. We [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com/healthcare-in-west-virginia/"&gt;Healthcare in West Virginia&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com"&gt;Cardinal Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 15:44:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] If You Want Parent Power, Only HB2 Will Do</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/if-you-want-parent-power-only-hb2-will-do/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past few years, Mississippi lawmakers have passed some critical conservative reforms.&amp;#160;Last year, Mississippi became the first state in America to legislate to eliminate the income tax in 40 years.&amp;#160; In 2022, we implemented flat tax reform.&amp;#160; A few years before that, we passed important labor market reforms.&amp;#160; In 2024, we reformed school funding [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/if-you-want-parent-power-only-hb2-will-do/" rel="nofollow"&gt;If You Want Parent Power, Only HB2 Will Do&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 16:09:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Rifreedom] MEDIA RELEASE: Center Launches Petition Calling for Affordable Energy Policies</title><link>https://rifreedom.org/2026/01/media-release-center-launches-petition-calling-for-affordable-energy-policies/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Rhode Island Center for Freedom &amp;#038; Prosperity today announced that it has launched an online petition drive calling for policymakers to support a fundamental pivot away from our state's current energy strategy, which will lead to staggeringly high electricity prices and potentially dangerous blackouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org/2026/01/media-release-center-launches-petition-calling-for-affordable-energy-policies/"&gt;MEDIA RELEASE: Center Launches Petition Calling for Affordable Energy Policies&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org"&gt;RI Center for Freedom and Prosperity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 14:19:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Open enrollment: Know the basics</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2026/01/open-enrollment-know-the-basics/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In 2025, New Hampshire legislators passed a law allowing students to enroll in any public school within their assigned district, as long as the school had room. This year, lawmakers might allow students to enroll in any New Hampshire public school that has room. This policy brief answers six core questions commonly raised about open [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2026/01/open-enrollment-know-the-basics/"&gt;Open enrollment: Know the basics&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 19:28:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] Day One, Energy First: Governor Mikie Sherrill’s Opening Strategy on Affordability</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/01/day-one-energy-first-governor-mikie-sherrills-opening-strategy-on-affordability/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Sean Barry, NJPI Jr. Fellow When Governor Mikie Sherrill was sworn in as New Jersey’s 57th governor, she did [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/01/day-one-energy-first-governor-mikie-sherrills-opening-strategy-on-affordability/"&gt;Day One, Energy First: Governor Mikie Sherrill’s Opening Strategy on Affordability&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 19:08:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] A New Governor Takes Office. Will She Deliver on Education?</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/01/a-new-governor-takes-office-will-she-deliver-on-education/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;by Aiden DeMarsey, NJPI Jr. Fellow &amp;#160; Governor Mikie Sherrill, sworn into office last week, enters her term with a [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/01/a-new-governor-takes-office-will-she-deliver-on-education/"&gt;A New Governor Takes Office. Will She Deliver on Education?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 19:10:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] New housing permits are highest since 2006, but single-family homes lag</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2026/01/new-housing-permits-are-highest-since-2006-but-single-family-homes-lag/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New Hampshire towns and cities are permitting more residential housing units than they have in years, which is great news. But the new units are skewed heavily toward rentals, suggesting that local restrictions on small, single-family homes remain a significant barrier. Local governments issued permits for 5,822 new housing units in 2024, the highest number [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2026/01/new-housing-permits-are-highest-since-2006-but-single-family-homes-lag/"&gt;New housing permits are highest since 2006, but single-family homes lag&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:16:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] The Denial of Distinctions</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/the-denial-of-distinctions/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Denial of Distinctions By Abe Greenwald Yesterday, I wrote about the return of American disorder in the form of mobs that obstruct ICE raids. Part of what makes anti-ICE/open-border activism so strange is that it attacks the most fundamental aspect of what it means to be a country: its physical boundaries. When leftists repeat, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/the-denial-of-distinctions/"&gt;The Denial of Distinctions&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:37:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Crime is down, and it should end ‘root cause’ excuse-making for good</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/crime-is-down-and-it-should-end-root-cause-excuse-making-for-good/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/crime-is-down-and-it-should-end-root-cause-excuse-making-for-good/"&gt;Crime is down, and it should end ‘root cause’ excuse-making for good&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 22:13:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Introducing TennSight, Tennessee’s only hub for voter insights</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/introducing-tennsight-tennessees-only-hub-for-voter-insights/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=introducing-tennsight-tennessees-only-hub-for-voter-insights</link><description>We hope that TennSight will become the go-to source for you to learn what matters most to your fellow Tennesseans, why it matters, and what can be done about it.</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 13:08:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Idaho schools paying $1.2 million per year for IEA/NEA dues</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/labor/idaho-schools-paying-1-2-million-per-year-for-iea-nea-dues/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;According to a new Freedom Foundation analysis, the Boise and Twin Falls School Districts are spending more than $1.2 million per year on programs to cover the cost of teachers union dues to the Idaho Education Association. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/labor/idaho-schools-paying-1-2-million-per-year-for-iea-nea-dues/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Idaho schools paying $1.2 million per year for IEA/NEA dues&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 17:33:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Beacon Poll: January 2026 Results</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/beacon-poll-january-2026-results/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=beacon-poll-january-2026-results</link><description>Today, we released the latest installment of the Beacon Poll, a statewide survey of 1,200 Tennessee voters featuring questions about voters’ views on property taxes, the federal school choice tax credit included in the One Big Beautiful Bill Act, and political approval ratings at the state and federal level, and more. Tennesseans continue to prioritize key...</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 19:35:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Age Verification Isn’t Parenting</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/age-verification-isnt-parenting/</link><description>Kansas lawmakers are weighing a proposal that would require new age-verification measures for online platforms, part of a growing national effort to address concerns about children’s safety in digital spaces. The goal is understandable. Parents across Kansas want their kids protected online. The harder question is how far government should go—and whether mandates aimed at [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 16:00:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cardinalinstitute] Op-Ed: Hospitals Collect Tax Breaks. West Virginians Collect Medical Debt.</title><link>https://cardinalinstitute.com/op-ed-hospitals-collect-tax-breaks-west-virginians-collect-medical-debt/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;To many West Virginians, healthcare continues to be a burden more than a lifeline as roughly 180,000 residents, or 13.3% of adults, now facing some sort of  medical debt. This is well above the national average of 8.6% and, even worse, nearly one in four of these residents in rural Appalachia have medical debt in [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com/op-ed-hospitals-collect-tax-breaks-west-virginians-collect-medical-debt/"&gt;Op-Ed: Hospitals Collect Tax Breaks. West Virginians Collect Medical Debt.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com"&gt;Cardinal Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 15:16:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Why Portland’s Suggested Statewide Eviction Moratorium Would Hurt Maine’s Housing Market</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/why-portlands-suggested-statewide-eviction-moratorium-would-hurt-maines-housing-market/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Portland city officials are urging Gov. Janet Mills to impose a 60-day statewide eviction moratorium in response to “fear and instability” that they are linking to federal immigration enforcement. While the resolution is framed as an emergency measure that they are claiming is only meant to protect “vulnerable residents,” such a moratorium risks repeating a [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/why-portlands-suggested-statewide-eviction-moratorium-would-hurt-maines-housing-market/"&gt;Why Portland&amp;#8217;s Suggested Statewide Eviction Moratorium Would Hurt Maine’s Housing Market&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 16:38:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] Tim Pawlenty: The Crisis Will Subside in Minnesota, but Trust Will Need to be Rebuilt</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/tim-pawlenty-the-crisis-will-subside-in-minnesota-but-trust-will-need-to-be-rebuilt/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;We’ll all be part of that task. Here’s where efforts could be focused. By Tim Pawlenty For the Star Tribune It’s been said that trust is the glue that holds relationships together. That may well explain why recent events in Minnesota have stretched our relationship with government to the breaking point. Fraudsters stole a ton [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/tim-pawlenty-the-crisis-will-subside-in-minnesota-but-trust-will-need-to-be-rebuilt/"&gt;Tim Pawlenty: The Crisis Will Subside in Minnesota, but Trust Will Need to be Rebuilt&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 19:57:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] The Numbers Don’t Lie: The CHOOSE Act is Empowering Alabama’s Families</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2026/02/04/the-numbers-dont-lie-the-choose-act-is-empowering-alabamas-families/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For decades, the Alabama Policy Institute has championed a simple, powerful idea: every child in Alabama deserves a high-quality education, regardless of their zip code or their size of their parents’ bank account. With the passage and implementation of the CHOOSE Act, that vision is finally becoming a reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2026/02/04/the-numbers-dont-lie-the-choose-act-is-empowering-alabamas-families/"&gt;The Numbers Don’t Lie: The CHOOSE Act is Empowering Alabama’s Families&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 22:48:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] 312 Out of More than 3 Million Votes</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/312-out-of-more-than-3-million-votes/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Federal prosecutors are closing in on prosecuting more than 100 Minnesotans for rampant fraud in several social service programs designed to serve children and low-income residents. By the time the US Attorney’s office is done investigating, charging, convicting, and sentencing these felons, this unchecked fraud will significantly increase Minnesota’s prison population. But there’s one other [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/312-out-of-more-than-3-million-votes/"&gt;312 Out of More than 3 Million Votes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 13:58:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Education Is Economic Development: Why Business Leaders Should Support House Bill</title><link>https://empowerms.org/education-is-economic-development-why-business-leaders-should-support-house-bill/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This article was originally published in the February 2026 edition of the Mississippi Business Journal. Mississippi’s business community understands a basic but often overlooked reality: economic development does not begin with tax incentives or site selectors. It begins with people. If we want our state to grow, we must be able to attract, retain, and&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/education-is-economic-development-why-business-leaders-should-support-house-bill/"&gt;Education Is Economic Development: Why Business Leaders Should Support House Bill&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 18:43:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Record-breaking start to 2026: 6,000 employees opt out</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/record-breaking-start-to-2026-6000-employees-opt-out/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Freedom Foundation set an all-time record in January with 6,000 public employees opting out—topping our previous record by nearly 3,000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/record-breaking-start-to-2026-6000-employees-opt-out/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Record-breaking start to 2026: 6,000 employees opt out&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 18:57:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] A Badger Institute policy report: Character education and teacher retention</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/a-badger-institute-policy-report-character-education-and-teacher-retention/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Wisconsinites should be concerned the state's growing crisis of disappearing educators — a phenomenon the Badger Institute has been taking a closer look at. Multiple studies confirm that retaining good teachers is essential to school effectiveness and student achievement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/a-badger-institute-policy-report-character-education-and-teacher-retention/"&gt;A Badger Institute policy report: Character education and teacher retention&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 20:25:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Rifreedom] TESTIMONY: Senate Commission to Study the Successful Implementation of the Act on Climate</title><link>https://rifreedom.org/2026/02/senate-commission-act-on-climate/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In this powerful testimony, Mike Stenhouse, CEO of the RI Center for Freedom &amp;#038; Prosperity, explains why energy policy—not taxes, not housing, not government services—is the single most important determinant of Rhode Island’s future prosperity or poverty. Whether one believes in climate change or not, the economic consequences of the Act on Climate are unavoidable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org/2026/02/senate-commission-act-on-climate/"&gt;TESTIMONY: Senate Commission to Study the Successful Implementation of the Act on Climate&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org"&gt;RI Center for Freedom and Prosperity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 21:12:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] BERGEN RECORD: NJ climate superfund is a blank check with no accountability | Opinion</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/02/bergen-record-nj-climate-superfund-is-a-blank-check-with-no-accountability-opinion/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;#160; New Jersey’s Climate Superfund Is a Blank Check With No Accountability by Rosemary Becchi New Jersey lawmakers are considering [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/02/bergen-record-nj-climate-superfund-is-a-blank-check-with-no-accountability-opinion/"&gt;BERGEN RECORD: NJ climate superfund is a blank check with no accountability | Opinion&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 13:58:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Governor Mills’ Supplemental Budget Abandons Fiscal Discipline, Sets Maine Up for Higher Costs</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/governor-millss-supplemental-budget-abandons-fiscal-discipline-sets-maine-up-for-higher-costs/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Governor Janet Mills’ FY 2026 supplemental budget marks a clear break from the fiscal restraint her administration often claimed to practice. Rather than using Maine’s strong revenue growth to stabilize taxpayers after years of tax increases and inflation, the proposal dramatically expands spending, broadens emergency powers, and doubles down on distortionary tax policy choices that [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/governor-millss-supplemental-budget-abandons-fiscal-discipline-sets-maine-up-for-higher-costs/"&gt;Governor Mills’ Supplemental Budget Abandons Fiscal Discipline, Sets Maine Up for Higher Costs&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 17:22:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Stacked Local Taxes Are Making Virginia Less Affordable, Not More</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/stacked-local-taxes-are-making-virginia-less-affordable-not-more/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="630" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/virginia-local-taxes-v2.jpg" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Virginia’s restaurant and lodging sector is still in a fragile post-COVID recovery, yet local governments across the Commonwealth are piling on new and higher taxes that make affordability worse for families and survival harder for small businesses. A new statewide analysis of meals, lodging, and related sales taxes across all 133 Virginia localities by the&amp;#160;Virginia [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/stacked-local-taxes-are-making-virginia-less-affordable-not-more/"&gt;Stacked Local Taxes Are Making Virginia Less Affordable, Not More&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 17:43:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Affordability tops the list of state priorities for 2026</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/affordability-tops-the-list-of-state-priorities-for-2026/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/affordability-tops-the-list-of-state-priorities-for-2026/"&gt;Affordability tops the list of state priorities for 2026&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 21:36:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] 2026 Capitol Chat: Week 5</title><link>https://empowerms.org/2026-capitol-chat-week-5/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Capitol Chat: Week 5 Week 5 at the Capitol featured some of the most consequential policy and political moves yet. In this episode, we walk through some of the biggest developments, including shifts in the education debate, major House action, an update on the ballot initiative, and another big deadline on the horizon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/2026-capitol-chat-week-5/"&gt;2026 Capitol Chat: Week 5&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 22:11:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Ayotte: Maximize economic freedom, and New Hampshire will thrive</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2026/02/ayotte-maximize-economic-freedom-and-new-hampshire-will-thrive/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Gov. Kelly Ayotte’s 2026 State of the State address can be summed up in seven words: New Hampshire wins by competing on freedom. Leading with a list of eight No. 1 national rankings for the state—including economic freedom, economic opportunity and taxpayer return on investment—Ayotte noted that, overall, “U.S. News ranks us the #2 state [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2026/02/ayotte-maximize-economic-freedom-and-new-hampshire-will-thrive/"&gt;Ayotte: Maximize economic freedom, and New Hampshire will thrive&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 14:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Nine More Massachusetts Towns Subject of State Litigation over MBTA Communities Act Noncompliance</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/nine-more-massachusetts-towns-subject-of-state-litigation-over-mbta-communities-act-noncompliance/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;February's edition of The House Call discusses new legal action over Massachusetts' multifamily zoning mandate for transit-accessible communities. It also highlights a new federal data release that shows where many Massachusetts homeowners tend to overestimate - or underestimate - their property values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/nine-more-massachusetts-towns-subject-of-state-litigation-over-mbta-communities-act-noncompliance/"&gt;Nine More Massachusetts Towns Subject of State Litigation over MBTA Communities Act Noncompliance&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 16:58:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] Alabama Senate unanimously passes App Store Accountability Act</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2026/02/09/alabama-senate-unanimously-passes-app-store-accountability-act/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The App Store Accountability Act passed the Alabama Senate with a unanimous vote on Feb. 5. The bill is focused on online safety for children and teens by requiring parental approval for kids to download apps from the App Store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2026/02/09/alabama-senate-unanimously-passes-app-store-accountability-act/"&gt;Alabama Senate unanimously passes App Store Accountability Act&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 23:47:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] Alabama Senate passes App Store age verification requirement</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2026/02/10/alabama-senate-passes-app-store-age-verification-requirement/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Lawmakers spoke before the Senate in favor of shielding minors from inappropriate content, requiring parental permission for account creation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2026/02/10/alabama-senate-passes-app-store-age-verification-requirement/"&gt;Alabama Senate passes App Store age verification requirement&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 02:12:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Legislators Not Curious About Cost, Safety or Efficiency As Massive Battery Mandate Rushes Toward Approval</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/legislators-not-curious-about-cost-safety-or-efficiency-as-massive-battery-mandate-rushes-toward-approval/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="720" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Virginia-green-battery-mandate.jpg" width="1280" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, a Senate committee is scheduled to take up the bill directing Virginia’s two investor-owned utilities to propose huge battery installations that will cover square miles of ground, cost ratepayers billions of dollars, and produce zero energy to power our homes and businesses. The bill has Governor Abigail Spanberger’s endorsement. So far, legislators have been in a “see, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/legislators-not-curious-about-cost-safety-or-efficiency-as-massive-battery-mandate-rushes-toward-approval/"&gt;Legislators Not Curious About Cost, Safety or Efficiency As Massive Battery Mandate Rushes Toward Approval&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 03:40:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Testimony of Bill Hammond on the Health and Medicaid Budget for FY 2027</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/testimony-of-bill-hammond-on-the-health-and-medicaid-budget-for-fy-2027/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Testimony of Bill Hammond Senior Fellow, Empire Center for Public Policy Before the Joint Legislative Fiscal Committees February 10, 2026....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/testimony-of-bill-hammond-on-the-health-and-medicaid-budget-for-fy-2027/"&gt;Testimony of Bill Hammond on the Health and Medicaid Budget for FY 2027&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 13:36:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Hammond Calls for Restraint on Medicaid Spending</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/hammond-calls-for-restraint-on-medicaid-spending/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Albany, N.Y. — The state and its taxpayers cannot afford to allow Medicaid spending to keep growing at five times the....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/hammond-calls-for-restraint-on-medicaid-spending/"&gt;Hammond Calls for Restraint on Medicaid Spending&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 13:36:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Freedom Foundation Attorneys Secure Compensation from SEIU 099 for a Public-School Employee</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/litigation/freedom-foundation-attorneys-secure-compensation-from-seiu-099-for-a-public-school-employee/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Freedom Foundation attorneys have successfully freed California public school employee Keshawna Adams from SEIU 099’ unconstitutional dues deductions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/litigation/freedom-foundation-attorneys-secure-compensation-from-seiu-099-for-a-public-school-employee/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation Attorneys Secure Compensation from SEIU 099 for a Public-School Employee&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 17:52:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] Book: ‘Decade of Disunion’</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2026/02/book-decade-of-disunion/</link><description>by Mark Franke I have a fondness for counter-factual history, perhaps too much so. This category of fiction begins with a what if question about some critical point in history and then hypothesizes a chain of events to follow. Some end up with a radically different ending while others argue that history would have worked&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2026/02/book-decade-of-disunion/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 12:09:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Strengthening families for generational change: GCO welcomes Travis Thorne to the team</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/welcoming-travis-thorne/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/welcoming-travis-thorne/"&gt;Strengthening families for generational change: GCO welcomes Travis Thorne to the team&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 14:26:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Fox News: Gradually, Then Suddenly, Blue State America Is Heading for Financial Disaster</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/fox-news-gradually-then-suddenly-blue-state-america-is-heading-for-financial-disaster/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In his famous 20th century novel &amp;#8220;The Sun Also Rises,&amp;#8221; Ernest Hemingway’s character, Mike Campbell, was asked by...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/fox-news-gradually-then-suddenly-blue-state-america-is-heading-for-financial-disaster/"&gt;Fox News: Gradually, Then Suddenly, Blue State America Is Heading for Financial Disaster&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 14:34:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF talks to KOAT TV about roads</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-talks-to-koat-tv-about-roads/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;SB 2 has passed which means that the road issue has been &amp;#8220;put to bed&amp;#8221; for the time being. The bill which has been signed by the Gov. includes: $1.5 billion in new road spending via a bond (debt) package. This also includes: A 35% increase in the weight-distance tax on trucks A 25% increase [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-talks-to-koat-tv-about-roads/"&gt;RGF talks to KOAT TV about roads&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 16:09:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Wisconsin Senate Passes WILL-Backed ﻿“Red Tape Reset”</title><link>https://will-law.org/wisconsin-senate-passes-will-backed-red-tape-reset/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The WILL-backed “Red Tape Reset” is one step closer to becoming law after the Wisconsin State Senate voted in favor of the legislative package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/wisconsin-senate-passes-will-backed-red-tape-reset/"&gt;Wisconsin Senate Passes WILL-Backed ﻿“Red Tape Reset”&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 19:13:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Watch: The Public Safety Climate in the City of St Louis</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/article/state-and-local-government/watch-the-public-safety-climate-in-the-city-of-st-louis/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On January 21, 2026, the Show-Me Institute hosted an in-depth discussion on crime and public safety trends in the City of St. Louis at the Knight Center at Washington University. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/article/state-and-local-government/watch-the-public-safety-climate-in-the-city-of-st-louis/"&gt;Watch: The Public Safety Climate in the City of St Louis&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 19:57:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] More Evidence on Grade Inflation in Our Schools</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/article/performance/more-evidence-on-grade-inflation-in-our-schools/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Listen to this article QNS, a local news outlet covering Queens, New York, released an interesting article about a local high school under investigation by New York City Public Schools. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/article/performance/more-evidence-on-grade-inflation-in-our-schools/"&gt;More Evidence on Grade Inflation in Our Schools&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 22:10:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Governor Evers To Consider “Teacher Bill of Rights” Legislation</title><link>https://will-law.org/governor-evers-to-consider-teacher-bill-of-rights-legislation/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL applauds the Wisconsin State Assembly and State Senate for acting on AB 614 / SB 611, known as the Teacher Bill of Rights. The bill creates protections for teachers and students by strengthening teachers’ authority to manage their classrooms, requiring parental notification when serious incidents occur, and establishing clear accountability so teachers can focus on teaching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/governor-evers-to-consider-teacher-bill-of-rights-legislation/"&gt;Governor Evers To Consider “Teacher Bill of Rights” Legislation&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 23:36:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Governor Newsom: Turn Up the Delta Pumps!</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/turn-up-the-delta-pumps/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=turn-up-the-delta-pumps</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When it comes to the water supply in California for cities and farms, nothing matters more than how we manage the Sacramento-San Joaquin Delta. As of 2/09 we were 132 days into the 2025-26 rainfall season which began on 10/01/2025. That’s enough time to get an idea of how delta management is shaping up this...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/turn-up-the-delta-pumps/"&gt;Governor Newsom: Turn Up the Delta Pumps!&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 23:47:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] California Forever Stagnating</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/california-forever-stagnating/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=california-forever-stagnating</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When Permission Replaces Property Rights, the California Dream Becomes a Dream Deferred For over a century, California stood as a frontier of first resort for the ambitious, attracting those eager to escape old-world constraints in exchange for a promise of radical autonomy. This California Dream was not a byproduct of luck; it was forged by...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/california-forever-stagnating/"&gt;California Forever Stagnating&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 01:05:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Michigan only enacted 74 laws in 2025. So what?</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2026/michigan-only-enacted-74-laws-in-2025-so-what</link><description>It’s more important to kill bad bills than to pass good ones</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG: DPI’s Refusal to Explain $368,885 Secret Waterpark Meeting  Risks Invalidation of New Exam Standards</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-dpis-refusal-to-explain-368885-secret-waterpark-meeting-risks-invalidation-of-new-exam-standards/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;IRG: DPI’s Refusal to Explain $368,885 Secret Waterpark Meeting  Risks Invalidation of New Exam Standards 3 Questions The Legislature Needs DPI to Immediately Answer Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government is raising new questions surrounding the Department of Public Instruction’s actions to hold its Wisconsin Forward Exam standard-setting workshop in private, at a [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-dpis-refusal-to-explain-368885-secret-waterpark-meeting-risks-invalidation-of-new-exam-standards/"&gt;IRG: DPI’s Refusal to Explain $368,885 Secret Waterpark Meeting  Risks Invalidation of New Exam Standards&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 13:59:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Domestic Outmigration is Hollowing Out Massachusetts’ Workforce and Economy</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/domestic-outmigration-is-hollowing-out-massachusetts-workforce-and-economy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;From April 2020 through July 2025, Massachusetts experienced a net loss of approximately 182,000 residents to domestic outmigration — the equivalent of losing one-and-a-half Cambridges. While a recent surge in international immigration temporarily boosted labor force numbers, new research from Pioneer Institute shows that underlying demographic, workforce, and economic challenges continue to threaten the Commonwealth’s long-term competitiveness. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/domestic-outmigration-is-hollowing-out-massachusetts-workforce-and-economy/"&gt;Domestic Outmigration is Hollowing Out Massachusetts’ Workforce and Economy &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 14:37:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Florida Politics: Florida’s A+ Plan To Help ‘Plan B’ Families</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/floridas-a-plan-to-help-plan-b-families/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;February 11, 2026 Lawmakers seek to expand private school classroom access It was a curious finding that seemed...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/floridas-a-plan-to-help-plan-b-families/"&gt;Florida Politics: Florida’s A+ Plan To Help ‘Plan B’ Families&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 14:47:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] The Wisconsin Higher-Ed Reform Model</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/the-wisconsin-higher-ed-reform-model/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Republican lawmakers managed to pass a conservative-coded policy in a purple state with a Democratic governor. It’s all well and good to point to Florida or Texas and wish that every state could do likewise. Unfortunately, not every state capitol boasts a conservative governor ready to pick controversial fights backed up by a large Republican majority. Wisconsin demonstrates that even purple states can win meaningful, albeit limited, conservative victories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/the-wisconsin-higher-ed-reform-model/"&gt;The Wisconsin Higher-Ed Reform Model&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 15:34:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Bipartisan electoral politics stand in the way of property tax relief</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/electoral-politics-property-tax-relief/</link><description>Kansas homeowners aren’t just facing higher property taxes — they’re facing unaffordable assessed valuation increases that make it impossible to budget for life essentials or stay in their homes. Property tax is the #1 affordability issue facing many Kansans, but nothing may be done about it – again – because electoral politics is the #1 [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 15:59:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] An Open Letter to Maine’s Legislature: Stop Advancing a Bill You Know is Unconstitutional</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/an-open-letter-to-maines-legislature-stop-advancing-a-bill-you-know-is-unconstitutional/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Last June, Maine Policy Institute urged Governor Janet Mills to veto LD 1666, a bill expanding ranked-choice voting (RCV) to elections for governor, state senator, and state representative. That request was grounded in clear constitutional text, the Maine Supreme Judicial Court’s 2017 advisory opinion, and Governor Mills’ own legal analysis as Attorney General. Since then, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/an-open-letter-to-maines-legislature-stop-advancing-a-bill-you-know-is-unconstitutional/"&gt;An Open Letter to Maine’s Legislature: Stop Advancing a Bill You Know is Unconstitutional&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 16:39:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Medicaid mission-creeps its way into the housing business</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/medicaid-mission-creeps-its-way-into-providing-homes-for-wisconsinites/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Very few people know it, but Wisconsin’s Medicaid program is in the housing business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not construction or real estate, but assistance in finding a home for any Medicaid recipient with a qualifying health or mental health issue and a qualifying risk of homelessness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/medicaid-mission-creeps-its-way-into-providing-homes-for-wisconsinites/"&gt;Medicaid mission-creeps its way into the housing business&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 17:31:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2026/02/the-outstater-327/</link><description>The Media: Prescience Matters &amp;#8220;A journalist needs a disciplined reverence for the facts, because the temptations of story-telling are strong and seductive.&amp;#8221; — Lance Morrow in &amp;#8220;The Noise of Typewriters&amp;#8221; A SCHOLAR OF OUR FOUNDATION&amp;#160;is an expert at framing questions, instructions and context for Artificial Intelligence (AI). He&amp;#160;and others are training a new profession, Prompt&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2026/02/the-outstater-327/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 18:20:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Louisiana’s Grid Gambit: Is It Time to Let Private Power Play?</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/energy/private-power-play/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Last month, the New Orleans City Council voted unanimously to impose a one-year moratorium on data center development across the city. The debate was heated and familiar: overwhelming concerns about the strain these facilities could place on an already vulnerable grid, the risk of compromised reliability during our next storm season, and the potential for higher electricity...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/energy/private-power-play/"&gt;Louisiana’s Grid Gambit: Is It Time to Let Private Power Play?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 18:45:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Texas Parents Break Records for School Choice Applications</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/education/texas-parents-break-records-for-school-choice-applications/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Kathryn Hickok At last count, more than one and a half million...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/education/texas-parents-break-records-for-school-choice-applications/"&gt;Texas Parents Break Records for School Choice Applications&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 19:45:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Metro’s Plan for Making Housing More Expensive</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/reports/metros-plan-for-making-housing-more-expensive/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Randal O’Toole High housing prices in the Portland area led to a&amp;#160;legislative...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/reports/metros-plan-for-making-housing-more-expensive/"&gt;Metro’s Plan for Making Housing More Expensive&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 20:18:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] Jake Curtis Joins the Benjamin Yount Show</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/jake-curtis-joins-the-benjamin-yount-show/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Listen to the interview here. https://youtu.be/sxbsni1kot4?si=EU3oINN-O1XkTNTN&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/jake-curtis-joins-the-benjamin-yount-show/"&gt;Jake Curtis Joins the Benjamin Yount Show&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 21:03:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG urges Wisconsin lawmakers to question DPI secrecy</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-urges-wisconsin-lawmakers-to-question-dpi-secrecy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;IRG urges Wisconsin lawmakers to question DPI secrecy (The Center Square) – It’s not just the nearly $400,000 expense that has one watchdog group wanting more from Wisconsin’s public school managers. The Institute for Reforming Government on Thursday said lawmakers in Madison need to question the secrecy around the Department of Public Instruction&amp;#8217;s 2024 meeting to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-urges-wisconsin-lawmakers-to-question-dpi-secrecy/"&gt;IRG urges Wisconsin lawmakers to question DPI secrecy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 21:08:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Legislature Advances WILL-Backed Initiatives to Rein in Regulatory Authority of Unelected Bureaucrats</title><link>https://will-law.org/legislature-advances-will-backed-initiatives-to-rein-in-regulatory-authority-of-unelected-bureaucrats/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Wisconsin Assembly voted in favor of several legislative initiatives supported by WILL to reign in the bureaucratic state, which has taken rulemaking and regulatory authority away from Wisconsin’s Legislative Branch.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/legislature-advances-will-backed-initiatives-to-rein-in-regulatory-authority-of-unelected-bureaucrats/"&gt;Legislature Advances WILL-Backed Initiatives to Rein in Regulatory Authority of Unelected Bureaucrats&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 23:19:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] California’s healthcare industrial complex is booming. Guess who’s paying?</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/californias-healthcare-industrial-complex-is-booming-guess-whos-paying/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=californias-healthcare-industrial-complex-is-booming-guess-whos-paying</link><description>&lt;p&gt;California’s hospitals recorded $11.3 billion in total net income in 2024 — 10% above pre-pandemic levels. The average hospital CEO in the state earns roughly $920,000 a year. And the largest union representing healthcare workers collected $114.5 million in dues in 2024 alone, according to its federal LM-2 filing — spending just 16 cents of...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/californias-healthcare-industrial-complex-is-booming-guess-whos-paying/"&gt;California’s healthcare industrial complex is booming. Guess who’s paying?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 03:28:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] I (heart) freedom, and you should too</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2026/i-(heart)-freedom-and-you-should-too</link><description>The Mackinac Center has many ways to show you care</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Tariffs: The high price homebuilding pays for protectionism</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/tariffs-the-high-price-homebuilding-pays-for-protectionism/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Reality-television stars are rarely consulted on matters of public policy. But in April, Realtor.com asked Tarek El Moussa to comment on the White House’s “Liberation Day” tariffs.. The Southern California entrepreneur, who rose to fame on the popularity of HGTV’s Flip or Flop franchise, warned that higher import taxes would harm “new-home builders” and “first-time buyers” the most [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/tariffs-the-high-price-homebuilding-pays-for-protectionism/"&gt;Tariffs: The high price homebuilding pays for protectionism&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 11:00:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Shedding Light on Louisiana’s Boards and Commissions: Opportunities for Transparency, Accountability, and Reform</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/legal-regulatory/shedding-light-louisiana/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Louisiana’s occupational licensing boards get a lot of attention, and rightfully so. The state requires a permission slip from the government to work in 77 of 102 lower income occupations, making it the sixth worst state for occupational licensing burden in the U.S., according to the Institute for Justice. However, there are hundreds of boards...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/legal-regulatory/shedding-light-louisiana/"&gt;Shedding Light on Louisiana’s Boards and Commissions: Opportunities for Transparency, Accountability, and Reform&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 14:22:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] A Better Path Forward – Winter 2026</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/a-better-path-forward-template-copy/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="A Better Path Forward &amp;#8211; Winter 2026" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/a-better-path-forward-02-2026.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Iowa landscape in winter is frozen, still, and largely dormant. The Iowa Legislature, on the other hand, is anything but once it convenes each January. This year is no exception. Within the first two weeks of the 2026 session, lawmakers introduced three major property tax reform bills—an early burst of activity we believe signals meaningful opportunities for taxpayer wins in the months ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/a-better-path-forward-template-copy/"&gt;A Better Path Forward &amp;#8211; Winter 2026&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 15:17:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] A new framework for reviewing Washington’s K–12 education mandates</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/post/a-new-framework-for-reviewing-washington-s-k-12-education-mandates</link><description>If the Legislature expects results from schools, it must also regularly assess whether its own policies are clear, relevant, and properly funded.</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 15:25:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Nebraska Shouldn’t Tax Social Media Accounts</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-shouldnt-tax-social-media-accounts/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Under LB 1025, Nebraska would implement a first-in-the-nation tax on social media accounts, at rates of up to $6 per account per year. Other states have considered similar taxes, but no state has adopted a social media tax to date, and with good reason. The proposed tax could deprive Nebraskans of free access to online...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-shouldnt-tax-social-media-accounts/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Nebraska Shouldn’t Tax Social Media Accounts&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 15:38:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Democrats Vote to ‘Disenfranchise’ Rural Voters by Outsourcing Virginia’s Presidential Vote and Gerrymandering Its Congressional Map</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/the-jefferson-journal-democrats-vote-to-disenfranchise-rural-voters-by-outsourcing-virginias-presidential-vote-and-gerrymandering-its-congressional-map/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="720" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/gerrymandering.jpg" width="1280" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a dizzying display of power, the Democrats in the General Assembly voted this week to assign Virginia’s electoral college votes to the Presidential candidate who wins voter-dense urban and suburban areas in other states nationwide. They also voted to approve a&amp;#160;gerrymandered&amp;#160;congressional map that will give progressive and populous Northern Virginia control over five Virginia [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/the-jefferson-journal-democrats-vote-to-disenfranchise-rural-voters-by-outsourcing-virginias-presidential-vote-and-gerrymandering-its-congressional-map/"&gt;Democrats Vote to &amp;#8216;Disenfranchise&amp;#8217; Rural Voters by Outsourcing Virginia&amp;#8217;s Presidential Vote and Gerrymandering Its Congressional Map&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 15:43:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] An Election-Year Budget That Keeps SEBAC Comfortable</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/02/13/an-election-year-budget-that-keeps-sebac-comfortable/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an election year, Connecticut’s state employee unions appear positioned for another significant round of compensation growth.   While lawmakers debate fiscal guardrails and warn of federal funding uncertainty, the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/02/13/an-election-year-budget-that-keeps-sebac-comfortable/"&gt;An Election-Year Budget That Keeps SEBAC Comfortable&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 16:52:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] New York’s Electricity Prices Among the Highest in the Country</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/new-yorks-electricity-prices-among-the-highest-in-the-country/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Albany, NY — New York households continue to pay some of the highest electricity prices in the nation, according to data from....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/new-yorks-electricity-prices-among-the-highest-in-the-country/"&gt;New York’s Electricity Prices Among the Highest in the Country&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 16:54:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] 2026 Capitol Chat: Week 6</title><link>https://empowerms.org/2026-capitol-chat-week-6/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Capitol Chat: Week 6 From floor votes to a few “spirited” House measures, Week 6 had a little bit of everything. We break down the education bills still moving, the buzz around a recent voice vote, and what’s brewing as lawmakers eye the next big deadline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/2026-capitol-chat-week-6/"&gt;2026 Capitol Chat: Week 6&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 17:22:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Newsmax: CMS Should Be Embracing Fla.’s Medicaid Success Story</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/newsmax-cms-should-be-embracing-fla-s-medicaid-success-story/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A decade ago, as speaker of the Florida House of Representatives, I&amp;#160;led&amp;#160;the fight against Medicaid expansion under Obamacare....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/newsmax-cms-should-be-embracing-fla-s-medicaid-success-story/"&gt;Newsmax: CMS Should Be Embracing Fla.&amp;#8217;s Medicaid Success Story&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 17:33:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Washington legislation would target parked cars to pay for light rail cost overruns</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/post/washington-legislation-would-target-parked-cars-to-pay-for-light-rail-cost-overruns</link><description>The phrase “render unto Caesar” comes into play here, but politicians should understand that they are to represent the people of Washington state, who have said time and time again that car tabs are just too damn high.</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 17:41:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Portland’s “Affordable” Housing Averages $800 per Square Foot</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/land-use/portlands-affordable-housing-averages-800-per-square-foot/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Randal O’Toole Note: This post is a sequel to Metro’s Plan for...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/land-use/portlands-affordable-housing-averages-800-per-square-foot/"&gt;Portland’s “Affordable” Housing Averages $800 per Square Foot&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 17:46:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] School Budget Questions We Should Be Asking</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/school-budget-questions-we-should-be-asking/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="School Budget Questions We Should Be Asking" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/school-board.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;School boards control spending and every budget involves choices. While administrators draft proposals, boards hold the legal responsibility to set priorities. Claims that “we have no choice” should be questioned, because budgeting always involves tradeoffs in programs, staffing, compensation, benefits, and district structure. Spending decisions should be evaluated through a per-pupil and outcomes lens. Enrollment trends drive funding, making per-pupil spending a critical metric. Programs and projects—whether new buildings or tutoring initiatives—should be evaluated based on cost per student and measurable results. Long-term sustainability requires aligning staffing, compensation, facilities, and reserves with enrollment realities. Declining enrollment and rising benefit costs create financial pressure, making it essential to right-size operations, strategically reward effective educators, responsibly manage benefits, and use reserves for stability, not to delay difficult decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/school-budget-questions-we-should-be-asking/"&gt;School Budget Questions We Should Be Asking&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 17:47:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Antonin Scalia died 10 years ago today</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/antonin-scalia-died-10-years-ago-today/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In commemoration, I&amp;#8217;m reposting something I wtote about Justice Scalia at the time of his death. The title was &amp;#8220;We shall not look upon his like again.&amp;#8221; If constitutional government survives in this country, much of the credit will go to one man — Antonin Scalia, who died on February 13th&amp;#160;having served for 30 years...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/antonin-scalia-died-10-years-ago-today/"&gt;Antonin Scalia died 10 years ago today&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 17:59:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Abolish fuel taxes to help reduce Hawaii’s high cost of living</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/02/abolish-fuel-taxes-to-help-reduce-hawaiis-high-cost-of-living/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Senate Committee on Transportation on Feb. 12, 2026._____________ Feb. 12, 2026, 3:01 p.m.Hawaii State CapitolConference Room 229 and Videoconference To: Senate Committee on Transportation&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Sen. Lorraine R. Inouye, Chair&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Sen. Brandon J.C. Elefante, Vice Chair From: Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/02/abolish-fuel-taxes-to-help-reduce-hawaiis-high-cost-of-living/"&gt;Abolish fuel taxes to help reduce Hawaii&amp;#8217;s high cost of living&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 18:06:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Redefine ‘farm dwelling’ to include employee housing structures</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/02/redefine-farm-dwelling-to-include-employee-housing-structures/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii on Feb. 12, 2026, for consideration by the Senate Committees on Agriculture and Environment and Housing._____________ Feb. 12, 2026, 1:05 p.m.Hawaii State CapitolConference Room 225 and Videoconference To: Senate Committee on Agriculture and Environment&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Sen. Mike Gabbard, Chair&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Sen. Herbert M. &amp;#8220;Tim&amp;#8221; Richards, III, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/02/redefine-farm-dwelling-to-include-employee-housing-structures/"&gt;Redefine &amp;#8216;farm dwelling&amp;#8217; to include employee housing structures&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 18:08:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Massive ‘carbon tax’ would reduce state’s total economic output</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/02/massive-carbon-tax-would-reduce-states-total-economic-output/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii on Feb. 12, 2026, for consideration by the House Committees on Energy &amp;#38; Environmental Protection and Agriculture &amp;#38; Food Systems._____________ Feb. 12, 2026, 10:20 a.m. &amp;#160;Hawaii State CapitolConference Room 325 and Videoconference To: House Committee on Energy &amp;#38; Environmental Protection&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Rep. Nicole E. Lowen, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/02/massive-carbon-tax-would-reduce-states-total-economic-output/"&gt;Massive &amp;#8216;carbon tax&amp;#8217; would reduce state&amp;#8217;s total economic output&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 18:12:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] New bill offers police and firefighters pension buyout option</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/new-bill-offers-police-and-firefighters-pension-buyout-option/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Giving police and fire retirees a pension cash-out option would help reduce long-term pension debt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/new-bill-offers-police-and-firefighters-pension-buyout-option/"&gt;New bill offers police and firefighters pension buyout option&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 18:35:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Warm homes in a cold emergency? Thank nuclear, coal, and gas</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/warm-homes-in-a-cold-emergency-thank-nuclear-coal-and-gas/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On Feb. 1, citing expected “[e]xtremely cold temperatures,” Duke Energy sent an alert to its customers requesting that they “voluntarily reduce their energy use from 4–10 a.m. on Monday, Feb. 2, to help lessen the energy demand on the grid and reduce the potential of temporary power outages.” Duke had already obtained an emergency waiver...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/warm-homes-in-a-cold-emergency-thank-nuclear-coal-and-gas/"&gt;Warm homes in a cold emergency? Thank nuclear, coal, and gas&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 19:47:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] It’s Time to Eliminate Occupational Licensing Fees</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/02/13/its-time-to-eliminate-occupational-licensing-fees/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="1024" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/ChatGPT-Image-Feb-13-2026-02_59_10-PM.png" width="1536" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the legislative session began on Feb. 4, few issues have unified Democrat and Republican as clearly as the elimination or capping of occupational licensing fees.  These fees are government-imposed charges that professionals — from home inspectors and electricians to hairdressers, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/02/13/its-time-to-eliminate-occupational-licensing-fees/"&gt;It’s Time to Eliminate Occupational Licensing Fees&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 20:00:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Islamist Influence</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/islamist-influence/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Right under our noses in Texas, Islamist actors — cloaked in the language of charity, education, and cultural outreach — have quietly extended their influence deep into our communities, schools, and universities. What was once fringe concern has now become a strategic issue of foreign influence and ideological penetration that demands serious attention. Governor Greg...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/islamist-influence/"&gt;Islamist Influence&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 20:54:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Kansas Restores Fairness in Court with Law Ending Agency Deference</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/kansas-restores-fairness-in-court-with-law-ending-agency-deference/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In a major win for individual liberty and the separation of powers, Kansas has officially ended the practice of judicial..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/kansas-restores-fairness-in-court-with-law-ending-agency-deference/"&gt;Kansas Restores Fairness in Court with Law Ending Agency Deference&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 20:59:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Is your school led by the Illinois Federation of Teachers?</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/is-your-school-led-by-the-illinois-federation-of-teachers/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Does it matter which union represents your child’s teachers? The Illinois Federation of Teachers represents a lot of school districts where student performance is lacking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/is-your-school-led-by-the-illinois-federation-of-teachers/"&gt;Is your school led by the Illinois Federation of Teachers?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 21:19:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Winners &amp; Losers: Bettencourt Deserves a Pulitzer</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/winners-losers-bettencourt-deserves-a-pulitzer/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Every Friday morning, I join the Cardle &amp;#38; Woolley Show on Talk 1370 Radio in Austin to announce the week’s Winners &amp;#38; Losers. Friday the 13th may be the reason for so many losers this week, but there are some big winners too. Here’s who made the list. WINNER: Sen. Paul Bettencourt Gets the Story...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/winners-losers-bettencourt-deserves-a-pulitzer/"&gt;Winners &amp; Losers: Bettencourt Deserves a Pulitzer&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 21:52:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Illinois “spending cuts” aren’t from good behavior</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/illinois-spending-cuts-arent-from-good-behavior/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Illinois lawmakers claim the state saved nearly $500 million in fiscal year 2026, but most “savings” are either from federal decisions or shifting costs, not serious fiscal restraint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/illinois-spending-cuts-arent-from-good-behavior/"&gt;Illinois “spending cuts” aren’t from good behavior&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 22:39:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Warning signs: Four California cities are facing fiscal crises in 2026</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/warning-signs-four-california-cities-are-facing-fiscal-crises-in-2026/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Many California cities will not fare so well on the fiscal roulette wheel. They’re not in Silicon Valley. Their local companies do not include Apple, NVIDIA, Meta/Facebook or Alphabet/Google (whose co-founders are leaving the state, while corporate HQ will remain). Those and many other companies’ rising stock valuations shed tax revenues like my dog Ollie’s [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/warning-signs-four-california-cities-are-facing-fiscal-crises-in-2026/"&gt;Warning signs: Four California cities are facing fiscal crises in 2026&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 11:00:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] A Piece of Heaven: Arizona Turns 114</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/a-piece-of-heaven-arizona-turns-114/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Senator Barry Goldwater once said that “Arizona is 113,400 square miles of heaven that God cut out.” On Arizona’s 114th birthday,..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/a-piece-of-heaven-arizona-turns-114/"&gt;A Piece of Heaven: Arizona Turns 114&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 12:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Voters can lower their own property taxes under Michigan rules</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2026/voters-can-lower-their-own-property-taxes-under-michigan-rules</link><description>Legislators ought to strengthen rules that require popular support of tax hikes</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 10:58:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Does California Need Billionaires?</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/does-california-need-billionaires/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;If supporters are able to rack up 874 ,641 signatures, the 2026 Billionaire Tax Act will appear on the Nov. 3 ballot. Should it pass, it will levy “a one-time 5% tax on billionaire wealth.” Rather than waiting until voters make their decision, a few billionaires have already left California, including PayPal and Palantir co-founder Peter Thiel and [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/does-california-need-billionaires/"&gt;Does California Need Billionaires?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 11:00:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] When “American Studies” Can’t Say Anything Good About America</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/when-american-studies-cant-say-anything-good-about-america/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;What would you say about a publication devoted to writing about America that never has anything positive to say about..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/when-american-studies-cant-say-anything-good-about-america/"&gt;When “American Studies” Can’t Say Anything Good About America&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 13:00:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] Franke: Daylight Saving Folly</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2026/02/franke-daylight-saving-folly/</link><description>by Mark Frank “Time is the only scarce commodity.”&amp;#160;I heard this on a Viking commercial from company chairman Torstein Hagen. His point, I assume, is don’t put off things you have always wanted to do. Since Viking’s clientele is largely aging retirees, his advice is certainly well given. The problem with time is that it&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2026/02/franke-daylight-saving-folly/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 13:41:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] What can Minnesotans expect from this legislative session?</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/what-can-minnesotans-expect-from-this-legislative-session/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Minnesota&amp;#8217;s legislature convenes tomorrow. What can we expect in terms of economic policy? Not too much, perhaps, given its partisan composition. The House remains tied between Republicans and Democrats and the DFL maintains its one-seat majority in the Senate. Even so, WCCO spoke to party leaders and offers a useful summary. Sifting through some of...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/what-can-minnesotans-expect-from-this-legislative-session/"&gt;What can Minnesotans expect from this legislative session?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 14:00:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Presidents’ Day: Two and a Half Centuries of Leadership—and the Limits That Sustain It</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/principles-of-liberty/presidents-day/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This year, Louisianans observe two holidays on the same day—celebrating Lundi Gras with their communities and Presidents’ Day with the rest of the nation. While the traditions and festivities of Carnival season should be enjoyed, the history and significance of Presidents’ Day should not be overlooked. Presidents’ Day was first established to honor the birthday...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/principles-of-liberty/presidents-day/"&gt;Presidents’ Day: Two and a Half Centuries of Leadership—and the Limits That Sustain It&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 14:12:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Statement of Jim Stergios, Executive Director of Pioneer Institute on Governor Healey’s Opposition to Lowering State Income Tax</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/statement-of-jim-stergios-executive-director-of-pioneer-institute-on-governor-healeys-opposition-to-lowering-state-income-tax/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On Friday, Governor Healey opposed a proposed cut in the personal income tax that would put an average of $1,300 back into people’s pockets. Her claim that it would devastate the budget and gut education is a wild distortion—and it ignores more...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/statement-of-jim-stergios-executive-director-of-pioneer-institute-on-governor-healeys-opposition-to-lowering-state-income-tax/"&gt;Statement of Jim Stergios, Executive Director of Pioneer Institute on Governor Healey’s Opposition to Lowering State Income Tax&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 14:12:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Rifreedom] Center Launches K-12 Student Video Contest to Celebrate America’s 250th Birthday #America250RI</title><link>https://rifreedom.org/2026/02/center-launches-k-12-student-video-contest-to-celebrate-americas-250th-birthday-america250ri/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In recognition of President's Day and George Washington's upcoming birthday, the  RI Center for Freedom &amp;#038; Prosperity today launched a video contest encouraging K-12 students to create a video about why they are proud to celebrate America's semiquincentennial, commemorating the 250th Anniversary of the US Declaration of Independence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org/2026/02/center-launches-k-12-student-video-contest-to-celebrate-americas-250th-birthday-america250ri/"&gt;Center Launches K-12 Student Video Contest to Celebrate America&amp;#8217;s 250th Birthday #America250RI&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org"&gt;RI Center for Freedom and Prosperity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 14:18:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Research Note: Updates in Regulatory Restraint</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/research-note-updates-in-regulatory-restraint/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In recent years, states across the country have taken renewed interest in reviewing longstanding and often outdated regulatory frameworks. Many legislatures are reassessing rules that may constrain economic growth, aiming to reduce regulatory accumulation and increase legislative oversight of unelected agencies. Although each state varies in its approach, a common goal has emerged: limiting high-cost...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/research-note-updates-in-regulatory-restraint/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Research Note: Updates in Regulatory Restraint&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 14:18:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] The Fast Track Permits Act could make housing more affordable and attainable in Wyoming</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/post/the-fast-track-permits-act-could-make-housing-more-affordable-and-attainable-in-wyoming</link><description>The Fast Track Permits Act is a great start to making housing more affordable and attainable in Wyoming. And in coming years, legislators should continue to find ways to allow more people across the income spectrum to enjoy home ownership and build generational wealth.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 14:57:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] The Cost of an Unforgiving Compliance System</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/the-cost-of-an-unforgiving-compliance-system/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="The Cost of an Unforgiving Compliance System" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/bank.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is often labeled “de-banking” is largely the result of an outdated and rigid federal regulatory framework rooted in the 1970s Bank Secrecy Act that incentivizes banks to over-comply to avoid severe penalties. Political signaling by regulators, combined with strict confidentiality rules around Suspicious Activity Reports, leaves banks cautious and opaque, fueling public frustration and perceptions of ideological targeting. Meaningful reform must occur at the federal level by modernizing compliance standards and disclosure rules; state-by-state approaches risk creating confusion without fixing the underlying problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/the-cost-of-an-unforgiving-compliance-system/"&gt;The Cost of an Unforgiving Compliance System&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 15:08:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Connecticut’s Latest Housing “Reform” Continues to Erode Local Control — Without Solving Affordability</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/02/16/connecticuts-latest-housing-reform-continues-to-erode-local-control-without-solving-affordability/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="1024" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/ChatGPT-Image-Feb-16-2026-at-11_17_14-AM.png" width="1536" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connecticut lawmakers are once again turning to a familiar strategy for addressing housing shortages: override local zoning authority and impose uniform rules from Hartford.  S.B. 151 — scheduled for a [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/02/16/connecticuts-latest-housing-reform-continues-to-erode-local-control-without-solving-affordability/"&gt;Connecticut’s Latest Housing “Reform” Continues to Erode Local Control — Without Solving Affordability &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 16:18:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Assessing Tax Trends in the City of El Paso</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/assessing-tax-trends-in-the-city-of-el-paso/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Does history suggest that property taxes are too high in the city of El Paso? And, if so, have local decision-makers actively helped or hurt the situation?   To help answer these questions, let’s review the city’s 2024 Annual Comprehensive Financial Report (ACFR) and gather four types of data—i.e., tax levies, local population, total tax rates, and taxable values—over a 10-year time horizon. Using these audited estimates, we can gauge the growth of government (i.e., tax...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/assessing-tax-trends-in-the-city-of-el-paso/"&gt;Assessing Tax Trends in the City of El Paso&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 17:34:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Economic Updates Suggest Kansas Can Lead</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/economic-updates-suggest-kansas-can-lead/</link><description>If you only look at Kansas’s unemployment rate, you might think everything is fine. That’s the political trap: point to a low number, declare victory, and move on.  But the latest state labor and economic output data show a more complicated truth. Kansas has real strengths, but it’s also leaving growth on the table because [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 19:15:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Virginiainstitute] Repealing Certificate of Need Laws: A Path to Affordable, Accessible Healthcare in Virginia</title><link>https://virginiainstitute.org/repealing-con/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=repealing-con</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The United States healthcare system faces a crisis of escalating costs, limited access, and stifled innovation. At the heart of these challenges lie outdated Certificate of Need (CON) laws—regulations rooted&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org/repealing-con/"&gt;Repealing Certificate of Need Laws: A Path to Affordable, Accessible Healthcare in Virginia&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org"&gt;Virginia Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 19:20:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] New tool tracks K-12 staffing changes by district</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/new-tool-tracks-k-12-staffing-changes-by-district/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A new interactive tool from Georgetown University&amp;#8217;s Edunomics Lab gives school leaders, parents, and community members the ability to assess how public school staffing has changed in recent years. The WANDA K-12 workforce dataset, which draws from the National Center for Education Statistics, allows users to compare staffing levels with enrollment trends by district and...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/new-tool-tracks-k-12-staffing-changes-by-district/"&gt;New tool tracks K-12 staffing changes by district&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 21:16:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] 2-16 data dump: Midterm primary off to a (relatively) brisk start</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/2-16-data-dump-midterm-primary-off-to-a-relatively-brisk-start/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Early voting for the March 3 primary is underway. Here are a few early data points from Vote Tracker. Note, the numbers in the 2024 link will change as some counties report submitted ballots later. Voting is ahead of the 2022 pace So far, turnout is higher than at a similar point in 2022. That...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/2-16-data-dump-midterm-primary-off-to-a-relatively-brisk-start/"&gt;2-16 data dump: Midterm primary off to a (relatively) brisk start&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 21:33:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Senate Bill 1294 — Infant hearing loss screening (-3)</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/senate-bill-1294-infant-hearing-loss-screening/</link><description>Bill Description:&amp;#160;Senate Bill 1294 would mandate hearing tests for newborns, contingent on continued receipt of federal funding. Rating: -3 Does it create, expand, or enlarge any agency, board, program, function, or activity of government? Conversely, does it eliminate or curtail the size or scope of government? Senate Bill 1294 would create Section 39-905A, Idaho Code, [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 22:36:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] House Bill 637 — Gold and silver, legal tender (+1)</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/house-bill-637-gold-and-silver-legal-tender/</link><description>Bill Description:&amp;#160;House Bill 637 would recognize that foreign-minted gold and silver coin and specie is legal tender.&amp;#160; Rating: +1 Does it violate the spirit or the letter of either the United States Constitution or the Idaho Constitution? Examples include restrictions on speech, public assembly, the press, privacy, private property, or firearms. Conversely, does it restore [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 22:40:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Teachers’ Unions Get Desperate</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/article/education/teachers-unions-get-desperate/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A recent editorial in the Wall Street Journal lays out what has been on the minds of many (or at least mine) for some time. The traditional education establishment that [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/article/education/teachers-unions-get-desperate/"&gt;Teachers’ Unions Get Desperate&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 22:42:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] House Bill 638 — Presidential primary (-2)</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/house-bill-638-presidential-primary/</link><description>Bill Description:&amp;#160;House Bill 638 would create a March primary for presidential elections at an estimated cost of $2.5 million.&amp;#160; Rating: -2 Does it create, expand, or enlarge any agency, board, program, function, or activity of government? Conversely, does it eliminate or curtail the size or scope of government? Currently, Idaho has a May Primary Election [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 22:43:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] North Dakota pioneers Lead Teacher Registered Apprenticeships</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/north-dakota-pioneers-lead-teacher-registered-apprenticeships/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;North Dakota will soon be experimenting with team-taught classroom models. The Peace Garden state recently became the first state in the nation to be approved by the U.S. Department of Labor for a new Lead Teacher Registered Apprenticeship. North Dakota educators utilizing the apprenticeship will receive support through a partnership between the North Dakota Department...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/north-dakota-pioneers-lead-teacher-registered-apprenticeships/"&gt;North Dakota pioneers Lead Teacher Registered Apprenticeships&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 22:52:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>