<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>State-Policy Think-Tank Digest</title><link>https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml</link><description>Latest posts from free-market policy institutes across the U.S.</description><atom:link href="https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 02:44:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>[Arkansaspolicyfoundation] ARKANSAS GOV. SARAH HUCKABEE SANDERS &amp; STATE INCOME TAX CUTS</title><link>https://arkansaspolicyfoundation.org/arkansas-gov-sarah-huckabee-sanders-state-income-tax-cuts/</link><description>(4Q-2025) Arkansas Gov. Sarah Huckabee Sanders is the Natural State’s first female governor. Since taking office in January 2023, Sanders has also distinguished herself by advancing three separate reductions in Arkansas’ top income tax rate from 4.9 to 3.9 percent. The income tax was reduced from 7.0% to 6.9% in 2013 under Democratic Gov. Mike [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 14:33:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Todd Schaible: The Importance of Career and Technical Education in Tennessee Schools</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/todd-schaible-the-importance-of-career-technical-education-in-tennessee-schools/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=todd-schaible-the-importance-of-career-technical-education-in-tennessee-schools</link><description>By elevating CTE in Tennessee schools, we can increase support for employers and improve workforce readiness for students across the state.</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 15:34:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] Albuquerque Journal editorializes in defense of free speech, Rio Grande Foundation in “hoodie-gate”</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/albuquerque-journal-editorializes-in-defense-of-free-speech-rio-grande-foundation-in-hoodie-gate/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Rio Grande Foundation has received a great deal of publicity from all corners of Albuquerque&amp;#8217;s political scene due to our involvement in reporting on the I ♥ Tim Keller &amp;#8220;hoodies for the homeless&amp;#8221; effort. As we&amp;#8217;ve discussed at length here and in other locations the Mayor&amp;#8217;s campaign has reacted to our reporting and refusal [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/albuquerque-journal-editorializes-in-defense-of-free-speech-rio-grande-foundation-in-hoodie-gate/"&gt;Albuquerque Journal editorializes in defense of free speech, Rio Grande Foundation in &amp;#8220;hoodie-gate&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 16:53:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Mississippi's Free-Market Turnaround: A Model for America</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/mississippis-free-market-turnaround-a-model-for-america/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For decades, Mississippi has been the punchline in national discussions about economic performance - often ranked at the bottom in income, education, and opportunity. But something remarkable has happened in recent years: the Magnolia State is undergoing a genuine resurgence, driven not by federal handouts or gimmicks, but by principled free-market reforms. A major national [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/mississippis-free-market-turnaround-a-model-for-america/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi&amp;#039;s Free-Market Turnaround: A Model for America&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 21:13:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Enrollment and Employment: Is Tennessee Preparing K-12 Students for Today’s Economy?</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/enrollment-and-employment-is-tennessee-preparing-k-12-students-for-todays-economy/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=enrollment-and-employment-is-tennessee-preparing-k-12-students-for-todays-economy</link><description>Tennessee is doing well in providing Career and Technical Education (CTE) opportunities to students, but policymakers should recognize that improvements can be made.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 02:17:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Pioneer New England Legal Foundation and Sullivan &amp; Worcester Sue Boston Over Retaliatory Tax Scheme</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/pioneer-legal-foundation-sullivan-worcester-sue-boston-over-retaliatory-tax-scheme/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Class action challenges city’s unlawful penalties against commercial taxpayers who exercised their right to appeal; seeks court intervention to end this retaliatory scheme in next fiscal year&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/pioneer-legal-foundation-sullivan-worcester-sue-boston-over-retaliatory-tax-scheme/"&gt;Pioneer New England Legal Foundation and Sullivan &amp;amp; Worcester Sue Boston Over Retaliatory Tax Scheme&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 18:43:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Youngkin Proposes More Tax Relief in His Final Budget, Which Still Sets New Records for Revenue, Spending</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/youngkin-proposes-more-tax-relief-in-his-final-budget-which-still-sets-new-records-for-revenue-spending/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="720" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Glenn-Youngkin-Closeup.jpg" width="1280" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Governor Glenn Youngkin has proposed that Virginia conform its tax rules to most of the changes in federal taxes adopted by Congress last summer, including recognizing a state tax deduction for tip income, overtime pay and interest payments on car loans. Those tax policy recommendations are part of the Republican’s final introduced state budget package, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/youngkin-proposes-more-tax-relief-in-his-final-budget-which-still-sets-new-records-for-revenue-spending/"&gt;Youngkin Proposes More Tax Relief in His Final Budget, Which Still Sets New Records for Revenue, Spending&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 06:49:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Florida Politics: The Ghost (Students) of Public School Future?</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/florida-politics-the-ghost-students-of-public-school-future/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;U.S. Secretary of Education Linda McMahon announced last week that her department plans to step up efforts to...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/florida-politics-the-ghost-students-of-public-school-future/"&gt;Florida Politics: The Ghost (Students) of Public School Future?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 14:49:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Santa aids Freedom Foundation outreach for another holiday season</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/santa-aids-freedom-foundation-outreach-for-another-holiday-season/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;To cut through the holiday and end-of-year chaos, we took a familiar twist. As they do every year, our outreach team members suited up as Santa Claus and his helpers to spark conversations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/santa-aids-freedom-foundation-outreach-for-another-holiday-season/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Santa aids Freedom Foundation outreach for another holiday season&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 21:05:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] U.S. House defangs federal protection of gray wolves in Wisconsin</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/us-house-defangs-federal-protection-of-gray-wolves-in-wisconsin/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The U.S. House of Representatives Thursday passed a bill that would remove the state’s rapidly expanding and aggressive gray wolf population from the endangered species list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/us-house-defangs-federal-protection-of-gray-wolves-in-wisconsin/"&gt;U.S. House defangs federal protection of gray wolves in Wisconsin&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 22:32:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Ugly Math for Taxpayers</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/ugly-math-for-taxpayers/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=ugly-math-for-taxpayers</link><description>Taxpayer-funded lobbying (TFL) is nothing new in Tennessee, but it is almost universally frowned upon.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 22:52:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Oregon’s “Prosperity Roadmap” Must Follow the Path of Liberty</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/economic-opportunity/oregons-prosperity-roadmap-must-follow-the-path-of-liberty/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Naomi Inman Early this December, Governor Tina Kotek’s newsroom unveiled “Oregon’s Prosperity...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/economic-opportunity/oregons-prosperity-roadmap-must-follow-the-path-of-liberty/"&gt;Oregon’s “Prosperity Roadmap” Must Follow the Path of Liberty&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 00:20:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Ninety New York Educators Receive $300k+ in Annual Pay</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/ninety-new-york-educators-receive-300k-in-annual-pay/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Ninety employees from New York’s school districts (outside New York City) received more than $300,000 during fiscal year 2025, according....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/ninety-new-york-educators-receive-300k-in-annual-pay/"&gt;Ninety New York Educators Receive $300k+ in Annual Pay&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 14:27:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] CDC Labels Minority Neighborhoods as “Vulnerable,” Encouraging the Spread of DEI Spending Nationwide</title><link>https://will-law.org/cdc-labels-minority-neighborhoods-as-vulnerable-encouraging-the-spread-of-dei-spending-nationwide/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In new findings provided to the Trump Administration’s Health and Human Services (HHS) agency, WILL has uncovered that the Center for Disease Control (CDC) uses a race-based criteria to declare whole communities and neighborhoods as “socially vulnerable” based on the number of minorities living there. Cities and states around the country rely on the CDC’s “social vulnerability index” (SVI) to allocate taxpayer funding for parks, drinking water, and disaster assistance.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/cdc-labels-minority-neighborhoods-as-vulnerable-encouraging-the-spread-of-dei-spending-nationwide/"&gt;CDC Labels Minority Neighborhoods as “Vulnerable,” Encouraging the Spread of DEI Spending Nationwide&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 18:18:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Modernizing Financial Oversight: Senator Tim Scott’s STREAMLINE Act and the Case for Reducing Regulatory Burden</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/modernizing-financial-oversight-senator-tim-scotts-streamline-act-and-the-case-for-reducing-regulatory-burden/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Streamlining Transaction Reporting and Ensuring Anti-Money Laundering Improvements for a New Era Act (STREAMLINE Act), introduced by...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/modernizing-financial-oversight-senator-tim-scotts-streamline-act-and-the-case-for-reducing-regulatory-burden/"&gt;Modernizing Financial Oversight: Senator Tim Scott’s STREAMLINE Act and the Case for Reducing Regulatory Burden&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] California Home Care Workers Take on Union Abuse in Court</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/litigation/california-home-care-workers-take-on-union-abuse-in-court/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, the Freedom Foundation filed a class-action lawsuit against United Domestic Workers of America, AFSCME Local 3930 (UDW) on behalf of in-home supportive services (IHSS) workers across California. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/litigation/california-home-care-workers-take-on-union-abuse-in-court/" rel="nofollow"&gt;California Home Care Workers Take on Union Abuse in Court&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 15:50:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] In Case You Missed It: WILL Raised Key Voter Roll Concerns Ahead of DOJ Lawsuit</title><link>https://will-law.org/in-case-you-missed-it-will-raised-key-voter-roll-concerns-ahead-of-doj-lawsuit/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Department of Justice has filed a lawsuit against the Wisconsin Election Commission’s (WEC) for refusing to comply with their investigation into the state’s voter rolls. The request from USDOJ was for a copy of Wisconsin’s computerized registration list including information necessary to audit the list for ineligible voters, including driver’s license number and/or the last 4 digits of the social security number. The lawsuit also comes after an investigation from our organization released earlier this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/in-case-you-missed-it-will-raised-key-voter-roll-concerns-ahead-of-doj-lawsuit/"&gt;In Case You Missed It: WILL Raised Key Voter Roll Concerns Ahead of DOJ Lawsuit&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 15:57:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] Civic Foundations: Are we Properly Preparing the Next Generation of Citizens?</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/12/civic-foundations-are-we-properly-preparing-the-next-generation-of-citizens/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;by Aiden DeMarsey – Evesham Twp. Board of Ed. Member &amp;#38; NJPI Junior Education Policy Fellow The state of New [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/12/civic-foundations-are-we-properly-preparing-the-next-generation-of-citizens/"&gt;Civic Foundations: Are we Properly Preparing the Next Generation of Citizens?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 18:30:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] The Economic and Legal Risks of New Jersey’s Proposed Climate Superfund Act</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/12/the-economic-and-legal-risks-of-new-jerseys-proposed-climate-superfund-act/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Sean Barry, NJPI Junior Energy Policy Fellow For the past several months, New Jersey lawmakers have been considering Assembly [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/12/the-economic-and-legal-risks-of-new-jerseys-proposed-climate-superfund-act/"&gt;The Economic and Legal Risks of New Jersey’s Proposed Climate Superfund Act&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 18:35:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF discusses MLG National Guard deployment as they depart</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-discusses-mlg-national-guard-deployment-as-they-depart/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In a unique example of the Rio Grande Foundation being more positive about the Gov.&amp;#8217;s policy than the Gov. herself, the Rio Grande Foundation was asked to comment on whether MLG&amp;#8217;s deployment of the National Guard to Albuquerque was &amp;#8220;a disappointment.&amp;#8221; On the one hand, while we 100% agree with the Gov. that &amp;#8220;lax engagement [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-discusses-mlg-national-guard-deployment-as-they-depart/"&gt;RGF discusses MLG National Guard deployment as they depart&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 18:49:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] From Magna Carta to Mass Arrests: Britain’s Warning to America</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/from-magna-carta-to-mass-arrests-britains-warning-to-america/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Imagine facing arrest simply for posting sharp or critical comments online. Picture police at your door for expressing opposition to mass immigration. Envision a country where you could be imprisoned for years without a jury ever deciding your guilt. This isn't dystopian fiction - it's the reality unfolding in Britain today, my former home and [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/from-magna-carta-to-mass-arrests-britains-warning-to-america/" rel="nofollow"&gt;From Magna Carta to Mass Arrests: Britain’s Warning to America&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 20:01:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Trump’s Pause on Offshore Wind: A Chance for Reform, or a Step Towards Cancellation</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/trumps-pause-on-offshore-wind-a-chance-for-reform-or-a-step-towards-cancellation/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="720" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Trump-Offshore.jpg" width="1280" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;President Trump’s decision to suspend Dominion Energy’s massive Coastal Virginia Offshore Wind (CVOW) project is sure to stir up another gale of political fights across the Commonwealth.  While some will hail it as a triumph for fiscal and national security; others will see it as an assault on clean energy. Both sides are worthy of debate before [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/trumps-pause-on-offshore-wind-a-chance-for-reform-or-a-step-towards-cancellation/"&gt;Trump’s Pause on Offshore Wind: A Chance for Reform, or a Step Towards Cancellation&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 15:30:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Guest Editorial: The role of Credit Unions in Nebraska</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/guest-editorial-the-role-of-credit-unions-in-nebraska/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Credit unions have always stood apart from other financial services providers because of how and why they were first built starting in 1864. Credit Unions are formed by people — workers such as manufacturing employees, farmers, teachers,firefighters, church groups and more to pool their resources and provide low-cost credit to one another. That origin story...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/guest-editorial-the-role-of-credit-unions-in-nebraska/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Guest Editorial: The role of Credit Unions in Nebraska&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 16:46:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] What Is the School Choice Situation in Kansas?</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/what-is-the-school-choice-situation-in-kansas/</link><description>The debate over school choice in Kansas often gets bogged down in politics and process. But the latest data make the stakes clear. The 2026 ABCs of School Choice from EdChoice is the most comprehensive inventory of private school choice programs in the country. After 25 years of tracking these policies, EdChoice doesn’t just catalog [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:00:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] New York’s Education Shows Improvement, but Questions Remain</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/new-yorks-education-shows-improvement-but-questions-remain/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In the effort to improve transparency and accountability of New York’s education system, the Empire Center has systematized and published....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/new-yorks-education-shows-improvement-but-questions-remain/"&gt;New York&amp;#8217;s Education Shows Improvement, but Questions Remain&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 14:15:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] Allen Mendenhall: API’s Christmas wish list</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/12/26/allen-mendenhall-apis-christmas-wish-list/</link><description>&lt;p&gt; The Alabama Policy Institute (API) has delivered its "Blueprint for 2026: Building a Stronger Alabama" with the seasonal timing of a policy wonk’s Christmas morning, complete with 30 wrapped proposals arranged beneath three conceptual ornaments: free markets, limited government, and strong families.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/12/26/allen-mendenhall-apis-christmas-wish-list/"&gt;Allen Mendenhall: API&amp;#8217;s Christmas wish list&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 18:50:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF president discusses massive cost of MLG’s “free” childcare plans on KOAT 7</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-president-discusses-massive-cost-of-mlgs-free-childcare-plans-on-koat-7/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;RGF has raised concerns about the impact of the Gov&amp;#8217;s plans to expand &amp;#8220;free&amp;#8221; child care to those New Mexico families who make MORE THAN 400% of the federal poverty level (about $128,000 for a family of four). Is the program financially sustainable at a time of moderating oil revenues? According to the Legislative Finance [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-president-discusses-massive-cost-of-mlgs-free-childcare-plans-on-koat-7/"&gt;RGF president discusses massive cost of MLG&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8220;free&amp;#8221; childcare plans on KOAT 7&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 16:18:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] $2 billion Chiefs stadium deal won’t fix the Kansas economy, but property tax relief would help</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/chiefs-stadium-deal-wont-fix-kansas-economy/</link><description>Kansas Governor Laura Kelly declared it a “once-in-a-generation opportunity” to transform the state’s economy by delivering thousands of new jobs and billions of dollars in new business activity. That was in 2022, when she announced the state would give Panasonic $829 million to build an electric battery plant in Johnson County. Her hoped-for economic transformation [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 17:03:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Libertas] A Year of Impact: 1.3+ Million Families</title><link>https://libertas.org/2025-report/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In early 2025 we set out an ambitious &amp;#8220;Vivid Vision&amp;#8221; for our team to grow our impact and scale up our work, and the end-of-year results demonstrate significant progress across all our initiatives. In total, we positively impacted more than 1.3 million families! Below, watch a 15-minute update sharing our 2025 impact, presented by our [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://libertas.org/2025-report/"&gt;A Year of Impact: 1.3+ Million Families&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://libertas.org"&gt;The Libertas Network: Changing Hearts, Minds, and Laws&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 01:49:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Shrinking 82nd Avenue: John Charles Responds to Tyler Frisbee</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/transportation/shrinking-82nd-avenue-john-charles-responds-to-tyler-frisbee/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By John A. Charles, Jr. At TriMet’s December 10 board meeting, director Tyler...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/transportation/shrinking-82nd-avenue-john-charles-responds-to-tyler-frisbee/"&gt;Shrinking 82nd Avenue: John Charles Responds to Tyler Frisbee&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 23:06:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Matt’s Top Stories of 2025</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/matts-top-stories-of-2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On Matt&amp;#8217;s last WGAN show of 2025, he reflects on significant events of the year: Listen here: Newsradio WGAN · Matt&amp;#x27;s Top Stories Of 2025 Listen to Matt discuss what to anticipate in 2026: Newsradio WGAN · Looking At 2026&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/matts-top-stories-of-2025/"&gt;Matt&amp;#8217;s Top Stories of 2025&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 18:08:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Questions Come as Twin Falls School District Protects Teacher’s Explicit Content Instead of Children</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/questions-come-as-twin-falls-school-district-protects-teachers-explicit-content-instead-of-children/</link><description>For any reasonable individual, protecting children from people who engage in sexual deviance and celebrate political violence should be a no-brainer. Yet the events that unfolded in Twin Falls, Idaho, involving one concerned mother and substitute teacher, leave us wondering.&amp;#160; On October 1, 2025, Cierra Clarke — a substitute teacher and parent of a 1st [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 23:25:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Rifreedom] Stenhouse Challenges Zurier’s Special Senate Energy Commission to “Act” on the Act On Climate</title><link>https://rifreedom.org/2026/01/stenhouse-challenges-zuriers-special-senate-energy-commission-to-act-on-the-act-on-climate/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;With "affordability" top of mind for Ocean State residents, the CEO of the RI Center for Freedom &amp;#038; Prosperity  today called upon  Senator  Sam Zurier  and all members of the special Senate Energy Commission he chairs to take a w holistic and realistic look at Rhode Island's net-zero policies and Act On Climate  mandates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org/2026/01/stenhouse-challenges-zuriers-special-senate-energy-commission-to-act-on-the-act-on-climate/"&gt;Stenhouse Challenges Zurier&amp;#8217;s Special Senate Energy Commission to &amp;#8220;Act&amp;#8221; on the Act On Climate&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org"&gt;RI Center for Freedom and Prosperity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 15:02:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] NJPI Urges Lawmakers Not to Advance Bill Targeting Homeschooling Families</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/01/njpi-urges-lawmakers-not-to-advance-bill-targeting-homeschooling-families/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;by Wells Winegar, NJPI Executive Director The New Jersey Policy Institute has formally urged members of the Assembly Health Committee [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/01/njpi-urges-lawmakers-not-to-advance-bill-targeting-homeschooling-families/"&gt;NJPI Urges Lawmakers Not to Advance Bill Targeting Homeschooling Families&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 15:07:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Week in Review: The Year Freedom Fought Back</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-the-year-freedom-fought-back/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;They told parents to stay silent. They told patients to wait. They told taxpayers to pay up. In 2025, the..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-the-year-freedom-fought-back/"&gt;Week in Review: The Year Freedom Fought Back&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 16:57:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2026/01/the-outstater-317/</link><description>&amp;#8216;Alabama 27, Indiana 24&amp;#8216; THE LATE BOB BARTLEY,&amp;#160;editor of&amp;#160;the Wall Street Journal&amp;#160;editorial pages, understood the intrinsic value of journalism. He imagined a campfire of prehistoric hunters where one in the circle had a better memory for game trails than the others. That member of the party earned special privileges (a Mammoth rib perhaps) irrespective of&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2026/01/the-outstater-317/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 00:36:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2026/01/the-outstater-318/</link><description>A Word for our Times solipsism &amp;#124; ˈsäləpˌsizəm &amp;#124; noun. The quality of being self-centered or selfish. In philosophy it is the view or theory that the self is all that can be known to exist. &amp;#8220;SOLIPSISM&amp;#8221; IS A GOOD WORD.&amp;#160;More use can be made of it.&amp;#160;The late Charles Krauthammer&amp;#160; used it to characterize persons&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2026/01/the-outstater-318/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 10:58:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Freedom Foundation Sues to Block Oregon Law Silencing Worker Rights Speech</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/press-release/freedom-foundation-sues-to-block-oregon-law-silencing-worker-rights-speech/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Freedom Foundation filed a federal lawsuit challenging Oregon House Bill 3789, a law that hands public-sector unions the power to sue the organization into oblivion for doing what it's done for years: informing public employees about their constitutional rights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/press-release/freedom-foundation-sues-to-block-oregon-law-silencing-worker-rights-speech/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation Sues to Block Oregon Law Silencing Worker Rights Speech &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 17:59:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Why the approved Chiefs deal is bad economics</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/why-the-approved-chiefs-deal-is-bad-economics/</link><description>In December 2025, the deal to bring the Kansas City Chiefs across the state line was agreed upon. Supporters called it a historic win. In reality, it locked Kansas into a multi-decade financial commitment that violates one of the most basic principles of good economics: government should not pick winners and losers. This deal is [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 21:43:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Dominion Describes Efforts to Limit Turbine Radar Interference</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/dominion-describes-efforts-to-limit-turbine-radar-interference/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="720" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Turbine-Radar-Inteference.jpg" width="1280" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dominion Energy Virginia’s team building its offshore wind facility spent years working with the U.S. Navy and the air defense agency NORAD on ways to mitigate the problems that would be caused by the 836-foot-tall turbines, reaching several agreements, the utility has told a federal court. The company – meaning ultimately the company’s customers – [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/dominion-describes-efforts-to-limit-turbine-radar-interference/"&gt;Dominion Describes Efforts to Limit Turbine Radar Interference&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 03:15:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Research Note: How Changes in AI Regulation Could Affect Nebraska</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/research-note-how-changes-in-ai-regulation-could-affect-nebraska/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of weeks before Christmas, following the President’s recent executive order on artificial intelligence (AI), the Nebraska Examiner published an article examining the potential implications for Nebraska. While the precise impact of the order remains uncertain, the state’s recent legislative activity related to AI suggests the possibility of conflict between state and federal approaches....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/research-note-how-changes-in-ai-regulation-could-affect-nebraska/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Research Note: How Changes in AI Regulation Could Affect Nebraska&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 15:05:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Hartford Lawmakers Step Into a Local Labor Dispute — and Leave City Hall With the Bill</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/01/06/hartford-lawmakers-step-into-a-local-labor-dispute-and-leave-city-hall-with-the-bill/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="675" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/union_zoom_thumbnail_1200x675-1.png" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On December 23, the New Haven Federation of Teachers (NHFT) announced on social media that its bargaining team had met privately with members of New Haven’s delegation to the General [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/01/06/hartford-lawmakers-step-into-a-local-labor-dispute-and-leave-city-hall-with-the-bill/"&gt;Hartford Lawmakers Step Into a Local Labor Dispute — and Leave City Hall With the Bill &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 21:03:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Expand height-limit exemption to all buildings destroyed in Lahaina fires</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/01/expand-height-limit-exemption-to-all-buildings-destroyed-in-lahaina-fires/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Maui County Council on Jan. 7, 2026._____________ Jan. 7, 2026, 9 a.m.Kalana O Maui Building To: Maui County Council       Alice Lee, Chair       Yuki Lei Sugimura, Vice Chair From: Grassroot Institute of Hawaii            Jonathan Helton, Policy Analyst RE: Bill 183 (2025) [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/01/expand-height-limit-exemption-to-all-buildings-destroyed-in-lahaina-fires/"&gt;Expand height-limit exemption to all buildings destroyed in Lahaina fires&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 21:12:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] NEW: Findings from IRG Listening Tour and new Poll— a ground-level look at the issues Wisconsinites care about most</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/new-findings-from-irg-listening-tour-and-new-poll-a-ground-level-look-at-the-issues-wisconsinites-care-about-most/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;NEW: Findings from IRG Listening Tour and New Poll— a ground-level look at the issues Wisconsinites care about most Key lessons and insights gathered from four months of listening across Wisconsin. Delafield, Wis. – What common challenges are on Wisconsinites’ minds heading into 2026? The Institute for Reforming Government released its newest community engagement report, Wisconsin [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/new-findings-from-irg-listening-tour-and-new-poll-a-ground-level-look-at-the-issues-wisconsinites-care-about-most/"&gt;NEW: Findings from IRG Listening Tour and new Poll— a ground-level look at the issues Wisconsinites care about most&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 22:25:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Waste watch: Illinois gives $12M to NASCAR</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/waste-watch-illinois-gives-12m-to-nascar/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Illinois’ opaque budget process handed $12 million to NASCAR. Fast and furious is no way to treat taxpayers’ money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/waste-watch-illinois-gives-12m-to-nascar/"&gt;Waste watch: Illinois gives $12M to NASCAR&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 22:49:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] New Grassroot report outlines ways to build more farmworker housing</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/01/new-grassroot-report-outlines-ways-to-build-more-farmworker-housing/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Actions at the state and county levels would benefit the employees as well as farmers, ranchers and everyone who enjoys Hawaii-grown products  HONOLULU, Jan. 6, 2026 &amp;#62;&amp;#62; Hawaii farmers and ranchers often attest that attracting, training and retaining quality employees is difficult, given their sometimes remote locations and the cost of housing. The Grassroot Institute [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/01/new-grassroot-report-outlines-ways-to-build-more-farmworker-housing/"&gt;New Grassroot report outlines ways to build more farmworker housing&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 00:44:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Happy New Year! A Blueprint for Mississippi in 2026!</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/happy-new-year-a-blueprint-for-mississippi-in-2026/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As we kick off 2026, the Mississippi Center for Public Policy is more energized than ever.&amp;#160;&amp;#160;We are excited about the successes our state has seen – and we have a plan to build on that momentum with further free market reform!&amp;#160;For decades, our state lagged behind.&amp;#160;&amp;#160;Growth was slow and too many young people left our [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/happy-new-year-a-blueprint-for-mississippi-in-2026/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Happy New Year! A Blueprint for Mississippi in 2026!&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 15:35:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] House Bill 500 — Placeholder (0)</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/house-bill-500-placeholder-0/</link><description>Bill Description: House Bill 500 (2026) does not yet exist. This is a placeholder. Rating: 0 NOTE: House Bill 500 placeholder. Does it violate the spirit or the letter of either the U.S. Constitution or the Idaho Constitution? Examples include restrictions on speech, public assembly, the press, privacy, private property, or firearms. Conversely, does it restore or [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 17:35:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Proposed Ballot Questions for 2026: What Mainers Should Know</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/proposed-ballot-questions-for-2026-what-mainers-should-know/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Maine’s ballot initiative process is often described as a direct democratic safeguard, a way for citizens to place pressing policy questions before the voters when the Legislature declines to do so. But it also frequently functions as a pressure valve for interest groups attempting to bypass the scrutiny, hearings, fiscal analyses, and compromise that accompany [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/proposed-ballot-questions-for-2026-what-mainers-should-know/"&gt;Proposed Ballot Questions for 2026: What Mainers Should Know&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 17:47:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Under The Dome: Senate Education Committee Advances School Choice Bill</title><link>https://empowerms.org/senate-education-committee-advances-school-choice-bill/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, the Senate Education Committee passed Senate Bill 2002, a small but important step toward expanding educational opportunity for families across our state. For years, Mississippi law has allowed a student’s assigned public school district to effectively veto a family’s attempt to transfer to another district, even when the receiving district is willing to accept&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/senate-education-committee-advances-school-choice-bill/"&gt;Under The Dome: Senate Education Committee Advances School Choice Bill&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 18:08:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Is the Chiefs Move to Kansas Really a Done Deal?</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/budget-and-spending/is-the-chiefs-move-to-kansas-really-a-done-deal/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Patrick Tuohey joined Pete Mundo on Mundo in the Morning on KCMO Talk Radio to question whether the Kansas City [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/budget-and-spending/is-the-chiefs-move-to-kansas-really-a-done-deal/"&gt;Is the Chiefs Move to Kansas Really a Done Deal?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 20:45:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Government makes a bad Santa Claus</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2026/government-makes-a-bad-santa-claus</link><description>I know because I knew the real one</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2026/01/the-outstater-319/</link><description>Creating a Homeless Magnet AGAIN, AS CITIES throughout the nation gear up to lure business away from New York City’s socialist mayor, my city is taking a different tact. We are striving to become as much like New York City as our meager resources permit — complete with a government grocery, a casino and upgraded homeless&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2026/01/the-outstater-319/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 14:59:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Rethinking teacher compensation</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/rethinking-teacher-compensation</link><description>Teacher compensation should move beyond outdated salary schedules and begin rewarding what matters most: results for students.</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 15:29:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Crime and Public Safety in St. Louis: Upcoming Events</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/criminal-justice/crime-and-public-safety-in-st-louis-upcoming-events/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Please join us for an in-depth discussion on crime and public safety trends in St. Louis. Patrick Tuohey, Senior Fellow [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/criminal-justice/crime-and-public-safety-in-st-louis-upcoming-events/"&gt;Crime and Public Safety in St. Louis: Upcoming Events&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 15:50:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Statewide Coalition of Free Market Groups Calls for Action on “Red Tape Reset” Package</title><link>https://will-law.org/statewide-coalition-of-free-market-groups-calls-for-action-on-red-tape-reset-package/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A wide coalition of free market groups and associations representing Wisconsin’s largest job creators are calling on the Wisconsin Legislature to vote on a legislative package known as the “Red Tape Reset.”  The package was formally introduced last year and has advanced out of committee in both houses.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/statewide-coalition-of-free-market-groups-calls-for-action-on-red-tape-reset-package/"&gt;Statewide Coalition of Free Market Groups Calls for Action on “Red Tape Reset” Package&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 15:52:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Set the Floor, Not the Ceiling: Lessons From Florida’s AI Week</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/set-the-floor-not-the-ceiling-lessons-from-floridas-ai-week/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Florida House of Representatives&amp;#8217; final committee week featured their inaugural “AI week” following a directive from the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/set-the-floor-not-the-ceiling-lessons-from-floridas-ai-week/"&gt;Set the Floor, Not the Ceiling: Lessons From Florida’s AI Week&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 16:49:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Statement of Jim Stergios on New Economic Modeling of Proposed Income Tax Reduction</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/statement-of-jim-stergios-on-new-economic-modeling-of-proposed-income-tax-reduction/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;MassOpportunity&amp;#160;Alliance’s&amp;#160;new economic modeling&amp;#160;of the proposed ballot question to reduce the personal income tax from 5.0% to 4.0% confirms the findings of Pioneer Institute’s November report, Lessons from the 2000 Massachusetts Income-Tax Rollback, which&amp;#160;analyzed what&amp;#160;actually happened&amp;#160;after Massachusetts cut the income tax from 5.95 percent...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/statement-of-jim-stergios-on-new-economic-modeling-of-proposed-income-tax-reduction/"&gt;Statement of Jim Stergios on New Economic Modeling of Proposed Income Tax Reduction&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 17:19:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Nebraska’s Tax Code Lets It Compete for Data Center Investment</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/nebraskas-tax-code-lets-it-compete-for-data-center-investment/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Midwest grows many things—including, increasingly, data centers. That’s good news, generating substantial local tax revenue, creating high-paying jobs, and expanding economic opportunities.  With 39 data centers (about 19 per 1 million people), Nebraska punches above its weight nationally, while trailing neighboring Iowa, which boasts the second-highest number of data centers per capita at 32...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/nebraskas-tax-code-lets-it-compete-for-data-center-investment/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Nebraska’s Tax Code Lets It Compete for Data Center Investment&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 17:26:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Pioneer Institute Statement on Mayor Wu’s Decision to Add $100 Million to the Cost of Building a New Madison Park Technical Vocational High School</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/pioneer-institute-statement-on-mayor-wus-decision-to-add-100-million-to-the-cost-of-building-a-new-madison-park-technical-vocational-high-school/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Mayor Wu continues to push her effort to further raise Boston’s commercial property tax rate, even though as of 2022 the city already had the&amp;#160;second highest ratio of commercial to residential effective tax rates&amp;#160;among the largest cities in each state.&amp;#160;&amp;#160;Wu claims&amp;#160;that&amp;#160;cutting&amp;#160;Boston’s budget&amp;#160;to...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/pioneer-institute-statement-on-mayor-wus-decision-to-add-100-million-to-the-cost-of-building-a-new-madison-park-technical-vocational-high-school/"&gt;Pioneer Institute Statement on Mayor Wu’s Decision to Add $100 Million to the Cost of Building a New Madison Park Technical Vocational High School   &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 17:41:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] “Oregon System” Sends Governor Back to Square One</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/tax-and-budget/oregon-system-sends-governor-back-to-square-one/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Naomi Inman The final signatures were plunked down on December 30—down on...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/tax-and-budget/oregon-system-sends-governor-back-to-square-one/"&gt;“Oregon System” Sends Governor Back to Square One&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 18:01:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] How the Left and Right Can Unite to Restore Opportunity in America</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/how-the-left-and-right-can-unite-to-restore-opportunity-in-america/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=how-the-left-and-right-can-unite-to-restore-opportunity-in-america</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The scandals erupting in Minnesota offer another example of how easy it is for generous U.S. welfare programs to squander billions of dollars. And while it’s important to hold accountable the individuals who figured out how to scam the system, until the system itself is changed, for every billion-dollar fraud that is uncovered, others will take...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/how-the-left-and-right-can-unite-to-restore-opportunity-in-america/"&gt;How the Left and Right Can Unite to Restore Opportunity in America&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 18:01:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Under The Dome: House Introduces the Education Freedom Act</title><link>https://empowerms.org/house-introduces-the-education-freedom-act/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, the Mississippi House of Representatives introduced House Bill 2, the Mississippi Education Freedom Act, one of the most comprehensive education reform bills our state has considered in years. Authored by House Speaker Jason White and Representative Jansen Owen, this bill puts families first by expanding school choice, increasing transparency, and giving parents and local communities&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/house-introduces-the-education-freedom-act/"&gt;Under The Dome: House Introduces the Education Freedom Act&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 18:27:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Montana Entrepreneur Wins Right to Challenge Anti-Competitive Licensing Law</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/montana-entrepreneur-wins-right-to-challenge-anti-competitive-licensing-law/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;It may seem obvious, but budding entrepreneurs shouldn’t need permission from their prospective competitors to start a business—but that’s exactly..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/montana-entrepreneur-wins-right-to-challenge-anti-competitive-licensing-law/"&gt;Montana Entrepreneur Wins Right to Challenge Anti-Competitive Licensing Law&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 18:51:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Fewer homes on market, higher prices for Illinois buyers</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/fewer-homes-on-market-higher-prices-for-illinois-buyers/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Elevated prices thanks to low inventory continued to create problems for Illinois homebuyers in November.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/fewer-homes-on-market-higher-prices-for-illinois-buyers/"&gt;Fewer homes on market, higher prices for Illinois buyers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 18:58:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] School Choice for All Idaho Families</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/school-choice-for-all-idaho-families/</link><description>A local left-leaning podcast host had me on his show recently to talk about, among other things, Idaho’s new school choice opportunity — the Parental Choice Tax Credit (PCTC), which passed in 2025. He asked how in the world Idaho’s school choice could be “held accountable” if there were no mandatory testing or other state [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 19:58:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Matthew Gagnon on Gateway Fraud, Gubernatorial Race, Big Gov.</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/matthew-gagnon-on-gateway-fraud-gubernatorial-race-big-gov/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On his show on WGAN this week, Maine Policy Institute CEO Matthew Gagnon covered the Mills administration’s handling of the DHHS investigation into Gateway and fraud, highlighting the inadequacy of clawing back $1 million, and assails big government for its inevitable corruption. He goes on to address the Maine gubernatorial race, including Jonathan Bush&amp;#8217;s fundraising [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/matthew-gagnon-on-gateway-fraud-gubernatorial-race-big-gov/"&gt;Matthew Gagnon on Gateway Fraud, Gubernatorial Race, Big Gov.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 21:08:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Connecticut Declared a Housing Emergency. The Clock Started Ticking — and Nothing Happened</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/01/08/connecticut-declared-a-housing-emergency-the-clock-started-ticking-and-nothing-happened/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="1280" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/92098019-1920x1280-1.jpg" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;House Bill 8002 was enacted during a November special session after state leaders argued that Connecticut faced a housing emergency requiring immediate legislative action. The bill advanced without a public [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/01/08/connecticut-declared-a-housing-emergency-the-clock-started-ticking-and-nothing-happened/"&gt;Connecticut Declared a Housing Emergency. The Clock Started Ticking — and Nothing Happened&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 21:30:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Up to Data (Centers): What’s Ahead for Data Centers, Technology, and Energy in Louisiana</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/up-to-data-centers-whats-ahead-for-data-centers-technology-and-energy-in-louisiana/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In 2025, Louisiana cemented itself as an up-and-coming force in the tech industry. From leading the nation in Broadband Equity Access and Deployment (BEAD) program approvals, to showcasing artificial intelligence (AI) powered breakthroughs in our universities and hospitals, to breaking ground on multibillion-dollar data centers, the state has been busy attracting industry and innovation. As...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/up-to-data-centers-whats-ahead-for-data-centers-technology-and-energy-in-louisiana/"&gt;Up to Data (Centers): What’s Ahead for Data Centers, Technology, and Energy in Louisiana&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 21:41:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Flat Tax Success and the Case for Staying Competitive</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/flat-tax-success-and-the-case-for-staying-competitive/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Flat Tax Success and the Case for Staying Competitive" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/iowa-capitol-at-night.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Iowa has transformed its income tax system from one of the nation’s worst to a flat 3.8% rate, cutting the top rate by nearly 60% and dramatically improving the state’s tax competitiveness. This reform was made possible by conservative budgeting and spending discipline, which allowed Iowa to lower rates responsibly while maintaining strong reserves and fiscal stability. As other states continue to cut income tax rates in 2026, Iowa cannot afford to stand still, and continued spending restraint will be key to making future tax reductions possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/flat-tax-success-and-the-case-for-staying-competitive/"&gt;Flat Tax Success and the Case for Staying Competitive&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 22:08:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Lead paint: The 50-year saga continues</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/lead-paint-the-50-year-saga-continues/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Nearly 50 years after the U.S. government banned lead-based paint, Milwaukee Public Schools officials have again been trying to cover up or remove the toxic substance that parents likely presume was dealt with long ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/lead-paint-the-50-year-saga-continues/"&gt;Lead paint: The 50-year saga continues&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 22:53:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Superior coal terminal is latest victim of declining Great Lakes shipments</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/superior-coal-terminal-is-latest-victim-of-declining-great-lakes-shipments/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A decline in cargo moving across the Great Lakes via United States-flagged “lakers” has led to widely felt impacts in port towns, including at a major Superior coal terminal now slated to shutter its operations by this upcoming summer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/superior-coal-terminal-is-latest-victim-of-declining-great-lakes-shipments/"&gt;Superior coal terminal is latest victim of declining Great Lakes shipments&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 22:54:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Let subdivision planning proceed while waiting on water approval</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/01/let-subdivision-planning-proceed-while-waiting-on-water-approval/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Maui County Council on Jan. 7, 2026._____________ Jan. 7, 2026, 9 a.m.Kalana O Maui Building To: Maui County Council       Alice Lee, Chair       Yuki Lei Sugimura, Vice Chair From: Grassroot Institute of Hawaii            Joe Kent, Executive Vice President RE: Bill 1 [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/01/let-subdivision-planning-proceed-while-waiting-on-water-approval/"&gt;Let subdivision planning proceed while waiting on water approval&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 23:17:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Shaping Georgia’s future: Opportunities for the year ahead</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/top-issues-shaping-georgia-future/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The well-being of many Georgians, their families, and their communities is at stake as pressing concerns like welfare reform, the cost of living, educational opportunities, and public safety take center stage in 2026. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/top-issues-shaping-georgia-future/"&gt;Shaping Georgia’s future: Opportunities for the year ahead&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 23:49:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Trump agrees to leave 66 ‘wasteful’ global groups</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/trump-agrees-to-leave-66-wasteful-global-groups/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Jasmine Baehr writes for FoxNews.com about a significant development within the Trump administration. President Donald Trump on Wednesday signed a presidential memorandum directing the U.S. to withdraw from 66 international organizations, ordering executive departments and agencies to cease participation in and funding of entities the administration says no longer serve U.S. interests. The memorandum follows...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/trump-agrees-to-leave-66-wasteful-global-groups/"&gt;Trump agrees to leave 66 &amp;#8216;wasteful&amp;#8217; global groups&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 10:36:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Newsom confronts California’s $18B budget ‘disaster’</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/newsom-confronts-californias-18b-budget-disaster/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Annie Gaus writes for the New York Post about the California governor’s latest predicament. California Gov. Gavin Newsom is waking up to a $18 billion budget hangover — and fixing it won’t be pretty. After years of surpluses, the Golden State is facing staggering deficits that could balloon to $35 billion in the coming years,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/newsom-confronts-californias-18b-budget-disaster/"&gt;Newsom confronts California&amp;#8217;s $18B budget &amp;#8216;disaster&amp;#8217;&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 10:39:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Ag-to-Urban law creates a farmer’s market for Arizona housing</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/ag-to-urban-law-creates-a-farmers-market-for-arizona-housing/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Ag-to-Urban law creates a farmer’s market for Arizona housing By D. Dowd Muska &amp;#124; January 9, 2026 If it unites farmers, developers and environmentalists, it’s probably a sound policy reform. Some observers consider Senate Bill 1611, approved last summer by a GOP-majority Legislature and a Democratic governor, “one of the most significant pieces of legislation [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/ag-to-urban-law-creates-a-farmers-market-for-arizona-housing/"&gt;Ag-to-Urban law creates a farmer’s market for Arizona housing&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 10:39:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Documenting America’s ‘great divorce’</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/documenting-americas-great-divorce/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Editors at Issues and Insights ponder America’s migration trends. When U-Haul released its latest “Growth Index” this week, it made us wonder if blue states will ever get a clue. Once again, the index found a strong migration out of blue states and into red states. “Florida, North Carolina, and Tennessee follow Texas as prime...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/documenting-americas-great-divorce/"&gt;Documenting America&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8216;great divorce&amp;#8217;&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 10:42:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] ‘People are very bad at managing their own finances’</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/podcasts/the-overton-window/chris-surprenant-talks-integrating-financial-literacy-at-the-high-school-level-to-improve-outcomes</link><description>Chris Surprenant talks integrating financial literacy at the high school level to improve outcomes</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Legislature Approved Zero New Business Subsidies in 2025</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/pressroom/2026/legislature-approved-zero-new-business-subsidies-in-2025</link><description>Mackinac Center applauds historic win for taxpayers</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 14:24:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] School Choice Has Come to Texas</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/school-choice-has-come-to-texas/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Last month, Comptroller Kelly Hancock’s office launched the official website for the state’s new school choice program, known as Texas Education Freedom Accounts. Under TEFA, eligible Texas children can receive public funds deposited into a personalized account to be used for approved education expenses. These include private school tuition, textbooks, tutoring, specialized therapies, transportation to...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/school-choice-has-come-to-texas/"&gt;School Choice Has Come to Texas&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 15:26:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Session Preview: Property Taxes</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/session-preview-property-taxes-2026/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Session Preview: Property Taxes" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/iowa-capitol-rotunda-1200x630-1.png" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Property tax reform is shaping up to be the defining issue of Iowa’s upcoming legislative session, with bipartisan attention and growing public pressure. Rising property taxes are driven by unchecked local government spending, not by isolated flaws in the tax system. A firm 2% cap on property tax growth is essential to delivering real, lasting relief, and must be central to any serious reform effort. As Iowa lawmakers return to the Capitol, one issue has emerged as the defining policy debate of the upcoming legislative session: property taxes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/session-preview-property-taxes-2026/"&gt;Session Preview: Property Taxes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 15:40:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Breaking the K-Shaped Divide in Texas Education: Time for Bold Accountability Reforms</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/breaking-the-k-shaped-divide-in-texas-education-time-for-bold-accountability-reforms/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When I entered the first grade, I was assigned to the lowest reading group. This came as a shock to my mom, as I had always loved books. Over the winter break, my mom and I read from “Fun with Zip and Zap,” a phonics chapter book. When I returned to school after the break,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/breaking-the-k-shaped-divide-in-texas-education-time-for-bold-accountability-reforms/"&gt;Breaking the K-Shaped Divide in Texas Education: Time for Bold Accountability Reforms&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 15:40:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Pulling up the ladder: How short-term rental bans hurt families and punish success</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/pulling-up-the-ladder-how-short-term-rental-bans-hurt-families-and-punish-success</link><description>History is rarely kind to policies that treat property rights as expendable. Housing affordability will not be achieved by suffocating peaceful uses of private property, but by expanding supply and allowing markets to respond to demand.</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 15:54:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Week in Review: Families, Not Bureaucrats</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-families-not-bureaucrats/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;From Fox News to the Maine Wire, news outlets across the country are taking notice of the Goldwater Institute’s petition..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-families-not-bureaucrats/"&gt;Week in Review: Families, Not Bureaucrats&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 16:44:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] State Delays Disclosing Emails About $1B Home Health Contract</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/state-delays-disclosing-emails-about-1b-home-health-contract/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For a third time the state Health Department has postponed releasing records related to a disputed $1 billion Medicaid contract,....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/state-delays-disclosing-emails-about-1b-home-health-contract/"&gt;State Delays Disclosing Emails About $1B Home Health Contract&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 18:25:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] ‘Bridge payments’ to nowhere: time for ag to find its own path</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/bridge-payments-to-nowhere-time-for-ag-to-find-its-own-path/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Trump administration recently announced $12 billion in “bridge payments” for American farmers and ranchers to provide relief from tariffs and “other economic challenges.” American farmers and ranchers are suffering. The national Farm Aid suicide prevention hotline has reported an increase in calls year-over-year and farm bankruptcies for 2025 have already surpassed all of 2024’s [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/bridge-payments-to-nowhere-time-for-ag-to-find-its-own-path/"&gt;&amp;#8216;Bridge payments’ to nowhere: time for ag to find its own path&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 20:07:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Fading Ripples from Gov. Newsom’s Last State of the State Address</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/newsoms-last-state-of-the-state/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=newsoms-last-state-of-the-state</link><description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been years since Gov. Gavin Newsom put on a tie and made his way to the Assembly Chambers to grace the legislature with his presence and share some witty lines his whip-smart crisis communications team put together for him. He is, afterall, preparing to storm the country with his not-yet-declared-but-super-obvious campaign for the presidency...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/newsoms-last-state-of-the-state/"&gt;Fading Ripples from Gov. Newsom’s Last State of the State Address&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 20:17:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] The importance of NH’s 1776 constitution</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2026/01/the-importance-of-nhs-1776-constitution/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On Jan. 5, 1776, New Hampshire became the first self-governing British colony in North America. That astonishing decision, made 250 years ago this week, deserved a bigger celebration than it received.  After a quarter of a millennium, Americans have become accustomed to thinking that self-government is normal. It isn’t. Achieving it in 1776 was extraordinary. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2026/01/the-importance-of-nhs-1776-constitution/"&gt;The importance of NH&amp;#8217;s 1776 constitution&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 20:34:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Short Session, Long Consequences: What Labor’s 2026 Agenda Would Mean for Connecticut</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/01/09/short-session-long-consequences-what-labors-2026-agenda-would-mean-for-connecticut/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connecticut lawmakers will return to Hartford on February 4 for the state’s so-called short session — a three-month legislative sprint intended primarily for technical fixes and budget adjustments.  In practice, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/01/09/short-session-long-consequences-what-labors-2026-agenda-would-mean-for-connecticut/"&gt; Short Session, Long Consequences: What Labor’s 2026 Agenda Would Mean for Connecticut &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 20:49:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] 2026 Capitol Chat: Week 1</title><link>https://empowerms.org/2026-capitol-chat-week-1/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Capitol Chat: Week 1 Capitol Chat is back for the 2026 legislative session, which is off to a quick start after only one week! Host Wil Ervin highlights early Senate action on teacher pay and public school choice, a sweeping House education bill, and a major Senate proposal to shore up PERS, setting the tone for a&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/2026-capitol-chat-week-1/"&gt;2026 Capitol Chat: Week 1&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 21:09:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] 2026 Legislative Sessions: What lawmakers should and shouldn't do</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/mspc-policy-recommendations-for-the-2026-legislative-sessions</link><description>We have dozens of policy recommendations for lawmakers to consider. These reforms can be acted on even with the challenging budget situations across the states. Here are a couple of our top recommendations for Idaho, Washington and Wyoming lawmakers</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 21:12:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Pelican Institute CEO Daniel Erspamer Available for Media Interviews on Louisiana Coastal Litigation &amp; U.S. Supreme Court Oral Arguments</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/press-release/media-interviews-la-coastal-litigation/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE Media Contact: sydney@pelicaninstitute.org January 9, 2026 &amp;#160; New Orleans, LA— As the U.S. Supreme Court prepares to hear oral arguments Monday in Chevron U.S.A. Inc. v. Plaquemines Parish, the Pelican Institute for Public Policy is making its CEO, Daniel Erspamer, and General Counsel, Sarah Harbison, available to reporters for on camera interviews,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/press-release/media-interviews-la-coastal-litigation/"&gt;Pelican Institute CEO Daniel Erspamer Available for Media Interviews on Louisiana Coastal Litigation &amp;#038; U.S. Supreme Court Oral Arguments &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 21:14:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] The Amazing Case of Steubenville, Ohio</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/performance/the-amazing-case-of-steubenville-ohio/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Over at The74, Chad Aldeman wrote an excellent article about the remarkable reading results in Steubenville, Ohio. He shows that [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/performance/the-amazing-case-of-steubenville-ohio/"&gt;The Amazing Case of Steubenville, Ohio&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 21:28:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Winners &amp; Losers: Maduro’s in Jail, Somali’s Steal Billions and Red Meat is Back on the Menu</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/winners-losers-maduros-in-jail-somalis-steal-billions-and-red-meat-is-back-on-the-menu/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Every Friday morning, I join the Cardle &amp;#38; Woolley Show on Talk 1370 Radio in Austin to announce the week’s Winners &amp;#38; Losers. The holidays are totally over now, and 2026 is up and running in earnest with big happenings all over the world—and in Texas. Here’s who made the list:   WINNER: Trump Takes...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/winners-losers-maduros-in-jail-somalis-steal-billions-and-red-meat-is-back-on-the-menu/"&gt;Winners &amp; Losers: Maduro’s in Jail, Somali’s Steal Billions and Red Meat is Back on the Menu&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 21:34:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Louisiana’s Energy Moment: Why Competition—Not Regulatory Shortcuts—Will Power Growth and Lower Costs</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/energy/louisianas-energy-moment/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As Louisiana enters 2026, energy and infrastructure policy remain front and center. Last month’s announcement of another major artificial intelligence data center project coming to the state underscores Louisiana’s economic potential—and the growing importance of getting our regulatory framework right. The challenge is immediate and significant. Electricity demand is rising rapidly, driven by aging generation...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/energy/louisianas-energy-moment/"&gt;Louisiana’s Energy Moment: Why Competition—Not Regulatory Shortcuts—Will Power Growth and Lower Costs&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 22:28:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Chicago gets lowest employment score since 2009</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/chicago-gets-lowest-employment-score-since-2009/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Chicago’s worst employment climate score since 2009 drove a 25th month of business decline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/chicago-gets-lowest-employment-score-since-2009/"&gt;Chicago gets lowest employment score since 2009&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 22:36:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Who Took from Who’s Pocket (?) – Haiti, Colonialism, and Third World Wealth Overall</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/who-took-from-whos-pocket-haiti-colonialism-and-third-world-wealth-overall/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Killa Mike – one half of my 3rd favorite rap crew, Run the Jewels – recently went hyper-viral for his televised “wither Haiti” argument with hip comedian Bill Maher. During a live taping of Maher’s hit TV show, the hip-hopper and community activist accused European France of “eating off” and “living” off the poor Caribbean [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/who-took-from-whos-pocket-haiti-colonialism-and-third-world-wealth-overall/"&gt;Who Took from Who’s Pocket (?) – Haiti, Colonialism, and Third World Wealth Overall&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 11:00:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Session Preview: Conservative Budgeting</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/session-preview-conservative-budgeting/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Session Preview: Conservative Budgeting" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/iowa-capitol-winter.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conservative budgeting is the foundation of fiscal conservatism and the key to sustaining Iowa’s tax reforms. Spending growth has accelerated in recent budgets, even as economic uncertainty and revenue pressures increase. As lawmakers craft the FY 2027 budget, spending discipline will be essential to protecting Iowa’s fiscal stability and future tax relief. As economist Art Laffer has observed, “government spending is taxation, pure and simple.” For that reason, the starting point for any sound tax policy discussion must be spending restraint. The state budget is the foundational product of each legislative session, shaping other policy debates and determining whether past tax reforms can be sustained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/session-preview-conservative-budgeting/"&gt;Session Preview: Conservative Budgeting&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 13:20:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] The war on ICE</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/the-war-on-ice/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In just the past few weeks we&amp;#8217;ve had a rash of assaults on federal officers take place in the Metro area, which haven&amp;#8217;t been making many headlines. A few examples and a Minnesota Man update, Juan Carlos Rodriquez Romero, of Cuba, was indicted on three counts of assaulting three (3) U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/the-war-on-ice/"&gt;The war on ICE&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 17:37:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] What’s the Matter With Minnesota?</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/whats-the-matter-with-minnesota/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A culture has developed in the Walz administration that prioritizes getting money out the door to desired groups, while punishing those who get in the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/whats-the-matter-with-minnesota/"&gt;What&amp;#8217;s the Matter With Minnesota?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 13:37:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Dregs of society: the “neighbors” removed from Minnesota</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/dregs-of-society-the-neighbors-removed-from-minnesota/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A lot of Minnesotans are asking the question, “How did we get to this place where people are protesting and impeding federal law enforcement as they carry out the orders of a duly elected president?” Aren’t we all on the same team? At the moment, no, we are not on the same team. A little...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/dregs-of-society-the-neighbors-removed-from-minnesota/"&gt;Dregs of society: the “neighbors” removed from Minnesota&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 16:47:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] The Union that May Have Broken California</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/the-union-that-may-have-broken-california/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=the-union-that-may-have-broken-california</link><description>&lt;p&gt;2026 began with revelations that numerous billionaires owning upwards of $1 trillion in assets had cut ties with California just before the ball dropped on January 1. These well-heeled folks did not suddenly get tired of California’s weather, scenery, culture, or social scene. Instead, they were avoiding a potential wealth tax hatched by a group...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/the-union-that-may-have-broken-california/"&gt;The Union that May Have Broken California&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 22:43:09 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>