<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>State-Policy Think-Tank Digest</title><link>https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml</link><description>Latest posts from free-market policy institutes across the U.S.</description><atom:link href="https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 12:05:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] Day 100 of State Budget Impasse</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/10/08/day-100-of-state-budget-impasse/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On Hundredth Day of the Shapiro Shutdown, PA Democrats Push Spending &amp;#38; Tax Hikes  Harrisburg, Pa., October 8, 2025 — Day 100 of the state budget shutdown brought chaos to the Capitol rotunda, with partisan political theater from Pennsylvania House and Senate Democrats placing parties even farther apart at the negotiating&amp;#160;table.&amp;#160; After previously rejecting and [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/10/08/day-100-of-state-budget-impasse/"&gt;Day 100 of State Budget Impasse&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 00:25:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Decarceration’s Disconnect: Corrections spending rises in Georgia even as prison population declines</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/georgia-prison-spending-and-reform/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Prison reform debates often focus on reducing prison populations to save taxpayers money. But is that actually possible? In a new report for the Manhattan Institute, Joshua Crawford, Public Safety Fellow at the Georgia Center for Opportunity, reveals some surprising answers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/georgia-prison-spending-and-reform/"&gt;Decarceration’s Disconnect: Corrections spending rises in Georgia even as prison population declines&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 04:09:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] New Report: Corrections spending rises in Georgia even as prison population declines</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/new-report-corrections-spending-rises-in-georgia/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A new report by Joshua Crawford, Public Safety Fellow at the Georgia Center for Opportunity, shows that the decreasing number of inmates hasn’t translated to meaningful savings or improvements in public safety for Georgians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/new-report-corrections-spending-rises-in-georgia/"&gt;New Report: Corrections spending rises in Georgia even as prison population declines&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 23:02:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Tariffs – why we will hear a lot more about them</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/tariffs-why-we-will-hear-a-lot-more-about-them/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Remember the tariff debates that dominated Washington just a few months ago?&amp;#160; For a while it was the only thing anyone seemed to talk about.&amp;#160;First tariffs were raised by eyewatering amounts.&amp;#160; Then they weren’t.&amp;#160;&amp;#160;Eventually, after all sorts of back and forth, we saw tariffs imposed at the highest rates in decades. Free trade advocates warned [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/tariffs-why-we-will-hear-a-lot-more-about-them/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Tariffs – why we will hear a lot more about them&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 16:00:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF provides comments in support of unlocking new water supplies for New Mexicans</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-provides-comments-in-support-of-unlocking-new-water-supplies-for-new-mexicans/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;They say &amp;#8220;agua es vida&amp;#8221; in New Mexico (water is life). In the desert southwest water is critical to human flourishing and the broader economy of the state and region. So, when we were presented with an opportunity to put water that is produced alongside oil and gas, we had only one question: &amp;#8220;Is it [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-provides-comments-in-support-of-unlocking-new-water-supplies-for-new-mexicans/"&gt;RGF provides comments in support of unlocking new water supplies for New Mexicans&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 16:38:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Accountability and Action: The Path to Safer Communities</title><link>https://empowerms.org/accountability-and-action-the-path-to-safer-communities/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This past weekend, our state was rocked by a wave of violent crime. Over the course of twenty-four hours, five shootings claimed the lives of at least nine Mississippians. While these horrific acts do not appear to be connected, they are alarming nevertheless. Words like horrific, tragic, and avoidable all come to mind. First and&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/accountability-and-action-the-path-to-safer-communities/"&gt;Accountability and Action: The Path to Safer Communities&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 14:16:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] NH voters want to cut regulations to build more housing, polling confirms</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/10/nh-voters-want-to-cut-regulations-to-build-more-housing-polling-confirms/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On New Hampshire’s top economic issue, a broad consensus has formed. Voters want more housing, and they want government to make it easier to build, according to new polling. St. Anselm College’s 2025 statewide housing survey, released this week, shows that opinions have settled overwhelmingly in favor of deregulating the housing market to let builders [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/10/nh-voters-want-to-cut-regulations-to-build-more-housing-polling-confirms/"&gt;NH voters want to cut regulations to build more housing, polling confirms&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 11:30:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] New Statewide Ad Calls Out Governor Shapiro For Budget Impasse</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/10/19/new-statewide-ad-end-the-impasse-governor-shapiro/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Harrisburg, Pa., October 19, 2025 —&amp;#160;The Commonwealth Foundation has launched a new statewide ad calling on Gov. Josh Shapiro to end the state budget impasse by getting to work negotiating a bipartisan, fiscally responsible compromise that protects Pennsylvania taxpayers. Pennsylvania remains the only state in the nation without a state budget. The new ad calls [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/10/19/new-statewide-ad-end-the-impasse-governor-shapiro/"&gt;New Statewide Ad Calls Out Governor Shapiro For Budget Impasse&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 23:35:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] NJ ED REPORT: New Report: Most NJ School Districts Lack Smart Student-Centered Strategic Plans</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/10/nj-ed-report-new-report-most-nj-school-districts-lack-smart-student-centered-strategic-plans/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New Report: Most NJ School Districts Lack Smart Student-Centered Strategic Plans By  NJER Newsroom  October 15, 2025 Study of 50 district [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/10/nj-ed-report-new-report-most-nj-school-districts-lack-smart-student-centered-strategic-plans/"&gt;NJ ED REPORT: New Report: Most NJ School Districts Lack Smart Student-Centered Strategic Plans&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 13:12:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] WALL STREET JOURNAL: A Teachers Union Candidate Took My Money and Ran for Office</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/10/wall-street-journal-a-teachers-union-candidate-took-my-money-and-ran-for-office/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A Teachers Union Candidate Took My Money and Ran for Office By Marie Dupont Oct. 17, 2025 As the New [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/10/wall-street-journal-a-teachers-union-candidate-took-my-money-and-ran-for-office/"&gt;WALL STREET JOURNAL: A Teachers Union Candidate Took My Money and Ran for Office&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 13:16:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Decision Time for TriMet’s 82nd Ave. Road Diet</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/transportation/decision-time-for-trimets-82nd-ave-road-diet/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By John A. Charles, Jr. TriMet’s “Road Diet” planned for 82nd Avenue is...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/transportation/decision-time-for-trimets-82nd-ave-road-diet/"&gt;Decision Time for TriMet’s 82nd Ave. Road Diet&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 17:34:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] The Federal Shutdown Explained: What it Means for Maine</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/the-federal-shutdown-explained-what-it-means-for-maine/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Congress isn’t known as the place for bipartisan cooperation, but since October 1, inter-party arguing has led to a shutdown of the federal government. This has caused the closing of offices, the suspension of services, and the placing of hundreds of thousands of workers on furlough. The reason, as usual, is infuriating but straightforward: Congress [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/the-federal-shutdown-explained-what-it-means-for-maine/"&gt;The Federal Shutdown Explained: What it Means for Maine&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 19:26:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Empire Center Calls for Release of PPL Records</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/empire-center-calls-for-release-of-ppl-records/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Empire Center is calling on the Hochul administration to promptly release records of its spring 2024 communications with Public....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/empire-center-calls-for-release-of-ppl-records/"&gt;Empire Center Calls for Release of PPL Records&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 15:03:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] Pennsylvania Senate Passes Budget Plan, RGGI Abrogation, Regulatory Reform</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/10/22/pennsylvania-senate-passes-budget-plan/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Harrisburg, Pa., October 22, 2025&amp;#160;— This week, the Pennsylvania Senate advanced legislation, including a spending bill (Senate Bill 160), that protects taxpayers and fosters economic growth. The commonwealth remains the only state in the country without an operating budget or stop gap plan. Now weeks into a federal government shutdown, Pennsylvania’s four-month-long impasse holds the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/10/22/pennsylvania-senate-passes-budget-plan/"&gt;Pennsylvania Senate Passes Budget Plan, RGGI Abrogation, Regulatory Reform&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 18:11:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG CIO Submits Request to DPI Seeking Teacher Licensing and Misconduct Scandal Public Records</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-cio-submits-request-to-dpi-seeking-teacher-licensing-and-misconduct-scandal-public-records/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government’s (IRG) Center for Investigative Oversight (CIO) submitted a public records request to the Wisconsin Department of Public Instruction (DPI), seeking to uncover details surrounding the Department’s handling of teacher licenses for educators accused of misconduct and grooming. Recent reporting by The Capital Times revealed serious concerns surrounding [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-cio-submits-request-to-dpi-seeking-teacher-licensing-and-misconduct-scandal-public-records/"&gt;IRG CIO Submits Request to DPI Seeking Teacher Licensing and Misconduct Scandal Public Records&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 19:07:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] New Jersey’s Bag Ban Backfired. Repeal It—and Cut Waste the Smart Way.</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/10/new-jerseys-bag-ban-backfired-repeal-it-and-cut-waste-the-smart-way/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Wells Winegar, Executive Director, New Jersey Policy Institute (NJPI) &amp;#160; Walk into any New Jersey kitchen and open the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/10/new-jerseys-bag-ban-backfired-repeal-it-and-cut-waste-the-smart-way/"&gt;New Jersey’s Bag Ban Backfired. Repeal It—and Cut Waste the Smart Way.&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 19:51:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] If Lawmakers Are Trying to Defund Public Education, They Aren’t Very Good at It</title><link>https://empowerms.org/if-lawmakers-are-trying-to-defund-public-education-they-arent-very-good-at-it/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;You’ve probably heard the claim that Mississippi’s Republican leaders are “defunding” public education, and that school choice is just another way to siphon dollars away from public schools. But if that’s true, they’re doing a remarkably bad job of it.  Over the past decade, Mississippi has dramatically increased its investment in public education. According to&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/if-lawmakers-are-trying-to-defund-public-education-they-arent-very-good-at-it/"&gt;If Lawmakers Are Trying to Defund Public Education, They Aren’t Very Good at It&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 02:00:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Acton Dinner: “The Future of Faith and Freedom” with Rev. Robert A. Sirico</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/economic-opportunity/acton-dinner-the-future-of-faith-and-freedom-with-rev-robert-a-sirico/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Naomi Inman On October 21, the Acton Institute held its Portland Dinner...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/economic-opportunity/acton-dinner-the-future-of-faith-and-freedom-with-rev-robert-a-sirico/"&gt;Acton Dinner: “The Future of Faith and Freedom” with Rev. Robert A. Sirico&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 22:36:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Feds to New Hampshire: Snip SNAP or pay us back</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/10/feds-to-new-hampshire-snip-snap-or-pay-us-back/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On Thursday, the state Department of Health and Human Services (DHHS) announced a plan to deliver food to New Hampshire food stamp recipients should the federal government shutdown continue into November.  The partnership with the New Hampshire Food Bank was announced just 13 days after the U.S. Department of Agriculture warned states that funding for [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/10/feds-to-new-hampshire-snip-snap-or-pay-us-back/"&gt;Feds to New Hampshire: Snip SNAP or pay us back&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 15:15:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Freedom Foundation Backs 51 Cities Fighting California’s Housing Speech Mandate</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/press-release/freedom-foundation-backs-51-cities-fighting-californias-housing-speech-mandate/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Freedom Foundation is joining an amicus brief with 51 cities supporting Huntington Beach's Petition for Writ of Certiorari to the United States Supreme Court in City of Huntington Beach v. Newsom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/press-release/freedom-foundation-backs-51-cities-fighting-californias-housing-speech-mandate/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation Backs 51 Cities Fighting California’s Housing Speech Mandate&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 15:58:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Judge Certifies Class Action for Parents and Teachers in Lawsuit Challenging California’s Gender Secrecy Rules</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/judge-certifies-class-action/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=judge-certifies-class-action</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A federal judge has certified a landmark class action lawsuit that could finally bring an end to California’s state-sanctioned “Parental Exclusion Policies” that order teachers to hide a child’s gender transition at school from their own parents. U.S. District Judge Roger Benitez of the Southern District of California issued the October 15 order in Mirabelli v. Olson, a lawsuit...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/judge-certifies-class-action/"&gt;Judge Certifies Class Action for Parents and Teachers in Lawsuit Challenging California’s Gender Secrecy Rules&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 21:43:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Nebraska’s Tax Treatment of Non-Profits</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/nebraskas-tax-treatment-of-non-profits/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The origins of favorable tax treatment for nonprofit and not-for-profit organizations in the United States were based on the admirable ideals promoting community service and public good.    However, today the United States’ federally tax-exempt economy makes up 15% of gross domestic output (GDP) and spans 1.8 million organizations. A total of $3.3 trillion dollars of...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/nebraskas-tax-treatment-of-non-profits/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Nebraska&amp;#8217;s Tax Treatment of Non-Profits&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 19:37:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Tennessee’s Time for Energy Abundance</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/tennessees-time-for-energy-abundance/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=tennessees-time-for-energy-abundance</link><description>By embracing Tennessee's nuclear roots, small modular reactor and micro modular reactor technologies will have a chance to thrive in a new era of energy independence.</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 19:39:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] The Good, Bad, and Ugly of 2nd Session Bill Requests</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/the-good-bad-and-ugly-of-2nd-session-bill-requests/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Legislative Council has released the list of bill titles under consideration for the Maine Legislature’s 2026 legislative session, and on October 23, the Council met for an initial bill screening. The full list of results is available here.&amp;#160; The Legislative Council is made up of 10 members of legislative leadership. For a bill request [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/the-good-bad-and-ugly-of-2nd-session-bill-requests/"&gt;The Good, Bad, and Ugly of 2nd Session Bill Requests&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 19:40:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] Court ratifies City of Albuquerque donation to Planned Parenthood</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/court-ratifies-city-of-albuquerque-donation-to-planned-parenthood/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In what can only be described as a ruling based on twisted logic a New Mexico District Judge (Denise Barela Shepherd) has decided that it is somehow NOT a violation of New Mexico&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8220;anti-donation clause&amp;#8221; for the City of Albuquerque to explicitly donation $250,000 of our tax dollars to Planned Parenthood.  Our friends at the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/court-ratifies-city-of-albuquerque-donation-to-planned-parenthood/"&gt;Court ratifies City of Albuquerque donation to Planned Parenthood&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 22:24:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Kansas Doesn’t Need Medicaid Expansion — It Needs to Empower Patients</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/kansas-doesnt-need-medicaid-expansion/</link><description>Governor Laura Kelly’s Healthcare Access for Working Kansans (HAWK) Act was sold as a “middle-of-the-road” plan to expand Medicaid to 150,000 more Kansans when it was introduced during the 2025 legislative session. But there’s nothing moderate about growing a failing federal program that already leaves millions of patients nationwide waiting in line for care. Expanding [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 15:00:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] New Video Exposes How Unions Trap Public Employees in Membership</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/press-release/new-video-exposes-how-unions-trap-public-employees-in-membership/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Freedom Foundation today released a new video exposing the deliberate obstacles unions place in front of public employees trying to exercise their constitutional right to leave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/press-release/new-video-exposes-how-unions-trap-public-employees-in-membership/" rel="nofollow"&gt;New Video Exposes How Unions Trap Public Employees in Membership&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 15:22:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Frightfully pricey treats: Why Halloween fun is costing Georgia families more</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/georgia-halloween-candy-prices/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As Halloween approaches, Georgia families look forward to making great memories involving adorable costumes and fun candy hauls. But candy prices have become nothing short of scary for families trying to make ends meet. Here's why prices are on the rise for Georgia's favorite Halloween treats. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/georgia-halloween-candy-prices/"&gt;Frightfully pricey treats: Why Halloween fun is costing Georgia families more&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 16:01:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Moms For Liberty Activist Scarlett Johnson Wins Her Appeal</title><link>https://will-law.org/moms-for-liberty-activist-scarlett-johnson-wins-her-appeal/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Wisconsin Court of Appeals ruled in favor of WILL’s client, Scarlett Johnson, a Wisconsin Moms for Liberty activist sued for defamation for criticizing her school district. The Court agreed with WILL’s argument that Scarlett’s posts were statements of opinion that are not provably false and therefore cannot be defamatory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/moms-for-liberty-activist-scarlett-johnson-wins-her-appeal/"&gt;Moms For Liberty Activist Scarlett Johnson Wins Her Appeal&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 17:35:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] PRESS RELEASE: Governor Reeves and Rich Lowry Highlight Mississippi's Success</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/press-release-governor-reeves-and-rich-lowry-highlight-mississippis-success/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASEOctober 28, 2025 Mississippi Center for Public Policy Celebrates Statewide Success with Governor Tate Reeves and National Review Editor Rich Lowry Jackson, Miss. — October 28, 2025 — The Mississippi Center for Public Policy hosted its Celebration of Mississippi Success Gala on Thursday, October 23, at the Country Club of Jackson, honoring the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/press-release-governor-reeves-and-rich-lowry-highlight-mississippis-success/" rel="nofollow"&gt;PRESS RELEASE: Governor Reeves and Rich Lowry Highlight Mississippi&amp;#039;s Success&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 19:43:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Mayor John Horhn: Jackson Rising</title><link>https://empowerms.org/mayor-john-horhn-jackson-rising/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Mayor John Horhn: Jackson Rising What does it take to turn around a city? In this special episode recorded at Jackson City Hall, host Grant Callen talks with Mayor John Horhn about his love for Jackson, the lessons from his childhood and career in public service, and his mission to restore trust, safety, and opportunity&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/mayor-john-horhn-jackson-rising/"&gt;Mayor John Horhn: Jackson Rising&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 01:00:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG Court Watch: Options for Structural Reforms for our Courts</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-court-watch-options-for-structural-reforms-for-our-courts/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;IRG Court Watch: Options for Structural Reforms for our Courts Voters Open to Reform after Multi-Million Dollar, Partisan Judicial Elections Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government’s (IRG)‘s Court Watch initiative released a report, Structural Reform of Judicial Selection in Wisconsin, detailing potential structural reforms to strengthen judicial integrity and public trust in Wisconsin [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-court-watch-options-for-structural-reforms-for-our-courts/"&gt;IRG Court Watch: Options for Structural Reforms for our Courts&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 13:38:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Harvard’s Leo Damrosch on Robert Louis Stevenson &amp; Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/harvards-leo-damrosch-on-robert-louis-stevenson-dr-jekyll-and-mr-hyde/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In this week’s episode of The Learning Curve, co-hosts U-Arkansas Prof. Albert Cheng and Great Hearts Academies’ Dr. Helen Baxendale interview Leo Damrosch, Ernest Bernbaum Professor of Literature Emeritus at Harvard University, and acclaimed biographer of some of the world's greatest literary figures. Prof. Damrosch discusses his newest book Storyteller: The Life of Robert Louis Stevenson. He reflects on Stevenson's childhood in Scotland and the close relationship he maintained with his nanny, Alison Cunningham. He shares how Stevenson lived an adventurous life, with his travel inspiring classics like Treasure Island, Kidnapped, and A Child’s Garden of Verses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/harvards-leo-damrosch-on-robert-louis-stevenson-dr-jekyll-and-mr-hyde/"&gt;Harvard’s Leo Damrosch on Robert Louis Stevenson &amp;#038; Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 15:27:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Benjamin Franklin and the Birth of American Liberty—11/21 Virtual Event</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/benjamin-franklin-and-the-birth-of-american-liberty-11-21-virtual-event/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Benjamin Franklin—statesman, inventor, and journalist—stands among the great heroes of American history. And who better to tell his story than..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/benjamin-franklin-and-the-birth-of-american-liberty-11-21-virtual-event/"&gt;Benjamin Franklin and the Birth of American Liberty—11/21 Virtual Event&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 20:35:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] New Study Shows Success of School Choice in Action</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/new-study-shows-success-of-school-choice-in-action/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=new-study-shows-success-of-school-choice-in-action</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As California wallows in continued low student performance, a new study shows that school choice is making a positive difference in student outcomes in Arkansas. Recently released scores on California’s state tests in English and math show huge proportions of students failing to achieve proficiency in the basic subjects. More than half of California students...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/new-study-shows-success-of-school-choice-in-action/"&gt;New Study Shows Success of School Choice in Action&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 21:49:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Dear PPS Bond Committee: Please Tell the Taxpayers</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/testimony/testimony-before-the-pps-bond-accountability-committee/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By John A. Charles, Jr. Cascade’s president, John Charles, testified online at the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/testimony/testimony-before-the-pps-bond-accountability-committee/"&gt;Dear PPS Bond Committee: Please Tell the Taxpayers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 23:13:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Nichols v. DOT</title><link>https://will-law.org/nichols-v-dot/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL is challenging a state law that unlawfully restricts Wisconsin drivers’ First Amendment rights. The state uses subjective and arbitrary decisions to decide what drivers can print on their personalized license plates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/nichols-v-dot/"&gt;Nichols v. DOT&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 13:52:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Debunking 2 more property tax myths: setting mill rates and blaming legislators for unfunded mandates</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/2-property-tax-myths-mill-rates-unfunded-mandates/</link><description>Last month, we debunked several property tax myths that some local officials are using to shift the blame for their unaffordable tax increases, and now there are two more excuses to address. For years, many local officials tried to blame County Clerks for setting mill rates, saying something along the lines of ‘we just set [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 15:31:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Killing the I&amp;D Tax leaps N.H. to No. 3 on national tax competitiveness index</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/10/killing-the-id-tax-leaps-n-h-to-no-3-on-national-tax-competitiveness-index/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Killing New Hampshire’s Interest &amp;#38; Dividends Tax has breathed new life into the New Hampshire Advantage. That’s the conclusion from reading the Tax Foundation’s 2026 State Tax Competitiveness Index, released on Oct. 30.  Last year, New Hampshire slipped past Texas to claim the No. 6 spot on the index. Passing the famously conservative and economically [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/10/killing-the-id-tax-leaps-n-h-to-no-3-on-national-tax-competitiveness-index/"&gt;Killing the I&amp;#038;D Tax leaps N.H. to No. 3 on national tax competitiveness index&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 17:51:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Large Scale Desalination Could Transform California</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/large-scale-desalination-could-transform-california/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=large-scale-desalination-could-transform-california</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Why is it axiomatic among California’s water agencies and policymakers that large scale desalination is inconceivable in California? That certainly isn’t the case in other arid locales. In 2024, an estimated 30 million acre feet of fresh water was produced by desalination plants worldwide. On the coast of the Red Sea, about 60 miles south of the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/large-scale-desalination-could-transform-california/"&gt;Large Scale Desalination Could Transform California&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 17:53:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Port Washington to be land of opportunity for job-seekers</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/port-washington-to-be-land-of-opportunity-for-job-seekers/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Technical college graduates and small business owners will be big winners in the massive Vantage Data Centers development soon expected to become the largest employer in Port Washington.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/port-washington-to-be-land-of-opportunity-for-job-seekers/"&gt;Port Washington to be land of opportunity for job-seekers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 19:23:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Honoring Courage: Elijah Stacy, Goldwater’s 2025 Freedom Award Winner</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/honoring-courage-elijah-stacy-goldwaters-2025-freedom-award-winner/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Goldwater Institute is proud to honor Elijah Stacy as the recipient of our 2025 Freedom Award. Elijah’s unwavering courage,..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/honoring-courage-elijah-stacy-goldwaters-2025-freedom-award-winner/"&gt;Honoring Courage: Elijah Stacy, Goldwater&amp;#8217;s 2025 Freedom Award Winner&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 19:49:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Parsing the Impact of Mamdani’s Tax Hike Plans</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/parsing-the-impact-of-mamdanis-tax-hike-plans/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The front-running candidate for New York City mayor, Zohran Mamdani, has said he can finance his costly campaign promises –....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/parsing-the-impact-of-mamdanis-tax-hike-plans/"&gt;Parsing the Impact of Mamdani&amp;#8217;s Tax Hike Plans&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 20:28:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] 2025 Tools for Keeping Kids Safe Online: Innovations Empower Parents, but Parents Must Use Them</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/2025-tools-for-keeping-kids-safe-online-innovations-empower-parents-but-parents-must-use-them/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Pew Research Center reported last year that teenagers are more online than ever before. The majority own smartphones, 90% use YouTube, around 60% use TikTok and Instagram, and over half report that they are online “almost constantly.” Lawmakers, caretakers, and even teens themselves have expressed concern about these trends. A variety of tools have emerged...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/2025-tools-for-keeping-kids-safe-online-innovations-empower-parents-but-parents-must-use-them/"&gt;2025 Tools for Keeping Kids Safe Online: Innovations Empower Parents, but Parents Must Use Them&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 20:54:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Maine’s 2025 Ballot Questions: What Voters Should Know</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/maines-2025-ballot-questions-what-voters-should-know/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As Maine heads into the 2025 election, voters will face two ballot questions that cut to the heart of the state’s debates over election integrity and gun rights. Both questions resurrect legislative fights that failed in Augusta and are now placed directly before the people. Ballot Question 1: Election Integrity Ballot Summary:“Do you want to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/maines-2025-ballot-questions-what-voters-should-know/"&gt;Maine’s 2025 Ballot Questions: What Voters Should Know&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 21:09:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Milwaukee will pay someone to say nice things about The Hop</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/milwaukee-will-pay-someone-to-say-nice-things-about-the-hop/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The City of Milwaukee is willing to pay a new marketing and communications officer for The Hop, its little-used $128 million streetcar, up to $108,000 per year plus benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/milwaukee-will-pay-someone-to-say-nice-things-about-the-hop/"&gt;Milwaukee will pay someone to say nice things about The Hop&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 21:09:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] As hunger looms, Democrats in ‘non-winnable’ situation</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/as-hunger-looms-democrats-in-non-winnable-situation/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;“Democrats put themselves in the situation we’re in, and it’s non-winnable,” says Rachidi, a researcher who has written extensively about FoodShare and SNAP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/as-hunger-looms-democrats-in-non-winnable-situation/"&gt;As hunger looms, Democrats in ‘non-winnable’ situation&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 21:22:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Beacon Wins Final Approval in $1.4 Million Stormwater Settlement, Bringing Justice to Nashville Homeowners</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/beacon-wins-final-approval-in-1-4-million-stormwater-settlement-bringing-justice-to-nashville-homeowners/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=beacon-wins-final-approval-in-1-4-million-stormwater-settlement-bringing-justice-to-nashville-homeowners</link><description>This ruling is a landmark win for property owners and sends a clear message that government overreach will not go unchecked.</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 21:26:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] WI Speaks Polling Results</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/wi-speaks-survey-results/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WI 1023 Toplines (1) WI 1023 Summary of Key Findings (2) WI 1023 Summary of Key Findings (2)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/wi-speaks-survey-results/"&gt;WI Speaks Polling Results&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 00:18:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Virginiainstitute] Examining HJ6007 and Its Implications for Virginia’s Redistricting Process</title><link>https://virginiainstitute.org/examining-hj6007/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=examining-hj6007</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As lawmakers consider HJ6007, Virginians are asking how the proposal aligns with the 2020 constitutional amendment supporting fair maps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org/examining-hj6007/"&gt;Examining HJ6007 and Its Implications for Virginia’s Redistricting Process&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org"&gt;Virginia Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 01:53:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] NYC Employees Receive $300k+ in Overtime</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/nyc-employees-receive-300k-in-overtime/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Two New York City employees received more than $300,000 in overtime payouts, according to fiscal year 2025 payroll data posted....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/nyc-employees-receive-300k-in-overtime/"&gt;NYC Employees Receive $300k+ in Overtime&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 13:20:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Florida Politics: No, Georgia, It’s Not a Trick; Florida Just Wants To Share a Kid-Friendly Treat</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/florida-politics-no-georgia-its-not-a-trick-florida-just-wants-to-share-a-kid-friendly-treat/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As Saturday’s&amp;#160;Georgia-Florida game&amp;#160;approaches, much attention is being paid to the fact that the Gators just fired their head...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/florida-politics-no-georgia-its-not-a-trick-florida-just-wants-to-share-a-kid-friendly-treat/"&gt;Florida Politics: No, Georgia, It’s Not a Trick; Florida Just Wants To Share a Kid-Friendly Treat&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 14:08:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] LA GATOR: Fund the Promise</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/education/la-gator-fund-the-promise/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Louisiana’s education landscape took a transformative turn in 2024 with the creation of the Louisiana Giving All True Opportunity to Rise (LA GATOR) program, a universal education savings account (ESA) initiative designed to empower families with unprecedented flexibility in choosing their child’s educational path. Modeled after successful ESA programs in states like Arizona and Florida,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/education/la-gator-fund-the-promise/"&gt;LA GATOR: Fund the Promise&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 15:21:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Week in Review: $117K to see what a school is teaching?</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-117k-to-see-what-a-school-is-teaching/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When a Rhode Island teacher made headlines for publishing videos celebrating the assassination of conservative activist Charlie Kirk, one local..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-117k-to-see-what-a-school-is-teaching/"&gt;Week in Review: $117K to see what a school is teaching?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 15:54:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Rebuilding Civic Knowledge for the Next Generation</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/rebuilding-civic-knowledge-for-the-next-generation/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Rebuilding Civic Knowledge for the Next Generation" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/classroom.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reflecting on his early education, President Calvin Coolidge wrote that in his studies he “was attracted to civil government.” He recalled:&lt;br /&gt;
“This was my first introduction to the Constitution of the United States. Although I was but thirteen years old, the subject interested me exceedingly. The study of it which I then began never ceased, and the more I study it, the more I have come to admire it, realizing that no other document devised by the hand of man ever brought so much progress and happiness to humanity. The good it has wrought can never be measured.”&lt;br /&gt;
The education Coolidge received was very different from what most students—especially those in public schools—receive today. The importance of studying American history, government, and Western civilization can no longer be sidelined. Too often, discussions about education focus solely on spending, finance, or the promotion of STEM programs—science, technology, engineering, and math.&lt;br /&gt;
Of course, students need a curriculum that prepares them for higher education and the workforce. But education must also do more—it should prepare students to be informed, responsible citizens. Education is not just about acquiring skills; it is about citizenship.&lt;br /&gt;
For decades, the nation has faced a civic education crisis. Students are leaving K–12 schools and colleges with an alarming lack of understanding of American history, government, and Western civilization. Too often, civics instruction has become politicized, with curricula emphasizing narrow or revisionist viewpoints rather than a balanced appreciation of our shared history.&lt;br /&gt;
As a result, many young people are developing shallow or distorted views of America’s founding principles and institutions. Classrooms increasingly frame citizenship in global rather than national terms, and higher education is often dominated by a limited range of political and cultural perspectives.&lt;br /&gt;
In response, the Iowa Legislature has acted to strengthen civic education and refocus instruction on the values of liberty, republican self-government, and civic virtue that define the American tradition. In 2024, lawmakers directed a revision of the state’s social studies standards to ensure those principles are emphasized throughout the curriculum. The standards remain under review, but the goal is clear: reinforce rigorous instruction in American history, government, and Western civilization so that every Iowa student gains a deeper understanding of what it means to be an informed citizen.&lt;br /&gt;
The Legislature also required all high school students to pass the U.S. citizenship exam before graduation. This modest measure at least ensures that students demonstrate a basic understanding of our nation’s founding and institutions. Iowa already requires high school students to complete a course in civics prior to graduation, but strengthening the standards in the curriculum is essential to reversing the decline.&lt;br /&gt;
When it comes to higher education the situation is different. Iowa’s Regent Universities do not require a course in civic education to graduate. Further, the James G. Martin Center for Academic Renewal notes that Iowa’s flagship institution, the University of Iowa, is absent from the list of the “most civically aligned teacher preparation programs.”&lt;br /&gt;
America’s civic ignorance contributes to its deep divisions. Patrick J. Buchanan warned in The Death of the West:&lt;br /&gt;
“How does one sever a people’s roots? Destroy its memory. Deny a people the knowledge of who they are and where they came from... Destroy the record of a people’s past, leave it in ignorance of who its ancestors were and what they did, and one can fill the empty vessels of their souls with a new history.”&lt;br /&gt;
Political philosopher Russell Kirk echoed this sentiment, writing that “ignorance is a dangerous luxury” and that Americans who lack understanding of their nation’s principles “will be susceptible to ideologies and endanger the moral security of the nation.”&lt;br /&gt;
This civic decay explains why anti-American sentiment is rising among young people—and why so many now embrace socialism and even communism. How can constitutional principles like federalism or the Electoral College survive if they are no longer taught or understood?&lt;br /&gt;
This doesn’t mean avoiding difficult chapters in our history, such as slavery.  In fact, Americans have a duty to develop an informed knowledge of history and institutions.  As author James S. Robbins wrote in Erasing America, “History is the source of all life’s lessons, the good and the bad. We turn to history to see what to embrace and what to avoid.”&lt;br /&gt;
Civic education must be about more than memorizing facts. It should cultivate responsible citizens, not activists. It should inspire patriotism, respect for America’s heritage, and a lifelong desire to learn—just as it did for Coolidge. We owe it to both our ancestors and future generations to preserve our Republic and its ideals.&lt;br /&gt;
It’s time to restore that lesson to our schools and to heed the advice President Ronald Reagan provided us, “Let’s start with some basics: more attention to American history and a greater emphasis on civic ritual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/rebuilding-civic-knowledge-for-the-next-generation/"&gt;Rebuilding Civic Knowledge for the Next Generation&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 17:48:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] PRESS RELEASE: MISSISSIPPI CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY HONORS LEGISLATIVE HEROES AT ANNUAL GALA CELEBRATING STATE SUCCESS</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/press-release-mississippi-center-for-public-policy-honors-legislative-heroes-at-annual-gala-celebrating-state-success/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASEOctober 30, 2025 MISSISSIPPI CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY HONORS LEGISLATIVE HEROES AT ANNUAL GALA CELEBRATING STATE SUCCESS JACKSON, MS – October 30, 2025 –Six of Mississippi’s leading lawmakers were presented with award to honor them for championing principled conservative policy. Rich Lowry, editor of the National Review, presented each of the winners. HealthcareRep. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/press-release-mississippi-center-for-public-policy-honors-legislative-heroes-at-annual-gala-celebrating-state-success/" rel="nofollow"&gt;PRESS RELEASE: MISSISSIPPI CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY HONORS LEGISLATIVE HEROES AT ANNUAL GALA CELEBRATING STATE SUCCESS&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 19:21:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Income: You Earned It, You Should Keep It</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/income-you-earned-it-you-should-keep-it/</link><description>Income Taxes: We have options Are you getting the idea that the Idaho Freedom Foundation (IFF) thinks government takes too much in taxes? Good, let’s keep going. By applying our 2026 Freedom and Family Agenda’s strong position on tax cuts, we have proposed eliminating the sales tax on groceries and have offered a plan to [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 23:08:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Virginiainstitute] Press Release – HJ 6007: “one of the worst ideas” passed by the General Assembly</title><link>https://virginiainstitute.org/press-release-hj6007/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=press-release-hj6007</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Virginia Institute for Public Policy has expressed concern over HJ6007, a proposed amendment to Virginia’s Constitution that would alter the state’s current redistricting process. The Institute emphasized that Virginia voters approved a bipartisan approach in 2020 to ensure fair and transparent elections for all citizens. Citing constitutional and procedural issues surrounding HJ6007, the Institute encourages lawmakers to uphold established safeguards that protect the integrity and balance of Virginia’s electoral system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org/press-release-hj6007/"&gt;Press Release – HJ 6007: “one of the worst ideas” passed by the General Assembly&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org"&gt;Virginia Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 00:15:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Tallahassee Democrat: Florida’s Established Approach to Kids’ Online Safety Doesn’t Need Tweaking</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/floridas-established-approach-to-kids-online-safety-doesnt-need-tweaking-opinion/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In the ongoing debate about how to best protect children online, a new proposal gaining traction would force...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/floridas-established-approach-to-kids-online-safety-doesnt-need-tweaking-opinion/"&gt;Tallahassee Democrat: Florida’s Established Approach to Kids’ Online Safety Doesn’t Need Tweaking&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 14:55:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Week in Review: Everything Should Be Smaller in Taxes</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/week-in-review-everything-should-be-smaller-in-taxes/</link><description>That’s right, the title says “Taxes,” not “Texas.” Even in Idaho, taxes are out of control. Please enjoy — if that’s the right word — this mini-series on Idaho taxes. But, before you read, one word of reminder: high taxes are merely the symptom of the true disease: out-of-control government spending. This symptom inflicts real [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 20:04:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] Franke: Civic Bargain Book Review</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/11/franke-civic-bargain-book-review/</link><description>by Mark Franke One hears the word democracy so often these days — and in so many contexts &amp;#160;—&amp;#160;that it has lost its meaning. There is the tiresome charge that anything Donald Trump does is a threat to democracy on one hand and on the other hand a rather pedantic academic argument that we are&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/11/franke-civic-bargain-book-review/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 12:31:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] New Pioneer Institute Analysis Finds Proposed Massachusetts Income-Tax Cut Unlikely to Cause Major State Revenue Decline</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/news/2026-tax-cut/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Lessons from the 2000 Massachusetts Income-Tax Rollback: A Reality-Check for the 2025 Ballot Debate is an empirical analysis of Massachusetts revenue data from FY1998–FY2021. The study concludes that a one-point rate reduction is unlikely to produce large, persistent revenue shortfalls, and that long-term fiscal stability depends far more on economic performance than on marginal rate differences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/news/2026-tax-cut/"&gt;New Pioneer Institute Analysis Finds Proposed Massachusetts Income-Tax Cut Unlikely to Cause Major State Revenue Decline&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 15:06:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Legislators should end judicial deference to state agencies</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/legislators-should-end-judicial-deference-to-state-agencies</link><description>The U.S. Supreme Court’s 2024 decision in Loper Bright Enterprises  v. Raimondo  is reshaping federal land use in Wyoming and policy throughout the United States. The ruling reversed decades of precedent requiring courts to defer to a U.S. agency’s interpretation of laws. This meant that federal judges were required to favor the government over individual taxpayers or businesses, regardless of how far off base an agency's interpretation strayed from common sense or a plain reading of the law....</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 16:23:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] New Report Calls for More Freedom and Consumer Choice in Energy Policy to Lower Costs</title><link>https://will-law.org/new-report-calls-for-more-freedom-and-consumer-choice-in-energy-policy-to-lower-costs/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A new report from WILL, titled “Energy Choice for Wisconsin: A Free-Market Case for Community Solar,” outlines how privately financed community solar projects can expand consumer choice, strengthen the electric grid, preserve farmland, and inject market competition into Wisconsin’s monopoly utility system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/new-report-calls-for-more-freedom-and-consumer-choice-in-energy-policy-to-lower-costs/"&gt;New Report Calls for More Freedom and Consumer Choice in Energy Policy to Lower Costs&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 17:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/11/the-outstater-299/</link><description>Grades: All Rhinestones Now &amp;#8220;Personally, I liked working for the university. They gave us money and facilities. We didn&amp;#8217;t have to produce anything. You&amp;#8217;ve never been out of college. You don&amp;#8217;t know what it&amp;#8217;s like out there. I’ve worked in the private sector — they expect results.”&amp;#160;— Dr. Raymond Stantz (Dan Aykroyd) in the 1984&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/11/the-outstater-299/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 18:43:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Per-Pupil Spending Tells More of the Story</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/per-pupil-spending-tells-more-of-the-story/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Per-Pupil Spending Tells More of the Story" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/school-spending-1200x630-1.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;School bond campaigns often highlight levy rates to suggest affordability, but that figure alone doesn’t reveal how districts spend—or the true cost to taxpayers and students. Looking at districtwide per-student expenditures provides a clearer picture of financial trends and priorities. For instance, Des Moines’ per-student spending is up 24% in five years, and Southeast Polk’s has risen 66%. Districts should routinely publish per-student cost data by program or activity to help voters, taxpayers, and educators evaluate whether new borrowing truly delivers educational value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/per-pupil-spending-tells-more-of-the-story/"&gt;Per-Pupil Spending Tells More of the Story&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 19:16:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF in National Review: New Mexico’s ‘Free’ Child Care an Attempt to Cover for Past Failures</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-in-national-review-new-mexicos-free-child-care-an-attempt-to-cover-for-past-failures/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following appeared at National Review on November 11, 2025. Child care isn’t cheap, especially once the government gets involved. Recently, New Mexico’s Democratic Governor Michelle Lujan Grisham announced a new plan for taxpayers to fund “free” child care for all New Mexicans, regardless of their income levels. The announcement generated favorable news coverage in [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-in-national-review-new-mexicos-free-child-care-an-attempt-to-cover-for-past-failures/"&gt;RGF in National Review: New Mexico’s ‘Free’ Child Care an Attempt to Cover for Past Failures&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 21:15:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Halloween is over, but spooky creatures still haunt us</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/11/halloween-is-over-but-spooky-creatures-still-haunt-us/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Halloween was yesterday, but we still have a lot of spooky creatures in Hawaii to worry about. I’m thinking of the Jones Act goblin, the budget banshee and the grasping rail, among many others. The Jones Act goblin’s purpose is to frighten people away from reforming or repealing the Jones Act, which restricts shipping competition [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/11/halloween-is-over-but-spooky-creatures-still-haunt-us/"&gt;Halloween is over, but spooky creatures still haunt us&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 22:39:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] AEA Has Shown Alabamians Who They Are: Believe Them</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/11/04/aea-has-shown-alabamians-who-they-are-believe-them/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;AEA has worked for decades to stop school choice legislation. AEA actively worked against the passage of the AAA Scholarship program, the PRICE Act, and the CHOOSE Act. AEA used political influence and political contributions to people and parties to weaken parental rights in the CHOOSE Act and then tried to kill the CHOOSE Act unless they could “control the spending” with a cap. Further, AEA worked last legislative session to minimize funding for special needs kids, military kids, and kids whose families are living in poverty; they are currently working against future CHOOSE Act schoolchildren. AEA is trying to render void the promises legislators made to Alabama parents when they passed the law in 2024. They are attempting to undercut the work and the word of Governor Kay Ivey, Lt. Governor Will Ainsworth, Speaker Nathaniel Ledbetter, Chairman Danny Garrett, Chairman Arthur Orr, and each of the ninety-two legislators who voted on behalf of the people they represent for universal school choice for Alabama’s children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/11/04/aea-has-shown-alabamians-who-they-are-believe-them/"&gt;AEA Has Shown Alabamians Who They Are: Believe Them&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 05:04:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] California’s Great Gasoline Panic of ‘25</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/californias-great-gasoline-panic-of-25/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;“California&amp;#8217;s Refinery Rethink” Politico Pro, Oct. 22 “Newsom Courts Big Oil as Gas Prices Threaten Political Ambition” Bloomberg, Sept. 29 “Faced with looming gasoline shortage, California&amp;#8217;s governor backs off oil companies” Le Monde, Oct. 11 “Gas Price Map Shock: Why Gas Is $4.60 in California but $2.60 in Oklahoma?” Autoblog, Oct. 18 The headlines keep [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/californias-great-gasoline-panic-of-25/"&gt;California’s Great Gasoline Panic of ‘25&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 11:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] McGowan: AI Flunks the Baseball Test</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/11/mcgowan-ai-flunks-the-baseball-test/</link><description>by Richard McGowan, Ph.D. This year’s world series and all the attention paid to Shohei Ohtani reminded me of the way students used to get by when writing papers.&amp;#160;They used CliffsNotes instead of doing research.&amp;#160;Can AI be far behind? I had a bright student who wrote a paper on Plato’s &amp;#8220;Crito&amp;#8221; as explained by every&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/11/mcgowan-ai-flunks-the-baseball-test/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 13:43:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Michigan’s Licensing Laws Block Second Chances</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/pressroom/2025/michigans-licensing-laws-block-second-chances</link><description>Mackinac Center urges lawmakers to remove job barriers for rehabilitated residents</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 14:06:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] This bipartisan proposal is a logical step to improve Medicare solvency</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/this-bipartisan-proposal-is-a-logical-step-to-improve-medicare-solvency</link><description>The federal Medicare health insurance program for seniors has been overbudget since its inception in 1965. By 1990, the plan was at least nine times over the original budget  as determined by the Congressional Budget Office (CBO). Eliminating waste, fraud, and abuse in the program would seem to be a noncontroversial first step to decrease the financial burden on taxpayers and guarantee that future generations of seniors have access to Medicare. A bipartisan bill, The No UPCODE Act , has been...</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 15:17:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] SNAP in Nebraska: Current Rules, Economic Impact, and What’s Next</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/snap-in-nebraska-current-rules-economic-impact-and-whats-next/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Program Overview  The Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP), formerly known as the Food Stamp Program, is the most extensive federal nutrition assistance program in the United States. It serves as a &amp;#8220;safety net&amp;#8221; program that helpslow-income individuals and families access and purchase healthy food. The program is funded by the Department of Agriculture (USDA) and...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/snap-in-nebraska-current-rules-economic-impact-and-whats-next/" rel="nofollow"&gt;SNAP in Nebraska: Current Rules, Economic Impact, and What’s Next&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 16:16:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Nebraska lost $300 million from tax migration in 2022</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-lost-300-million-from-tax-migration-in-2022/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Elections occur every other November. But taxpayers vote with their feet every day, and these votes should be counted and tallied just like the votes for a November election.  A “Great Pandemic Wealth Migration” began when the coronavirus pandemic caused Americans to move to work-from-home employment. This meant workers were no longer tied to aphysical...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-lost-300-million-from-tax-migration-in-2022/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Nebraska lost $300 million from tax migration in 2022&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 19:03:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] How Much Tax Support Do Iowa’s County Hospitals Really Need?</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/how-much-tax-support-do-iowas-county-hospitals-really-need/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="How Much Tax Support Do Iowa’s County Hospitals Really Need?" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/da-co-hospital.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Across Iowa, more than 40 county hospitals receive a portion of their funding from local property taxpayers, totaling more than $150 million a year. These facilities are often essential—especially in rural areas where they may be the only source of emergency care. But when public dollars are involved, financial transparency takes on heightened importance. One key question Iowans are always entitled to ask is: How many tax dollars are actually necessary?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/how-much-tax-support-do-iowas-county-hospitals-really-need/"&gt;How Much Tax Support Do Iowa’s County Hospitals Really Need?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 21:21:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Pritzker vetoes 5th lowest of 16 Democrat-controlled states</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/pritzker-vetoes-5th-lowest-of-16-democrat-controlled-states/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In Illinois, 99% of state bills passed by the Democratic supermajority become law with no objection by Gov. J.B. Pritzker. Democracy suffers without checks and balances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/pritzker-vetoes-5th-lowest-of-16-democrat-controlled-states/"&gt;Pritzker vetoes 5th lowest of 16 Democrat-controlled states&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 21:43:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Are Missouri’s Public Schools Ready for Declining Enrollment?</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/education-finance/are-missouris-public-schools-ready-for-declining-enrollment/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The fertility rate—the average number of children a woman will have over her lifetime—has been falling steadily in the United [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/education-finance/are-missouris-public-schools-ready-for-declining-enrollment/"&gt;Are Missouri’s Public Schools Ready for Declining Enrollment?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 22:26:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Obamacare’s Policy Failures Come To Idaho</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/obamacares-policy-failures-come-to-idaho/</link><description>As the shutdown of the federal government extends beyond 30 days, the key reasons become apparent: it is about healthcare costs and who pays them. The debate over temporarily expanded healthcare premium subsidies and Medicaid eligibility is really about who pays what. You see, the notion that the Affordable Care Act (often referred to as [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 22:45:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] State Board of Education gets bad legal guidance from the Kansas Department of Education</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/state-board-of-education-bad-legal-guidance/</link><description>The October meeting of the Kansas State Board of Education contained another déjà vu moment: attempting to cover up another violation of state laws designed to improve student outcomes (see here and here for past examples.) State Board Chair Cathy Hopkins commented on a Kansas Policy Institute discovery that school districts were not complying with [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 23:33:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Vallas: Legislation buys CTA time to fix itself, but will it?</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/vallas-legislation-buys-cta-time-to-fix-itself-but-will-it/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New taxes buy the Chicago Transit Authority some time, but state lawmakers failed fix anything that led to the crisis. Here are three ways city leaders can fix the CTA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/vallas-legislation-buys-cta-time-to-fix-itself-but-will-it/"&gt;Vallas: Legislation buys CTA time to fix itself, but will it?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 23:51:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Why does it cost so much to build? We’ve lost an abundance mindset</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/why-does-it-cost-so-much-to-build-weve-lost-an-abundance-mindset</link><description>‘Good intentions tell you nothing about the actual consequences’</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] After Voters Pass Prop. 50, What Comes Next?</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/after-voters-pass-prop-50-what-comes-next/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;First, despite what President Obama said in Prop. 50 commercials, its passage does not protect the independent redistricting commission in any way. By enacting Prop. 50, voters have done away with the independent commission’s work for the rest of this decade. Remember that California stands to lose two more congressional seats in the 2030 reapportionment. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/after-voters-pass-prop-50-what-comes-next/"&gt;After Voters Pass Prop. 50, What Comes Next?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 11:00:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] November 2025 Beacon Poll Results</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/november-2025-beacon-poll/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=november-2025-beacon-poll</link><description>Today, we released the latest installment of the Beacon Poll, a statewide survey of 1,200 Tennessee voters featuring questions about voters&amp;#8217; views on socialism versus capitalism, the National Guard in Memphis, political violence, and more. In a surprising result that could have a national impact, a majority of Democrats in Tennessee hold a favorable view...</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 13:00:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] MA Teacher Kelley Brown on Founding Documents, U.S. History, &amp; Civics</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/ma-teacher-kelley-brown-on-founding-documents-u-s-history-civics/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In this week’s episode of The Learning Curve, co-hosts Center for Strong Public Schools’ Alisha Searcy and American Federation for Children’s Walter Blanks interview Kelley Brown, an award-winning civics and government teacher at Easthampton High School and former Massachusetts Teacher of the Year. Ms. Brown discusses her background as an educator, her work with the “We the People": The Citizen and the Constitution program, and how it helps students engage with America’s Founding Documents, U.S. history, and enduring civic ideals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/ma-teacher-kelley-brown-on-founding-documents-u-s-history-civics/"&gt;MA Teacher Kelley Brown on Founding Documents, U.S. History, &amp;#038; Civics&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 14:35:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] MSPC provides digital safety keynote address at Idaho Department of Education conference</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/mspc-provides-digital-safety-keynote-address-at-idaho-department-of-education-conference</link><description>On October 24 th , 2025, I was honored to be a keynote speaker at the Idaho Department of Education’s 10th Annual Family and Community Engagement Conference in Sun Valley, ID. Over 300 teachers, principals, and community leaders came together for this year's event, giving a state-wide perspective on all the things we should be doing to better equip our parents and students with what they need to succeed in educating their youth. The keynote addressed my most recent research project: “ The...</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 15:38:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Georgia Leaders Should Not Vilify Technology. Social Media and AI Hold Promise.</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/georgia-leaders-should-not-vilify-technology-social-media-and-ai-hold-promise/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;November 5, 2025 In the waning hours of Georgia&amp;#8217;s brief 40-day legislative session this past April, state senators...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/georgia-leaders-should-not-vilify-technology-social-media-and-ai-hold-promise/"&gt;Georgia Leaders Should Not Vilify Technology. Social Media and AI Hold Promise.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 16:04:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Let’s Expect Better</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/performance/lets-expect-better/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Following up on an earlier blog post, it should be noted that the Missouri Department of Elementary and Secondary Education [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/performance/lets-expect-better/"&gt;Let’s Expect Better&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 16:35:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Diverting Taxpayer Dollars to Political Non-Profits is Much Worse Than You Think</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/diverting-taxpayer-dollars-to-political-non-profits-is-much-worse-than-you-think/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In a recent investigation, the Austin American-Stateman revealed that Austin City Council member Ryan Alter has been inappropriately, and potentially illegally, transferring thousands of taxpayer dollars to advocacy organizations and other non-profits. “Organizations that have received taxpayer-funded donations from Alter’s office include nonprofits like Liberal Austin Democrats and Hispanic Advocates Business Leaders of Austin, or...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/diverting-taxpayer-dollars-to-political-non-profits-is-much-worse-than-you-think/"&gt;Diverting Taxpayer Dollars to Political Non-Profits is Much Worse Than You Think&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 16:53:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Low-income students 16 points below Illinois average</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/low-income-students-16-points-below-illinois-average/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New Illinois State Board of Education data shows low-income and minority public school students are struggling, scoring well below average. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/low-income-students-16-points-below-illinois-average/"&gt;Low-income students 16 points below Illinois average&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 18:22:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] China, Cartels Make Inroads as U.S. Judges Fumble Cases</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/china-cartels-make-inroads-as-u-s-judges-fumble-cases/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past week, a chain of decisions from Beijing to the Rio Grande has revealed how economic policy, narcotics flows, and national security now move on the same axis. On November 4, the White House issued an executive order cutting the fentanyl tariff on Chinese imports to 10 percent. Within twenty-four hours, China’s Finance Ministry...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/china-cartels-make-inroads-as-u-s-judges-fumble-cases/"&gt;China, Cartels Make Inroads as U.S. Judges Fumble Cases&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 18:58:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Jacob Frey fends off challenge from Fateh</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/jacob-frey-fends-off-challenge-from-fateh/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;From&amp;#160;the Minneapolis&amp;#160;Star Tribune, Mayor Jacob Frey beat back a challenge from democratic socialist Omar Fateh for a third term leading Minnesota’s largest city. We had to wait a few extra hours for the result, to see if the colossally-stupid, ranked-choice voting system would screw things up. It didn’t. In the end, Frey was&amp;#160;credited&amp;#160;with just over...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/jacob-frey-fends-off-challenge-from-fateh/"&gt;Jacob Frey fends off challenge from Fateh&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 19:07:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Let household hennery owners sell their produce for extra income</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/11/let-household-hennery-owners-sell-their-produce-for-extra-income/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Hawai’i County Council on Nov. 5, 2025._____________ Nov. 5, 2025, 9 a.m.Hawai‘i County Council Chambers in Hilo To: Hawai‘i County Council       Holeka Goro Inaba, Chair       Dennis “Fresh” Onishi, Vice Chair From: Grassroot Institute of Hawaii            Jonathan Helton, Policy Analyst RE: [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/11/let-household-hennery-owners-sell-their-produce-for-extra-income/"&gt;Let household hennery owners sell their produce for extra income&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 20:08:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Allow taller buildings for housing in city’s affordable rentals program</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/11/allow-taller-buildings-for-housing-in-citys-affordable-rentals-program/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Honolulu City Council on Nov. 5, 2025._____________ Nov. 5, 2025, 10 a.m.Honolulu Hale To: Honolulu City Council       Tommy Waters, Chair       Andria Tupola, Vice Chair From: Grassroot Institute of Hawaii            Ted Kefalas, Director of Strategic Campaigns RE: Bill 72 (2025) — [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/11/allow-taller-buildings-for-housing-in-citys-affordable-rentals-program/"&gt;Allow taller buildings for housing in city&amp;#8217;s affordable rentals program&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 20:35:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Oranges Don’t Grow on a Willow Tree</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/oranges-dont-grow-on-a-willow-tree/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On Nov. 9, 1989, the Berlin Wall fell. A scant 36 years later, on Nov. 4, 2025, America’s most populous city welcomed a “democratic socialist” with open arms. These two things aren’t unrelated. Zohran Mamdani’s election is the rotten fruit of the rotten tree. Good old American capitalism beat the dastardly commies in the 1980s...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/oranges-dont-grow-on-a-willow-tree/"&gt;Oranges Don’t Grow on a Willow Tree&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 21:11:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Escape the Partisan &amp; Populist Traps: Why Free Markets and Limited Government Are Your Antidote to Political Frustration</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/principles-of-liberty/escape-the-partisan-populist-traps-why-free-markets-and-limited-government-are-your-antidote-to-political-frustration/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Take the Quiz! In an era where partisan shouting matches dominate headlines and populist promises echo from every podium, it’s easy to feel disillusioned. Whether it’s red-vs-blue gridlock in Washington or fiery rhetoric in statehouses like Louisiana’s, the constant drumbeat of “us vs. them” leaves many craving something better. If you’re tired of politicians pitting...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/principles-of-liberty/escape-the-partisan-populist-traps-why-free-markets-and-limited-government-are-your-antidote-to-political-frustration/"&gt;Escape the Partisan &amp;#038; Populist Traps: Why Free Markets and Limited Government Are Your Antidote to Political Frustration&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 21:31:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] HCMC: Refocus the Mission, Reform the Funding – Save Minnesota’s Trauma Lifeline</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/hcmc-refocus-the-mission-reform-the-funding-save-minnesotas-trauma-lifeline/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In both the Annunciation attack and the 35W bridge collapse, every single victim who made it to the hospital survived. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/hcmc-refocus-the-mission-reform-the-funding-save-minnesotas-trauma-lifeline/"&gt;HCMC: Refocus the Mission, Reform the Funding – Save Minnesota’s Trauma Lifeline&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 22:03:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Improving Teacher Quality to Improve Reading Quality</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/performance/improving-teacher-quality-to-improve-reading-quality/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In my recent report, An Expedition to Improve Student Reading, I described Missouri’s falling reading scores and potential policy solutions. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/performance/improving-teacher-quality-to-improve-reading-quality/"&gt;Improving Teacher Quality to Improve Reading Quality&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 22:42:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Is America’s strongest advocate your local teacher?</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/is-americas-strongest-advocate-your-local-teacher/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The past decade of American soul-searching has left many adrift. Is America a fundamentally good country? Has it ever been&amp;#8211;or will it ever be in the future? Should children be told that America is fundamentally evil, or fundamentally good? Within the debate, teachers have received a good portion of blame for the impulse to rewrite...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/is-americas-strongest-advocate-your-local-teacher/"&gt;Is America&amp;#8217;s strongest advocate your local teacher?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 23:07:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] California Just Blew Past Last Year’s Record — And We’re Still Climbing</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/california-just-blew-past-last-years-record-and-were-still-climbing/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;California public employees are opting out of their unions in record numbers thanks to the work of the Freedom Foundation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/california-just-blew-past-last-years-record-and-were-still-climbing/" rel="nofollow"&gt;California Just Blew Past Last Year’s Record — And We’re Still Climbing&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 23:30:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] NYC headed toward ‘Marxist governance’</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/nyc-headed-toward-marxist-governance/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Jon Levine writes for the Washington Free Beacon about the impact of New York City’s mayoral election. Democratic nominee Zohran Mamdani secured a comfortable victory in the 2025 New York City mayoral election, ushering in a new era of Marxist governance in the United States&amp;#8217; largest city. Mamdani clinched his win with 50.4 percent of...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/nyc-headed-toward-marxist-governance/"&gt;NYC headed toward &amp;#8216;Marxist governance&amp;#8217;&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 10:36:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Congressional Republicans could cave while winning shutdown impasse</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/congressional-republicans-could-cave-while-winning-shutdown-impasse/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Eddie Scarry of the Federalist wonders whether congressional Republicans will snatch defeat from the jaws of victory. Not that anyone should count on congressional Republicans to take a win when it’s presented on a gold-plated platter, but with each passing second, their position on this stupid, Democrat-driven government “shut down” only grows stronger. Food stamp...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/congressional-republicans-could-cave-while-winning-shutdown-impasse/"&gt;Congressional Republicans could cave while winning shutdown impasse&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 10:39:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Trump’s favorability takes hit among independents</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/trumps-favorability-takes-hit-among-independents/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Terry Jones of Issues and Insights analyzes new polling data involving President Donald Trump. With the never-ending swirl of action around President Donald Trump, it’s often hard to tell how voters perceive his actions. In this month’s I&amp;#38;I/TIPP Poll, there’s been some erosion in Trump’s scores from voters as they pause to ponder the dizzying...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/trumps-favorability-takes-hit-among-independents/"&gt;Trump&amp;#8217;s favorability takes hit among independents&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 10:42:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Michigan budget deal: two steps forward, one step back</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/michigan-budget-deal-two-steps-forward-one-step-back</link><description>Divided state government managed to agree on some good policy</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] No need for hysteria over federal cuts to homeless housing</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/no-need-for-hysteria-over-federal-cuts-to-homeless-housing/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The usually levelheaded CalMatters reported that the expected deep cuts are the “latest blow in a seemingly endless barrage of bad news for the California agencies tasked with fighting homelessness.” The “news has sent counties throughout California into a panic” and they are “bracing to lose hundreds of millions of dollars,” the publication added. It’s time to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/no-need-for-hysteria-over-federal-cuts-to-homeless-housing/"&gt;No need for hysteria over federal cuts to homeless housing&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 11:00:20 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>