<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>State-Policy Think-Tank Digest</title><link>https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml</link><description>Latest posts from free-market policy institutes across the U.S.</description><atom:link href="https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 17:03:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>[Virginiainstitute] In memory of Charlie Kirk (1993-2025)</title><link>https://virginiainstitute.org/in-memory-of-charlie-kirk-1993-2025/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=in-memory-of-charlie-kirk-1993-2025</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Virginia Institute for Public Policy tonight remembers Charlie Kirk, his beautiful wife Erika, and his young daughter and son who will grow up without a father&amp;#8217;s loving care and&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org/in-memory-of-charlie-kirk-1993-2025/"&gt;In memory of Charlie Kirk (1993-2025)&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org"&gt;Virginia Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 02:59:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Virginiainstitute] Press Release – Coalition Applauds Executive Order 53</title><link>https://virginiainstitute.org/press-release-coalition-applauds-executive-order-53/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=press-release-coalition-applauds-executive-order-53</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Summary Virginia Fair Elections (VFE), a coalition committed to ensuring transparent and secure elections in Virginia, has publicly praised Governor Glenn Youngkin’s Executive Order 53, issued on September 12, 2025.&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org/press-release-coalition-applauds-executive-order-53/"&gt;Press Release – Coalition Applauds Executive Order 53&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org"&gt;Virginia Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 16:17:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Reflecting on a Grim Week</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/reflecting-on-a-grim-week/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The past few days have been deeply unsettling. &amp;#160;The assassination of Charlie Kirk, gunned down while addressing young Americans on a Utah college campus, was horrifying. It seems clear that Charlie was targeted for his beliefs, which he expressed with remarkable clarity and conviction. Over the past decade, Charlie Kirk emerged as one of a [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/reflecting-on-a-grim-week/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Reflecting on a Grim Week&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 21:18:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Rebekah Staples: Work Work Work</title><link>https://empowerms.org/rebekah-staples-work-work-work/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Rebekah Staples: Work Work Work More than just a paycheck, work is the foundation of prosperity and the pathway to earned success. This week, host Grant Callen sits down with Rebekah Staples President &amp;#38; Founder of Free State Strategies and a Contributing Fellow at Empower Mississippi. Hailing from The Free State of Jones (County), Rebekah&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/rebekah-staples-work-work-work/"&gt;Rebekah Staples: Work Work Work&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 23:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] GCO welcomes new team members to grow our BETTER WORK initiative</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/gco-welcomes-new-team-members/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/gco-welcomes-new-team-members/"&gt;GCO welcomes new team members to grow our BETTER WORK initiative&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 17:55:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] In defense of murder</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/09/17/in-defense-of-murder/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The alarming responses to the cold-blooded assassination of Charlie Kirk from both sides of the political aisle are derived from the same source: false worldview.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/09/17/in-defense-of-murder/"&gt;In defense of murder&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 18:52:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG: The Real State of Education</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-the-real-state-of-education/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;IRG: The Real State of Education Wisconsin Students are Left Behind Despite Record Investment in Schools Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government (IRG) released the following statement outlining the real State of Education in Wisconsin ahead of Superintendent of Public Instruction Jill Underly’s annual State of Education Address. &amp;#160; THE REAL STATE OF [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-the-real-state-of-education/"&gt;IRG: The Real State of Education&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 13:25:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Hugh Hewitt to headline Libertas Award Dinner; Frank Edelblut to receive 2025 Libertas Award</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/09/hugh-hewitt-to-headline-libertas-award-dinner-frank-edelblut-to-receive-2025-libertas-award/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Josiah Bartlett Center for Public Policy is proud to announce our 2025 Libertas Award Dinner on Monday, Nov. 10, featuring special guest Hugh Hewitt and recognizing Frank Edelblut with our 2025 Libertas Award.  “At a time when fair, honest, and open discourse is so important for New Hampshire and the nation, we’re thrilled to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/09/hugh-hewitt-to-headline-libertas-award-dinner-frank-edelblut-to-receive-2025-libertas-award/"&gt;Hugh Hewitt to headline Libertas Award Dinner; Frank Edelblut to receive 2025 Libertas Award&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 18:31:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] Sec. McMahon, TPUSA, AFPI, API, and Partners Launch National Civics Coalition</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/09/18/sec-mcmahon-tpusa-afpi-api-and-partners-launch-national-civics-coalition/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Department of Education (the Department), in partnership the America First Policy Institute (AFPI), Turning Point USA, Hillsdale College and more than 40 leading national and state-based organizations, today announced the launch of the America 250 Civics Education Coalition. This landmark initiative is dedicated to renewing patriotism, strengthening civic knowledge, and advancing a shared understanding of America’s founding principles in schools across the nation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/09/18/sec-mcmahon-tpusa-afpi-api-and-partners-launch-national-civics-coalition/"&gt;Sec. McMahon, TPUSA, AFPI, API, and Partners Launch National Civics Coalition&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 23:19:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Kansas Needs More Capitalism, Not Cronyism or Socialism</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/kansas-needs-more-capitalism/</link><description>Gallup recently found that just 54% of Americans now view capitalism positively, the lowest share since they began asking the question in 2010. That’s down from 60% in 2021, which is about where it has been since at least 2010. Meanwhile, 39% still view socialism positively, a number that hasn’t changed much overall but masks [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 14:00:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Weight Loss Drugs Pack on the Fat to State Spending</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/weight-loss-drugs-pack-on-the-fat-to-state-spending/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/weight-loss-drugs-pack-on-the-fat-to-state-spending/" rel="nofollow" title="Weight Loss Drugs Pack on the Fat to State Spending"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Article-Headers-2025-09-19T163637.101.png" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Well, isn’t that generous? The Group Insurance Advisory Committee (GIAC), under the Office of Group Insurance (OGI) within the Department of Administration — ever the example of fiscal responsibility — unilaterally decided to extend the GLP-1 weight-loss drugs to the employee health benefits plan for the previous few years. But don’t worry, when it was [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 23:51:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] Governor Shapiro Again Blames PJM for High Energy Prices, Ignores True Culprit: His Policies</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/09/22/governor-shapiro-again-blames-pjm-for-high-energy-prices-ignores-true-culprit-his-policies/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Harrisburg, Pa., September 22, 2025 — This week, Gov. Josh Shapiro is speaking as Pennsylvania hosts PJM governors for the Multi-State Technical Conference in Philadelphia. The conference comes on the heels of rising criticism of PJM from certain governors, expressing concerns over rising electricity costs, reliability of the electric grid, and project delays. Gov. Shapiro [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/09/22/governor-shapiro-again-blames-pjm-for-high-energy-prices-ignores-true-culprit-his-policies/"&gt;Governor Shapiro Again Blames PJM for High Energy Prices, Ignores True Culprit: His Policies&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 20:11:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Freedom Wins: The Future of Education is Here</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/freedom-wins-the-future-of-education-is-here/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=freedom-wins-the-future-of-education-is-here</link><description>While the EFS success is a great reason to celebrate, there is more work to be done to unlock education freedom for all Tennesseans.</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 16:17:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Mississippi Leadership Academy Kicks Off 2025 Program with State Leaders</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/mississippi-leadership-academy-kicks-off-2025-program-with-state-leaders/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For Immediate Release Jackson, MS – September 23, 2025&amp;#160;— Students from across Mississippi gathered in Jackson on Saturday for the&amp;#160;opening session of the 2025 Mississippi Leadership Academy, a program that equips high school and college students with leadership training, civic knowledge, and direct access to state leaders. This year’s kickoff featured&amp;#160;State Auditor Shad White, Representative [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/mississippi-leadership-academy-kicks-off-2025-program-with-state-leaders/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Leadership Academy Kicks Off 2025 Program with State Leaders&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 20:50:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] We Are Charlie Kirk: The Call of a Generation</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/we-are-charlie-kirk-the-call-of-a-generation/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/we-are-charlie-kirk-the-call-of-a-generation/" rel="nofollow" title="We Are Charlie Kirk: The Call of a Generation"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Article-Headers-2.jpg" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;It’s been 13 days since one of the most influential political and religious figures of the 21st century was assassinated on a university campus in Orem, Utah. September 10, 2025, will forever be branded as one of the most significant dates in contemporary American history. It will live in infamy alongside dates such as November [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 23:28:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Nebraskanomics: Governor Jim Pillen on Moving Nebraska Forward</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/nebraskanomics-governor-jim-pillen-on-moving-nebraska-forward/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Tune in to the latest episode of Nebraskanomics as we welcome the 41st Governor of the State of Nebraska, Governor Jim Pillen. During the episode Governor Pillen and Platte Institute Chief Executive Officer Jim Vokal discuss how we provide property tax reform for Nebraskans, the importance of making the most of federal funds, and what’s...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/nebraskanomics-governor-jim-pillen-on-moving-nebraska-forward/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Nebraskanomics: Governor Jim Pillen on Moving Nebraska Forward&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 14:43:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Improve Education Outcomes by Removing Barriers</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/education/improve-education-outcomes-by-removing-barriers/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Kathryn Hickok The National Association of Education Progress (NAEP) annually releases a...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/education/improve-education-outcomes-by-removing-barriers/"&gt;Improve Education Outcomes by Removing Barriers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 17:12:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Nebraska Property Taxes Keep Rising Despite Tax Caps</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-property-taxes-keep-rising-despite-tax-caps/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Nebraska’s Truth-in-Taxation season brings surprises each year, shining a light on local government tax increases. That’s because Nebraska’s Truth-in-Taxation law requires local governments to notify property owners of proposed tax increases as a prelude to public hearings about the tax proposals.  Residents of Omaha were hit with another set of unsustainable tax increases in 2025, as...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-property-taxes-keep-rising-despite-tax-caps/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Nebraska Property Taxes Keep Rising Despite Tax Caps&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 15:30:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF in National Review: Take It from Albuquerque: Free Transit Is a Bad Idea</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-in-national-review-take-it-from-albuquerque-free-transit-is-a-bad-idea/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following appeared at National Review on September 25, 2025. Zohran Mamdani should get the hint and scrap his proposal for New York City. The cities of Albuquerque and New York don’t have a great deal in common. One is a densely packed East Coast metropolis, while the other is a relatively spread out (and much [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-in-national-review-take-it-from-albuquerque-free-transit-is-a-bad-idea/"&gt;RGF in National Review: Take It from Albuquerque: Free Transit Is a Bad Idea&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 16:44:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Statement of Pioneer Institute on Board Member Mike Kennealy’s Bid for Governor</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/transparency/statement-of-pioneer-institute-on-board-member-mike-kennealys-bid-for-governor/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This statement was released on April 15, 2025. BOSTON – Congratulations to Mike Kennealy on his decision to run for Governor of Massachusetts. Mike has served as a thoughtful and deeply engaged member of Pioneer Institute’s board since 2023. We are grateful for his contributions and his commitment to the Commonwealth. Pioneer is an independent, non-partisan think tank with offices in Boston and Washington, D.C. Our work is grounded in four policy areas essential to human potential: K–12 education, healthcare, economic opportunity, and American civic values. These issues are especially vital in Massachusetts—a state whose success depends on attracting talent and capital. Innovation has always come from the states, and democracy depends on citizens who bring ideas, commitment, and a spirit [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/transparency/statement-of-pioneer-institute-on-board-member-mike-kennealys-bid-for-governor/"&gt;Statement of Pioneer Institute on Board Member Mike Kennealy’s Bid for Governor&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 17:14:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] Test Scores Changes Backfire on Education Establishment</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/test-scores-changes-backfire-on-education-establishment/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Test Scores Changes Backfire on Education Establishment Test score changes display widening gaps Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government (IRG) released the following statement following the release of Forward Exam and ACT test scores on Thursday showing mixed performance of K-12 schools in Wisconsin.  WHAT HAPPENED: Under Superintendent of Public Instruction Jill Underly’s [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/test-scores-changes-backfire-on-education-establishment/"&gt;Test Scores Changes Backfire on Education Establishment&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 17:52:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] The ‘I do not care about your economics’ approach to housing</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/09/the-i-do-not-care-about-your-economics-approach-to-housing/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;With a single heated remark to a developer, a Portsmouth Planning Board member last week showed exactly how the municipal development process is broken. Developer Mark McNabb has proposed converting a property he owns on Congress Street to a 125-unit co-living apartment building. Co-living units, once common, were zoned nearly out of existence in U.S. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/09/the-i-do-not-care-about-your-economics-approach-to-housing/"&gt;The &amp;#8216;I do not care about your economics&amp;#8217; approach to housing&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 13:47:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Idaho’s Parental Choice Tax Credit Is Constitutional</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/idahos-parental-choice-tax-credit-is-constitutional/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/idahos-parental-choice-tax-credit-is-constitutional/" rel="nofollow" title="Idaho’s Parental Choice Tax Credit Is Constitutional"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Article-Headers-2025-09-26T132715.417.png" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;A coalition of Leftist activists, including the Idaho Education Association, the Moscow School District, and Rep. Stephanie Mickelsen (R), has filed a challenge to block the implementation of Idaho’s parental choice tax credit. However, petitioners’ frivolous claims lack any basis in either our state constitution or Idaho Supreme Court precedent. Idaho’s school choice program is [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 19:54:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] The Silent Decline of Hillcrest Christian School: When Private Doesn’t Mean Privileged</title><link>https://empowerms.org/the-silent-decline-of-hillcrest-christian-school-when-private-doesnt-mean-privileged/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In the heart of Mississippi sits Hillcrest Christian School, a beacon of faith-based education serving predominantly African-American students in south Jackson. Once bustling with 1,200 students, today the halls echo with just over 200 enrolled children. This steep decline is more than just numbers—it’s a story of a community at risk of losing a vital&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/the-silent-decline-of-hillcrest-christian-school-when-private-doesnt-mean-privileged/"&gt;The Silent Decline of Hillcrest Christian School: When Private Doesn’t Mean Privileged&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 18:00:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] KSDE and the Kansas State Board of Education ignore state literacy law; will the Legislature let them get away with it?</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/ksdes-state-board-of-education-literacy-law/</link><description>Time after time, the Kansas Department of Education and the State Board of Education allow school districts to violate state laws designed to improve student outcomes, and now they’ve shamelessly done it again. The Legislature passed the Every Child Can Read Act in 2022, requiring literacy to be attained through the Science of Reading, evidence-based [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 12:15:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Why Affordable Housing is Unaffordable</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/land-use/why-affordable-housing-is-unaffordable/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Randal O’Toole Last week KGW news reported that Portland area rents are...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/land-use/why-affordable-housing-is-unaffordable/"&gt;Why Affordable Housing is Unaffordable&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 12:48:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Overtime Spiking in the State Police</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/09/30/overtime-spiking-in-the-state-police/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="876" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Screenshot-2025-09-25-092253-1.jpg" width="1224" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new report commissioned by Yankee Institute and the Nutmeg Research Initiative uncovers widespread overtime (OT) spiking within the Connecticut State Police that inflates pensions and imposes significant costs on [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/09/30/overtime-spiking-in-the-state-police/"&gt;Overtime Spiking in the State Police&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 15:25:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Jere Nash: Reconstruction in Mississippi</title><link>https://empowerms.org/jere-nash-reconstruction-in-mississippi/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Jere Nash: Reconstruction in Mississippi On this episode, host Grant Callen sits down with historian Jere Nash, a Greenville native, retired political consultant, and co-author of award-winning books. Jere’s latest work, Reconstruction in Mississippi, 1862-1877, offers a definitive look at a pivotal era. We discuss why Jere chose to explore Reconstruction, debunk common myths, and examine&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/jere-nash-reconstruction-in-mississippi/"&gt;Jere Nash: Reconstruction in Mississippi&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 22:00:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Recasting Lawrenceville as a resilient, connected community</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/recast-lawrenceville-josiah-story/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Through our partnership with the ReCAST initiative, residents in Lawrenceville are finding purpose, hope, and connection through employment.   One powerful example is Josiah, who found a path forward by participating in our Jobs for Life class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/recast-lawrenceville-josiah-story/"&gt;Recasting Lawrenceville as a resilient, connected community&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:04:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] Hours Away from Federal Government Shutdown, Pennsylvania Remains Vulnerable</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/09/30/governor-shapiros-failed-leadership-resulting-in-a-monthslong-state-budget-impasse-has-left-pennsylvanians-more-vulnerable-in-the-event-of-a-federal-shutdown/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Harrisburg, Pa., September 30, 2025 —&amp;#160;A federal government shutdown is set to begin at midnight, barring a last-minute deal.&amp;#160;For Pennsylvania residents, the commonwealth remains in a dangerously precarious position, with a looming federal shutdown overlapping with its four-month-long state budget impasse. Despite reporting that a budget deal was “very, very close” in June, Gov. Josh [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/09/30/governor-shapiros-failed-leadership-resulting-in-a-monthslong-state-budget-impasse-has-left-pennsylvanians-more-vulnerable-in-the-event-of-a-federal-shutdown/"&gt;Hours Away from Federal Government Shutdown, Pennsylvania Remains Vulnerable &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 01:50:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] New Study Shows Hidden Costs of Portland’s Rent Control</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/new-study-shows-hidden-costs-of-portlands-rent-control/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Portland’s leaders sold rent control as a lifeline for struggling tenants. But a new independent economic study reveals it’s becoming a noose around the neck of the city’s homeowners, who are already shouldering rising costs across the board. The Greater Portland Board of Realtors recently released an independent study conducted by Wallace Economic Advisers that [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/new-study-shows-hidden-costs-of-portlands-rent-control/"&gt;New Study Shows Hidden Costs of Portland&amp;#8217;s Rent Control&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 12:54:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Nebraska Property Taxes Now 4th Highest Nationwide</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-property-taxes-now-4th-highest-nationwide/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Nebraska’s property taxes have risen to fourth highest in the United States, according to a 2025 study from the Tax Foundation using 2023 tax data. Illinois (1.83%) has the highest taxes as a share of home value, followed closely by New Jersey (1.77%). Following New Jersey is Connecticut (1.48%) which is only slightly higher than...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-property-taxes-now-4th-highest-nationwide/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Nebraska Property Taxes Now 4th Highest Nationwide&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 13:48:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] U-Ark’s Randall Woods on John Quincy Adams: Statesman of the Early Republic</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/news/u-arks-randall-woods-on-john-quincy-adams-statesman-of-the-early-republic/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In this week’s episode of The Learning Curve, co-hosts U-Arkansas Prof. Albert Cheng and Center for Public Schools’ Alisha Searcy interview Randall Woods, John A. Cooper Distinguished Professor of History at the University of Arkansas, and author of John Quincy Adams: A Man for the Whole People. Prof. Woods shares the life and career of American statesman John Quincy Adams, the “first son of the Republic,” whose upbringing in the household of John and Abigail Adams shaped his lifelong devotion to public service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/news/u-arks-randall-woods-on-john-quincy-adams-statesman-of-the-early-republic/"&gt;U-Ark&amp;#8217;s Randall Woods on John Quincy Adams: Statesman of the Early Republic&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 15:33:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] NJ ED REPORT: Two NJ Teachers Sue NJEA For Misusing Their Union Dues In Bid for Governor</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/10/nj-ed-report-two-nj-teachers-sue-njea-for-misusing-their-union-dues-in-bid-for-governor/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;#160; Two NJ Teachers Sue NJEA For Misusing Their Union Dues In Bid for Governor By Laura Waters  October 1, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/10/nj-ed-report-two-nj-teachers-sue-njea-for-misusing-their-union-dues-in-bid-for-governor/"&gt;NJ ED REPORT: Two NJ Teachers Sue NJEA For Misusing Their Union Dues In Bid for Governor&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 15:49:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Why New York’s Health Premiums Keep Going Up</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/why-new-yorks-health-premiums-keep-going-up/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New Yorkers continue to face some of the costliest health premiums in the U.S., and the insurance industry&amp;#8217;s recently finalized....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/why-new-yorks-health-premiums-keep-going-up/"&gt;Why New York&amp;#8217;s Health Premiums Keep Going Up&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 16:29:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] First Principles Series: The Importance of Protecting our First Amendment Rights</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/first-amendment-fp/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=first-amendment-fp</link><description>Beacon tirelessly advocates for the principles of liberty whether government officials like them or not. Thanks to the First Amendment, all Americans are free to do the same.</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 18:16:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] Opinion piece: In New Mexico, there’s money for everything but roads</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/opinion-piece-in-new-mexico-theres-money-for-everything-but-roads/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following appeared in the Santa Fe New Mexican on September 27, 2025 (and other New Mexico papers). New Mexico is facing an increasingly dire situation on its roads. A recent Albuquerque Journal story stated that “New Mexico faces a $471.6 million gap in funding for priority projects around the state.” A total of $5.6 billion is [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/opinion-piece-in-new-mexico-theres-money-for-everything-but-roads/"&gt;Opinion piece: In New Mexico, there&amp;#8217;s money for everything but roads&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 19:30:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Keep it Simple</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/keep-it-simple/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon, an American technology company, is no stranger to the Federal Trade Commission (FTC), its role, and the way it has recently been carrying out its responsibilities. Antitrust action and allegations of anticompetitive behavior have haunted Amazon as the company grows and expands its offerings for consumers. While the court of public opinion clearly values...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/keep-it-simple/"&gt;Keep it Simple&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 15:02:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] Alabama Fights for Freedom</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/10/02/alabama-fights-for-freedom/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Defending higher education means defending SB 129. The core of SB 129 is not to censor but to restore balance between individual liberty and government overreach in education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/10/02/alabama-fights-for-freedom/"&gt;Alabama Fights for Freedom&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 16:48:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] BERGEN RECORD: The NJEA’s funding of Sean Spiller’s campaign was wrong. We need accountability | Opinion</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/10/bergen-record-the-njeas-funding-of-sean-spillers-campaign-was-wrong-we-need-accountability-opinion/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The NJEA&amp;#8217;s funding of Sean Spiller&amp;#8217;s campaign was wrong. We need accountability &amp;#124; Opinion &amp;#160; By: Rosemary Becchi October 2, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/10/bergen-record-the-njeas-funding-of-sean-spillers-campaign-was-wrong-we-need-accountability-opinion/"&gt;BERGEN RECORD: The NJEA’s funding of Sean Spiller’s campaign was wrong. We need accountability | Opinion&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 18:19:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] SPOTLIGHT NJ: NJ teachers sue over $40 million campaign boost for union president</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/10/spotlight-nj-nj-teachers-sue-over-40-million-campaign-boost-for-union-president/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;NJ teachers sue over $40 million campaign boost for union president NJEA used member dues to get its president elected [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/10/spotlight-nj-nj-teachers-sue-over-40-million-campaign-boost-for-union-president/"&gt;SPOTLIGHT NJ: NJ teachers sue over $40 million campaign boost for union president&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 18:24:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Gov. Mills Opposes Question 2, but for the Wrong Reasons</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/gov-mills-opposes-question-2-but-for-the-wrong-reasons/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Last week, Governor Janet Mills came out against Question 2, the so-called “Red Flag” law referendum on this November’s ballot. In public statements and op-eds, the governor argued that the measure was poorly constructed, potentially confusing, and burdensome on Maine families. On these points, she is absolutely right. But while Governor Mills urges a “No” [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/gov-mills-opposes-question-2-but-for-the-wrong-reasons/"&gt;Gov. Mills Opposes Question 2, but for the Wrong Reasons&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 18:44:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] First Principles Series: The Practical Case for Protecting Free Speech</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/free-speech-fp/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=free-speech-fp</link><description>Our “First Principles Series” is an ongoing awareness effort by Beacon to restore our nation’s commitment to those principles of free markets, individual liberty, and limited government that have made America the best nation in the history of the world. Often, politicians eager to appease constituents can stray from these principles. And voters can be misled...</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 19:21:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] WASHINGTON: Email pitch targets UW workers</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/washington-email-pitch-targets-uw-workers/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Another union finds itself in the Freedom Foundation’s opt-out radar thanks to an email sent last month to University of Washington workers represented by United Auto Workers Local 4121.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/washington-email-pitch-targets-uw-workers/" rel="nofollow"&gt;WASHINGTON: Email pitch targets UW workers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 22:23:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Yankee Institute Welcomes Jack DeOliveira as its New Director of Policy</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/10/03/yankee-institute-welcomes-jack-deoliveira-as-its-new-director-of-policy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Yankee Institute is pleased to announce that Jack DeOliveira has joined the organization as its new Director of Policy, where he will lead Yankee’s research and advocacy initiatives. A Connecticut native, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/10/03/yankee-institute-welcomes-jack-deoliveira-as-its-new-director-of-policy/"&gt;Yankee Institute Welcomes Jack DeOliveira as its New Director of Policy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 14:23:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] New York’s Immigrant Health Coverage Becomes a National Flash Point</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/new-yorks-immigrant-health-coverage-becomes-a-national-flash-point/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A little-noticed New York program that provides Medicaid coverage to elderly undocumented immigrants was thrust onto the national stage this....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/new-yorks-immigrant-health-coverage-becomes-a-national-flash-point/"&gt;New York&amp;#8217;s Immigrant Health Coverage Becomes a National Flash Point&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 17:22:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Unleash home builders to fight socialism</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/10/unleash-home-builders-to-fight-socialism/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On Monday, a young woman from New Hampshire was featured prominently in a front-page Wall Street Journal story. She didn’t found a company or create a valuable new product. Quite the opposite; she spent the summer canvassing for the Democratic Socialists of America in New York City, where she hopes to get socialist Zohran Mamdani [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/10/unleash-home-builders-to-fight-socialism/"&gt;Unleash home builders to fight socialism&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 20:36:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] 85% of Americans Want Union Transparency. Connecticut’s Labor Dept Says No</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/10/03/85-of-americans-want-union-transparency-connecticuts-labor-dept-says-no/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A U.S. Chamber of Commerce survey finds 85% of Americans want to know how unions spend their dues. In Connecticut, however, the Department of Labor (CTDOL) charged with enforcing a [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/10/03/85-of-americans-want-union-transparency-connecticuts-labor-dept-says-no/"&gt;85% of Americans Want Union Transparency. Connecticut’s Labor Dept Says No&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 21:29:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Wyoming is overexposed to impacts of a changing federal budget</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/wyoming-is-overexposed-to-impacts-of-a-changing-federal-budget</link><description>With a federal government shutdown upon us and even more importantly, ballooning national debt jeopardizing the solvency of Social...</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 14:24:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cardinalinstitute] One Big Beautiful Opportunity to Reconnect West Virginians with Stable Work</title><link>https://cardinalinstitute.com/one-big-beautiful-opportunity-to-reconnect-west-virginians-with-work/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;One Big Beautiful Bill is One Big Beautiful Opportunity to Reconnect West Virginians with Stable Work On July 4, President Donald Trump signed the latest congressional reconciliation package, known colloquially as the One Big Beautiful Bill Act (OBBB), a sweeping package of federal budget measures including extension of the 2017 tax cuts, spending cuts and [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com/one-big-beautiful-opportunity-to-reconnect-west-virginians-with-work/"&gt;One Big Beautiful Opportunity to Reconnect West Virginians with Stable Work&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com"&gt;Cardinal Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 17:57:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Gov. Mills Declines to Use New Authority to Deliver Tax Relief</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/gov-mills-declines-to-use-new-authority-to-deliver-tax-relief/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In mid-2025, Congress passed the One Big Beautiful Bill Act (OBBBA), a comprehensive federal tax reform measure designed to alleviate the burden on working families, seniors, and small businesses. Its numerous provisions include the following: All of these changes apply retroactively to January 1, 2025, but unless Maine acts, state taxes will still apply to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/gov-mills-declines-to-use-new-authority-to-deliver-tax-relief/"&gt;Gov. Mills Declines to Use New Authority to Deliver Tax Relief&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 18:26:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] All schools win under new Michigan budget</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/all-schools-win-under-new-michigan-budget</link><description>2026 school aid plan includes charters, benefits public schools</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] JMI Releases 2026 Policy Priorities</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/jmi-releases-2026-policy-priorities/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASEOctober 7th, 2025 CONTACTLogan Elizabeth Padgett850-386-3131 JMI Releases 2026 Policy Priorities TALLAHASSEE – Today, The James Madison Institute...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/jmi-releases-2026-policy-priorities/"&gt;JMI Releases 2026 Policy Priorities&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Cartels are now ‘unlawful combatants.’ About time.</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/cartels-are-now-unlawful-combatants-about-time/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For decades, the US fought crime while the cartels fought war. Trump’s designation ends the fantasy and gives America the legal authority to strike back — hard. President Donald Trump has finally named the enemy: Mexican drug cartels. Declaring them unlawful combatants and recognizing a “non-international armed conflict” marks one of the most consequential national...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/cartels-are-now-unlawful-combatants-about-time/"&gt;Cartels are now ‘unlawful combatants.’ About time.&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 13:15:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Washington state agencies discredit their own plastic bag ban study</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/washington-state-agencies-discredit-their-own-plastic-bag-ban-study</link><description>This article was originally published by the Washington Policy Center . It is reposted with permission. Washington state’s ban on thin...</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 14:10:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] The Unsafe School Choice Option (USCO)</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/education/the-unsafe-school-choice-option-usco/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Unsafe School Choice Option (USCO) is a federal safeguard created under the Every Student Succeeds Act (ESSA), which ensures [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/education/the-unsafe-school-choice-option-usco/"&gt;The Unsafe School Choice Option (USCO)&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 14:51:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Kansas Can Learn from Washington’s Shutdown Mistakes</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/kansas-can-learn-shutdown-mistakes/</link><description>The federal government shutdown on October 1 because Congress couldn’t agree on how much more of our money to spend. It’s become routine in Washington: wait until the last minute, pass a short-term fix, and promise to deal with the problem later. That’s how we ended up with a national debt of more than $37.4 [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 17:00:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] California Justice Center Urges Supreme Court to End School Policies that Hide Student Gender Transitions from Parents</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/amicus-littlejohn-v-school-board-of-leon-county/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=amicus-littlejohn-v-school-board-of-leon-county</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Amicus Brief Filed in Littlejohn v. School Board of Leon County, Florida Washington, DC — The California Justice Center joined the Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;#38; Policy and Liberty Justice Center in filing an amicus curiae brief with the U.S. Supreme Court on Monday in support of the parents in Littlejohn v. School Board of Leon...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/amicus-littlejohn-v-school-board-of-leon-county/"&gt;California Justice Center Urges Supreme Court to End School Policies that Hide Student Gender Transitions from Parents&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 18:13:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Teachers allege union president diverted $40 million into his own gubernatorial campaign</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/new-jersey/teachers-allege-union-president-diverted-40-million-into-his-own-gubernatorial-campaign/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Their claim? The NJEA secretly funneled more than $40 million of teachers’ dues to political groups supporting Spiller’s failed run for governor — money that was never approved, never disclosed, and never meant for politics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/new-jersey/teachers-allege-union-president-diverted-40-million-into-his-own-gubernatorial-campaign/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Teachers allege union president diverted $40 million into his own gubernatorial campaign&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 20:43:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Don’t Hate, Congratulate: A Victory for America’s HBCUs</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/dont-hate-congratulate-a-victory-for-americas-hbcus/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The truth about HBCU funding is simple: Major and meaningful investments are being made, and the numbers tell the story. Yet in today’s virtual reality, false narratives often move faster than facts, and innuendo overshadows action. Fortunately, in the real world, results speak louder than rhetoric. For more than a century, our HBCUs have carried...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/dont-hate-congratulate-a-victory-for-americas-hbcus/"&gt;Don’t Hate, Congratulate: A Victory for America’s HBCUs&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 22:06:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Without reforms, pension insolvency will eat Chicago alive</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/without-reforms-pension-insolvency-will-eat-chicago-alive/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;If Chicago’s pension systems become insolvent, the city will have to reduce benefits or make serious cuts to city services. The only way out is constitutional reform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/without-reforms-pension-insolvency-will-eat-chicago-alive/"&gt;Without reforms, pension insolvency will eat Chicago alive&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 10:00:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Ten for Tech in 2026</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/ten-for-tech-in-2026/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;FOSTERING INNOVATION: A STATE POLICYMAKER’S GUIDE TO TECHNOLOGICAL PROGRESS An American from 1926, transported to 2026, would witness...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/ten-for-tech-in-2026/"&gt;Ten for Tech in 2026&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] WILL Lawsuit Challenges “Cream City Carve Out”</title><link>https://will-law.org/will-lawsuit-challenges-cream-city-carve-out/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL has filed a new lawsuit against Milwaukee County to end an unconstitutional carve out allowing Milwaukee County withhold millions from Wisconsin’s Common School Fund.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/will-lawsuit-challenges-cream-city-carve-out/"&gt;WILL Lawsuit Challenges “Cream City Carve Out”&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 13:45:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Idaho is powering up its nuclear efforts</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/idaho-is-powering-up-its-nuclear-efforts</link><description>The future of nuclear power in Idaho is looking strong. The Gem State recently took two important steps demonstrating its commitment to...</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 14:20:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Stueland v. Cullen</title><link>https://will-law.org/stueland-v-cullen/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL has filed a new lawsuit against Milwaukee County to end an unconstitutional carve out allowing Milwaukee County to withhold millions from Wisconsin’s Common School Fund. This fund, mandated by the Wisconsin Constitution, supports libraries in schools and communities across Wisconsin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/stueland-v-cullen/"&gt;Stueland v. Cullen&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 14:45:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG Report: Federal Bureaucrats Are Quietly Shaping Wisconsin Policy</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-report-federal-bureaucrats-are-quietly-shaping-wisconsin-policy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;IRG Report: Federal Bureaucrats Are Quietly Shaping Wisconsin Policy Guidance documents bypass legislature and voters, change state policy &amp;#160; Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government (IRG) released a new report on Wednesday detailing how federal agencies are quietly steering Wisconsin policy through informal “guidance documents,” often bypassing state legislative oversight. &amp;#160; READ THE [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-report-federal-bureaucrats-are-quietly-shaping-wisconsin-policy/"&gt;IRG Report: Federal Bureaucrats Are Quietly Shaping Wisconsin Policy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 15:11:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Corporate Welfare: Picking Winners and Creating Losers</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/tax-budget/corporate-welfare-picking-winners-and-creating-losers/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Politicians love to announce “big wins” when a new factory breaks ground or a large company pledges to bring jobs to town. The photo ops are flashy, the headlines are positive, and taxpayers are told it’s all part of a smart economic development strategy. Some may even point to these announcements as evidence that our...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/tax-budget/corporate-welfare-picking-winners-and-creating-losers/"&gt;Corporate Welfare: Picking Winners and Creating Losers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 15:27:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Podcast: DEI Is Built on A Lie</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/podcast-dei-is-built-on-a-lie/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;What happens when the language of progress—“diversity,” “equity,” “inclusion”—becomes a mask for a new kind of orthodoxy? In the latest..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/podcast-dei-is-built-on-a-lie/"&gt;Podcast: DEI Is Built on A Lie&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 16:04:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] U-Ark’s Robert Maranto &amp; BASIS Ed Texas’ Sean Woytek on Academically Intensive Charter Schools</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/u-arks-robert-maranto-basis-ed-texas-sean-woytek-on-academically-intensive-charter-schools/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In this week’s episode of The Learning Curve, co-hosts U-Arkansas Prof. Albert Cheng and Walter Blanks of the American Federation for Children interview Prof. Robert Maranto and Sean Woytek co-authors of the Education Next piece, “Why Academically Intensive Charter Schools Deserve Our Attention.” They explore how rigorous charter school networks like BASIS Ed have achieved exceptional outcomes and what their success can teach policymakers and educators nationwide about improving academic performance nationwide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/u-arks-robert-maranto-basis-ed-texas-sean-woytek-on-academically-intensive-charter-schools/"&gt;U-Ark&amp;#8217;s Robert Maranto &amp;#038; BASIS Ed Texas&amp;#8217; Sean Woytek on Academically Intensive Charter Schools&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 16:09:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Give Me Your Innovators, Your AI: The Promise of America for European Technology</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/give-me-your-innovators-your-ai-the-promise-of-america-for-european-technology/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;There is a growing disconnect between America’s technology industry and America’s technology legislation. The dissonance between a culture where competition is driving profound feats of innovation and one wherein risk-aversion trumps all has become more pronounced with the proliferation of artificial intelligence (AI). Uniting policy and practice will be essential to maintaining American leadership in...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/give-me-your-innovators-your-ai-the-promise-of-america-for-european-technology/"&gt;Give Me Your Innovators, Your AI: The Promise of America for European Technology&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 16:30:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] In the Fight Over ACA Tax Credits, the Stakes Are Lowest for New York</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/in-the-fight-over-aca-tax-credits-the-stakes-are-lowest-for-new-york/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As Washington skirmishes over the future of enhanced tax credits under the Affordable Care Act, New York has relatively little....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/in-the-fight-over-aca-tax-credits-the-stakes-are-lowest-for-new-york/"&gt;In the Fight Over ACA Tax Credits, the Stakes Are Lowest for New York&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 18:14:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Is Taxpayer-Funded Lobbying an Even Bigger Problem than We Know?</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/is-taxpayer-funded-lobbying-an-even-bigger-problem-than-we-know/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Is taxpayer-funded lobbying a bigger problem than many Texans suspect? It certainly seems so based on one Dallas city councilmember’s recent verbal slip-up. On August 27, 2025, the Dallas city council held a regular hearing to discuss public business, including an agenda item (#51) to: “Authorize a two-year personal services contract, with one two-year renewal...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/is-taxpayer-funded-lobbying-an-even-bigger-problem-than-we-know/"&gt;Is Taxpayer-Funded Lobbying an Even Bigger Problem than We Know?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 20:19:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Vapes of Wrath: Fighting E-Cigarette Censorship at the Oregon Supreme Court</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/vapes-of-wrath-fighting-e-cigarette-censorship-at-the-oregon-supreme-court/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;All business owners have the right — and the need — to communicate truthfully with their customers. But even though..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/vapes-of-wrath-fighting-e-cigarette-censorship-at-the-oregon-supreme-court/"&gt;Vapes of Wrath: Fighting E-Cigarette Censorship at the Oregon Supreme Court&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 21:41:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] The Progressive’s “Affordability Agenda” is a Fraud</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/the-progressives-affordability-agenda/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=the-progressives-affordability-agenda</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In the wake of devastating setbacks in the 2024 elections, Progressives are deemphasizing identity politics and instead are prioritizing economic issues. Progressives are now embracing an “abundance movement” and claiming they are the party to deliver abundance to working families. The latest iteration of this new strategy was expressed by progressive activist and pundit Donna...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/the-progressives-affordability-agenda/"&gt;The Progressive’s “Affordability Agenda” is a Fraud&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 21:45:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] Day 100 of State Budget Impasse</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/10/08/day-100-of-state-budget-impasse/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On Hundredth Day of the Shapiro Shutdown, PA Democrats Push Spending &amp;#38; Tax Hikes  Harrisburg, Pa., October 8, 2025 — Day 100 of the state budget shutdown brought chaos to the Capitol rotunda, with partisan political theater from Pennsylvania House and Senate Democrats placing parties even farther apart at the negotiating&amp;#160;table.&amp;#160; After previously rejecting and [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/10/08/day-100-of-state-budget-impasse/"&gt;Day 100 of State Budget Impasse&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 00:25:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] California’s Transit Industrial Complex is Monetizing Mobility</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/californias-transit-industrial-complex-is-monetizing-mobility/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=californias-transit-industrial-complex-is-monetizing-mobility</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Those of us who prefer smaller, more cost-effective government often applaud privatization. But if private companies can profit by making the public sector bigger and more expensive, they will do so. That&amp;#8217;s the case with the private engineering firms that profit from such costly California rail boondoggles as the high-speed rail project. The phenomenon of...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/californias-transit-industrial-complex-is-monetizing-mobility/"&gt;California’s Transit Industrial Complex is Monetizing Mobility&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 02:55:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Decarceration’s Disconnect: Corrections spending rises in Georgia even as prison population declines</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/georgia-prison-spending-and-reform/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Prison reform debates often focus on reducing prison populations to save taxpayers money. But is that actually possible? In a new report for the Manhattan Institute, Joshua Crawford, Public Safety Fellow at the Georgia Center for Opportunity, reveals some surprising answers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/georgia-prison-spending-and-reform/"&gt;Decarceration’s Disconnect: Corrections spending rises in Georgia even as prison population declines&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 04:09:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Chicago Teachers Union undermines yet another charter school</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/chicago-teachers-union-undermines-yet-another-charter-school/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Chicago Teachers Union’s attacks on charter schools are to blame for the upcoming closure of the Chicago High School for the Arts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/chicago-teachers-union-undermines-yet-another-charter-school/"&gt;Chicago Teachers Union undermines yet another charter school&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 10:00:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] A brief case for electricity choice</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/a-brief-case-for-electricity-choice</link><description>Turns out, free market competition benefits customers</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Unsafe Schools and Parental Empowerment with Tiara Jordan-Sutton</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/education/unsafe-schools-and-parental-empowerment-with-tiara-jordan-sutton/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Susan Pendergrass talks with Tiara Jordan-Sutton, Founder and Executive Director of Activate Missouri, about school safety, parental power in education, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/education/unsafe-schools-and-parental-empowerment-with-tiara-jordan-sutton/"&gt;Unsafe Schools and Parental Empowerment with Tiara Jordan-Sutton&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 15:02:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Direct-To-Consumer Sales Can Fulfill Trump’s Drug Pricing Promises</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/direct-to-consumer-sales-can-fulfill-trumps-drug-pricing-promises/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Trump administration wants to enable more Americans to purchase prescription medications directly from manufacturers at transparent, discounted prices—thus collectively saving patients tens of billions of dollars by cutting out middlemen in the drug supply chain. Voters overwhelmingly like the president’s idea. In a recent poll, 90% of Republican voters in congressional battleground districts, along [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/direct-to-consumer-sales-can-fulfill-trumps-drug-pricing-promises/"&gt;Direct-To-Consumer Sales Can Fulfill Trump’s Drug Pricing Promises&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 17:20:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Extend partial relief for late filers of homeowner, rental exemptions</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/10/extend-partial-relief-for-late-filers-of-homeowner-rental-exemptions/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Maui County Council on Oct. 10, 2025._____________ Oct. 10, 2025, 9 a.m.Kalana O Maui Building To: Maui County Council       Alice Lee, Chair       Yuki Lei Sugimura, Vice Chair From: Grassroot Institute of Hawaii            Jonathan Helton, Policy Analyst Re: Bill 113 (2025) [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/10/extend-partial-relief-for-late-filers-of-homeowner-rental-exemptions/"&gt;Extend partial relief for late filers of homeowner, rental exemptions&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 18:28:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] How did your legislators vote during New Mexico’s recent special session?</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/how-did-your-legislators-vote-during-new-mexicos-recent-special-session/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s not &amp;#8220;normal.&amp;#8221; In fact, this was an &amp;#8220;extra special&amp;#8221; session of New Mexico&amp;#8217;s Legislature. The Governor called it because she wanted to keep subsidies flowing to core political constituencies and keep New Mexicans dependent on government. She and the Legislature dominated by her fellow Democrats have had ample opportunities (including the special) to reform [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/how-did-your-legislators-vote-during-new-mexicos-recent-special-session/"&gt;How did your legislators vote during New Mexico&amp;#8217;s recent special session?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 19:06:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] What’s Wrong with the Housing Market?</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/economy/whats-wrong-with-the-housing-market/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;If you’ve been in the market for a home recently, you know prices are through the roof. Prices went up [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/economy/whats-wrong-with-the-housing-market/"&gt;What’s Wrong with the Housing Market?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 19:16:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] VIDEO: California Caregiver Exposes SEIU 2015 for Coercion and Silencing Members</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/litigation/video-california-caregiver-exposes-seiu-2015-for-coercion-and-silencing-members/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In a video released today by the Freedom Foundation, Chaquan May, a California mother and in-home healthcare provider for her medically fragile daughter, exposes how SEIU 2015 has ignored, coerced, and trapped her in union membership against her will.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/litigation/video-california-caregiver-exposes-seiu-2015-for-coercion-and-silencing-members/" rel="nofollow"&gt;VIDEO: California Caregiver Exposes SEIU 2015 for Coercion and Silencing Members &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 20:19:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] School choice is the rare consensus policymakers should act on</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/school-choice-is-the-rare-consensus-policymakers-should-act-on/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;At a time when political polarization dominates nearly every policy debate, educational choice stands out as a surprising area of consensus. Polling consistently shows support for school choice policies — including private school choice policies — from voters across political and demographic lines. For policymakers, this rare alignment isn’t just encouraging; it’s a strategic opportunity. With...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/school-choice-is-the-rare-consensus-policymakers-should-act-on/"&gt;School choice is the rare consensus policymakers should act on&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 21:05:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] A housing victory: zoning to match community plan</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/a-housing-victory-zoning-to-match-community-plan/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Wisconsin Assembly voted largely along party lines this week in support of a crucial housing bill, AB453, that will rein in NIMBYism — the “not in my back yard” outcry that greets developers trying to increase housing supply in communities where elected officials want the same thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/a-housing-victory-zoning-to-match-community-plan/"&gt;A housing victory: zoning to match community plan&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 21:06:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Announcing The Freedom Agenda: Goldwater’s State Policy Handbook</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/announcing-the-freedom-agenda-goldwaters-state-policy-handbook/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;You can view and download the PDF of The Freedom Agenda here. For decades, the Goldwater Institute has led the..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/announcing-the-freedom-agenda-goldwaters-state-policy-handbook/"&gt;Announcing The Freedom Agenda: Goldwater’s State Policy Handbook&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 21:28:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Fight over Obamacare is fight worth having</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/fight-over-obamacare-is-fight-worth-having/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Wisconsin taxpayers ought to be rooting hard for conservatives to hold the line during this current federal government shutdown and let the pandemic-era super-subsidies for the Affordable Care Act run out at the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/fight-over-obamacare-is-fight-worth-having/"&gt;Fight over Obamacare is fight worth having&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 21:35:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Fixing regulatory rampage will require amendment, say observers</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/fixing-regulatory-rampage-will-require-amendment-say-observers/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;But reforms via statute might help Wisconsin avoid a still more onerous environment Fixing the damage wreaked by the Wisconsin Supreme Court when it stripped the Legislature of its power to halt bureaucrats’ regulations will take a constitutional amendment, say legal experts — though reforms in statute can help in the interim. That damage so [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/fixing-regulatory-rampage-will-require-amendment-say-observers/"&gt;Fixing regulatory rampage will require amendment, say observers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 22:09:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Patients Can’t Wait for Federal Action on Knock-Off Medicines</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/patients-cant-wait-for-federal-action-on-knock-off-medicines/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For millions of Americans, the new class of GLP-1 weight-loss drugs are as close to a miracle as modern medicine gets. Sold under brand names like Wegovy and Zepbound, these drugs have proven astoundingly successful at helping patients shed pounds. Unfortunately, a number of unscrupulous companies have sought to capitalize on the growing demand for [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/patients-cant-wait-for-federal-action-on-knock-off-medicines/"&gt;Patients Can&amp;#8217;t Wait for Federal Action on Knock-Off Medicines&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 23:04:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Minnesota Dad cops a plea</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/minnesota-dad-cops-a-plea/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Erick Jorge Diego Alvarez-Henandez, age 46, pled guilty in federal court in downtown St. Paul today to two felony counts: (1) illegal re-entry of a previously deported alien and (2) failure to register as a felony sex offender. Last month, I profiled this unregistered dad here. I&amp;#8217;ll quote myself on the charges he faced in...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/minnesota-dad-cops-a-plea/"&gt;Minnesota Dad cops a plea&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 00:11:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Longer deed restrictions could make affordable housing less attractive</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/10/longer-deed-restrictions-could-make-affordable-housing-less-attractive/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Maui County Council on Oct. 10, 2025_____________ Oct. 10, 2025, 9 a.m.Kalana O Maui Building To: Maui County Council       Alice Lee, Chair       Yuki Lei Sugimura, Vice Chair From: Grassroot Institute of Hawaii            Joe Kent, Executive Vice President RE: Bill 40, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/10/longer-deed-restrictions-could-make-affordable-housing-less-attractive/"&gt;Longer deed restrictions could make affordable housing less attractive&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 02:16:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Allow building ‘encroachments’ that comprised part of Lahaina’s charm</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/10/allow-building-encroachments-that-comprised-part-of-lahainas-charm/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Maui County Council on Oct. 10, 2025_____________ Oct. 10, 2025, 9 a.m.Kalana O Maui Building To: Maui County Council&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; &amp;#160;Alice Lee, Chair&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; &amp;#160;Yuki Lei Sugimura, Vice Chair From: Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Jonathan Helton, Policy Analyst Re: Bill 156 (2025) [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/10/allow-building-encroachments-that-comprised-part-of-lahainas-charm/"&gt;Allow building &amp;#8216;encroachments&amp;#8217; that comprised part of Lahaina&amp;#8217;s charm&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 02:32:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] The Center for Black Student Excellence Should Be a Private Venture</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/education/the-center-for-black-student-excellence-should-be-a-private-venture/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By John A. Charles, Jr. In September, the Portland Public Schools Board voted...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/education/the-center-for-black-student-excellence-should-be-a-private-venture/"&gt;The Center for Black Student Excellence Should Be a Private Venture&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 07:06:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Congestion pricing an open question, but equity concerns are bogus</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/congestion-pricing-an-open-question-but-equity-concerns-are-bogus/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Congestion pricing an open question, but equity concerns are bogus by Rafael Perez &amp;#124; October 10, 2025 New York City in January became the first city in America to implement congestion charges in an effort to curb traffic, reduce pollution and raise funds to improve transit systems. Los Angeles is currently producing a study about [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/congestion-pricing-an-open-question-but-equity-concerns-are-bogus/"&gt;Congestion pricing an open question, but equity concerns are bogus&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 09:58:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] ‘Millionaire’s tax’ ballot proposal would hurt all Michiganders</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/millionaires-tax-ballot-proposal-would-hurt-all-michiganders</link><description>‘Invest in MI Kids’ is a foot in the door to taxing everyone</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 09:59:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Illinois grows enough pumpkins for 8B pumpkin-spice lattes</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/illinois-grows-enough-pumpkins-for-8b-pumpkin-spice-lattes/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Illinois can take credit for plenty of Starbucks’ pumpkin spice lattes. The state produces enough pumpkins to make nearly 8 billion pumpkin spice lattes, the most pumpkins in the U.S. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/illinois-grows-enough-pumpkins-for-8b-pumpkin-spice-lattes/"&gt;Illinois grows enough pumpkins for 8B pumpkin-spice lattes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 10:00:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Florida Politics: The Real Threat to Florida Jobs Isn’t AI – It’s Ignoring It</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/florida-politics-the-real-threat-to-florida-jobs-isnt-ai-its-ignoring-it/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;While artificial intelligence (AI) transforms American business, Florida risks being left behind. Recent polling by&amp;#160;The James Madison Institute&amp;#160;reveals...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/florida-politics-the-real-threat-to-florida-jobs-isnt-ai-its-ignoring-it/"&gt;Florida Politics: The Real Threat to Florida Jobs Isn’t AI – It’s Ignoring It&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 14:27:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] WILL Urges Dismissal of New Attempt to Overturn Congressional Maps</title><link>https://will-law.org/will-urges-dismissal-of-new-attempt-to-overturn-congressional-maps/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The News: WILL is once again defending Wisconsin’s congressional maps, filing briefs in opposition to an overtly political, nonsensical, and last-minute attempt to redraw Wisconsin’s maps on the eve of the midterm election.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/will-urges-dismissal-of-new-attempt-to-overturn-congressional-maps/"&gt;WILL Urges Dismissal of New Attempt to Overturn Congressional Maps&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 14:35:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Parent support remains high for Education Savings Accounts</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/parent-support-remains-high-for-education-savings-accounts/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;What parent wouldn&amp;#8217;t be overjoyed with an extra $7,000 or more in the bank account each year? That&amp;#8217;s the difference between a cash-strapped family and one that enjoys things like academic tutoring, specialized coursework for special education students, private school, and college counseling. Quality life-changing educational pathways would no longer be confined to the wealthier...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/parent-support-remains-high-for-education-savings-accounts/"&gt;Parent support remains high for Education Savings Accounts&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 16:37:08 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>