<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>State-Policy Think-Tank Digest</title><link>https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml</link><description>Latest posts from free-market policy institutes across the U.S.</description><atom:link href="https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 12:05:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>[Empowerms] Rep. Jansen Owen: Special Session Report and 2026 Preview</title><link>https://empowerms.org/rep-jansen-owen-special-session-report-and-2026-preview/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;﻿ Rep. Jansen Owen: Special Session Report and 2026 Preview Representative Jansen Owen is a key leader in the Mississippi House of Representatives. In his six-year legislative career, he has already seen several of his bills signed into law. In this episode of the Empower Podcast, host Grant Callen speaks with Rep. Owen about the&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/rep-jansen-owen-special-session-report-and-2026-preview/"&gt;Rep. Jansen Owen: Special Session Report and 2026 Preview&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 00:00:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Beacon Asks Court to Approve $1.4 Million Settlement for Property Owners in Class Action Lawsuit Against Nashville</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/beacon-asks-court-to-approve-1-4-million-dollar-settlement-for-property-owners-in-class-action-lawsuit-against-nashville/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=beacon-asks-court-to-approve-1-4-million-dollar-settlement-for-property-owners-in-class-action-lawsuit-against-nashville</link><description>The Beacon Center and the city of Nashville jointly asked a federal court to preliminarily approve a settlement in a class action lawsuit Beacon filed challenging the city’s stormwater capacity fees.</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 16:15:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] Microschooling Spreads In Choice-Friendly States</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/06/11/microschooling-spreads-in-choice-friendly-states/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Since 2020, microschools have spread rapidly all across the U.S., but they are particularly popular in states with expansive school-choice programs. These choice-friendly states have passed legislation that enables families to use a portion of state-allocated education funding toward their preferred learning environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/06/11/microschooling-spreads-in-choice-friendly-states/"&gt;Microschooling Spreads In Choice-Friendly States&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 02:16:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alaskapolicyforum] PRESS RELEASE: Alaska Policy Forum Elects Ray Kreig Board President</title><link>https://alaskapolicyforum.org/2025/06/press-release-alaska-policy-forum-elects-ray-kreig-board-president/#utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=press-release-alaska-policy-forum-elects-ray-kreig-board-president</link><description>&lt;div style="margin: 5px 5% 10px 5%;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" height="630" src="https://alaskapolicyforum.org/wp-content/uploads/APF-Press-Release.png" title="Press Release" width="1280" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anchorage, Alaska (June 9, 2025) – Alaska Policy Forum (APF) has elected Ray Kreig as the President of the Board of Directors. Kreig was a co-founder of Alaska Policy Forum in 2009. ARead More&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alaskapolicyforum.org/2025/06/press-release-alaska-policy-forum-elects-ray-kreig-board-president/"&gt;PRESS RELEASE: Alaska Policy Forum Elects Ray Kreig Board President&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://alaskapolicyforum.org"&gt;Alaska Policy Forum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 21:36:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alaskapolicyforum] Want better schools? Healthy competition is the difference</title><link>https://alaskapolicyforum.org/2025/06/want-better-schools-healthy-competition-is-the-difference/#utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=want-better-schools-healthy-competition-is-the-difference</link><description>&lt;div style="margin: 5px 5% 10px 5%;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" height="1440" src="https://alaskapolicyforum.org/wp-content/uploads/school-6900381_1920.jpg" title="" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite significant disparities in funding and adequacy, Florida dramatically outperforms Alaska in the quality of high school graduates. This is despite having a higher poverty rate than Alaska and twice the rate ofRead More&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alaskapolicyforum.org/2025/06/want-better-schools-healthy-competition-is-the-difference/"&gt;Want better schools? Healthy competition is the difference&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://alaskapolicyforum.org"&gt;Alaska Policy Forum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 00:54:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Immigration is the Defining Issue of our Time</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/immigration-is-the-defining-issue-of-our-time/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Immigration is the most critical issue facing America.&amp;#160;&amp;#160;In recent weeks, ICE has been busy.&amp;#160; There have been lots of raids and approximately 800 daily arrests of illegal immigrants nationwide. &amp;#160;The administration wants one million deportations this year.&amp;#160;In Los Angeles, this crackdown triggered protests that turned violent.&amp;#160; President Trump has now sent National Guard troops and [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/immigration-is-the-defining-issue-of-our-time/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Immigration is the Defining Issue of our Time&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 19:37:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Frontierinstitute] The 20th President</title><link>https://frontierinstitute.org/the-20th-president/</link><description>"Garfield argued that the nation’s financial ailments, the soaring prices of the Civil War especially, stemmed from the federal government’s monetary mischief."</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 14:32:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Rep. Lee Yancey: Kratom, Underground Markets, and the Demon Chipmunk</title><link>https://empowerms.org/rep-lee-yancey-kratom-underground-markets-and-the-demon-chipmunk/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;﻿ Rep. Lee Yancey: Kratom, Underground Markets, and the Demon Chipmunk In this episode, host, Grant Callen sits down with State Representative Lee Yancey, a seasoned lawmaker with 11 years of service in the Mississippi Legislature. A one-time Senator, Rep. Yancey now chairs the House Business and Commerce Committee and serves on eight other committees&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/rep-lee-yancey-kratom-underground-markets-and-the-demon-chipmunk/"&gt;Rep. Lee Yancey: Kratom, Underground Markets, and the Demon Chipmunk&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 01:00:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Frontierinstitute] Let’s Start at the Beginning: Vouchers, Tax Credit Scholarships and ESAs</title><link>https://frontierinstitute.org/lets-start-at-the-beginning-vouchers-tax-credit-scholarships-and-esas/</link><description>"Education choice represents a fundamental shift toward recognizing student diversity and parental agency while maintaining our collective commitment to ensuring every child receives a quality education."</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 08:00:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Much to like in Republicans’ tax plan</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/much-to-like-in-republicans-tax-plan/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Legislative Republicans’ proposed tax measure “is a relatively well-structured way to provide relief for lower- and middle-income Wisconsinites,” said Katherine Loughead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/much-to-like-in-republicans-tax-plan/"&gt;Much to like in Republicans’ tax plan&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 20:18:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Arkansaspolicyfoundation] RIGHT TO TRY 2.0</title><link>https://arkansaspolicyfoundation.org/right-to-try-2-0/</link><description>RIGHT TO TRY 2.0   (2025-2Q) The idea behind Right-To-Try is that &amp;#8220;terminally ill patients who have exhausted their government-approved options&amp;#8221; should have the freedom to access treatments that may help them.(1)  The idea originated with the Goldwater Institute of Arizona, a member of the State Policy Network (SPN), a market-based group that includes the [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 06:11:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Open Letter to Gov. Mills: Veto LD 1666, Unconstitutional RCV Expansion</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/open-letter-to-gov-mills-please-veto-ld-1666-rcv-expansion/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On June 18, 2025, the Maine Legislature passed LD 1666, a bill that aims to extend ranked-choice voting (RCV) to elections for Governor, State Senators, and State Representatives. This post is a call to Governor Janet Mills to veto LD 1666. As she herself once advised the Maine Supreme Judicial Court as Attorney General in [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/open-letter-to-gov-mills-please-veto-ld-1666-rcv-expansion/"&gt;Open Letter to Gov. Mills: Veto LD 1666, Unconstitutional RCV Expansion&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 13:30:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Virginiainstitute] How to navigate and improve Virginia’s education options</title><link>https://virginiainstitute.org/how-to-navigate-and-improve-virginias-education-options/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=how-to-navigate-and-improve-virginias-education-options</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 14:25:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Virginiainstitute] Elections in Virginia: Your Guide to Navigating the Law</title><link>https://virginiainstitute.org/elections-in-virginia-your-guide-to-navigating-the-law/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=elections-in-virginia-your-guide-to-navigating-the-law</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Lindsey Zea Senior Fellow Dr. Clara Belle Wheeler Senior Fellow&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org/elections-in-virginia-your-guide-to-navigating-the-law/"&gt;Elections in Virginia: Your Guide to Navigating the Law&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org"&gt;Virginia Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 14:49:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] Matthew Mitchell’s presentation/conversation on economic freedom in New Mexicco</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/matthew-mitchells-presentation-conversation-on-economic-freedom-in-new-mexicco/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Matthew Mitchell of the Canadian free market think tank Fraser Institute (Matt lives in Angel Fire, NM) recently made a compelling presentation on economic freedom (or the lack thereof) in New Mexico at a Rio Grande Foundation sponsored event in Albuquerque. You can find Matt&amp;#8217;s highly informative slides here.  While we don&amp;#8217;t have a recording [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/matthew-mitchells-presentation-conversation-on-economic-freedom-in-new-mexicco/"&gt;Matthew Mitchell’s presentation/conversation on economic freedom in New Mexicco&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 21:33:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Cuomo’s suspect COVID statistics</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/cuomos-suspect-covid-statistics/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Five years after the pandemic, Andrew Cuomo is still gaslighting New Yorkers about how many people died in nursing homes.....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/cuomos-suspect-covid-statistics/"&gt;Cuomo’s suspect COVID statistics&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2025 15:13:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Albany’s Looming Energy Shock</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/albanys-looming-energy-shock/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For all Governor Hochul’s talk about “affordability”, it seems electricity prices have not received that memo. Recent data from the....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/albanys-looming-energy-shock/"&gt;Albany’s Looming Energy Shock&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 17:00:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] The Importance of Charitable Giving, State Think Tanks and the “Big, Beautiful Bill”</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/the-importance-of-charitable-giving-state-think-tanks-and-the-big-beautiful-bill/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;At the Platte Institute, our mission is simple: we work to remove barriers that limit growth and opportunity in Nebraska. We believe every Nebraskan deserves the freedom to pursue their version of the Good Life—our state’s own take on the American Dream.  Nonprofits like ours are vital to making that vision a reality. Across the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/the-importance-of-charitable-giving-state-think-tanks-and-the-big-beautiful-bill/" rel="nofollow"&gt;The Importance of Charitable Giving, State Think Tanks and the “Big, Beautiful Bill”&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 17:18:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Rifreedom] Center CEO Mike Stenhouse To Be Inducted Into College Baseball Hall Of Fame</title><link>https://rifreedom.org/2025/06/center-ceo-mike-stenhouse-to-be-inducted-into-college-baseball-hall-of-fame/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;?The Rhode Island Center for Freedom &amp;#38; Prosperity Congratulates CEO Mike Stenhouse on Induction into College Baseball Hall of Fame Providence, RI &amp;#8211; The Rhode Island Center for Freedom &amp;#38; [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org/2025/06/center-ceo-mike-stenhouse-to-be-inducted-into-college-baseball-hall-of-fame/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Center CEO Mike Stenhouse To Be Inducted Into College Baseball Hall Of Fame&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;RI Center for Freedom and Prosperity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 18:23:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Virtual Event: 2025 Supreme Court Round-Up</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/virtual-event-2025-supreme-court-round-up/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;What did the U.S. Supreme Court decide this term—and what does it mean for liberty? You can find out at..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/virtual-event-2025-supreme-court-round-up/"&gt;Virtual Event: 2025 Supreme Court Round-Up&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:51:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Research Note: LB106 and the Nebraska livestock siting assessment matrix</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/research-note-lb106-and-the-nebraska-livestock-siting-assessment-matrix/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Note: This is the first in a series of Research Notes authored by this year&amp;#8217;s Platte Institute Summer Intern, Jakob Myers. Jakob is researching information related to zoning issues involving livestock facilities. The continued growth of Nebraska’s agricultural sector depends significantly on the development and expansion of livestock operations across the state. These projects typically...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/research-note-lb106-and-the-nebraska-livestock-siting-assessment-matrix/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Research Note: LB106 and the Nebraska livestock siting assessment matrix&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 20:32:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF opinion piece:  Arizona policy runs circles around NM</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-opinion-piece-arizona-policy-runs-circles-around-nm/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following appeared in Albuquerque Journal on June 22nd, 2025. Similar versions appeared in numerous other media outlets. Recently, a group of Albuquerque business and economic leaders traveled to Phoenix to get some ideas on why the Phoenix economy is so much stronger than New Mexico’s. Ideas were exchanged and I’m sure a good time [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-opinion-piece-arizona-policy-runs-circles-around-nm/"&gt;RGF opinion piece:  Arizona policy runs circles around NM&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 23:26:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alaskapolicyforum] Alaska’s schools are rolling in cash, so why aren’t the results better?</title><link>https://alaskapolicyforum.org/2025/06/alaskas-schools-are-rolling-in-cash-so-why-arent-the-results-better/#utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=alaskas-schools-are-rolling-in-cash-so-why-arent-the-results-better</link><description>&lt;div style="margin: 5px 5% 10px 5%;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" height="1707" src="https://alaskapolicyforum.org/wp-content/uploads/Money-scaled.jpg" title="" width="2560" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alaska was ranked the second most adequately funded school system in the US by a 2024 study from Rutgers University. The rest of the story — the study actually understates how well neighborhood schoolsRead More&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alaskapolicyforum.org/2025/06/alaskas-schools-are-rolling-in-cash-so-why-arent-the-results-better/"&gt;Alaska’s schools are rolling in cash, so why aren’t the results better?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://alaskapolicyforum.org"&gt;Alaska Policy Forum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 02:25:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Does Connecticut Have a City Problem?</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/06/24/does-connecticut-have-a-city-problem/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="1920" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/shutterstock_1121373920-scaled.jpg" width="2560" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connecticut has a problem with its major cities.   In two separate 2025 WalletHub studies, Bridgeport, Hartford, New Haven, Stamford, and Waterbury were among the least affordable housing markets in America. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/06/24/does-connecticut-have-a-city-problem/"&gt;Does Connecticut Have a City Problem?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 14:26:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] Court Watch: Wisconsin Supreme Courts Hands a Win to Bureaucracy</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/court-watch-wisconsin-supreme-courts-hands-a-win-to-bureaucracy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Court Watch: Wisconsin Supreme Courts Hands a Win to Bureaucracy Liberal Majority Holds That Bureaucrats Can Make Important Policy Determinations Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government (IRG) released the following statement following the Wisconsin Supreme Court’s ruling in Wisconsin Manufacturers and Commerce, Inc. v. Wisconsin Department of Natural Resources. The ruling cements widespread [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/court-watch-wisconsin-supreme-courts-hands-a-win-to-bureaucracy/"&gt;Court Watch: Wisconsin Supreme Courts Hands a Win to Bureaucracy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 14:27:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Listen: Will Gov. Mills Veto LD 1666?</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/listen-will-gov-mills-veto-ld-1666/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Policy analyst, Harris Van Pate, joined the WGAN Morning News to discuss Maine Policy&amp;#8217;s recent open letter to Gov. Janet Mills calling on her to abide by her 2017 opinions as attorney general and veto LD 1666, a bill that would expand the use of ranked-choice voting to include Maine&amp;#8217;s general elections for state-level offices [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/listen-will-gov-mills-veto-ld-1666/"&gt;Listen: Will Gov. Mills Veto LD 1666?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 16:24:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Thank Goodness for Mississippi!</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/thank-goodness-for-mississippi/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When I first moved to Mississippi, one or two of my friends back in England raised their eyebrows.&amp;#160;“Mississippi!” the expression of their faces seemed to say. Like many people who’ve never had the good fortune to live in this state, when they hear the word “Mississippi”, they think of the river, or a riverboat or [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/thank-goodness-for-mississippi/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Thank Goodness for Mississippi!&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 18:19:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] New Hampshire Is First in New England to Enact Universal School Choice</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/education/new-hampshire-is-first-in-new-england-to-enact-universal-school-choice/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Kathryn Hickok New Hampshire has removed the income cap for families applying...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/education/new-hampshire-is-first-in-new-england-to-enact-universal-school-choice/"&gt;New Hampshire Is First in New England to Enact Universal School Choice&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 14:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Virginiainstitute] Press Release – VIPP Champions AI Moratorium, Invokes Commerce Clause</title><link>https://virginiainstitute.org/5850-2/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=5850-2</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Virginia Institute for Public Policy’s statement for memorandum highlights the urgent need for a coordinated federal approach to AI regulation, leveraging constitutional authority to avoid a fragmented and counterproductive patchwork of state laws. The proposed moratorium offers a pragmatic pathway to safeguard innovation, support small businesses, and ensure U.S. leadership in the rapidly evolving global AI landscape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org/5850-2/"&gt;Press Release – VIPP Champions AI Moratorium, Invokes Commerce Clause&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org"&gt;Virginia Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 14:10:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] Court Watch: Unanimous SCOWIS Declares Gov. Evers’s Partial Veto Unconstitutional in Literacy Case</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/court-watch-unanimous-scowis-declares-gov-everss-partial-veto-unconstitutional-in-literacy-case/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Court Watch: Unanimous SCOWIS Declares Gov. Evers’s Partial Veto Unconstitutional in Literacy Case Court’s Ruling Allows IRG-Backed Reading Reforms to Move Forward Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government (IRG) released the following statement following the Wisconsin Supreme Court’s unanimous ruling in Wisconsin State Legislature v. Wisconsin Department of Public Instruction. WHAT HAPPENED: The [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/court-watch-unanimous-scowis-declares-gov-everss-partial-veto-unconstitutional-in-literacy-case/"&gt;Court Watch: Unanimous SCOWIS Declares Gov. Evers’s Partial Veto Unconstitutional in Literacy Case&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 15:43:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Understanding the 2025 state budget pension fight</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/06/understanding-the-2025-state-budget-pension-fight/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Republican leaders in Concord have entered the final week of the fiscal year in a dramatic showdown with each other—not over cutting spending, but increasing it. Gov. Kelly Ayotte wants legislators to honor her campaign promise to police officers and firefighters to undo retirement benefit reforms passed in the 2011-2012 budget.  Those changes improved the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/06/understanding-the-2025-state-budget-pension-fight/"&gt;Understanding the 2025 state budget pension fight&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 18:12:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Why Missouri Needs Universal Open Enrollment</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/education/why-missouri-needs-universal-open-enrollment/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Missouri parents deserve real choices when it comes to their children’s education. Open enrollment—the ability for students to attend a [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/education/why-missouri-needs-universal-open-enrollment/"&gt;Why Missouri Needs Universal Open Enrollment&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 18:27:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Kathy Hochul’s ambition cancels out claims of coming ‘climate disaster’</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/kathy-hochuls-ambition-cancels-out-claims-of-coming-climate-disaster/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New York politicians are extremely worried about the threat of global climate change. Their only bigger worry is that the....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/kathy-hochuls-ambition-cancels-out-claims-of-coming-climate-disaster/"&gt;Kathy Hochul’s ambition cancels out claims of coming ‘climate disaster’&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 18:51:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/06/the-outstater-275/</link><description>Auditing Good Intentions FOR ONCE, my mid-sized Indiana city is ahead of New York City&amp;#160;fashion — policy fashion, at least.&amp;#160;The Democratic nominee for mayor there is promising to build municipal-run grocery stores. Heck, we’ve had one of those for more than two years. It was a political promise of our mayor as well. In both&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/06/the-outstater-275/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 19:48:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Unions and General Assembly Allies Throw a Fit Over Lamont’s Veto</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/06/25/unions-and-general-assembly-allies-throw-a-fit-over-lamonts-veto/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gov. Ned Lamont followed through this week on a promise that sent shockwaves through his party: he vetoed S.B. 8, a bill that would have offered unemployment benefits to workers [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/06/25/unions-and-general-assembly-allies-throw-a-fit-over-lamonts-veto/"&gt;Unions and General Assembly Allies Throw a Fit Over Lamont’s Veto&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 20:49:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] New Poll: Voters Concerned About Increased Spending, Lack of Leadership</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/06/25/new-poll-voters-concerned-about-increased-spending-lack-of-leadership/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;69% of voters believe Gov. Josh Shapiro needs to take a more active role in budget negotiations. Harrisburg, Pa., June 25, 2025 —&amp;#160;As the June 30th deadline looms, voters made their stance on negotiations clear — Gov. Josh Shapiro must play a more active role at the negotiating table, with a focus on achieving bipartisan [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/06/25/new-poll-voters-concerned-about-increased-spending-lack-of-leadership/"&gt;New Poll: Voters Concerned About Increased Spending, Lack of Leadership&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 21:09:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] WILL Statement on Wisconsin Supreme Court Rejecting Partisan Efforts to Redraw Congressional Maps</title><link>https://will-law.org/will-statement-on-wisconsin-supreme-court-rejecting-partisan-efforts-to-redraw-congressional-maps/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The News: The Wisconsin Supreme Court today declined to hear challenges seeking to redraw the state’s current congressional district maps, effectively ensuring the maps will remain in place for the 2026 midterm elections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/will-statement-on-wisconsin-supreme-court-rejecting-partisan-efforts-to-redraw-congressional-maps/"&gt;WILL Statement on Wisconsin Supreme Court Rejecting Partisan Efforts to Redraw Congressional Maps&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 23:25:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Virginia’s Elections Should Be About Virginia’s Future — Not a Referendum on President Trump</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/virginias-elections-should-be-about-virginias-future-not-a-referendum-on-president-trump/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="630" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Virginia-and-Trump.jpg" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senator Tim Kaine recently sent out a fundraising email where he quoted the Washington Post that the Virginia “elections are seen as a referendum on the Trump administration.&amp;#8221; This suggests that voters should cast their ballots based on how they feel about our current President, rather than the pressing issues facing our Commonwealth today. This kind of [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/virginias-elections-should-be-about-virginias-future-not-a-referendum-on-president-trump/"&gt;Virginia’s Elections Should Be About Virginia’s Future — Not a Referendum on President Trump&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 15:27:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cardinalinstitute] Colleges Must Educate for Freedom</title><link>https://cardinalinstitute.com/colleges-must-educate-for-freedom/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Colleges Must Educate for Freedom A great American college or university will prepare students for self-governance as both a wise human being and a prudent, productive citizen. Rightly understood, the liberal arts are the intellectual potentials shared by the leaders of a free people. That is, education policy should consider, first of all, how to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com/colleges-must-educate-for-freedom/"&gt;Colleges Must Educate for Freedom&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com"&gt;Cardinal Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 16:31:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] The Verdict on AI</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/the-verdict-on-ai/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Few practices have higher stakes for human error than that of criminal justice. An oversight or delay can be the difference between life or death, justice or injustice. Artificial intelligence (AI) holds both opportunities and trials in the pursuit of safer communities and effective systems. In December 2024, the United States Department of Justice (DOJ)...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/the-verdict-on-ai/"&gt;The Verdict on AI&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 16:52:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Education Freedom: A Lifeline for Tennessee Families</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/education-freedom-a-lifeline-for-tennessee-families/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=education-freedom-a-lifeline-for-tennessee-families</link><description>Education Freedom Scholarships won’t just change where kids go to school. They’ll change who they become.</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 18:15:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Group II pension compromise allows, but limits, pension spiking</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/06/group-ii-pension-compromise-allows-but-limits-pension-spiking/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Legislative leaders and Gov. Kelly Ayotte worked out a compromise on Group II pension benefits on Wednesday, the day before the House and Senate were scheduled to vote on the budget the governor had threatened to veto over those benefits. The late deal settles six main points of disagreement, including one of the big disputes [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/06/group-ii-pension-compromise-allows-but-limits-pension-spiking/"&gt;Group II pension compromise allows, but limits, pension spiking&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 19:15:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Cursing the rain — and tax cuts — cuz everyone benefits</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/cursing-the-rain-and-tax-cuts-cuz-everyone-benefits/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Progressives object because proposed Wisconsin tax relief goes to people they envy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/cursing-the-rain-and-tax-cuts-cuz-everyone-benefits/"&gt;Cursing the rain — and tax cuts — cuz everyone benefits&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 19:23:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Taxpayers getting jobbed</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/taxpayers-getting-jobbed-northern-wisconsin-job-corps/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A federal judge’s injunction is blocking the closing down Job Corps centers — including two in Wisconsin — that have an expensive and dismal record ostensibly training the young and disadvantaged for work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/taxpayers-getting-jobbed-northern-wisconsin-job-corps/"&gt;Taxpayers getting jobbed&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 20:21:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] The Slippery Slope of Market Intervention: Why Louisiana Must Choose Economic Freedom</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/legal-regulatory/the-slippery-slope-of-market-intervention-why-louisiana-must-choose-economic-freedom/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Louisiana Legislature just wrapped up its regular session, and while lawmakers accomplished much good work, a troubling pattern emerged that should concern anyone who believes in economic opportunity and free markets. Louisiana faces a choice: Will we transform into a state where families and entrepreneurs can flourish, or will we remain the big-government populist...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/legal-regulatory/the-slippery-slope-of-market-intervention-why-louisiana-must-choose-economic-freedom/"&gt;The Slippery Slope of Market Intervention: Why Louisiana Must Choose Economic Freedom&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 20:23:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Chicago Teachers Union Thinks Your Kids Are Theirs</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/illinois/chicago-teachers-union-thinks-your-kids-are-theirs/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Chicago Teachers Union president Stacy Davis Gates just said the quiet part out loud: “CTU thinks your children are its children.” That’s not their families. Not their teachers. Not even their parents. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/illinois/chicago-teachers-union-thinks-your-kids-are-theirs/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Chicago Teachers Union Thinks Your Kids Are Theirs &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 23:43:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] The Maine House Restored Rep. Libby’s Rights. What now?</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/the-maine-house-restored-rep-libbys-rights-what-now/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On the final day of the 2025 legislative session, the Maine House of Representatives voted to reinstate Rep. Laurel Libby’s right to speak and vote on the House floor, formally lifting the limits imposed on her earlier this year by her censure.&amp;#160; While the Legislature offered no explicit justification for this reversal, it was clearly [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/the-maine-house-restored-rep-libbys-rights-what-now/"&gt;The Maine House Restored Rep. Libby&amp;#8217;s Rights. What now?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 23:51:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Arkansaspolicyfoundation] MEDICAL CARE IDEAS ADVANCE</title><link>https://arkansaspolicyfoundation.org/medical-care-ideas-advance/</link><description>(2025-2Q) The Arkansas Policy Foundation was founded by business leaders to serve the community and advance ideas to create more prosperity for Arkansans. The Policy Foundation was founded 30 years ago as a 501(c)(3) nonprofit, nonpartisan think tank that publishes credible research, hosts forums to encourage citizenship and is cited in national and state news [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 06:09:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Week in Review: Freedom Builds Homes Faster</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-freedom-builds-homes-faster/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Housing costs are sky high, and the American Dream is out of reach for too many families—even in liberty-loving Texas...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-freedom-builds-homes-faster/"&gt;Week in Review: Freedom Builds Homes Faster&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 09:50:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] Franke: America and Dante’s Inferno</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/06/franke-america-and-dantes-inferno/</link><description>by Mark Franke I am grateful these days for the time I can devote to reading. I have always loved to read, with eclectic tastes as to subject matter. Sometimes my reading choices land on disciplines I never took the opportunity to study while in school.&amp;#160; Theology is one such subject area. Having been granted&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/06/franke-america-and-dantes-inferno/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 12:55:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Mapping the Public Workforce: State Government Employment Trends in 2024</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/blog/usdatalabs/mapping-the-public-workforce-state-government-employment-trends-in-2024/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;During the COVID-19 pandemic, state and federal policy sought to stabilize the economy and job market. Today we still see the effects on public employment, where some states have experienced recovery at differing rates.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/blog/usdatalabs/mapping-the-public-workforce-state-government-employment-trends-in-2024/"&gt;Mapping the Public Workforce: State Government Employment Trends in 2024&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 14:09:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] This Week Proves Again Wind and Solar Cannot Take the Heat</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/this-week-proves-again-wind-and-solar-cannot-take-the-heat/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="630" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Green-Energy-Fail.jpg" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once again, a spell of hot weather has proven that our economy and comfort depend on hydrocarbon fuels. As you can see from these simple pie graphs from the PJM regional energy market, two-thirds of the electricity sustaining Virginia on a recent hot afternoon was produced by natural gas, oil and coal.&amp;#160; One graph shows [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/this-week-proves-again-wind-and-solar-cannot-take-the-heat/"&gt;This Week Proves Again Wind and Solar Cannot Take the Heat&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 15:13:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] Speaker Emerita Melissa Hortman, Husband, and Golden Retriever Will Lie in State Today</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/speaker-emerita-melissa-hortman-husband-and-golden-retriever-will-lie-in-state-today/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Speaker Emerita Melissa Hortman, her husband Mark, and their golden retriever Gilbert will lie in state in the Minnesota State Capitol Rotunda on Friday from noon to 5 p.m. Melissa Hortman’s rise to power was slow, steady and remarkable KSTP-TV Melissa Hortman’s rise to power as a state representative from Brooklyn Park in the Minnesota House [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/speaker-emerita-melissa-hortman-husband-and-golden-retriever-will-lie-in-state-today/"&gt;Speaker Emerita Melissa Hortman, Husband, and Golden Retriever Will Lie in State Today&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 15:29:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Is It Time for a Local Government Balanced Budget Requirement?</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/is-it-time-for-a-local-government-balanced-budget-requirement/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Most people understand that you shouldn’t spend more than you make. But many independent school districts (ISDs) don’t seem to have gotten the message. Over the last few weeks, numerous ISDs have been observed adopting deficit budgets. For those not well-versed, deficit budgeting “occurs when government expenses exceed revenue.” As you might imagine, there are...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/is-it-time-for-a-local-government-balanced-budget-requirement/"&gt;Is It Time for a Local Government Balanced Budget Requirement?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 16:36:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] Paul sits down with Vance Ginn for “Let People Prosper” podcast</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/paul-sits-down-with-vance-ginn-for-let-people-prosper-podcast/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Why does New Mexico, rich in resources and culture, remain poor in economic freedom? That’s the question I explore in this week’s Let People Prosper Show with Paul Gessing, president of the Rio Grande Foundation. Paul brings nearly two decades of insight into New Mexico’s political and economic trends, offering a sobering look at why the state is falling behind and [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/paul-sits-down-with-vance-ginn-for-let-people-prosper-podcast/"&gt;Paul sits down with Vance Ginn for &amp;#8220;Let People Prosper&amp;#8221; podcast&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 17:59:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Frontierinstitute] Recent Permitting Reforms Are Protecting Property Rights</title><link>https://frontierinstitute.org/recent-permitting-reforms-are-protecting-property-rights/</link><description>"What property rights are unequivocally not, however, is a license to control what others do with their own property."</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 18:27:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Allowing kitchenettes would help achieve several county goals</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/06/allowing-kitchenettes-would-help-achieve-several-county-goals/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Maui County Council on June 27, 2025._____________ June 27, 2025, 9 a.m.Kalana O Maui Building To: Maui County Council       Alice Lee, Chair       Yuki Lei Sugimura, Vice Chair From: Grassroot Institute of Hawaii            Jonathan Helton, Policy Researcher RE: Bill 104 (2024), [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/06/allowing-kitchenettes-would-help-achieve-several-county-goals/"&gt;Allowing kitchenettes would help achieve several county goals&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 21:26:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] WILL Reacts to SCOTUS Parental Rights Ruling</title><link>https://will-law.org/will-reacts-to-scotus-parental-rights-ruling/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL released a statement praising the U.S. Supreme Court’s (SCOTUS) 6–3 ruling in Mahmoud v. Taylor—a landmark parental rights case that confirms parents’ ability to challenge school curricula and potentially other school policies and practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/will-reacts-to-scotus-parental-rights-ruling/"&gt;WILL Reacts to SCOTUS Parental Rights Ruling&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 21:56:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Japan buys Gulf Coast oil, Hawaii doesn’t, thanks to 1920 Jones Act</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/06/japan-buys-gulf-coast-oil-hawaii-doesnt-thanks-to-1920-jones-act/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Above, the Diyyinah I is shown on its way to Japan with U.S. oil that Hawaii&amp;#8217;s refinery prefers but doesn&amp;#8217;t buy because of the Jones Act, which increases shipping cost between U.S. ports._______________ Earlier this month, the crude oil tanker&amp;#160;Diyyinah I&amp;#160;departed the port of Houston, transited the Panama Canal and&amp;#160;began sailing&amp;#160;along the coast of Central [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/06/japan-buys-gulf-coast-oil-hawaii-doesnt-thanks-to-1920-jones-act/"&gt;Japan buys Gulf Coast oil, Hawaii doesn&amp;#8217;t, thanks to 1920 Jones Act&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 21:57:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Winners &amp; Losers: Peace Prize for Trump, Wesley Hunt Wins, NYC Loses</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/winners-losers-peace-prize-for-trump-wesley-hunt-wins-nyc-loses/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Every Friday morning, I join the Cardle &amp;#38; Woolley Show on 1370 Talk Radio in Austin to announce the week’s Winners &amp;#38; Losers. There is absolutely no debate that President Donald J. Trump is a world-class winner this week. Here’s the list: WINNER: Trump Should Get the Nobel Peace Prize American presidents have been trying to...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/winners-losers-peace-prize-for-trump-wesley-hunt-wins-nyc-loses/"&gt;Winners &amp; Losers: Peace Prize for Trump, Wesley Hunt Wins, NYC Loses&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 21:58:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Hill hails interstate telehealth as easy way to boost local medical care</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/06/hill-hails-interstate-telehealth-as-easy-way-to-boost-local-medical-care/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;One easy, virtually cost-free way to improve healthcare access and quality in Hawaii would be to remove the state’s regulations on interstate telehealth, according to Malia Hill, Grassroot Institute of Hawaii’s policy director and author of a new white paper on the subject. Speaking on Sunday, June 22, with host Johnny Miro on the H. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/06/hill-hails-interstate-telehealth-as-easy-way-to-boost-local-medical-care/"&gt;Hill hails interstate telehealth as easy way to boost local medical care&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 22:10:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Systems of Power and Oppression: Ethnic Studies and The Dark Side of Teachers’ Unions</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/systems-of-power-and-oppression-ethnic-studies-and-the-dark-side-of-teachers-unions/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=systems-of-power-and-oppression-ethnic-studies-and-the-dark-side-of-teachers-unions</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Most parents assume the greatest threats to student learning are budget shortfalls or outdated curricula. Yet, the real danger may be hiding in plain sight: politically entrenched teachers&amp;#8217; unions.  Cloaked in promises of social justice and equity, these influential groups have quietly seized control of K–12 classrooms, steering education toward radical ideologies with deliberately deceiving...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/systems-of-power-and-oppression-ethnic-studies-and-the-dark-side-of-teachers-unions/"&gt;Systems of Power and Oppression: Ethnic Studies and The Dark Side of Teachers’ Unions&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 22:45:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] SCOTUS Delivers Major Wins for Parents and Kids</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/scotus-delivers-major-wins-for-parents-and-kids/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=scotus-delivers-major-wins-for-parents-and-kids</link><description>&lt;p&gt;CPC Calls for Immediate Policy Reforms in California SACRAMENTO — California Policy Center applauds today’s U.S. Supreme Court ruling in Mahmoud v. Taylor as a decisive victory for parental rights. The High Court has made it clear: parents cannot be sidelined in their child’s education. In a 6–3 ruling, the Court upheld the right of...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/scotus-delivers-major-wins-for-parents-and-kids/"&gt;SCOTUS Delivers Major Wins for Parents and Kids&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 23:56:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Jennifer Sey’s HR rebellion is just what America needs</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/jennifer-seys-hr-rebellion-is-just-what-america-needs/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;She said what we’ve all known deep down: The best workplaces run on trust and clarity, not surveillance and seminars. Jennifer Sey struck a nerve when she declared that her company, XX-XY Athletics, operates without an HR department. “They produce nothing,” Sey said at Freedom Fest earlier this month. “They monitor our words. They tell...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/jennifer-seys-hr-rebellion-is-just-what-america-needs/"&gt;Jennifer Sey’s HR rebellion is just what America needs&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 11:47:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] What Georgia Can Learn from Other States About Fixing Welfare</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/what-georgia-can-learn-from-other-states-about-fixing-welfare/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Like most states, Georgia's welfare system is a maze of complex rules and disconnected programs that trap people in a cycle of frustration and dependence. A few states are beginning to rethink how welfare operates and are making changes that could also work in Georgia. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/what-georgia-can-learn-from-other-states-about-fixing-welfare/"&gt;What Georgia Can Learn from Other States About Fixing Welfare&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 13:05:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Job Licensing Reviews: Business and Labor Committee and General Affairs Committee</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/job-licensing-reviews-business-general-affairs-and-labor-committee-and-general-affairs-committee/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;[Note: This is the second in a group of articles reviewing occupational licensing reviews for the first five-plus years of the Occupational Board Reform Act. For more context, see this post.] The Business and Labor Committee has reviewed a number of licenses from 2019 to 2024. Their areas of review included: Boiler Safety/Pressure Vessel Inspectors...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/job-licensing-reviews-business-general-affairs-and-labor-committee-and-general-affairs-committee/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Job Licensing Reviews: Business and Labor Committee and General Affairs Committee&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 13:19:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Candidate Policy Briefing – Wichita | Property Tax</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/cpb-2025-wichita-property-tax/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 14:36:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Candidate Policy Briefing – Wichita | K-12 Finance</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/cpb-2025-wichita-k12-finance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 14:38:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Sutherlandinstitute] SCOTUS says public schools must accommodate religious families. Here’s what education leaders should do next</title><link>https://sutherlandinstitute.org/scotus-says-public-schools-must-accommodate-religious-families/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In a landmark case, the Supreme Court upheld parents’ rights to direct their child’s education – prompting calls for stronger laws and curriculum transparency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://sutherlandinstitute.org/scotus-says-public-schools-must-accommodate-religious-families/"&gt;SCOTUS says public schools must accommodate religious families. Here’s what education leaders should do next&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://sutherlandinstitute.org"&gt;Sutherland Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 16:41:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Closing the Gap: A Blueprint for Funding Success and Empowering Parents</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/closing-the-gap-a-blueprint-for-funding-success-and-empowering-parents/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="630" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/IMG_1904.jpeg" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It shouldn’t be hard for both political parties to agree that among those who suffered most from covid school shut-downs were low-income children. In the National Assessment of Educational Progress (NAEP), the assessment against which all states judge their progress, the percentage of Virginia students scoring at proficient or above in the 2024 NAEP exams demonstrate a huge [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/closing-the-gap-a-blueprint-for-funding-success-and-empowering-parents/"&gt;Closing the Gap: A Blueprint for Funding Success and Empowering Parents &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 17:29:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Lewis and Clark</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/lewis-and-clark/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/lewis-and-clark/" rel="nofollow" title="Lewis and Clark"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="580" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Prop-1-Exposed-2-22.png" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;In celebration of our national heritage, we continue our Pride in America series by honoring famous explorers Meriwether Lewis and William Clark. From at least 1783, Thomas Jefferson had eyed an opportunity to send men east of the Mississippi to not only explore more of the continent but also to determine if a direct passage [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 17:39:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG’s Work Bridging the Political Divide and Digging into the Impact of the Immigration Crisis in Wisconsin Named as Finalists for National Awards</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irgs-work-bridging-the-political-divide-and-digging-into-the-impact-of-the-immigration-crisis-in-wisconsin-named-as-finalists-for-national-awards/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;IRG’s Work Bridging the Political Divide and Digging into the Impact of the Immigration Crisis in Wisconsin Named as Finalists for National Awards  State Policy Network Recognizes IRG as a finalist for the Bob Williams Award for Most Influential Research and Innovation in Marketing Delafield, Wis. – The State Policy Network (SPN) nominated the Institute [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irgs-work-bridging-the-political-divide-and-digging-into-the-impact-of-the-immigration-crisis-in-wisconsin-named-as-finalists-for-national-awards/"&gt;IRG’s Work Bridging the Political Divide and Digging into the Impact of the Immigration Crisis in Wisconsin Named as Finalists for National Awards&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 17:41:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/06/the-outstater-276/</link><description>Meet the New IEDC Board (Yawn) A FRIEND, a former submarine commander now a troubleshooter for a regional manufacturer, shared a management technique: Cancel the company picnic. Please, stick with me; this will explain why Gov. Mike Braun missed a golden eco-devo opportunity. My friend’s experience told him that nobody coming&amp;#160;to his office to complain would be&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/06/the-outstater-276/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 18:22:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] Children Deserve Better Outcomes</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/children-deserve-better-outcomes/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;“In Minnesota, more than half of Fosters experience homelessness by age 24.” That was a shocking headline from a group advocating for legislative changes for Minnesota children caught up in an often-failing foster care system.  A system that doesn’t have uniform standards in all 87 counties.  A government-run system that cites as progress federal data [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/children-deserve-better-outcomes/"&gt;Children Deserve Better Outcomes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 19:27:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Idaho Government has a Spending Problem, not a Revenue Problem</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/idaho-government-has-a-spending-problem-not-a-revenue-problem/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/idaho-government-has-a-spending-problem-not-a-revenue-problem/" rel="nofollow" title="Idaho Government has a Spending Problem, not a Revenue Problem"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Article-Headers-2025-06-30T122540.190.png" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Could Idaho’s government run out of money? That might be a reasonable worry based on your first reading of a recent article highlighting how Idaho’s General Fund revenue was $141 million behind legislative projections for Fiscal Year 2025 (FY25, ending June 30, 2025).&amp;#160; We are told to be concerned because Idaho taxes won’t catch up. [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 19:35:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] Shapiro, House Democrats Miss the Budget Deadline Again, With No Deal in Sight</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/06/30/shapiro-house-democrats-miss-the-budget-deadline-again-with-no-deal-in-sight/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Harrisburg, Pa., June 30, 2025 —Today marks the end of Pennsylvania’s fiscal year and the deadline for lawmakers to pass the FY 2025–26 state budget, with no apparent deal in sight. Pennsylvania stares down yet another budget impasse under Gov. Josh Shapiro, his third in as many years. In this year’s proposed budget, Democratic leaders [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/06/30/shapiro-house-democrats-miss-the-budget-deadline-again-with-no-deal-in-sight/"&gt;Shapiro, House Democrats Miss the Budget Deadline Again, With No Deal in Sight&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 20:15:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Lawmakers should change approach to funding higher education</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/lawmakers-should-change-approach-to-funding-higher-education</link><description>House committee supports per-student funding formula</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] 2025 City Freedom Index: How Free is Your City?</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/2025-city-freedom-index/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=2025-city-freedom-index</link><description>In 2020, Beacon released its first-ever City Freedom Index to shed light on the ways taxpayers are impacted by local government policies. Five years and many changed local policies later, the time has come for an update.</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 11:30:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] Thousands of Arkansas Kids Now Eligible to Receive a Better Education</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/thousands-of-arkansas-kids-now-eligible-to-receive-a-better-education/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;While Minnesota policymakers continue to throw gobs and gobs more taxpayer funds toward our sub-standard public schools while expecting better outcomes, other states are moving ahead, including Arkansas. Created by the LEARNS Act, a “2023 law that made sweeping changes to the state’s K-12 education system,” Arkansas school children are now eligible to participate in [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/thousands-of-arkansas-kids-now-eligible-to-receive-a-better-education/"&gt;Thousands of Arkansas Kids Now Eligible to Receive a Better Education&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 12:39:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Sutherlandinstitute] Does government spend too much money on higher ed? | Josh Bandoch</title><link>https://sutherlandinstitute.org/does-government-spend-too-much-money-on-higher-ed-josh-bandoch/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Is college still the best path to a good job? We explore how career-first education and apprenticeships can better meet today’s workforce needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://sutherlandinstitute.org/does-government-spend-too-much-money-on-higher-ed-josh-bandoch/"&gt;Does government spend too much money on higher ed? | Josh Bandoch&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://sutherlandinstitute.org"&gt;Sutherland Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 13:17:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Louisiana’s public schools are improving. Do families still need choice?</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/education/louisianas-public-schools-are-improving-do-families-still-need-choice/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For the past several months, state K-12 education officials have touted Louisiana’s climb to 32nd in the nation, as measured by the National Assessment of Educational Progress (NAEP). And rightly so—let’s give credit where credit is due. For the past decade, the Louisiana Department of Education (LDOE) and the State Board of Elementary and Secondary...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/education/louisianas-public-schools-are-improving-do-families-still-need-choice/"&gt;Louisiana’s public schools are improving. Do families still need choice?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 13:22:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] WATCH: Megan Martin on PCN Discussing State Budget, Mass Transit Bail-out, and More</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/07/01/watch-megan-martin-on-pcn-discussing-state-budget-mass-transit-bail-out-and-more/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Megan Martin, Commonwealth Foundation&amp;#8217;s Chief Operating Officer and General Counsel, joins PCN&amp;#8217;s Capitol Preview to talk all things state budget. From public transit to Lifeline Scholarships, Martin outlines what good looks like in this year&amp;#8217;s budget, and which proposals will damage Pennsylvania&amp;#8217;s economic future. Watch below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/07/01/watch-megan-martin-on-pcn-discussing-state-budget-mass-transit-bail-out-and-more/"&gt;WATCH: Megan Martin on PCN Discussing State Budget, Mass Transit Bail-out, and More&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 13:27:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Refocusing taxpayer-funded SNAP benefits on healthy food options</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/refocusing-taxpayer-funded-snap-benefits-on-healthy-food-options</link><description>For years, the United States Department of Agriculture (USDA) has ignored  the pleas of states wanting to study the implications of...</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 14:18:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Kelo v. New London Twenty Years Later</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/kelo-v-new-london-twenty-years-later/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Amazingly, it’s been two decades since the U.S. Supreme Court issued one of the most egregiously wrong decisions in constitutional..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/kelo-v-new-london-twenty-years-later/"&gt;Kelo v. New London Twenty Years Later&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 17:21:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] PRESS RELEASE: ONNJ DEBUTS NEW PUBLIC AFFAIRS SERIES: “ENERGY MATTERS”</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/07/press-release-onnj-debuts-new-public-affairs-series-energy-matters/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 17:49:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] BINJE: Energy Matters with Jeanette Hoffman launches today on ONNJ</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/07/binje-energy-matters-with-jeanette-hoffman-launches-today-on-onnj/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 17:56:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] How both sides lost the ConVal school funding case</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/07/how-both-sides-lost-the-conval-school-funding-case/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday morning, the New Hampshire Supreme Court for the first time ordered the state to spend a minimum amount of money—$7.356.01 per pupil—to educate public school students.  The state therefore lost this landmark school funding case, Contoocook Valley School District v. State, as it had tried to avoid such a decree. But a closer [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/07/how-both-sides-lost-the-conval-school-funding-case/"&gt;How both sides lost the ConVal school funding case&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 17:57:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Why Is PortKC Keeping Secrets?</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/transparency/why-is-portkc-keeping-secrets/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;PortKC has become Kansas City’s go-to agency for economic development incentives—but with a troubling condition. Applicants must sign a non-disclosure [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/transparency/why-is-portkc-keeping-secrets/"&gt;Why Is PortKC Keeping Secrets?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 18:40:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Uncle Sam’s Wallet: An Update on Federal Funds in Iowa</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/uncle-sams-wallet-an-update-on-federal-funds-in-iowa/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Iowa’s reliance on federal funds flowing through our state—which cumulatively exceed the $9.4 billion state General Fund—reveals a growing imbalance that puts Iowa at risk. With Congress considering ways to rein in federal deficits by cutting spending on programs like Medicaid or food assistance (SNAP), Iowa’s General Fund might be forced to make up the difference. This would give Iowa taxpayers serious pain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/uncle-sams-wallet-an-update-on-federal-funds-in-iowa/"&gt;Uncle Sam’s Wallet: An Update on Federal Funds in Iowa&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 20:20:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Blistering opt-out pace continues</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/blistering-opt-out-pace-continues/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Freedom Foundation is proud to report back-to-back record-breaking months in May and June, each surpassing 5,000 union opt-outs. That’s more than just a milestone. It’s a momentum shift.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/blistering-opt-out-pace-continues/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Blistering opt-out pace continues&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 22:18:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] James Armistead Lafayette</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/james-armistead-lafayette/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/james-armistead-lafayette/" rel="nofollow" title="James Armistead Lafayette"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="580" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Prop-1-Exposed-2-23.png" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;In celebration of our national heritage, we continue our Pride in America series by honoring one of the unsung heroes of the American Revolution, James Armistead Lafayette.&amp;#160; James Armistead was born into slavery in c. 1748 and spent the early years of his life working on a plantation in Virginia. He was owned by William [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:10:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Cascade Quarterly Spring 2025</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/newsletters/cascade-quarterly-spring-2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Download the full PDF here&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/newsletters/cascade-quarterly-spring-2025/"&gt;Cascade Quarterly Spring 2025&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:59:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Schools need accountability, not a blank check</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/schools-need-accountability-not-a-blank-check</link><description>A new coalition seeks massive tax hike for failing Michigan education system</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Mac Hoffmann: former Statehouse staffer turns Madigan downfall into folk music</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/mac-hoffmann-former-statehouse-staffer-turns-madigan-downfall-into-folk-music/</link><description>Former Illinois House Speaker Mike Madigan may be heading for a 7.5-year stint in the federal pen, but his corrupt legend lives on thanks to a folk song by a former staffer.</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 10:00:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Sutherlandinstitute] We need a “PostBS” civics – starting in elementary and middle school</title><link>https://s35049.pcdn.co/we-need-a-postbs-civics/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;To build lasting democratic habits, we must begin teaching civics in elementary school – through age-appropriate lessons, daily modeling, and real-life engagement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://sutherlandinstitute.org/we-need-a-postbs-civics/"&gt;We need a “PostBS” civics – starting in elementary and middle school&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://sutherlandinstitute.org"&gt;Sutherland Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 12:48:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Education officials top the 2024 KPERS ‘millionaires’ list</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/2024-kpers-millionaires/</link><description>Data provided by the Kansas Public Employees Retirement System shows that Kansas has 4,758 KPERS ‘millionaires’—state and local government retirees who will collect at least $1 million in pension benefits over their first 20 years of retirement. That is an increase of 380 over last year. The complete list of KPERS ‘millionaires’ can be found at KansasOpenGov.org. [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 13:25:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] AI Regulation’s State-by-State Chaos Shows the Need for Federal Leadership</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/ai-regulations-state-by-state-chaos-shows-the-need-for-federal-leadership/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Dr. Edward Longe and Taylor Barkley The fierce opposition to federal artificial intelligence preemption tells us everything we...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/ai-regulations-state-by-state-chaos-shows-the-need-for-federal-leadership/"&gt;AI Regulation’s State-by-State Chaos Shows the Need for Federal Leadership&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 13:36:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Truth on Trial: Relativism in the Classroom</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/blog/truth-on-trial-relativism-in-the-classroom/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As Steven Wilson argues in his new book, The Lost Decade: Returning to the Fight for Better Schools in America, “central to a liberal education is the pursuit of truth, however elusive.” Indeed, the quest for truth, and knowledge of it, is enshrined in the slogans of most universities, including my own—the University of Chicago—as a reminder of our purpose. It seems absurd to suggest otherwise, to propose educating students in anything but rationality, logic, and ultimately, truth; but absurdity has taken hold in education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/blog/truth-on-trial-relativism-in-the-classroom/"&gt;Truth on Trial: Relativism in the Classroom&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 13:45:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Restoring the Citizens’ Voice in Florida’s Citizen’s Initiative Process</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/restoring-the-citizens-voice-in-floridas-citizens-initiative-process/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As a lifelong Floridian who cares deeply about the future of our state, I was pleased to see...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/restoring-the-citizens-voice-in-floridas-citizens-initiative-process/"&gt;Restoring the Citizens’ Voice in Florida’s Citizen’s Initiative Process&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 13:47:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] MSPC joins policy leaders at national tech summit</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/mspc-joins-policy-leaders-at-jmi-tech-summit-2025</link><description>I was proud and honored to represent Mountain States Policy Center at the James Madison Institute’s annual Tech and Innovation Summit in...</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 14:03:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Voters Aren’t Interested in New Transportation Taxes</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/transportation/voters-arent-interested-in-new-transportation-taxes/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By John A. Charles, Jr. The Oregon legislature ended on June 27 without...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/transportation/voters-arent-interested-in-new-transportation-taxes/"&gt;Voters Aren’t Interested in New Transportation Taxes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 14:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Press Release: Mississippi Center for Public Policy Named Finalist for National Bob Williams Award</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/press-release-mississippi-center-for-public-policy-named-finalist-for-national-bob-williams-award/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE (Jackson, MS) Mississippi Center for Public Policy Named Finalist for National Bob Williams Award The Mississippi Center for Public Policy (MCPP) has been selected as a finalist for the prestigious Bob Williams Award for Outstanding Policy Achievement in the “Biggest Home State Win” category. This national recognition, awarded by the State Policy [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/press-release-mississippi-center-for-public-policy-named-finalist-for-national-bob-williams-award/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Press Release: Mississippi Center for Public Policy Named Finalist for National Bob Williams Award&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 15:02:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Stanford’s Pulitzer Winner Jack Rakove on American Independence</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/stanfords-pulitzer-winner-jack-rakove-on-american-independence/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In this week’s episode of The Learning Curve, co-hosts Alisha Searcy and Massachusetts civics teacher Kelley Brown interview Pulitzer Prize-winning historian Jack Rakove, Coe Professor Emeritus at Stanford University. Prof. Rakove explores the origins of the American Revolution and U.S. Constitution through the lives of the nation’s Founding Era figures. Reflecting on young John Adams’ vivid depiction of his schoolhouse in colonial Massachusetts, Rakove offers context for the political and social landscape of the 18th-century America.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/stanfords-pulitzer-winner-jack-rakove-on-american-independence/"&gt;Stanford&amp;#8217;s Pulitzer Winner Jack Rakove on American Independence&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 15:25:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Another Union Takeover – This Time Buried In Housing Bills</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/another-union-takeover-this-time-buried-in-housing-bills/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=another-union-takeover-this-time-buried-in-housing-bills</link><description>&lt;p&gt;You would have to dig into the fine print of legislation signed yesterday to see how non-union business owners and workers got screwed, again. If A Tree Falls In The Forest And No One Hears It &amp;#8211; Did It Make A Noise? What we witnessed yesterday afternoon should alarm every Californian who values free enterprise...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/another-union-takeover-this-time-buried-in-housing-bills/"&gt;Another Union Takeover – This Time Buried In Housing Bills&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 16:52:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Closing the Gap: How Wisconsin’s Budget Continues to Close the Funding Gap Between Public &amp; Parental Choice Options</title><link>https://will-law.org/closing-the-gap-how-wisconsins-budget-continues-to-close-the-funding-gap-between-public-parental-choice-options/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Will Flanders Kyle Koenen July 2nd, 2025 Like any budget that is a result of compromise in divided government, there are positive and negative aspects.  But one definite positive to come [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/closing-the-gap-how-wisconsins-budget-continues-to-close-the-funding-gap-between-public-parental-choice-options/"&gt;Closing the Gap: How Wisconsin’s Budget Continues to Close the Funding Gap Between Public &amp;#038; Parental Choice Options&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 18:57:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Is patriotism going extinct?! Plus: BBB passes the Senate</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/is-patriotism-going-extinct-plus-bbb-passes-the-senate/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In the 82nd episode of the American Experiment Podcast, Grace and Kathryn sit down to cover the news of the day before the 4th of July holiday! First, is patriotism going extinct? The latest polling shows patriotism is becoming a partisan issue. Next, breaking news of the day, the &amp;#8220;Big Beautiful Bill&amp;#8221; has officially passed...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/is-patriotism-going-extinct-plus-bbb-passes-the-senate/"&gt;Is patriotism going extinct?! Plus: BBB passes the Senate&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 19:07:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Highlights From the 2025 Florida Tech and Innovation Summit</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/highlights-from-the-2025-florida-tech-and-innovation-summit/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On Thursday, June 26, 2025, thought leaders from across the country joined The James Madison Institute in Coral...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/highlights-from-the-2025-florida-tech-and-innovation-summit/"&gt;Highlights From the 2025 Florida Tech and Innovation Summit&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 19:15:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] Trenton Just Made It Harder to Do Business in New Jersey</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/07/trenton-just-made-it-harder-to-do-business-in-new-jersey/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Andy Mulvihill, NJPI Board Chairman  New Jersey isn’t known for being an easy place to build or invest—but somehow, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/07/trenton-just-made-it-harder-to-do-business-in-new-jersey/"&gt;Trenton Just Made It Harder to Do Business in New Jersey&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 19:16:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Happy 2nd? The history of our Independence you may not know</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/happy-2nd-the-history-of-our-independence-you-may-not-know</link><description>The fireworks of July 4 celebrate the ideals of liberty and equality. But July 2 was when independence truly began—when courage triumphed over fear, and a group of revolutionaries voted to create a new nation.</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 19:44:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Is There a Medicaid Storm on the Horizon?</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/is-there-a-medicaid-storm-on-the-horizon/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Medicaid now consumes nearly 19% of Iowa’s General Fund, with a $2 billion annual cost that will likely increase in coming years due to growing enrollment and reduced federal support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iowa lawmakers have advanced a work requirement for able-bodied Medicaid recipients, but federal approval is needed to implement this reform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With over $13 billion in federal funding flowing into the state, policymakers must prepare for the risk of future federal cuts and reduce Iowa’s reliance on unpredictable federal dollars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/is-there-a-medicaid-storm-on-the-horizon/"&gt;Is There a Medicaid Storm on the Horizon?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 19:59:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Missouri Finally Dials in Telemedicine Reform</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/free-market-reform/missouri-finally-dials-in-telemedicine-reform/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Following years of unanswered calls, lawmakers finally delivered much-needed reform to the state’s telemedicine laws in the waning days of [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/free-market-reform/missouri-finally-dials-in-telemedicine-reform/"&gt;Missouri Finally Dials in Telemedicine Reform&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 19:59:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Let the Message Be Clear: Canadian Healthcare Failed</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/let-the-message-be-clear-canadian-healthcare-failed/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Meet Mary, a 60-year-old woman from British Columbia. She needed a colonoscopy to confirm her cancer diagnosis. Mary spent four months on a waiting list. Then her bowel ruptured, and she suffered life-threatening sepsis. Due to the delay in treating her cancer, she had to get chemotherapy, which came with serious neurological side effects. Read [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/let-the-message-be-clear-canadian-healthcare-failed/"&gt;Let the Message Be Clear: Canadian Healthcare Failed&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 20:45:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Understanding Preemption: What Iowa’s New Fireworks Law Means for Local Governments</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/understanding-preemption-what-iowas-new-fireworks-law-means-for-local-governments/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The fireworks law may seem like a small matter, but it serves as a powerful example of how preemption works—and why it’s important for local governments to stay informed and responsive to changes at the state level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iowa cities and counties enjoy a great deal of autonomy in managing their local affairs thanks to what’s known as “home rule.” Iowa’s constitution grants home rule authority to cities and counties, which means they have broad power to govern themselves. However, this authority is not absolute. One key limitation is that local governments cannot enact ordinances that conflict with state law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/understanding-preemption-what-iowas-new-fireworks-law-means-for-local-governments/"&gt;Understanding Preemption: What Iowa’s New Fireworks Law Means for Local Governments&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 20:50:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] SEIU 503’s ‘top priority’ goes down to defeat</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/oregon/seiu-503s-top-priority-goes-down-to-defeat/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Last week’s adjournment by the Oregon legislature marked the end of the road for SEIU 503’s “top priority bill” of the 2025 session, House Bill (HB) 3838, when the measure ultimately failed to make it out of committee in the face of stiff opposition and questions surrounding possible misconduct by the union officials promoting it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/oregon/seiu-503s-top-priority-goes-down-to-defeat/" rel="nofollow"&gt;SEIU 503’s ‘top priority’ goes down to defeat&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 21:01:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Lawmakers and Activists Celebrate Toothless Climate Bills</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/07/02/lawmakers-and-activists-celebrate-toothless-climate-bills/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="675" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/thumbnail_facebook_x_4.png" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On July 1, environmental activists, alongside state officials and lawmakers, praised Gov. Ned Lamont for signing two climate bills, H.B. 5004 and S.B. 9, heralded as groundbreaking legislation. Yet, despite [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/07/02/lawmakers-and-activists-celebrate-toothless-climate-bills/"&gt;Lawmakers and Activists Celebrate Toothless Climate Bills&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 21:45:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Illegal aliens are illegal again</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/illegal-aliens-are-illegal-again/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Trump Administration&amp;#8217;s increased efforts to oppose illegal immigration are being felt in Minnesota. Back in May, I wrote about an initiative of the U.S. Department of Justice to ramp up prosecutions for illegal border crossings. You frequently hear (false) statements to the effect that illegally crossing the border is not a &amp;#8220;crime&amp;#8221; and/or deportations...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/illegal-aliens-are-illegal-again/"&gt;Illegal aliens are illegal again&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 21:54:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Lessening California’s Energy Regulations Will Help Consumers</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/lessening-californias-energy-regulations-will-help-consumers/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Gas costs too much in the Golden State. Addressing this unaffordable energy problem should be a top priority for state legislators and the governor. California has taken a step backward toward this goal, however; but may be primed to take a step forward too. Read the op-ed here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/lessening-californias-energy-regulations-will-help-consumers/"&gt;Lessening California’s Energy Regulations Will Help Consumers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 22:19:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Back to Ecuador</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/back-to-ecuador/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;ICE now says that German Llangari Inga, age 35, has been deported to Ecudor. The Star Tribune reports. U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement removed German Llangari Inga, an illegally present Ecuadorean national, to Ecuador on June 24 &amp;#8230; pursuant to a final order of removal issued by a federal immigration judge. You will recall that...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/back-to-ecuador/"&gt;Back to Ecuador&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 01:51:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Ford Foundation turns to scandal-plagued Yale dean</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/ford-foundation-turns-to-scandal-plagued-yale-dean/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Collin Anderson writes for the Washington Free Beacon about a high-profile, left-of-center foundation’s questionable leadership selection. The left-wing Ford Foundation has a new president: Heather Gerken, the scandal-plagued dean of Yale Law School whose tenure attracted national attention when administrators threatened the professional prospects of a second-year student for his use of the term &amp;#8220;trap...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/ford-foundation-turns-to-scandal-plagued-yale-dean/"&gt;Ford Foundation turns to scandal-plagued Yale dean&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 09:36:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Justice Jackson plays her role as political activist</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/justice-jackson-plays-her-role-as-political-activist/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Shawn Fleetwood reminds Federalist readers that the nation’s newest Supreme Court justice was not appointed to be a jurist. While the Supreme Court’s 2024 term has come to an end, there’s one opinion that’s still generating widespread conversation within America’s political discourse. In the high court’s Trump v. CASA decision nuking lower courts’ abuse of...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/justice-jackson-plays-her-role-as-political-activist/"&gt;Justice Jackson plays her role as political activist&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 09:39:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Rubio pans American taxes propping up failed foreign governments</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/rubio-pans-american-taxes-propping-up-failed-foreign-governments/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Sarah Anderson writes for PJMedia.com about the secretary of state’s latest pronouncement. When he&amp;#8217;s not assisting with taking out Iran&amp;#8217;s nuclear capabilities, revoking visas from those who support terrorism, or helping the president broker peace in Africa, he&amp;#8217;s looking after your tax dollars. &amp;#8220;The era of government-sanctioned inefficiency is OVER. From now on, our foreign...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/rubio-pans-american-taxes-propping-up-failed-foreign-governments/"&gt;Rubio pans American taxes propping up failed foreign governments&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 09:42:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Innovation revolutionized the movie industry. Could it do the same for education?</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/innovation-revolutionized-the-movie-industry-could-it-do-the-same-for-education</link><description>Goals matter more than processes</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Illinois nurse shortage fix is blocked by unions</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/illinois-nurse-shortage-fix-is-blocked-by-unions/</link><description>Joining the multi-state Nurse Licensure Compact offers a solution to Illinois’ growing nurse shortage, but certain special interest groups stand in the way, limiting patients’ access to timely medical care.</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 10:00:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Nearly 32,000 Illinois government pensioners paid $100k-plus</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/nearly-32000-illinois-government-pensioners-paid-100k-plus/</link><description>State data shows 31,937 members of Illinois’ five pension systems collected $100,000 a year or more in retirement benefits during 2024. Some got over $500,000. See the full list below.</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 10:00:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Senate may save California from itself by ending EV mandate</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/senate-may-save-california-from-itself-by-ending-ev-mandate/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Senate voted 51-44 vote to revoke an EPA waiver that allowed the state to set emission standards stricter than those set by the federal government. Earlier this month, President Donald Trump signed the measure as well as two related ones. In 2020, Gov. Gavin Newsom signed an executive order requiring all new vehicles sold [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/senate-may-save-california-from-itself-by-ending-ev-mandate/"&gt;Senate may save California from itself by ending EV mandate&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 10:00:31 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>