<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>State-Policy Think-Tank Digest</title><link>https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml</link><description>Latest posts from free-market policy institutes across the U.S.</description><atom:link href="https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 23:03:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] Court ratifies City of Albuquerque donation to Planned Parenthood</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/court-ratifies-city-of-albuquerque-donation-to-planned-parenthood/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In what can only be described as a ruling based on twisted logic a New Mexico District Judge (Denise Barela Shepherd) has decided that it is somehow NOT a violation of New Mexico&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8220;anti-donation clause&amp;#8221; for the City of Albuquerque to explicitly donation $250,000 of our tax dollars to Planned Parenthood.  Our friends at the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/court-ratifies-city-of-albuquerque-donation-to-planned-parenthood/"&gt;Court ratifies City of Albuquerque donation to Planned Parenthood&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 22:24:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Frightfully pricey treats: Why Halloween fun is costing Georgia families more</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/georgia-halloween-candy-prices/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As Halloween approaches, Georgia families look forward to making great memories involving adorable costumes and fun candy hauls. But candy prices have become nothing short of scary for families trying to make ends meet. Here's why prices are on the rise for Georgia's favorite Halloween treats. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/georgia-halloween-candy-prices/"&gt;Frightfully pricey treats: Why Halloween fun is costing Georgia families more&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 16:01:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Mayor John Horhn: Jackson Rising</title><link>https://empowerms.org/mayor-john-horhn-jackson-rising/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Mayor John Horhn: Jackson Rising What does it take to turn around a city? In this special episode recorded at Jackson City Hall, host Grant Callen talks with Mayor John Horhn about his love for Jackson, the lessons from his childhood and career in public service, and his mission to restore trust, safety, and opportunity&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/mayor-john-horhn-jackson-rising/"&gt;Mayor John Horhn: Jackson Rising&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 01:00:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Maine’s 2025 Ballot Questions: What Voters Should Know</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/maines-2025-ballot-questions-what-voters-should-know/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As Maine heads into the 2025 election, voters will face two ballot questions that cut to the heart of the state’s debates over election integrity and gun rights. Both questions resurrect legislative fights that failed in Augusta and are now placed directly before the people. Ballot Question 1: Election Integrity Ballot Summary:“Do you want to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/maines-2025-ballot-questions-what-voters-should-know/"&gt;Maine’s 2025 Ballot Questions: What Voters Should Know&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 21:09:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] WI Speaks Polling Results</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/wi-speaks-survey-results/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WI 1023 Toplines (1) WI 1023 Summary of Key Findings (2) WI 1023 Summary of Key Findings (2)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/wi-speaks-survey-results/"&gt;WI Speaks Polling Results&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 00:18:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Virginiainstitute] Examining HJ6007 and Its Implications for Virginia’s Redistricting Process</title><link>https://virginiainstitute.org/examining-hj6007/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=examining-hj6007</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As lawmakers consider HJ6007, Virginians are asking how the proposal aligns with the 2020 constitutional amendment supporting fair maps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org/examining-hj6007/"&gt;Examining HJ6007 and Its Implications for Virginia’s Redistricting Process&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org"&gt;Virginia Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 01:53:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] NYC Employees Receive $300k+ in Overtime</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/nyc-employees-receive-300k-in-overtime/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Two New York City employees received more than $300,000 in overtime payouts, according to fiscal year 2025 payroll data posted....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/nyc-employees-receive-300k-in-overtime/"&gt;NYC Employees Receive $300k+ in Overtime&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 13:20:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Virginiainstitute] Press Release – HJ 6007: “one of the worst ideas” passed by the General Assembly</title><link>https://virginiainstitute.org/press-release-hj6007/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=press-release-hj6007</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Virginia Institute for Public Policy has expressed concern over HJ6007, a proposed amendment to Virginia’s Constitution that would alter the state’s current redistricting process. The Institute emphasized that Virginia voters approved a bipartisan approach in 2020 to ensure fair and transparent elections for all citizens. Citing constitutional and procedural issues surrounding HJ6007, the Institute encourages lawmakers to uphold established safeguards that protect the integrity and balance of Virginia’s electoral system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org/press-release-hj6007/"&gt;Press Release – HJ 6007: “one of the worst ideas” passed by the General Assembly&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org"&gt;Virginia Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 00:15:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] Average Twin Cities Commuter = 73 Hours Stuck in Traffic</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/average-twin-cities-commuter-73-hours-stuck-in-traffic/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Every year, the Texas A&amp;#38;M Transportation Institute issues a report documenting the price of road congestion on American roads. This 2025 report is notable for Minnesota commuters because it documented that the “average Twin Cities car commuter now spends a record 73 hours a year stuck in traffic.” This is an increase after a COVID-pandemic [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/average-twin-cities-commuter-73-hours-stuck-in-traffic/"&gt;Average Twin Cities Commuter = 73 Hours Stuck in Traffic&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 18:14:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF in National Review: New Mexico’s ‘Free’ Child Care an Attempt to Cover for Past Failures</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-in-national-review-new-mexicos-free-child-care-an-attempt-to-cover-for-past-failures/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following appeared at National Review on November 11, 2025. Child care isn’t cheap, especially once the government gets involved. Recently, New Mexico’s Democratic Governor Michelle Lujan Grisham announced a new plan for taxpayers to fund “free” child care for all New Mexicans, regardless of their income levels. The announcement generated favorable news coverage in [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-in-national-review-new-mexicos-free-child-care-an-attempt-to-cover-for-past-failures/"&gt;RGF in National Review: New Mexico’s ‘Free’ Child Care an Attempt to Cover for Past Failures&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 21:15:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] AEA Has Shown Alabamians Who They Are: Believe Them</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/11/04/aea-has-shown-alabamians-who-they-are-believe-them/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;AEA has worked for decades to stop school choice legislation. AEA actively worked against the passage of the AAA Scholarship program, the PRICE Act, and the CHOOSE Act. AEA used political influence and political contributions to people and parties to weaken parental rights in the CHOOSE Act and then tried to kill the CHOOSE Act unless they could “control the spending” with a cap. Further, AEA worked last legislative session to minimize funding for special needs kids, military kids, and kids whose families are living in poverty; they are currently working against future CHOOSE Act schoolchildren. AEA is trying to render void the promises legislators made to Alabama parents when they passed the law in 2024. They are attempting to undercut the work and the word of Governor Kay Ivey, Lt. Governor Will Ainsworth, Speaker Nathaniel Ledbetter, Chairman Danny Garrett, Chairman Arthur Orr, and each of the ninety-two legislators who voted on behalf of the people they represent for universal school choice for Alabama’s children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/11/04/aea-has-shown-alabamians-who-they-are-believe-them/"&gt;AEA Has Shown Alabamians Who They Are: Believe Them&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 05:04:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] SNAP in Nebraska: Current Rules, Economic Impact, and What’s Next</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/snap-in-nebraska-current-rules-economic-impact-and-whats-next/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Program Overview  The Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP), formerly known as the Food Stamp Program, is the most extensive federal nutrition assistance program in the United States. It serves as a &amp;#8220;safety net&amp;#8221; program that helpslow-income individuals and families access and purchase healthy food. The program is funded by the Department of Agriculture (USDA) and...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/snap-in-nebraska-current-rules-economic-impact-and-whats-next/" rel="nofollow"&gt;SNAP in Nebraska: Current Rules, Economic Impact, and What’s Next&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 16:16:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Nebraska lost $300 million from tax migration in 2022</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-lost-300-million-from-tax-migration-in-2022/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Elections occur every other November. But taxpayers vote with their feet every day, and these votes should be counted and tallied just like the votes for a November election.  A “Great Pandemic Wealth Migration” began when the coronavirus pandemic caused Americans to move to work-from-home employment. This meant workers were no longer tied to aphysical...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-lost-300-million-from-tax-migration-in-2022/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Nebraska lost $300 million from tax migration in 2022&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 19:03:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] November 2025 Beacon Poll Results</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/november-2025-beacon-poll/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=november-2025-beacon-poll</link><description>Today, we released the latest installment of the Beacon Poll, a statewide survey of 1,200 Tennessee voters featuring questions about voters&amp;#8217; views on socialism versus capitalism, the National Guard in Memphis, political violence, and more. In a surprising result that could have a national impact, a majority of Democrats in Tennessee hold a favorable view...</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 13:00:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] California Just Blew Past Last Year’s Record — And We’re Still Climbing</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/california-just-blew-past-last-years-record-and-were-still-climbing/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;California public employees are opting out of their unions in record numbers thanks to the work of the Freedom Foundation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/california-just-blew-past-last-years-record-and-were-still-climbing/" rel="nofollow"&gt;California Just Blew Past Last Year’s Record — And We’re Still Climbing&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 23:30:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] NH’s youngest lawmakers to discuss civility in politics at Civil Discourses kickoff event</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/11/nhs-youngest-lawmakers-to-discuss-civility-in-politics-at-civil-discourses-kickoff-event/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Josiah Bartlett Center for Public Policy will bring a bipartisan group of New Hampshire’s youngest state representatives together on Dec. 1 for a frank and open conversation on the importance of civility in public life.  Josiah Bartlett Center President Andrew Cline will moderate a conversation among:: Rep. Jessica Grill, Democrat of Manchester; Rep. Sam [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/11/nhs-youngest-lawmakers-to-discuss-civility-in-politics-at-civil-discourses-kickoff-event/"&gt;NH&amp;#8217;s youngest lawmakers to discuss civility in politics at Civil Discourses kickoff event&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 13:31:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] ROI-NJ: A blueprint for abundant, affordable energy for New Jersey families | Op-Ed</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/11/roi-nj-a-blueprint-for-abundant-affordable-energy-for-new-jersey-families-op-ed/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A blueprint for abundant, affordable energy for New Jersey families &amp;#124; Op-Ed By Erica Jedynak, New Jersey Policy Institute November [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/11/roi-nj-a-blueprint-for-abundant-affordable-energy-for-new-jersey-families-op-ed/"&gt;ROI-NJ: A blueprint for abundant, affordable energy for New Jersey families | Op-Ed&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 16:11:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] WFSE loses 1,000 members for second consecutive year</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/washington/wfse-loses-1000-members-for-second-consecutive-year/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For the second year in a row, the largest union representing Washington state employees has lost more than 1,000 members, thanks in large part to the ongoing outreach efforts of the Freedom Foundation to help of workers understand their right to opt out of paying union dues.&amp;#160; With annual union dues averaging around $1,000 per [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/washington/wfse-loses-1000-members-for-second-consecutive-year/" rel="nofollow"&gt;WFSE loses 1,000 members for second consecutive year&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 17:55:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] State Tax Competitiveness Index: Minnesota Falls to 44th out of 50!</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/state-tax-competitiveness-index-minnesota-falls-to-44th-out-of-50/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For 20 years, the Tax Foundation has released an annual report evaluating state tax codes – everything from income to property to sales taxes. Each state has its own summary including an interactive map that includes suggestions on how the state could become more competitive. Minnesota state leadership, however appears to be determined for our [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/state-tax-competitiveness-index-minnesota-falls-to-44th-out-of-50/"&gt;State Tax Competitiveness Index: Minnesota Falls to 44th out of 50!&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 19:06:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Enhanced Democratic Trifecta in Richmond Grants Them Control Over Energy Policy</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/enhanced-democratic-trifecta-in-richmond-grants-them-control-over-energy-policy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="720" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/Va-Dems-Energy.jpg" width="1280" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The return of the political trifecta Democrats enjoyed during the 2020 and 2021 General Assembly sessions – now bolstered with a 64-36 majority in the House of Delegates – leaves the question of how to deal with Virginia’s energy issues entirely in their hands. Only if the Democrats suffer a significant division within their own [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/enhanced-democratic-trifecta-in-richmond-grants-them-control-over-energy-policy/"&gt;Enhanced Democratic Trifecta in Richmond Grants Them Control Over Energy Policy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 13:42:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Budget Update Paints Less Alarming Picture of Federal Health Cuts</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/budget-update-paints-less-alarming-picture/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A new fiscal report from the state Budget Division suggests federal funding cuts will hit New York&amp;#8217;s health-care budget less....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/budget-update-paints-less-alarming-picture/"&gt;Budget Update Paints Less Alarming Picture of Federal Health Cuts&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 14:23:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Will Concord or Laconia reap the rewards of creating NH’s first social district?</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/11/will-concord-or-laconia-reap-the-rewards-of-creating-nhs-first-social-district/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The term “economic growth” seldom pops up in local news stories. But there it was in the third paragraph of the Concord Monitor’s story on Tuesday’s election results.  After quoting a former teacher who complained about the slow pace of change in Concord due to “a lot of governmental, bureaucratic red tape,” the Monitor described [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/11/will-concord-or-laconia-reap-the-rewards-of-creating-nhs-first-social-district/"&gt;Will Concord or Laconia reap the rewards of creating NH&amp;#8217;s first social district?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 17:30:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] Minnesotans Cannot Afford Four More Years of Walz Energy Policy</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/minnesotans-cannot-afford-four-more-years-of-walz-energy-policy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;What happens when working families see electric bills climb to meet the governor’s idealistic demands? By Annette Meeks Gov. Tim Walz officially announced that he wants to serve four more years leading Minnesota. He did not make this announcement in a public meeting, rally or policy speech, but with a carefully crafted video. It was a politically manufactured [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/minnesotans-cannot-afford-four-more-years-of-walz-energy-policy/"&gt;Minnesotans Cannot Afford Four More Years of Walz Energy Policy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 19:02:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] The fantasy that cutting prison populations saves a lot of money</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/the-fantasy-that-cutting-prison-populations-saves-a-lot-of-money/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/the-fantasy-that-cutting-prison-populations-saves-a-lot-of-money/"&gt;The fantasy that cutting prison populations saves a lot of money&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 16:02:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] New Report: Shapiro’s ‘Get Sh*t Done’ Slogan Doesn’t Match His Record</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/11/10/shapiro-get-sht-done-slogan-doesnt-match-record/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Gov. Josh Shapiro remains Pennsylvania’s least legislatively productive governor in the past 50 years. Harrisburg, Pa., November 10, 2025 — As presidential ambitions of Pennsylvania’s 48th governor become increasingly prominent, many question: Is Governor Shapiro as productive as he claims? A new report from the Commonwealth Foundation found Gov. Josh Shapiro to be the least [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/11/10/shapiro-get-sht-done-slogan-doesnt-match-record/"&gt;New Report: Shapiro’s ‘Get Sh*t Done’ Slogan Doesn’t Match His Record&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 19:58:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Shutdown Endgame: What the Deal Means for Maine and the Nation</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/shutdown-endgame-what-the-deal-means-for-maine-and-the-nation/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;After more than 40 days, the longest government shutdown in American history appears to be nearing an end. The Senate voted 60–40 on a short-term funding bill that would reopen shuttered federal agencies and extend operations through late January. In a rare show of bipartisanship, eight Democrats, including Senator Angus King, joined Republicans to advance [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/shutdown-endgame-what-the-deal-means-for-maine-and-the-nation/"&gt;Shutdown Endgame: What the Deal Means for Maine and the Nation&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 01:28:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] What You Need To Know For Special Session</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/11/11/what-you-need-to-know-for-special-session/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="1216" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/Screenshot-2025-08-19-134951.jpg" width="1736" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connecticut lawmakers are moving quickly in a special session — tackling housing, emergency spending, and healthcare policy from Nov. 12-13. Some proposals represent steps in the right direction. Others risk [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/11/11/what-you-need-to-know-for-special-session/"&gt;What You Need To Know For Special Session&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 15:50:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] DPI Rates 0 Districts 1 Star, Half of All Schools 4 or 5 Stars on New School Report Cards</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/dpi-rates-0-districts-1-star-half-of-all-schools-4-or-5-stars-on-new-school-report-cards/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;DPI Rates 0 Districts 1 Star, Half of All Schools 4 or 5 Stars on New School Report Cards DPI’s rankings make report cards mostly meaningless  Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government (IRG) released the following statement following the release of 2025 district and school report cards using a lenient formula, resulting in [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/dpi-rates-0-districts-1-star-half-of-all-schools-4-or-5-stars-on-new-school-report-cards/"&gt;DPI Rates 0 Districts 1 Star, Half of All Schools 4 or 5 Stars on New School Report Cards&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 17:31:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] NJBIZ: OPINION: Why New Jersey should repeal its bag ban</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/11/njbiz-opinion-why-new-jersey-should-repeal-its-bag-ban-wells-winegar/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;OPINION: Why New Jersey should repeal its bag ban by Wells Winegar November 10, 2025 &amp;#160; Walk into any New [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/11/njbiz-opinion-why-new-jersey-should-repeal-its-bag-ban-wells-winegar/"&gt;NJBIZ: OPINION: Why New Jersey should repeal its bag ban&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 18:56:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] TriMet Retreat Should Focus on Crisis, Not Expansion</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/transportation/trimet-retreat-should-focus-on-crisis-not-expansion/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By John A. Charles, Jr. On November 12, the TriMet Board will hold...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/transportation/trimet-retreat-should-focus-on-crisis-not-expansion/"&gt;TriMet Retreat Should Focus on Crisis, Not Expansion &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 22:56:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Dr. Brad Wilcox: Get Married</title><link>https://empowerms.org/dr-brad-wilcox-get-married/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Dr. Brad Wilcox: Get Married On this episode of The Empower Podcast, host Grant Callen talks with Dr. Brad Wilcox, Director of the National Marriage Project at the University of Virginia and author of Get Married: Why Americans Must Defy the Elites, Forge Strong Families, and Save Civilization. Dr. Wilcox shares striking research on how&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/dr-brad-wilcox-get-married/"&gt;Dr. Brad Wilcox: Get Married&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 00:00:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] UK Uni. of St Andrews’ Sir Hew Strachan on the First World War</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/uk-uni-of-st-andrews-sir-hew-strachan-on-the-first-world-war/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In this week’s episode of The Learning Curve, co-hosts U-Arkansas Prof. Albert Cheng and Center for Strong Public Schools’ Alisha Searcy speak with Sir Hew Strachan, Professor of International Relations at the University of St Andrews, Scotland, and recipient of the 2016 Pritzker Literature Award for Lifetime Achievement in Military Writing. Prof. Sir Hew, author of numerous award-winning books, including The First World War, the basis of the definitive 10-part Channel 4/BBC documentary, discusses how World War I shaped the 20th century and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/uk-uni-of-st-andrews-sir-hew-strachan-on-the-first-world-war/"&gt;UK Uni. of St Andrews&amp;#8217; Sir Hew Strachan on the First World War&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 16:56:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] Rio Grande Foundation Soiree a Huge Success!</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rio-grande-foundation-soiree-a-huge-success/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;What do you call 175 freedom loving New Mexicans gathered in one place? A good start! In all seriousness the Rio Grande Foundation hosted its 25th anniversary Laissez Faire Soiree this past Saturday night and we are pleased to report  the event was a smashing success with 175 attendees and lots of fun. Thanks to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rio-grande-foundation-soiree-a-huge-success/"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation Soiree a Huge Success!&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 19:40:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] Despite Shapiro’s Failed Leadership, 2025-26 Budget Secures Key Permitting Wins, Ends Threat of RGGI</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/11/12/pennsylvania-2025-26-budget-secures-key-permitting-wins-ends-rggi/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Harrisburg, Pa., November 12,&amp;#160;2025 —&amp;#160;Despite Gov. Josh Shapiro’s failed leadership and a 135-day stalemate, Pennsylvania lawmakers passed a compromise budget for the 2025–2026 fiscal year. The Commonwealth Foundation has released a comprehensive analysis of the newly passed budget, available here. The budget, totaling $50.09 billion, includes a 5.1 percent spending increase. While the agreement includes [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/11/12/pennsylvania-2025-26-budget-secures-key-permitting-wins-ends-rggi/"&gt;Despite Shapiro&amp;#8217;s Failed Leadership, 2025-26 Budget Secures Key Permitting Wins, Ends Threat of RGGI&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 19:42:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Volunteering for Higher Taxes? Assessing Tennessee’s Uncapped Property Taxes</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/volunteering-for-higher-taxes-assessing-tennessees-uncapped-property-taxes/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=volunteering-for-higher-taxes-assessing-tennessees-uncapped-property-taxes</link><description>If Tennessee wants to protect its residents in all aspects and truly take claim to being a low-tax state, lawmakers should look around the nation and see that we are in the small minority that fails to protect citizens from unjust property tax hikes.</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 19:52:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alaskapolicyforum] Is Anchorage’s New Proposed “Short-Term Rental-Only” Tax Really the Answer?</title><link>https://alaskapolicyforum.org/2025/11/is-anchorages-new-proposed-short-term-rental-only-tax-really-the-answer/#utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=is-anchorages-new-proposed-short-term-rental-only-tax-really-the-answer</link><description>&lt;div style="margin: 5px 5% 10px 5%;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" height="675" src="https://alaskapolicyforum.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/jon-tyson-XS_o-Iuf9Go-unsplash-scaled-e1762980183585.jpg" title="" width="506" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This blog looks at an urgent issue for Anchorage, which is considering a new short-term rental tax next week. That may seem like an easy fix for housing, but in reality, it raises seriousRead More&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alaskapolicyforum.org/2025/11/is-anchorages-new-proposed-short-term-rental-only-tax-really-the-answer/"&gt;Is Anchorage’s New Proposed “Short-Term Rental-Only” Tax Really the Answer?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://alaskapolicyforum.org"&gt;Alaska Policy Forum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 21:06:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Most UW System schools’ enrollments are stagnant as tech colleges flourish</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/most-uw-system-schools-enrollments-are-stagnant-as-tech-colleges-flourish/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;While undergraduate enrollment in most University of Wisconsin System schools trends downward, there has been a dramatic increase in students choosing the state’s technical colleges since the pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/most-uw-system-schools-enrollments-are-stagnant-as-tech-colleges-flourish/"&gt;Most UW System schools’ enrollments are stagnant as tech colleges flourish&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 22:08:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Multnomah Audit Finds Fraud in Construction Recycling</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/economic-opportunity/multnomah-audit-finds-fraud-in-construction-recycling/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Naomi Inman What happens to all that construction debris on public works...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/economic-opportunity/multnomah-audit-finds-fraud-in-construction-recycling/"&gt;Multnomah Audit Finds Fraud in Construction Recycling&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 17:13:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] The RGGI trap</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/11/the-rggi-trap/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;According to national media reports, Pennsylvania’s 2025 budget deal caused the state to “exit” RGGI. Media coverage also used the words “leave,” “quit” and “pull out” to describe Pennsylvania’s abandonment of RGGI. Pennsylvania, though, wasn’t actually a member of RGGI.  In 2019, then-Gov. Tom Wolf issued an executive order for his administration to adopt regulations [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/11/the-rggi-trap/"&gt;The RGGI trap&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 20:15:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Before the Ink Dried, the Union Was Already Calling the Shots at Waterbury Hospital</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/11/14/before-the-ink-dried-the-union-was-already-calling-the-shots-at-waterbury-hospital/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bill authorizing UConn Health to purchase Waterbury Hospital wasn’t even written when one of Connecticut’s most politically influential healthcare unions began issuing demands.   On Oct. 17 — weeks before [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/11/14/before-the-ink-dried-the-union-was-already-calling-the-shots-at-waterbury-hospital/"&gt;Before the Ink Dried, the Union Was Already Calling the Shots at Waterbury Hospital&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 20:33:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] A legacy of healing — Documentary tells ReCAST Lawrenceville’s journey through residents’ stories</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/recast-lawrenceville-documentary/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/recast-lawrenceville-documentary/"&gt;A legacy of healing — Documentary tells ReCAST Lawrenceville’s journey through residents’ stories&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:43:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Progressives Urge Assembly to Soak the Rich, But Likely Tax Increases Will Reach Everyone</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/progressives-urge-assembly-to-soak-the-rich-but-likely-tax-increases-will-reach-everyone/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/Virginia-Tax-Increase-Ahead.jpg" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a new Democratic Party trifecta looms in Virginia, a progressive policy group has floated a long list of old and new ways to soak Virginia’s upper-income residents through taxes in order to fund additional state spending.  The Commonwealth Institute for Fiscal Analysis doesn’t use the word “spending,” of course, but speaks of “investments” in “quality public [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/progressives-urge-assembly-to-soak-the-rich-but-likely-tax-increases-will-reach-everyone/"&gt;Progressives Urge Assembly to Soak the Rich, But Likely Tax Increases Will Reach Everyone&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 15:18:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] New Jersey Policy Institute Announces Inaugural Class of 2026 Junior Fellows</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/11/new-jersey-policy-institute-announces-inaugural-class-of-2026-junior-fellows/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Parsippany, NJ – The New Jersey Policy Institute (NJPI) is proud to announce the inaugural class of its 2026 Junior Fellowship [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/11/new-jersey-policy-institute-announces-inaugural-class-of-2026-junior-fellows/"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute Announces Inaugural Class of 2026 Junior Fellows&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 18:43:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] New WILL Lawsuit Targets the Beating Heart of Federal DEI Programs</title><link>https://will-law.org/new-will-lawsuit-targets-the-beating-heart-of-federal-dei-programs/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL and the Center for Individual Rights (CIR) filed a major lawsuit against the Trump Administration today, targeting the foundation for many of the remaining federal DEI programs: the preference for so-called “socially disadvantaged individuals.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/new-will-lawsuit-targets-the-beating-heart-of-federal-dei-programs/"&gt;New WILL Lawsuit Targets the Beating Heart of Federal DEI Programs&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 20:38:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Kansas Doesn’t Need to Play Ball With Corporate Welfare</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/kansas-doesnt-need-to-play-ball/</link><description>Taxpayers want markets, not handouts, to drive growth A new SurveyUSA poll of Overland Park and Leawood residents confirms what many Kansans already feel in their gut: people love their teams, but their desire to spend tax dollars on it declines as the taxes hit closer to home.  When asked if the state should use [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 22:00:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Mississippi Voters Demand Universal School Choice – New Poll Shows Overwhelming Support</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/mississippi-voters-demand-universal-school-choice-new-poll-shows-overwhelming-support/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Big news on School Choice this week!&amp;#160; A fresh poll shows massive support in Mississippi to have&amp;#160;families, not government, control their child’s education.&amp;#160; Mississippi voters say they’ll reward lawmakers who make it happen. The brand-new statewide survey (October 27-30, 2025) conducted by The Tarrance Group shows&amp;#160;rock-solid support&amp;#160;for expanding education freedom.&amp;#160; There is massive bipartisan support [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/mississippi-voters-demand-universal-school-choice-new-poll-shows-overwhelming-support/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Voters Demand Universal School Choice – New Poll Shows Overwhelming Support&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 22:06:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Study: Accessory Dwelling Units Now Legal Statewide, but Construction Still Lags</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/economic_opportunity/study-accessory-dwelling-units-now-legal-statewide-but-construction-still-lags/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;BOSTON – Even after statewide legalization in 2024, production of accessory dwelling units (ADUs) in Massachusetts remains far from that of other states due to local zoning and permitting practices that continue to discourage development, according to a new Pioneer Institute study. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/economic_opportunity/study-accessory-dwelling-units-now-legal-statewide-but-construction-still-lags/"&gt;Study: Accessory Dwelling Units Now Legal Statewide, but Construction Still Lags&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 12:51:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Statement From The James Madison Institute on the District Court Ruling in FTC v. Meta</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/statement-from-the-james-madison-institute-on-the-district-court-ruling-in-ftc-v-meta/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE November 19, 2025 CONTACT Nicole Kiser (850) 386-3131 TALLAHASSEE — Yesterday, the U.S. District Court...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/statement-from-the-james-madison-institute-on-the-district-court-ruling-in-ftc-v-meta/"&gt;Statement From The James Madison Institute on the District Court Ruling in FTC v. Meta&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 15:14:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Houston Supt. Mike Miles on Urban School District Reform</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/learning-curve/houston-supt-mike-miles-on-urban-school-district-reform/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In this week’s episode of The Learning Curve, co-hosts Great Heart Academies’ Dr. Helen Baxendale and American Federation for Children’s Shaka Mitchell speak with Mike Miles, superintendent of the Houston Independent School District. Miles has devoted his life to public service, starting as a soldier, then as a diplomat in Poland and Russia during the Cold War before moving into K-12 education reform. He discussed how his family background and early educational experiences shaped his commitment to service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/learning-curve/houston-supt-mike-miles-on-urban-school-district-reform/"&gt;Houston Supt. Mike Miles on Urban School District Reform&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 15:29:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Aaron Withe Statement on Trump Administration’s Bold Action to Dismantle Education Bureaucracy</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/education/aaron-withe-statement-on-trump-administrations-bold-action-to-dismantle-education-bureaucracy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Freedom Foundation CEO and Teacher Freedom Alliance President Aaron Withe issued the following statement regarding President Trump’s plans to dismantle the Department of Education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/education/aaron-withe-statement-on-trump-administrations-bold-action-to-dismantle-education-bureaucracy/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Aaron Withe Statement on Trump Administration&amp;#8217;s Bold Action to Dismantle Education Bureaucracy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 16:15:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Congress Must Act: Preempt State AI Patchwork to Fuel America’s—and Louisiana’s—Innovation Fire</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/congress-must-act-preempt-state-ai-patchwork-to-fuel-americas-and-louisianas-innovation-fire/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As the National Defense Authorization Act (NDAA) barrels toward a December showdown, House Republicans, led by Louisiana’s own Speaker Mike Johnson and Majority Leader Steve Scalise, are considering a much-needed moratorium on state AI regulations. This echoes President Donald J. Trump’s urgent X post: “Investment in AI is helping to make the U.S. Economy the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/congress-must-act-preempt-state-ai-patchwork-to-fuel-americas-and-louisianas-innovation-fire/"&gt;Congress Must Act: Preempt State AI Patchwork to Fuel America’s—and Louisiana’s—Innovation Fire&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 18:54:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Mississippi is globally recognized!</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/mississippi-is-globally-recognized/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/mississippi-is-globally-recognized/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi is globally recognized!&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 18:55:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Capital Young Professionals Gathering</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/capital-young-professionals-gathering/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;JMI, Red Hills Strategies, and Floridian Partners are back with another Capital Young Professionals Gathering on December 3....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/capital-young-professionals-gathering/"&gt;Capital Young Professionals Gathering&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 19:14:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] WILL Applauds Wisconsin Assembly for Passing Important Education Reforms</title><link>https://will-law.org/will-applauds-wisconsin-assembly-for-passing-important-education-reforms/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL applauded the Wisconsin State Assembly for its action in passing two important education reforms: the Wisconsin Teacher Bill of Rights (AB 614) and the Federal Scholarship Tax Credit Opt-in Bill (AB 602).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/will-applauds-wisconsin-assembly-for-passing-important-education-reforms/"&gt;WILL Applauds Wisconsin Assembly for Passing Important Education Reforms&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 21:42:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Shifting Costs Does Not Solve California’s Electricity Shortages</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/shifting-costs-does-not-solve-californias-electricity-shortages/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=shifting-costs-does-not-solve-californias-electricity-shortages</link><description>&lt;p&gt;California’s Little Hoover Commission was created in 1962 “as an independent and bipartisan state agency charged with making recommendations to the governor and Legislature on ways to make state programs more efficient.” Funded by taxpayers, officially nonpartisan, they’ve just released a set of recommendations to lower “The High Cost of Electricity in California.” They’re right about the high...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/shifting-costs-does-not-solve-californias-electricity-shortages/"&gt;Shifting Costs Does Not Solve California’s Electricity Shortages&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 04:03:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Republican candidates join nationwide scrutiny of tenure</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/republican-candidates-join-nationwide-scrutiny-of-tenure/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Republican candidates for Wisconsin governor are joining politicians across the country who are increasingly skeptical of tenure guarantees for professors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/republican-candidates-join-nationwide-scrutiny-of-tenure/"&gt;Republican candidates join nationwide scrutiny of tenure&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 11:07:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Wisconsin DPI mired in one scandal after another</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/wisconsin-dpi-mired-in-one-scandal-after-another/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Wisconsin Department of Public Instruction is facing a crisis of confidence after accusations of gutting academic standards, manipulating report cards, slacking on fiscal oversight and bungling oversight of sexual misconduct among teachers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/wisconsin-dpi-mired-in-one-scandal-after-another/"&gt;Wisconsin DPI mired in one scandal after another&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 12:16:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Newly Retired NYPD Retirees Average $100,000+ in Pension</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/newly-retired-nypd-retirees-average-100000-in-pension/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Newly retired1 “full career”2 members of the New York Police Department (NYPD) collected an average of $103,859, according to new....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/newly-retired-nypd-retirees-average-100000-in-pension/"&gt;Newly Retired NYPD Retirees Average $100,000+ in Pension&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 14:07:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] “Inspire Oregon” Tackles Rural Housing Crisis</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/land-use/inspire-oregon-tackles-rural-housing-crisis/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Madilynne Clark The University of Oregon’s Institute for Policy Research and Engagement...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/land-use/inspire-oregon-tackles-rural-housing-crisis/"&gt;“Inspire Oregon” Tackles Rural Housing Crisis&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Maine Human Rights Commission’s New Lawsuit a State-Level Battle in a National Storm</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/maine-human-rights-commissions-new-lawsuit-a-state-level-battle-in-a-national-storm/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On November 17, the Maine Human Rights Commission (MHRC) filed suit against five school systems, MSAD 70, RSU 24, RSU 73, Baileyville and Richmond, arguing that their recently enacted “biological sex” policies violate the Maine Human Rights Act (MHRA). The Commission is suing on its own authority, not through the Attorney General, and its core [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/maine-human-rights-commissions-new-lawsuit-a-state-level-battle-in-a-national-storm/"&gt;Maine Human Rights Commission’s New Lawsuit a State-Level Battle in a National Storm&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 17:27:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] BEAD the Call: What the First Four Years of BEAD can Teach Us</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/bead-the-call-what-the-first-four-years-of-bead-can-teach-us/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Broadband Equity Access and Deployment program (BEAD) has followed a long and winding road since its inception in 2021. Nationally, the final approval process for receiving BEAD funding is still ongoing, but one takeaway has become evident: competition and innovation, not red tape regulations, are the key to unlocking fast and accessible internet. Louisiana...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/bead-the-call-what-the-first-four-years-of-bead-can-teach-us/"&gt;BEAD the Call: What the First Four Years of BEAD can Teach Us&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 17:36:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/11/the-outstater-306/</link><description>Redistricting Disassembled O, beware, my lord, of jealousy;It is the green-eyed monster, which doth mockThe meat it feeds on.&amp;#8221; (Othello 3.3.165-167)  THERE IS A WAY to make sense of the Republican rift over redistricting. You start by eliminating all the stated explanations: Which leaves us with what is at the heart of every political story —&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/11/the-outstater-306/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 19:21:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Tennessee Tax System &amp; Reform Efforts Webinar</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/tennessee-tax-system-reform-efforts-webinar/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=tennessee-tax-system-reform-efforts-webinar</link><description>Join the Beacon Center for a timely discussion on Tennessee’s tax system, ongoing reform efforts, and how tax policy impacts families, workers, and businesses across the state. We’ll be joined by a panel of experts: Carey Bringle, Nashville business owner Patrick Gleason, Americans for Tax Reform, Beacon Senior Fellow for Tax Policy Justin Owen, CEO,...</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 20:38:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Civics Education Update</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/civics-education-update/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=civics-education-update</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The latest news on history, civics, and patriotism in our public schools is a mixed bag. In the early days of our republic, George Washington understood that civic education was essential for preserving freedom. More recently, the late Supreme Court Justice Sandra Day O’Connor reminded us that civic knowledge isn’t inherited genetically but must be...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/civics-education-update/"&gt;Civics Education Update&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 22:24:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] What the Government Shutdown Was Really About with Elias Tsapelas</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/health-care/what-the-government-shutdown-was-really-about-with-elias-tsapelas/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Susan Pendergrass is joined by Elias Tsapelas, director of state budget and fiscal policy at the Show-Me Institute, to explain [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/health-care/what-the-government-shutdown-was-really-about-with-elias-tsapelas/"&gt;What the Government Shutdown Was Really About with Elias Tsapelas&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 22:31:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] MSPC Welcomes Scholar Rob Natelson as Senior Fellow in Constitutional Jurisprudence</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/mspc-welcomes-scholar-robert-g-natelson-as-senior-fellow-in-constitutional-jurisprudence</link><description>One of America’s most respected constitutional scholars, his addition represents a major advance for MSPC and significantly expands the organization’s legal and constitutional research capacity.</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 04:26:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Hayek Saw It Coming: Why Centralized Education Was Destined to Fail</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/hayek-saw-it-coming-why-centralized-education-was-destined-to-fail/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;“The Department of Education is being torn apart in real time,” the New York Times declared this week. The Trump administration has kicked off the boldest federal education shake-up in 45 years, carving up its core functions across Labor, State, Interior, and HHS. To understand why this was inevitable, we must go back to the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/hayek-saw-it-coming-why-centralized-education-was-destined-to-fail/"&gt;Hayek Saw It Coming: Why Centralized Education Was Destined to Fail&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 13:50:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/11/the-outstater-307/</link><description>Our Cultural Disconnect WITH THE 250th ANNIVERSARY&amp;#160;of the Declaration of Independence ahead of us, we asked our&amp;#160;assistant, Grok, to review recent polling on what American youth know about this founding document. I leave the results with you to decide whether we have reached a state of total cultural disconnection: The Annenberg Public Policy Center’s Civics&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/11/the-outstater-307/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 13:59:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] AI Cuts School Paperwork and Puts Time Back Into Teaching</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/ai-cuts-school-paperwork-and-puts-time-back-into-teaching/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Sebastian Girstl Efficiency is a core principle that drives progress, yet this idea has often not received the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/ai-cuts-school-paperwork-and-puts-time-back-into-teaching/"&gt;AI Cuts School Paperwork and Puts Time Back Into Teaching&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 14:31:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Preserve Lahaina’s charm, waive overhead encroachment rules</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/11/preserve-lahainas-charm-waive-overhead-encroachment-rules/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Maui County Council on Nov. 21, 2025._____________ Nov. 21, 2025, 9 a.m.Kalana O Maui Building To: Maui County Council       Alice Lee, Chair       Yuki Lei Sugimura, Vice-Chair From: Grassroot Institute of Hawaii            Jonathan Helton, Policy Analyst Re: Bill 156 (2025) — [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/11/preserve-lahainas-charm-waive-overhead-encroachment-rules/"&gt;Preserve Lahaina&amp;#8217;s charm, waive overhead encroachment rules&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 16:00:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Property tax reform won’t reduce student achievement</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/property-tax-reform-student-achievement/</link><description>Kansas Representative Shannon Francis (R-Liberal) told KSNT-TV that he thinks higher property taxes may be bringing people to Kansas. He said higher property taxes have led to investment in schools, and that, as a result, “Kansas schools are a lot better than Oklahoma.” It may be intuitive to think that more spending translates to better [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 16:03:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Grassroot testimonies submitted in November 2025</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/11/grassroot-testimonies-submitted-in-november-2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following are testimonies submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii over the past few weeks for consideration by the Hawai‘i, Honolulu and Maui county councils, plus the state&amp;#8217;s Simplifying Permitting for Enhanced Economic Development Task Force: HAWAI‘I COUNTY &amp;#62;&amp;#62;&amp;#160;Bill 52 (2025)&amp;#160;— “Let household hennery owners sell their produce for extra income” and “Allow Hawaii [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/11/grassroot-testimonies-submitted-in-november-2025/"&gt;Grassroot testimonies submitted in November 2025&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 16:10:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Week in Review: Union Members Only? Nope.</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-union-members-only-nope/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When people apply for government jobs, they should be judged on their merits and their ability to do the work...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-union-members-only-nope/"&gt;Week in Review: Union Members Only? Nope.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 18:23:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Connecticut Cannot Solve Its Housing Crisis While Ignoring Union-Driven Costs</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/11/21/connecticut-cannot-solve-its-housing-crisis-while-ignoring-union-driven-costs/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Connecticut’s 2025 State of Housing Conference on Nov. 17 and 18, one panel stood out for all the wrong reasons. The session titled “Union-Built Affordable Housing” was billed as [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/11/21/connecticut-cannot-solve-its-housing-crisis-while-ignoring-union-driven-costs/"&gt;Connecticut Cannot Solve Its Housing Crisis While Ignoring Union-Driven Costs&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 19:01:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] New National Debt Analysis Offers Fresh Lens for Missouri’s Fiscal Picture</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/budget-and-spending/new-national-debt-analysis-offers-fresh-lens-for-missouris-fiscal-picture/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, I wrote about the annual rating by Truth in Accounting (TIA), which found that Missouri earned a [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/budget-and-spending/new-national-debt-analysis-offers-fresh-lens-for-missouris-fiscal-picture/"&gt;New National Debt Analysis Offers Fresh Lens for Missouri’s Fiscal Picture&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 21:14:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Winners &amp; Losers: Foreign Terrorists, College Degrees, Texas FEMA &amp; Jelly Roll</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/winners-losers-foreign-terrorists-college-degrees-texas-fema-jelly-roll/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Every Friday morning, I join the Cardle &amp;#38; Woolley Show on Talk 1370 Radio in Austin to announce the week’s Winners &amp;#38; Losers. While the congressional map wars continue and would-be candidates wait for the smoke to clear, here’s who made the list: WINNER: Gov. Greg Abbott Goes After Muslim Extremists in Texas After recent...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/winners-losers-foreign-terrorists-college-degrees-texas-fema-jelly-roll/"&gt;Winners &amp; Losers: Foreign Terrorists, College Degrees, Texas FEMA &amp; Jelly Roll&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 22:25:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Ending Bureaucratic Excess in Idaho</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/ending-bureaucratic-excess-in-idaho/</link><description>It’s no exaggeration to say that Idaho taxpayers spend millions of dollars every single day on wasteful and sometimes unconstitutional state-run programs. The Idaho Freedom Foundation’s (IFF) goal is to find and eliminate as many of these programs as possible. To this end, the IFF has submitted recommendations on wasteful spending to the state-level DOGE [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 01:01:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] America is Turning 250, but Debt is Pushing Independence Away</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/america-is-turning-250-but-debt-is-pushing-independence-away/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="America is Turning 250, but Debt is Pushing Independence Away" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/national-debt.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The U.S. is preparing to celebrate the 250th anniversary of the Declaration of Independence, yet rising national debt and dependence on foreign supply chains, especially China, threaten America’s economic independence.&lt;br /&gt;
Without major reforms, the U.S. faces soaring interest costs, impending insolvency in major entitlement programs, and reduced federal support for states, including Iowa, which relies heavily on federal funds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/america-is-turning-250-but-debt-is-pushing-independence-away/"&gt;America is Turning 250, but Debt is Pushing Independence Away&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 14:52:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Week in Review: Stopping Idaho's Spending Spree</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/week-in-review-stopping-idahos-spending-spree/</link><description>The Idaho state budget is out of control, and it is the Idaho Freedom Foundation’s duty to the citizens of this state to fight big government spending wherever and whenever possible. Even after accounting for the governor’s three percent holdback, agencies have still requested $14.5 billion for government operations in fiscal year 2027. This is [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 21:38:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Let nurse practitioners do their jobs</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/let-nurse-practitioners-do-their-jobs</link><description>Michigan is one of only 11 states severely restricting their practice</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] SCC Notes Growing Cost of VCEA Compliance,Rejects One Project, Makes a Second Contingent</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/scc-notes-growing-cost-of-vcea-compliancerejects-one-project-makes-a-second-contingent/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="720" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/Compliance-Costs-for-Virginia-Clean-Energy-Act-v2.jpg" width="1280" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Citing the high cost, the Virginia State Corporation Commission on Friday denied a request to add a battery project to the Appalachian Power Company grid. In the same&amp;#160;decision, an out-of-state wind project for Appalachian was approved, but only if it qualifies for major federal tax credits to keep down the cost. &amp;#160; Without those tax [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/scc-notes-growing-cost-of-vcea-compliancerejects-one-project-makes-a-second-contingent/"&gt;SCC Notes Growing Cost of VCEA Compliance,Rejects One Project, Makes a Second Contingent&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 12:55:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Are farm incomes bountiful or withering on the vine?</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/are-farm-incomes-bountiful-or-withering-on-the-vine</link><description>Farmers across the nation are unlikely to be taking a check to the bank at the end of harvest - at least not checks big enough to cover their debt payments. But the government’s so-called remedies are a lesson in contradiction. As statistics refute themselves, regulations harm more than protect, and trade barriers exasperate challenges facing domestic producers, the government’s role in farming is only adding to the red.   Government data ineptly grasps the financial condition facing farmers....</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 15:19:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Iowa Still Winning the Tax Rivalry with Nebraska</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/iowa-still-winning-the-tax-rivalry-with-nebraska/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Iowa Still Winning the Tax Rivalry with Nebraska" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/iowa-nebraska.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iowa outperforms Nebraska on tax policy, climbing rapidly in national competitiveness rankings thanks to major tax reforms, while Nebraska continues to lag behind in several key categories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iowa’s pro-growth tax “playbook”—including a flat 3.8% income tax, elimination of retirement income and inheritance taxes—has strengthened its economic position and attracted migration from neighboring states like Nebraska.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite Iowa’s strong lead, vulnerabilities such as high property taxes remain, underscoring the need for continued reform to maintain Iowa’s competitive edge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/iowa-still-winning-the-tax-rivalry-with-nebraska/"&gt;Iowa Still Winning the Tax Rivalry with Nebraska&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 17:57:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Trouble on the Right – Why Conservatives Need to be Wary</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/trouble-on-the-right-why-conservatives-need-to-be-wary/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I only recently learned what a “groyper” is - you may or may not be familiar with the term?&amp;#160;From what I can tell, a groyper is a hardline white nationalist.&amp;#160; Often anti-Semitic, groypers are hostile to mainstream conservatives.&amp;#160; To the extent they have a coherent agenda, groypers seem more national socialism than free-market capitalism.&amp;#160;Having been [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/trouble-on-the-right-why-conservatives-need-to-be-wary/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Trouble on the Right – Why Conservatives Need to be Wary&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 18:29:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] A Healthy Dose Of Competition Sends Weight-Loss Drug Prices Plummeting</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/a-healthy-dose-of-competition-sends-weight-loss-drug-prices-plummeting/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Prices for GLP-1 weight-loss medications are dropping fast. Last week, Novo Nordisk—maker of Ozempic and Wegovy—announced it would cut prices for monthly supplies of both drugs to as low as $349 for existing patients buying directly. For new customers, the price will fall to just $199 a month for the first two months. The move [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/a-healthy-dose-of-competition-sends-weight-loss-drug-prices-plummeting/"&gt;A Healthy Dose Of Competition Sends Weight-Loss Drug Prices Plummeting&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 19:06:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] State-funded marketing is not the answer to low tourist turnout</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/11/state-funded-marketing-is-not-the-answer-to-low-tourist-turnout/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When you make it difficult for people to visit you, they tend to take the hint and stop coming. That’s a good strategy for dealing with unwanted houseguests, but not the smartest move for a state that depends on visitor dollars to fuel its economy. Hawaii already has some of the highest visitor taxes in [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/11/state-funded-marketing-is-not-the-answer-to-low-tourist-turnout/"&gt;State-funded marketing is not the answer to low tourist turnout&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 20:05:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Parents’ Bill of Rights Ends They/Them Fight</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/parents-bill-of-rights-ends-they-them-fight/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;An enterprising reporter at the New York Post never believed the FBI when it said that Thomas Crooks, the 20-year-old young man who shot President Donald Trump in Butler, Pennsylvania, didn’t have a social media footprint. She kept digging and found that Crooks was hanging out in some dark corners of the Internet and had...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/parents-bill-of-rights-ends-they-them-fight/"&gt;Parents’ Bill of Rights Ends They/Them Fight&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 20:48:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Goldwater to Arizona Supreme Court: Rein in Phoenix’s Union Negotiation Secrecy</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/goldwater-to-arizona-supreme-court-rein-in-phoenixs-union-negotiation-secrecy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When the government negotiates with labor unions, it’s supposed to be doing so on the public’s behalf. After all, it’s negotiating contract terms for..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/goldwater-to-arizona-supreme-court-rein-in-phoenixs-union-negotiation-secrecy/"&gt;Goldwater to Arizona Supreme Court: Rein in Phoenix’s Union Negotiation Secrecy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 21:02:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Defending Donor Privacy from the IRS</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/defending-donor-privacy-from-the-irs/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Goldwater Institute today joined forces with our friends at the Rio Grande Foundation and the National Federation of Independent..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/defending-donor-privacy-from-the-irs/"&gt;Defending Donor Privacy from the IRS&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 21:50:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] LA apartment builders pull back as bureaucracy, taxes take toll</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/la-apartment-builders-pull-back-as-bureaucracy-taxes-take-toll/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;LA apartment builders pull back as bureaucracy, taxes take toll By Kerry Jackson &amp;#124; November 25, 2025 Los Angeles needs more apartments. No one will argue otherwise. Developers want to build more units to meet the demand. It’s what they do. But not in Los Angeles. A third party that should play the role of facilitator that [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/la-apartment-builders-pull-back-as-bureaucracy-taxes-take-toll/"&gt;LA apartment builders pull back as bureaucracy, taxes take toll&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 10:16:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Indiana's 201% cigarette tax hike will fuel smuggling, not just revenue</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/indianas-201-cigarette-tax-hike-will-fuel-smuggling-not-just-revenue</link><description>Some smokers will quit, but many others will engage in tax avoidance and evasion</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 10:35:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Warren makes millions on Wall Street while decrying the rich</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/warren-makes-millions-on-wall-street-while-decrying-the-rich/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Paul Sperry writes for the Federalist about another example of political hypocrisy. When Sen. Elizabeth A. Warren recently traveled to the Big Apple to endorse New York City mayoral candidate Zohran Mamdani, she was asked if overt socialism is really the best model for Democrats to adopt. “You bet,” she replied in her signature folksy...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/warren-makes-millions-on-wall-street-while-decrying-the-rich/"&gt;Warren makes millions on Wall Street while decrying the rich&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 10:39:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Clintons face legal peril if they ignore Epstein subpoenas</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/clintons-face-legal-peril-if-they-ignore-epstein-subpoenas/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Matt Margolis writes for PJMedia.com about a legal challenge for a former president and his high-profile wife. House Oversight Committee Chairman James Comer is laying down the law for Bill and Hillary Clinton: show up in person for depositions in the Jeffrey Epstein sex trafficking investigation, or face prison. Comer warned the former president and...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/clintons-face-legal-peril-if-they-ignore-epstein-subpoenas/"&gt;Clintons face legal peril if they ignore Epstein subpoenas&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 10:42:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Lech Walesa jumped a fence and changed history</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/lech-walesa-jumped-a-fence-and-changed-history</link><description>‘There can be no bread without freedom’</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Illinois students could boost ACT scores with scholarships</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/illinois-students-could-boost-act-scores-with-scholarships/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Federal scholarships could give low-income students access to ACT tutors and study materials to help them improve on the college exam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/illinois-students-could-boost-act-scores-with-scholarships/"&gt;Illinois students could boost ACT scores with scholarships&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 11:00:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Blacker Friday: Illinois shoppers face sales tax hit</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/blacker-friday-illinois-shoppers-face-sales-tax-hit/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Holiday shoppers are eager to spend this year. Illinois is overly eager to tax them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/blacker-friday-illinois-shoppers-face-sales-tax-hit/"&gt;Blacker Friday: Illinois shoppers face sales tax hit&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 11:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/11/the-outstater-308/</link><description>A Social Contract: Health and Human Capital &amp;#8216;SALUS POPULI&amp;#160;suprema lex esto” (Let the health of the people be the supreme law) was Cicero’s test of&amp;#160;good&amp;#160;government. It is the core social contract of our society, both the justification and the limit of state power. But an adjunct of this foundation, Dr. Berry Keating, will argue in&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/11/the-outstater-308/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:34:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] From Pilgrims to Property Taxes</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/from-pilgrims-to-property-taxes/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="From Pilgrims to Property Taxes" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/plymouth-plantation.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;America’s earliest settlers believed government existed only to protect natural rights—especially property—not to manage society. Families, churches, and communities handled most social needs through voluntary cooperation, cultivating a citizenry capable of self-rule.&lt;br /&gt;
This founding worldview clashes with today’s rising property-tax burdens. Drawing on John Locke’s social-contract theory, the article argues that when government taxes away the fruits of a family’s labor or threatens their ability to stay in their home, it violates the very purpose for which government was created.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/from-pilgrims-to-property-taxes/"&gt;From Pilgrims to Property Taxes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 13:35:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] NEW POLL: Louisiana Voters Call for Fiscal Restraint, Bold Tax Reforms, and Expanded School Choice as Costs Rise; Thanksgiving Traditions Add Flavor to Findings</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/press-release/new-poll-louisiana-voters-call-for-fiscal-restraint-bold-tax-reforms-and-expanded-school-choice-as-costs-rise-thanksgiving-traditions-add-flavor-to-findings/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As families across Louisiana prepare to gather for Thanksgiving, the Pelican Institute for Public Policy today released its latest Pelican Pulse poll, revealing strong voter demand for a leaner state government, deeper tax relief, and greater education options. The statewide survey shows clear support for solutions to curb spending, tackle lawsuit abuse, and empower families—while...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/press-release/new-poll-louisiana-voters-call-for-fiscal-restraint-bold-tax-reforms-and-expanded-school-choice-as-costs-rise-thanksgiving-traditions-add-flavor-to-findings/"&gt;NEW POLL: Louisiana Voters Call for Fiscal Restraint, Bold Tax Reforms, and Expanded School Choice as Costs Rise; Thanksgiving Traditions Add Flavor to Findings&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 13:49:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Our region leads on tax competitiveness, with one glaring exception</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/our-region-leads-on-tax-competitiveness-with-one-glaring-exception</link><description>Our region boasts three states in the top 10 for having the most competitive tax structure, according to the Tax Foundation. The latest numbers show that Wyoming is the most taxpayer-friendly state, Montana is 6th, and Idaho is 9th. While this is impressive, Washington coming in near last at 45th is cause for concern.   The Tax Foundation's  State Competitiveness Index  reveals which states are taxpayer-friendly for both individuals and businesses. States are ranked based on income, sales,...</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 15:14:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Here’s why buying an Illinois home can be hard</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/heres-why-buying-an-illinois-home-can-be-hard/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Illinois home prices have jumped nearly 50% since 2018 while available housing hasn’t recovered since the pandemic, creating a housing shortage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/heres-why-buying-an-illinois-home-can-be-hard/"&gt;Here’s why buying an Illinois home can be hard&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 15:46:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Eliminating Missouri’s Income Tax, Subsidies for Gas Stations, and Early Literacy Reform</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/economy/eliminating-missouris-income-tax-subsidies-for-gas-stations-and-early-literacy-reform/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;David Stokes, Elias Tsapelas, and Avery Frank join host Zach Lawhorn to outline what a responsible plan to eliminate Missouri’s [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/economy/eliminating-missouris-income-tax-subsidies-for-gas-stations-and-early-literacy-reform/"&gt;Eliminating Missouri’s Income Tax, Subsidies for Gas Stations, and Early Literacy Reform&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 16:34:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Lowering the bar on proficiency standards is a frightening fad sweeping public education</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/states-lowering-proficiency-standards/</link><description>State education administrators often say,  “It’s all about the kids,” yet their actions suggest it’s more about protecting adult reputations than improving student outcomes. They all want students to do better, but not if it means adults changing their behavior to make it happen. The most recent example of this is lowering the bar on [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 17:21:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] From Obamacare To Credit Cards, Price Controls Don’t Work</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/business-policy-from-obamacare-to-credit-cards-price-controls-dont-work/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The House of Representatives just passed a resolution condemning the “horrors of socialism” by a 285 to 98 margin. All the no votes were cast by Democrats indicating that a majority of the members from the left side of the aisle fail to recognize socialism’s overwhelming failures. Thus, despite the House’s clear rejection of socialism, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/business-policy-from-obamacare-to-credit-cards-price-controls-dont-work/"&gt;From Obamacare To Credit Cards, Price Controls Don’t Work&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 18:13:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Sen. Rod Hickman: Rural revitalization, public safety, and education opportunity</title><link>https://empowerms.org/sen-rod-hickman-rural-revitalization-public-safety-and-education-opportunity/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Sen. Rod Hickman: Rural revitalization, public safety, and education opportunity On this episode of The Empower Podcast, host Grant Callen sits down with Mississippi State Senator Rod Hickman, a lawyer, educator, and public servant representing a stretch of communities across East Mississippi from Macon to Louisville to Meridian. Sen. Hickman shares how growing up in&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/sen-rod-hickman-rural-revitalization-public-safety-and-education-opportunity/"&gt;Sen. Rod Hickman: Rural revitalization, public safety, and education opportunity&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 18:48:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Xcel knows that coal matters, but only in Colorado</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/xcel-knows-that-coal-matters-but-only-in-colorado/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This month, Xcel Energy asked state regulators in Colorado to extend the operating life of the coal-fired Comanche Unit 2 for another year. Xcel Energy seems to understand the importance of coal in Colorado. What will it take for Xcel to recognize the same in Minnesota? Comanche Unit 2, sited in Pueblo, Colorado, with a...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/xcel-knows-that-coal-matters-but-only-in-colorado/"&gt;Xcel knows that coal matters, but only in Colorado&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 19:03:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG Expands Oversight and Legal Work with Hire of Kevin Zielinski as Associate Counsel</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-expands-oversight-and-legal-work-with-hire-of-kevin-zielinski-as-associate-counsel/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government (IRG) announced that Kevin Zielinski has joined the organization as Associate Counsel for Legal Reform &amp;#38; Oversight, expanding the IRG team to 9.5 employees. WHY IT MATTERS: In this role, Kevin will support IRG’s work to promote accountable, limited, and effective governance through legal research, oversight initiatives, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-expands-oversight-and-legal-work-with-hire-of-kevin-zielinski-as-associate-counsel/"&gt;IRG Expands Oversight and Legal Work with Hire of Kevin Zielinski as Associate Counsel&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 19:18:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Anatomy of a viral video: On our way to 5 million views</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/anatomy-of-a-viral-video-on-our-way-to-5-million-views/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Have you watched this video yet? Three million others have (and counting). American Experiment released the video last month to promote our recent report titled Shattered Green Dreams: The Environmental Costs of Wind and Solar. The goal of the video was to reach people who might be predisposed to believing the hype of green energy,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/anatomy-of-a-viral-video-on-our-way-to-5-million-views/"&gt;Anatomy of a viral video: On our way to 5 million views&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 19:22:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Minnesota Taxpayers Fund Terror Abroad</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/minnesota-taxpayers-fund-terror-abroad/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome back to the American Experiment Podcast! This week, Grace and Kathryn take a behind-the-scenes look at the breaking news of the week: Minnesota taxpayers have been funding terrorism abroad. Then, because of that shocking discovery, President Trump decides to end Somalia’s TPS (Temporary Protected Status)&amp;#8230;.and Representative Ilhan Omar is NOT happy about it. Next,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/minnesota-taxpayers-fund-terror-abroad/"&gt;Minnesota Taxpayers Fund Terror Abroad&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 20:24:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Explainer and Model Policies: Assembly Bill 495 and Parental Rights</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/explainer-and-model-policies-assembly-bill-495-and-parental-rights/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=explainer-and-model-policies-assembly-bill-495-and-parental-rights</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Assembly Bill 495 (Celeste Rodriguez, D &amp;#8211; San Fernando Valley) was passed by the legislature and signed into law by Governor Newsom, over the objections of many parental rights advocates, attorneys, and policy experts. This explainer breaks down the parts of the law that pose a potential threat to parental rights, and presents three model...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/explainer-and-model-policies-assembly-bill-495-and-parental-rights/"&gt;Explainer and Model Policies: Assembly Bill 495 and Parental Rights&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 20:46:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Decoding bureaucracy: how AI could aid regulatory reform</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/decoding-bureaucracy-how-ai-could-aid-regulatory-reform/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For decades, the image of government regulation has been synonymous with dusty, overflowing binders and legal jargon. State regulatory codes tend to accumulate year after year, sometimes contradicting themselves and complicating life for those navigating the process. This accumulation of &amp;#8220;red tape&amp;#8221; creates significant burdens for small business owners trying to remain compliant, citizens trying...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/decoding-bureaucracy-how-ai-could-aid-regulatory-reform/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Decoding bureaucracy: how AI could aid regulatory reform&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 21:18:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] WILL Plans to Protect Lawful Congressional Maps Already in Place</title><link>https://will-law.org/will-plans-to-protect-lawful-congressional-maps-already-in-place/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Wisconsin Supreme Court allowed two new legal challenges to the state’s congressional maps to continue forward by appointing two separate three-judge panels to hear the cases. The Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;#038; Liberty (WILL) had argued against such an appointment as any attempt to redraw the Congressional district lines in this manner would violate the U.S. Constitution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/will-plans-to-protect-lawful-congressional-maps-already-in-place/"&gt;WILL Plans to Protect Lawful Congressional Maps Already in Place&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 21:24:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Idaho's Federal Funding Comes With Strings Attached</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/idahos-federal-funding-comes-with-strings-attached/</link><description>Federal dollars allocated to the state can often feel like free money, but there is no such thing as a free lunch. Something cannot come from nothing. In Fiscal Year 2025 — the last year with available data — the federal government accounted for 37.2% of the state’s total budget. This adds up to over [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 21:44:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Want to pick your own traditional public school in NC? Move</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/want-to-pick-your-own-traditional-public-school-in-nc-move/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;North Carolina remains one of the worst states in the country when it comes to promoting choice among traditional public schools (i.e., not counting charter schools), according to a 2025 study from the Reason Foundation. As the John Locke Foundation has observed, North Carolina lags behind nearly all other states in offering open enrollment for...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/want-to-pick-your-own-traditional-public-school-in-nc-move/"&gt;Want to pick your own traditional public school in NC? Move&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 22:15:20 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>