<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>State-Policy Think-Tank Digest</title><link>https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml</link><description>Latest posts from free-market policy institutes across the U.S.</description><atom:link href="https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 05:12:11 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>[Libertas] A Year of Impact: 1.3+ Million Families</title><link>https://libertas.org/2025-report/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In early 2025 we set out an ambitious &amp;#8220;Vivid Vision&amp;#8221; for our team to grow our impact and scale up our work, and the end-of-year results demonstrate significant progress across all our initiatives. In total, we positively impacted more than 1.3 million families! Below, watch a 15-minute update sharing our 2025 impact, presented by our [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://libertas.org/2025-report/"&gt;A Year of Impact: 1.3+ Million Families&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://libertas.org"&gt;The Libertas Network: Changing Hearts, Minds, and Laws&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 01:49:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Rifreedom] Stenhouse Challenges Zurier’s Special Senate Energy Commission to “Act” on the Act On Climate</title><link>https://rifreedom.org/2026/01/stenhouse-challenges-zuriers-special-senate-energy-commission-to-act-on-the-act-on-climate/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;With "affordability" top of mind for Ocean State residents, the CEO of the RI Center for Freedom &amp;#038; Prosperity  today called upon  Senator  Sam Zurier  and all members of the special Senate Energy Commission he chairs to take a w holistic and realistic look at Rhode Island's net-zero policies and Act On Climate  mandates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org/2026/01/stenhouse-challenges-zuriers-special-senate-energy-commission-to-act-on-the-act-on-climate/"&gt;Stenhouse Challenges Zurier&amp;#8217;s Special Senate Energy Commission to &amp;#8220;Act&amp;#8221; on the Act On Climate&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org"&gt;RI Center for Freedom and Prosperity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 15:02:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Research Note: How Changes in AI Regulation Could Affect Nebraska</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/research-note-how-changes-in-ai-regulation-could-affect-nebraska/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of weeks before Christmas, following the President’s recent executive order on artificial intelligence (AI), the Nebraska Examiner published an article examining the potential implications for Nebraska. While the precise impact of the order remains uncertain, the state’s recent legislative activity related to AI suggests the possibility of conflict between state and federal approaches....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/research-note-how-changes-in-ai-regulation-could-affect-nebraska/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Research Note: How Changes in AI Regulation Could Affect Nebraska&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 15:05:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Happy New Year! A Blueprint for Mississippi in 2026!</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/happy-new-year-a-blueprint-for-mississippi-in-2026/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As we kick off 2026, the Mississippi Center for Public Policy is more energized than ever.&amp;#160;&amp;#160;We are excited about the successes our state has seen – and we have a plan to build on that momentum with further free market reform!&amp;#160;For decades, our state lagged behind.&amp;#160;&amp;#160;Growth was slow and too many young people left our [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/happy-new-year-a-blueprint-for-mississippi-in-2026/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Happy New Year! A Blueprint for Mississippi in 2026!&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 15:35:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Nebraska’s Tax Code Lets It Compete for Data Center Investment</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/nebraskas-tax-code-lets-it-compete-for-data-center-investment/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Midwest grows many things—including, increasingly, data centers. That’s good news, generating substantial local tax revenue, creating high-paying jobs, and expanding economic opportunities.  With 39 data centers (about 19 per 1 million people), Nebraska punches above its weight nationally, while trailing neighboring Iowa, which boasts the second-highest number of data centers per capita at 32...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/nebraskas-tax-code-lets-it-compete-for-data-center-investment/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Nebraska’s Tax Code Lets It Compete for Data Center Investment&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 17:26:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Shaping Georgia’s future: Opportunities for the year ahead</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/top-issues-shaping-georgia-future/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The well-being of many Georgians, their families, and their communities is at stake as pressing concerns like welfare reform, the cost of living, educational opportunities, and public safety take center stage in 2026. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/top-issues-shaping-georgia-future/"&gt;Shaping Georgia’s future: Opportunities for the year ahead&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 23:49:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] HB2 – Mississippi’s School Choice Bill is Here!</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/hb2-mississippis-school-choice-bill-is-here/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Last week, House Speaker Jason White unveiled&amp;#160;HB2, the&amp;#160;Mississippi Education Freedom Act - the most exciting and ambitious advancement for school choice in our state in years, perhaps ever!&amp;#160;This comprehensive bill delivers everything supporters of parental power have long hoped for, and it aligns perfectly with President Trump’s strong commitment to education freedom.&amp;#160;This isn’t some minor [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/hb2-mississippis-school-choice-bill-is-here/" rel="nofollow"&gt;HB2 – Mississippi’s School Choice Bill is Here!&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 17:31:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] In Cambridge, New Lawsuit Challenges Constitutionality of Mandatory Set-Asides for Affordable Housing</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/in-cambridge-new-lawsuit-challenges-constitutionality-of-mandatory-set-asides-for-affordable-housing/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This edition of The House Call describes a legal complaint alleging that Cambridge&amp;#8217;s inclusionary zoning ordinance, which requires set-asides for below-market-rate housing in new development, is a regulatory taking under the Fifth Amendment to the Constitution. It also describes a number of actions the Commonwealth...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/in-cambridge-new-lawsuit-challenges-constitutionality-of-mandatory-set-asides-for-affordable-housing/"&gt;In Cambridge, New Lawsuit Challenges Constitutionality of Mandatory Set-Asides for Affordable Housing&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 19:18:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] ABQ Journal opinion piece: More investigative journalism is a must</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/abq-journal-opinion-piece-more-investigative-journalism-is-a-must/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following appeared in Albuquerque Journal on January 11, 2026. The Albuquerque Journal recently made appeals on its pages for donations to increase investigative journalism efforts. Even though the Rio Grande Foundation is in direct competition for limited donor dollars, we applaud the paper for focusing attention on investigative journalism currently. The issue of investigative journalism is [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/abq-journal-opinion-piece-more-investigative-journalism-is-a-must/"&gt;ABQ Journal opinion piece: More investigative journalism is a must&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 19:54:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Idaho GOP calls for an end to taxpayer support for teachers unions</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/teachers-unions/idaho-gop-calls-for-an-end-to-taxpayer-support-for-teachers-unions/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As the 2026 Idaho legislature convenes, the Idaho Republican Party has adopted a resolution calling for the “passage of legislation to prohibit taxpayer support for teachers’ unions in all forms, direct or indirect," a key Freedom Foundation initiative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/teachers-unions/idaho-gop-calls-for-an-end-to-taxpayer-support-for-teachers-unions/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Idaho GOP calls for an end to taxpayer support for teachers unions&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:39:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] PPS to Remove References to “Black Students” from Naming of “Center for Black Student Excellence” at Jan. 13 Board Meeting</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/global-news/pps-to-remove-references-to-black-students-from-naming-of-center-for-black-student-excellence-at-jan-13-board-meeting/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;January 12, 2026 FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE Cascade Policy Institute4850 SW Scholls Ferry Rd.,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/global-news/pps-to-remove-references-to-black-students-from-naming-of-center-for-black-student-excellence-at-jan-13-board-meeting/"&gt;PPS to Remove References to &amp;#8220;Black Students&amp;#8221; from Naming of &amp;#8220;Center for Black Student Excellence&amp;#8221; at Jan. 13 Board Meeting&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:41:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Alternatives to New England’s Energy Affordability Crisis</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/01/13/alternatives-to-new-englands-energy-affordability-crisis/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Energy-Paper-2026.png" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New Englanders would save hundreds of billions of dollars and avoid deadly power blackouts by replacing state-mandated renewable energy projects with nuclear and natural gas power, a study released today [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/01/13/alternatives-to-new-englands-energy-affordability-crisis/"&gt;Alternatives to New England’s Energy Affordability Crisis&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 12:00:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Utah Education Association sued over claims dues don’t fund politics</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/labor/utah-education-association-sued-over-claims-dues-dont-fund-politics/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Freedom Foundation, together with Utah public school teacher and member of the Utah State Board of Education Cole Kelley, has filed a lawsuit against the Utah Education Association for falsely claiming its members’ dues are not used to fund political activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/labor/utah-education-association-sued-over-claims-dues-dont-fund-politics/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Utah Education Association sued over claims dues don’t fund politics&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 12:01:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Rifreedom] NEW REPORT PROVIDES ALTERNATIVES TO RHODE ISLAND’S SUICIDAL ACT ON CLIMATE POLICIES</title><link>https://rifreedom.org/2026/01/new-report-provides-alternatives-to-rhode-islands-suicidal-act-on-climate-policies/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New Englanders would save hundreds of billions of dollars and avoid deadly power blackouts by replacing state-mandated renewable energy projects with nuclear and natural gas power, a study released today by a coalition of New England think tanks finds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alternatives to New England’s Energy Suicide, released by New England’s free-market think tanks along with Americans for Prosperity Foundation, estimated the effects of trying to meet the region’s energy needs through 2050 with nuclear and natural gas plants instead of wind and solar power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org/2026/01/new-report-provides-alternatives-to-rhode-islands-suicidal-act-on-climate-policies/"&gt;NEW REPORT PROVIDES ALTERNATIVES TO RHODE ISLAND&amp;#8217;S SUICIDAL ACT ON CLIMATE POLICIES&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org"&gt;RI Center for Freedom and Prosperity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 13:49:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2026/01/the-outstater-320/</link><description>Graduation for Graduation&amp;#8217;s Sake SOMETHING STRUCK ME&amp;#160;wrong about all the Indiana public school districts this week touting increases in their graduation rates. Shouldn’t we be worried about what is being graduated?&amp;#160; Civic&amp;#160;education, for instance.&amp;#160;Gallup tell us that only 41 percent of those born after 1997 are proud to be an American compared with 83 percent&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2026/01/the-outstater-320/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 14:11:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] New Englanders would save hundreds of billions of dollars by replacing mandated renewable energy with nuclear and natural gas</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2026/01/new-englanders-would-save-hundreds-of-billions-of-dollars-by-replacing-mandated-renewable-energy-with-nuclear-and-natural-gas/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New Englanders would save hundreds of billions of dollars and avoid deadly power blackouts by replacing state-mandated renewable energy projects with nuclear and natural gas power, a study released today by a coalition of New England think tanks finds. Alternatives to New England&amp;#8217;s Affordability Crisis, a new study released by a coalition of New England’s [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2026/01/new-englanders-would-save-hundreds-of-billions-of-dollars-by-replacing-mandated-renewable-energy-with-nuclear-and-natural-gas/"&gt;New Englanders would save hundreds of billions of dollars by replacing mandated renewable energy with nuclear and natural gas&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 17:26:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cardinalinstitute] A Conversation with Charles Mitchell</title><link>https://cardinalinstitute.com/a-conversation-with-charles-mitchell/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A Conversation with Charles Mitchell David and Laura Thayer Visiting Fellow, Cardinal Institute Editor’s Note: The Cardinal Institute is pleased to announce that Charles Mitchell, former CEO of the Commonwealth Foundation, has joined Cardinal as the David B. and Laura Thayer Visiting Fellow. Charles brings decades of national leadership experience in the conservative, free-market think [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com/a-conversation-with-charles-mitchell/"&gt;A Conversation with Charles Mitchell&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com"&gt;Cardinal Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 14:43:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] ABQ Ethics Board Dismisses frivolous “sweatshirt-gate” ethics complaint made by Keller campaign against RGF’s Paul Gessing</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/abq-ethics-board-dismisses-frivolous-sweatshirt-gate-ethics-complaint-made-by-keller-campaign-against-rgfs-paul-gessing/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This afternoon in a hearing, the Albuquerque Board of Ethics (BOE) unanimously dismissed a complaint filed by Daymon Ely for the Tim Keller campaign that was made against Rio Grande Foundation president Paul Gessing. The complaint arose out of the Foundation’s reporting over the purchase and delivery of yellow hoodie sweatshirts to members of Albuquerque’s [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/abq-ethics-board-dismisses-frivolous-sweatshirt-gate-ethics-complaint-made-by-keller-campaign-against-rgfs-paul-gessing/"&gt;ABQ Ethics Board Dismisses frivolous “sweatshirt-gate” ethics complaint made by Keller campaign against RGF’s Paul Gessing&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 22:08:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cardinalinstitute] 2026 State of the State Response</title><link>https://cardinalinstitute.com/2026-state-of-the-state-response/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;2026 State of the State Response On Wednesday evening, Governor Patrick Morrisey delivered his annual State of the State address, outlining his priorities for the year ahead and offering a window into his governing philosophy. As is customary, the speech functioned as both pep rally and agenda-setting exercise. State of the state addresses tend to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com/2026-state-of-the-state-response/"&gt;2026 State of the State Response&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com"&gt;Cardinal Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 15:07:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF opinion piece: Data centers are coming: How to handle them</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-opinion-piece-data-centers-are-coming-how-to-handle-them/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following appeared in the Santa Fe New Mexican on January 10, 2026. It has appeared in several other publications as well. &amp;#160; After years of failure to land a “big fish” business for New Mexico’s economy (or effectively use the oil and gas revenues to grow the economy) Gov. Michelle Lujan Grisham, with the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-opinion-piece-data-centers-are-coming-how-to-handle-them/"&gt;RGF opinion piece: Data centers are coming: How to handle them&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 15:48:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Empire Center Warns of Sharp Increase in New York Electricity Prices</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/empire-center-warns-of-sharp-increase-in-new-york-electricity-prices/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New York households pay some of the highest electricity prices in the nation, raising affordability concerns, according to the Empire....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/empire-center-warns-of-sharp-increase-in-new-york-electricity-prices/"&gt;Empire Center Warns of Sharp Increase in New York Electricity Prices&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 15:51:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Pine Tree Pulse, Episode 77: Jonathan Bush</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/pine-tree-pulse-episode-77-jonathan-bush/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Jonathan Bush, Republican candidate for governor of Maine, recently sat down with Maine Policy CEO Matt Gagnon and Policy Analyst Harris Van Pate at MPI headquarters to discuss the 2026 gubernatorial campaign, and his story. Bush is a technology entrepreneur, best known as the cofounder and former chief executive officer of athenahealth, a healthcare technology [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/pine-tree-pulse-episode-77-jonathan-bush/"&gt;Pine Tree Pulse, Episode 77: Jonathan Bush&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 17:21:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] A state takeover of Education Freedom Account administration would increase program costs</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2026/01/a-state-takeover-of-education-freedom-accounts-would-increase-program-costs/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Opponents of New Hampshire’s Education Freedom Account (EFA) program have always claimed its administration costs were too high. Yet a proposal from EFA critics to fold the program into the Education Department would increase administrative costs and allow them to grow unchecked. Currently, the state contracts with a non-profit charity, the Children’s Scholarship Fund-New Hampshire [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2026/01/a-state-takeover-of-education-freedom-accounts-would-increase-program-costs/"&gt;A state takeover of Education Freedom Account administration would increase program costs&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 16:07:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Florida Politics: Florida’s AI Laws Are Stronger Than You Think</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/florida-politics-floridas-ai-laws-are-stronger-than-you-think/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As Florida’s 2026 Legislative Session approaches, artificial intelligence is expected to be a major focus among Tallahassee’s policymakers....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/florida-politics-floridas-ai-laws-are-stronger-than-you-think/"&gt;Florida Politics: Florida’s AI Laws Are Stronger Than You Think&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 16:13:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Newsom Has His Own Massive State Fraud Problem</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/newsom-has-his-own-massive-state-fraud-problem/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=newsom-has-his-own-massive-state-fraud-problem</link><description>&lt;p&gt;California’s scandal dwarfs Minnesota’s. Tim Walz perp-walked himself out of the Minnesota governor’s race this past week, beset by evidence that fraudsters have plundered his state’s federally funded food, housing, daycare, and Medicaid programs. It’s “what has been described as the nation’s largest COVID-era scheme,” says Fox News, with the U.S. attorney in Minnesota estimating “the fraud...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/newsom-has-his-own-massive-state-fraud-problem/"&gt;Newsom Has His Own Massive State Fraud Problem&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 16:52:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Alleged savings from the proposed Wichita sales tax are based on flawed assumptions and won’t materialize</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/savings-wichita-sales-tax-wont-materialize/</link><description>Believe it or not, Wichita voters are being told they will pay lower taxes overall if they vote for a new 1% sales tax. Yes, you read that correctly; the message is ‘Pay more taxes so you can pay less tax.’ That’s the essence of the pitch the City of Wichita is making to encourage [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 18:42:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] The SEBAC ‘Concessions’ Narrative Collapses Under Its Own Accounting</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/01/16/the-sebac-concessions-narrative-collapses-under-its-own-accounting/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For nearly a decade, Connecticut officials have pointed to the 2017 SEBAC agreement as evidence that fiscal responsibility and political compromise can coexist. The deal, negotiated by the Malloy administration [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/01/16/the-sebac-concessions-narrative-collapses-under-its-own-accounting/"&gt;The SEBAC ‘Concessions’ Narrative Collapses Under Its Own Accounting&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 19:02:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2026/01/the-outstater-321/</link><description>Childcare and Charitable Exhaustion THE PROPHETS WARN&amp;#160;that the devil loves an impossible task. A newsroom corollary is that corruption follows an inarguable good. Both apply to the challenge of caring for children in troubled homes due to poverty, emotional crisis or the myriad snares of modern society. Indiana spends $147 million a year in state&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2026/01/the-outstater-321/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 19:18:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] 2026 Capitol Chat: Week 2</title><link>https://empowerms.org/2026-capitol-chat-week-2/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Capitol Chat: Week 2 A sweeping education bill, hours of debate, and a narrow House vote put school choice at the center of Week 2 action. In this edition of Capitol Chat, we unpack what happened with House Bill 2, take a quick look at early budget hearings, and highlight a few things to look&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/2026-capitol-chat-week-2/"&gt;2026 Capitol Chat: Week 2&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 20:37:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Bothfield v. WEC &amp; WBLD v WEC</title><link>https://will-law.org/bothfield-v-wec-wbld-v-wec/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On behalf of Wisconsin voters in all 8 of the state's congressional districts, WILL filed motions to intervene in two lawsuits seeking to overturn Wisconsin’s Congressional Maps. Seeking again to defend those maps on behalf of a group of Wisconsin voters, WILL argues that these new lawsuits are time-barred, the three-judge panel lacks authority to overrule the Wisconsin Supreme Court, and any attempt to impose new maps in this manner would violate federal law and the U.S. Constitution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/bothfield-v-wec-wbld-v-wec/"&gt;Bothfield v. WEC &amp;#038; WBLD v WEC&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 21:19:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Coming Soon: More LA GATOR Scholarship Applications, Decision Time for State Leaders</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/education/lagator-coming-soon/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Louisiana families should prepare now: applications for the LA GATOR Scholarship Program are expected to open soon for the 2026–27 school year. This innovative education scholarship account (ESA) program gives parents the power to tailor their children’s education by allowing funds to be used for private school tuition, tutoring, curricula, technology, courses, and other approved...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/education/lagator-coming-soon/"&gt;Coming Soon: More LA GATOR Scholarship Applications, Decision Time for State Leaders&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 21:33:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Congratulations to Governor Abigail Spanberger on Her Historic Inauguration — A Call for Collaboration and Principled Debate</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/congratulations-to-governor-abigail-spanberger-on-her-historic-inauguration-a-call-for-collaboration-and-principled-debate/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="1365" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/IMG_6880.jpeg" width="2048" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Immediate Release By the Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy Date: January 17, 2026 Today, the Thomas Jefferson Institute congratulates Governor Abigail Spanberger on her historic inauguration as the 75th governor of the Commonwealth of Virginia &amp;#8212; and the first woman in the nearly 250-year history of the Commonwealth to hold this office. Her [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/congratulations-to-governor-abigail-spanberger-on-her-historic-inauguration-a-call-for-collaboration-and-principled-debate/"&gt;Congratulations to Governor Abigail Spanberger on Her Historic Inauguration &amp;#8212; A Call for Collaboration and Principled Debate&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Subsidies Cost Kansans Even When Revenues Rise</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/subsidies-cost-kansans-even-when-revenues-rise/</link><description>Why the Chiefs deal hurts people today and tomorrow In a previous post, I explained why the now-approved deal to bring the Kansas City Chiefs to Kansas is bad economics—built on diverted taxes, weakened guardrails, and decades of fiscal risk. What’s become even clearer since then is an often-overlooked truth: even if a subsidy generates [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 16:00:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Portland Ends School Choice Policy for Jefferson High School</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/education/portland-ends-school-choice-policy-for-jefferson-high-school/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By John A. Charles, Jr. Fifteen years ago, the Portland Public Schools (PPS)...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/education/portland-ends-school-choice-policy-for-jefferson-high-school/"&gt;Portland Ends School Choice Policy for Jefferson High School&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 23:36:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Proposed Commission Would Expand Beyond Electricity to Oversee All Forms of Energy in Virginia</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/proposed-commission-would-expand-beyond-electricity-to-oversee-all-forms-of-energy-in-virginia/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="720" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Virginia-power-regulation.jpg" width="1280" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A legislative commission created in 2008 to oversee one narrow function of two electric utilities is about to expand its scope of oversight of all forms of energy in Virginia, including nuclear, coal, and natural gas.&amp;#160;It will be the legislative counterpart – and counterweight – to the politically independent State Corporation Commission. The bill to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/proposed-commission-would-expand-beyond-electricity-to-oversee-all-forms-of-energy-in-virginia/"&gt;Proposed Commission Would Expand Beyond Electricity to Oversee All Forms of Energy in Virginia &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 03:46:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Rifreedom] “Doc” Skoly Stepping Down as Center’s Chair to Pursue Congressional Seat</title><link>https://rifreedom.org/2026/01/doc-skoly-stepping-down-as-centers-chair-to-pursue-congressional-seat/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The  Rhode Island Center for Freedom &amp;#038; Prosperity announced today that Dr. Stephen "Doc" Skoly has stepped down as Chairman of its Board of Directors to pursue a run for the US House of Representatives in Rhode Island's second Congressional district.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org/2026/01/doc-skoly-stepping-down-as-centers-chair-to-pursue-congressional-seat/"&gt;&amp;#8220;Doc&amp;#8221; Skoly Stepping Down as Center&amp;#8217;s Chair to Pursue Congressional Seat&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org"&gt;RI Center for Freedom and Prosperity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 15:10:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Alternatives to New England’s Energy Affordability Crisis</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/alternatives-to-new-englands-energy-affordability-crisis/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In 2024 Maine Policy Institute, along with a coalition of New England’s free-market think tanks, released an energy report which modeled the economic and reliability impacts of the energy policies passed in the six New England states. Alternatives to New England&amp;#8217;s Energy Affordability Crisis, released earlier this month, is a direct sequel to that report. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/alternatives-to-new-englands-energy-affordability-crisis/"&gt;Alternatives to New England’s Energy Affordability Crisis&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 15:56:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] A New Chapter for New Jersey</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/01/a-new-chapter-for-new-jersey/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Today, New Jersey turns the page. With the inauguration of Mikie Sherrill as the state’s 57th governor, New Jersey begins [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/01/a-new-chapter-for-new-jersey/"&gt;A New Chapter for New Jersey&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 16:13:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] InsiderNJ: NJPI Statement on the Appointment of Dr. Lily Laux as Commissioner of Education</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/01/insidernj-njpi-statement-on-the-appointment-of-dr-lily-laux-as-commissioner-of-education/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The New Jersey Policy Institute (NJPI) congratulates Dr. Lily Laux on her nomination to serve as New Jersey’s next Commissioner of [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/01/insidernj-njpi-statement-on-the-appointment-of-dr-lily-laux-as-commissioner-of-education/"&gt;InsiderNJ: NJPI Statement on the Appointment of Dr. Lily Laux as Commissioner of Education&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 16:24:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Freedom Foundation Authors Amicus Brief in Support of Ohio Wage Theft Case</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/press-release/freedom-foundation-authors-amicus-brief-in-support-of-ohio-wage-theft-case/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Freedom Foundation attorney James Abernathy authored an amicus brief joined by other national workers’ rights protections groups to back The Buckeye Institute's appeal in asking the Ohio Supreme Court to hear their case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/press-release/freedom-foundation-authors-amicus-brief-in-support-of-ohio-wage-theft-case/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation Authors Amicus Brief in Support of Ohio Wage Theft Case&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 16:58:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Governor Tate Reeves: Momentum and Good Policy</title><link>https://empowerms.org/governor-tate-reeves-momentum-and-good-policy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Governor Tate Reeves: Momentum and Good Policy In this episode of the Empower Podcast, Grant Callen sits down with Governor Tate Reeves for a wide-ranging conversation about the state’s growing momentum and what comes next. Recorded from the Governor’s office overlooking the State Capitol, the discussion explores why Mississippi is climbing national rankings for wage&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/governor-tate-reeves-momentum-and-good-policy/"&gt;Governor Tate Reeves: Momentum and Good Policy&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 18:43:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Policy Pathway for Principled Tax Reform</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/policy-pathway-for-principled-tax-reform/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Policy Pathway for Principled Tax Reform outlines a framework for evaluating tax policy through the lens of sound tax principles including transparency, simplicity, stability, neutrality, and economic efficiency. The report examines Nebraska’s major tax types including property, income, and sales and offers practical, principle-based recommendations to improve affordability, competitiveness, and long-term fiscal sustainability. While designed...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/policy-pathway-for-principled-tax-reform/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Policy Pathway for Principled Tax Reform&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 19:40:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Florida Politics: Unused K-12 Scholarship Funds Are a Feature, Not a Bug</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/florida-politics-unused-k-12-scholarship-funds-are-a-feature-not-a-bug/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;If the&amp;#160;Florida Restaurant Association&amp;#160;ever detects a shortage of chefs in our state, the first place it should look...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/florida-politics-unused-k-12-scholarship-funds-are-a-feature-not-a-bug/"&gt;Florida Politics: Unused K-12 Scholarship Funds Are a Feature, Not a Bug&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 21:04:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] The Empire Center Reacts to Governor Hochul’s Budget Address</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/the-empire-center-reacts-to-governor-hochuls-budget-address/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In response to the release of Governor Hochul’s executive budget proposal for fiscal 2027, the Empire Center issued the following....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/the-empire-center-reacts-to-governor-hochuls-budget-address/"&gt;The Empire Center Reacts to Governor Hochul&amp;#8217;s Budget Address&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 21:32:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] New property tax assessed valuation limit legislation saves money, eliminates prior concerns</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/assessed-valuation-limit-saves-money/</link><description>New legislation to limit increases in taxable assessed valuation addresses two concerns opponents raised last year, with two major improvements. Some people last year feared that limiting appraised values would distort the property&amp;#8217;s market value. This year’s legislation, SCR 1616, doesn’t affect appraisals and instead limits the increase in the taxable assessed value of a [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 22:49:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Give credit where due on the roads deal</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2026/give-credit-where-due-on-the-roads-deal</link><description>Whitmer gets 20%</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Goldwater Asks Court for Transparency in Maricopa County Sheriff’s Case</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/goldwater-asks-court-for-transparency-in-maricopa-county-sheriffs-case/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Goldwater Institute on Tuesday filed a friend of the court brief in federal court asking the judge to allow..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/goldwater-asks-court-for-transparency-in-maricopa-county-sheriffs-case/"&gt;Goldwater Asks Court for Transparency in Maricopa County Sheriff’s Case&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 13:00:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cardinalinstitute] Healthcare in West Virginia</title><link>https://cardinalinstitute.com/healthcare-in-west-virginia/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Healthcare in West Virginia Healthcare policy is complicated. These resources make it understandable. If you are trying to make sense of West Virginia’s latest healthcare debates, you are not alone. PBM regulation, PEIA’s recurring funding crises, and Certificate of Need laws all affect what care costs, where it is available, and who has choices. We [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com/healthcare-in-west-virginia/"&gt;Healthcare in West Virginia&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com"&gt;Cardinal Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 15:44:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Reserves are a Cushion, Not a Strategy</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/reserves-are-a-cushion-not-a-strategy/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Reserves are a Cushion, Not a Strategy" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/iowa-us-flags.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iowa’s budget remains structurally sound, but spending is accelerating: The FY 2026 budget totals about $9.4 billion—up more than 5 percent year over year—raising sustainability concerns even as lawmakers face a $1 billion shortfall that is not a true deficit due to large reserve balances. Strong reserves and credit ratings provide a cushion, not a blank check: Iowa closed FY 2025 with nearly $1.9 billion in surplus, more than $900 million in reserves, and roughly $4 billion in the Taxpayer Relief Fund, helping maintain AAA credit ratings—but rating agencies warn disciplined spending must continue. Tax reform was planned and paid for by restraint, not federal windfalls: The full phase-in of the 3.8 percent flat tax reduced state revenues as expected, leaving more money with taxpayers; maintaining conservative budgeting—rather than using reserves to fuel faster spending growth—is essential to preserve fiscal stability and enable future reforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/reserves-are-a-cushion-not-a-strategy/"&gt;Reserves are a Cushion, Not a Strategy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 15:56:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Wisconsin Senate Passes WILL-Backed ﻿Amendment to End Tax-Veto Loopholes</title><link>https://will-law.org/wisconsin-senate-passes-will-backed-amendment-to-end-tax-veto-loopholes/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL issued a statement applauding the Wisconsin State Senate for passing Senate Joint Resolution 116 (SJR 116). This proposed amendment to the Wisconsin Constitution curbs executive overreach by prohibiting the governor from using the partial veto to create or increase taxes or fees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/wisconsin-senate-passes-will-backed-amendment-to-end-tax-veto-loopholes/"&gt;Wisconsin Senate Passes WILL-Backed ﻿Amendment to End Tax-Veto Loopholes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 17:40:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] The Wisconsin Higher-Ed Reform Model</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/the-wisconsin-higher-ed-reform-model/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Republican lawmakers managed to pass a conservative-coded policy in a purple state with a Democratic governor. It’s all well and good to point to Florida or Texas and wish that every state could do likewise. Unfortunately, not every state capitol boasts a conservative governor ready to pick controversial fights backed up by a large Republican majority. Wisconsin demonstrates that even purple states can win meaningful, albeit limited, conservative victories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/the-wisconsin-higher-ed-reform-model/"&gt;The Wisconsin Higher-Ed Reform Model&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 17:42:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Why Fossil Fuel Use Must Increase: The Numerical Reality</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/why-fossil-fuel-use-must-increase-the-numerical-reality/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=why-fossil-fuel-use-must-increase-the-numerical-reality</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Statistical Review of Global Energy, has been published every year since 2023 by The Energy Institute. For nearly 75 years before that it was published by British Petroleum. It is one of the most authoritative sources available for energy statistics. It is a terrific place, if not the place, to develop a deeper understanding of our global...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/why-fossil-fuel-use-must-increase-the-numerical-reality/"&gt;Why Fossil Fuel Use Must Increase: The Numerical Reality&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 19:30:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Cured of Cancer—and Now Advocating for Others’ Right to Try</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/cured-of-cancer-and-now-advocating-for-others-right-to-try/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;“A little soreness is just a symptom of a dual sport athlete.” That was the thought that Diego Morris and..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/cured-of-cancer-and-now-advocating-for-others-right-to-try/"&gt;Cured of Cancer—and Now Advocating for Others’ Right to Try&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 19:47:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Governor Evers’ property tax relief plan fails to constrain property tax growth</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/governor-evers-property-tax-relief-plan-fails-to-constrain-property-tax-growth/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Policymakers are scrambling for solutions as Wisconsin property tax burdens continue to rise. As homeowners clamor for relief, Gov. Tony Evers (D) has proposed using $1.3 billion from the state’s surplus to buy down property tax bills. Unfortunately, the proposal does nothing to address the structural drivers of high (and rising) property taxes and, if anything, puts more pressure on them in the future. His proposal commits the state to subsidies that shift burdens rather than alleviate them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/governor-evers-property-tax-relief-plan-fails-to-constrain-property-tax-growth/"&gt;Governor Evers’ property tax relief plan fails to constrain property tax growth&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 19:58:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] How Iowa Can Defend Property Rights Through Property Tax Reform</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/how-iowa-can-defend-property-rights-through-property-tax-reform/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="How Iowa Can Defend Property Rights Through Property Tax Reform" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/national-review-1200x630-1.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“As the Founders saw it, the right to property was not simply an economic concept and was much more than owning a bit of land. It was a first principle of liberty,” Spalding argued. Property is not limited to land or a home; it also includes financial assets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/how-iowa-can-defend-property-rights-through-property-tax-reform/"&gt;How Iowa Can Defend Property Rights Through Property Tax Reform&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 20:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] WILL-Backed Equality Amendment ﻿On November 2026 Ballot</title><link>https://will-law.org/will-backed-equality-amendment-on-november-2026-ballot/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The “Equality Amendment,” otherwise known as Assembly Joint Resolution 102 (AJR 102) will be on the November 2026 ballot after the Wisconsin State Senate voted in favor today. The Wisconsin State Assembly passed the amendment last week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/will-backed-equality-amendment-on-november-2026-ballot/"&gt;WILL-Backed Equality Amendment ﻿On November 2026 Ballot&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 20:58:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Statement in Response to Transportation for Massachusetts Report and MassBudget and Policy Center</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/statement-in-response-to-transportation-for-massachusetts-report-and-massbudget-and-policy-center/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Massachusetts taxpayers were told in 2022 that raising taxes and directing billions in new tax revenues to transportation would dramatically improve quality and reliability. Voters were told the surtax would fix the system. Barely three years later—here we go again.   The...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/statement-in-response-to-transportation-for-massachusetts-report-and-massbudget-and-policy-center/"&gt;Statement in Response to Transportation for Massachusetts Report and MassBudget and Policy Center&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 21:22:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Cascade Policy Institute is Hiring – Development Assistant</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/news/cascade-policy-institute-is-hiring-development-assistant/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;We are seeking a detail-oriented, organized, part-time Development Assistant to support Cascade Policy...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/news/cascade-policy-institute-is-hiring-development-assistant/"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute is Hiring &amp;#8211; Development Assistant&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 23:07:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Want to boost Michigan? Stop punishing R&amp;D</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2026/want-to-boost-michigan-stop-punishing-r-d</link><description>Tax policies penalize companies that invest in innovation</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Idaho joins the nation’s first federal education choice tax credit scholarship program</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/post/idaho-joins-the-nation-s-first-federal-education-choice-tax-credit-scholarship-program</link><description>Idaho has taken a significant step forward in expanding educational opportunity by joining the nation’s first federal education choice tax credit scholarship program.</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 13:18:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Three Plans, One Goal as Legislation is Introduced</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/three-plans-one-goal-as-legislation-is-introduced/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Three Plans, One Goal as Legislation is Introduced" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/AdobeStock_329581775-e1769093766888.jpeg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Property tax reform has moved quickly into action in 2026, with Republicans in both chambers and Governor Kim Reynolds advancing comprehensive proposals aimed at slowing property tax growth and addressing long-standing structural problems in Iowa’s system. The Senate, Governor, and House proposals share common goals but take different approaches, including caps on local government revenue growth, changes to assessment practices, shifts in school funding, limits on TIF, and varying mixes of exemptions, freezes, and tax base adjustments. The House proposal stands out by prioritizing transparency and structural restraint, improving property tax disclosure statements and avoiding targeted exemptions or freezes for specific groups, reflecting a broader debate over how to provide relief while minimizing unintended consequences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/three-plans-one-goal-as-legislation-is-introduced/"&gt;Three Plans, One Goal as Legislation is Introduced&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 14:54:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Assembly clears bill to tackle fears of data center spiking power rates</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/assembly-clears-bill-to-tackle-fears-of-data-center-spiking-power-rates/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The state Assembly this week passed a bill barring data centers from passing on any utility costs to other ratepayers in Wisconsin — targeting a key objection from Wisconsinites who oppose data center development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assembly Bill 840, passed 53-44 almost entirely along party lines, also requires new data centers to use water-conserving technology for cooling and to report annual water use to the Department of Natural Resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/assembly-clears-bill-to-tackle-fears-of-data-center-spiking-power-rates/"&gt;Assembly clears bill to tackle fears of data center spiking power rates&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 15:50:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] A “Free” Heat Pump Conversion for Oil and Propane Customers, Paid for by Virginia Ratepayers</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/a-free-heat-pump-conversion-for-oil-and-propane-customers-paid-for-by-virginia-ratepayers/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="1024" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/heat-pump.jpg" width="1536" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A free heat pump for thousands of Virginians who are now using oil or propane to heat their homes, paid for by Virginia’s general population of electricity ratepayers. That is the goal of legislation that passed its first hurdle in a House of Delegate subcommittee Tuesday on a bipartisan vote.  House Bill 2 is the same as legislation vetoed last year by former Governor Glenn Youngkin (R). The language linked is a substitute adopted [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/a-free-heat-pump-conversion-for-oil-and-propane-customers-paid-for-by-virginia-ratepayers/"&gt;A &amp;#8220;Free&amp;#8221; Heat Pump Conversion for Oil and Propane Customers, Paid for by Virginia Ratepayers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 16:50:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG Issues Demand Letter to DPI Over Year-Long Delay on Dairyland Sentinel’s Public Records Request</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-issues-demand-letter-to-dpi-over-year-long-delay-on-dairyland-sentinels-public-records-request/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;IRG Issues Demand Letter to DPI Over Year-Long Delay on Dairyland Sentinel&amp;#8217;s Public Records Request Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government (IRG) sent a formal demand letter to the Wisconsin Department of Public Instruction (DPI) on Thursday seeking the immediate release of public records that have been withheld for one year. The original [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-issues-demand-letter-to-dpi-over-year-long-delay-on-dairyland-sentinels-public-records-request/"&gt;IRG Issues Demand Letter to DPI Over Year-Long Delay on Dairyland Sentinel&amp;#8217;s Public Records Request&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 18:56:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Louisiana’s Legal Reforms: A Step Toward Fairer Courts and Lower Auto Insurance Rates</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/legal-regulatory/la_legal_reforms/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As 2026 gets underway, Louisiana residents finally have reason to celebrate real progress in our long fight against skyrocketing auto insurance rates. Governor Jeff Landry, Insurance Commissioner Tim Temple, and state lawmakers deserve credit for pushing through a series of reforms in 2025 that are now reshaping our legal system and helping to bring down...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/legal-regulatory/la_legal_reforms/"&gt;Louisiana’s Legal Reforms: A Step Toward Fairer Courts and Lower Auto Insurance Rates&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 19:01:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] New Jersey at a Crossroads: Looking back on Governor Murphy and Ahead to Mikie Sherrill</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/01/new-jersey-at-a-crossroads-looking-back-on-governor-murphy-and-ahead-to-mikie-sherrill/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;by Megan Whitman, NJPI Jr. Economy Fellow As Governor Phil Murphy officially left office this week after eight years, New [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/01/new-jersey-at-a-crossroads-looking-back-on-governor-murphy-and-ahead-to-mikie-sherrill/"&gt;New Jersey at a Crossroads: Looking back on Governor Murphy and Ahead to Mikie Sherrill&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 19:02:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Florida Politics: Skip the lawsuits, teach the kids</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/edward-longe-skip-the-lawsuits-teach-the-kids/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Teaching kids digital literacy beats unconstitutional mandates and endless lawsuits. For parents navigating the rise of social media...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/edward-longe-skip-the-lawsuits-teach-the-kids/"&gt;Florida Politics: Skip the lawsuits, teach the kids&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 19:29:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Missouri Forms an Advanced Nuclear Task Force</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/article/economy/missouri-forms-an-advanced-nuclear-task-force/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Governor Kehoe recently signed an executive order establishing the “Missouri Advanced Nuclear Task Force” as part of an “all-in” commitment on nuclear energy in Missouri. The new task force is [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/article/economy/missouri-forms-an-advanced-nuclear-task-force/"&gt;Missouri Forms an Advanced Nuclear Task Force&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 20:30:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] The Budget Mirage Reappears</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/article/budget-and-spending/the-budget-mirage-reappears/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;To borrow from Yogi Berra, it is déjà vu all over again. For the past two years, I have warned that Missouri’s budget totals are likely misleading. Lawmakers are routinely [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/article/budget-and-spending/the-budget-mirage-reappears/"&gt;The Budget Mirage Reappears&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 20:51:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Charter Schools Do Special Education Better</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/article/education/charter-schools-do-special-education-better/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A new study by Scott Imberman and Andrew Johnson shows that special education students benefit from attending charter schools. Using data from Michigan, the authors identify the effects of charter [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/article/education/charter-schools-do-special-education-better/"&gt;Charter Schools Do Special Education Better&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 21:01:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Is Hochul Really Going to Shut Down the Essential Plan?</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/is-hochul-really-going-to-shut-down-the-essential-plan/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Governor Hochul is hingeing a big chunk of her budget – and the state&amp;#8217;s health-care system – on a politically....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/is-hochul-really-going-to-shut-down-the-essential-plan/"&gt;Is Hochul Really Going to Shut Down the Essential Plan?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 21:41:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Facts Over Fear: What Mainers Should Know About ICE Enforcement</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/facts-over-fear-what-mainers-should-know-about-ice-enforcement/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Recent headlines have reignited debate in Maine over immigration enforcement and the authority of federal agents to operate within our communities. Immigration enforcement is a lawful federal responsibility. ICE operates under defined legal constraints, and claims that agents are “roaming without warrants” misrepresent how federal law enforcement works. Mischaracterizing immigration enforcement in Maine erodes trust [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/facts-over-fear-what-mainers-should-know-about-ice-enforcement/"&gt;Facts Over Fear: What Mainers Should Know About ICE Enforcement&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 21:42:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Deficits may save cities from democratic socialist pipedreams</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/deficits-may-save-cities-from-democratic-socialist-pipedreams/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Deficits may save cities from democratic socialist pipedreams By Sarah Downey  &amp;#124;  January 23, 2026 In New York City, the newly elected mayor, democratic socialist Zohran Mamdani, has pledged to make free or subsidize everything from rent to groceries, straining the city’s deficit to a projected $12 billion in 2027. Mamdani is right that the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/deficits-may-save-cities-from-democratic-socialist-pipedreams/"&gt;Deficits may save cities from democratic socialist pipedreams&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 10:14:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] ‘Everything exploded in the world of online teaching’</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/podcasts/the-overton-window/barbara-oakley-on-the-rise-retreat-and-future-of-online-learning</link><description>Barbara Oakley on the rise, retreat, and future of online learning</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Chicago Teachers Union president owes city over $3.3K</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/chicago-teachers-union-president-owes-city-over-3-3k/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Chicago Teachers Union President Stacy Davis Gates not only refuses to pay her Chicago utility bills, she refuses to pay city fines. She owes over $3,300.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/chicago-teachers-union-president-owes-city-over-3-3k/"&gt;Chicago Teachers Union president owes city over $3.3K&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 11:00:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] NC DPI celebrates choice — in NC public schools</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/nc-dpi-celebrates-choice-in-nc-public-schools/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Yes, the announcement listed above is from the North Carolina Department of Public Instruction (NC DPI). Truth be told, I did a double-take when I saw it. NC DPI hosting a press conference celebrating choice in NC public schools? In most years, you wouldn&amp;#8217;t hear a peep about the weeklong celebration of National School Choice...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/nc-dpi-celebrates-choice-in-nc-public-schools/"&gt;NC DPI celebrates choice — in NC public schools&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 15:13:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2026/01/the-outstater-322/</link><description>Haitian Stew Anyone? I AM ALWAYS ON THE LOOKOUT&amp;#160;for illustrations of exactly how out of touch is the staff of&amp;#160;the Indianapolis Star.&amp;#160;I can tell you that the pickings are rich. Here is the latest headline that caught my eye: “Comforting Haitian Stew Is Next Dish You Should Try in Indy” The Star’s&amp;#160;food editor has discovered&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2026/01/the-outstater-322/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 15:23:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Unemployment Isn’t Strike Pay — Federal Law Just Made That Clear</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/01/23/unemployment-isnt-strike-pay-federal-law-just-made-that-clear/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unemployment insurance (UI) was created as a safety net, a temporary support for workers who lose their jobs through no fault of their own and are actively seeking new employment. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/01/23/unemployment-isnt-strike-pay-federal-law-just-made-that-clear/"&gt;Unemployment Isn’t Strike Pay — Federal Law Just Made That Clear&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 15:44:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Week in Review: He Defeated Cancer…</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-he-defeated-cancer/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;It was just “a little soreness” in his leg. But that soreness turned out to be a rare bone cancer..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-he-defeated-cancer/"&gt;Week in Review: He Defeated Cancer…&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 16:18:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Statement of Jim Stergios, Executive Director of Pioneer Institute on State of the Commonwealth Address</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/statement-of-jim-stergios-executive-director-of-pioneer-institute-on-state-of-the-commonwealth-address/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;“Families won’t feel relief as long as state spending keeps growing at twice the pace of their paychecks. Massachusetts families listening to the Governor’s State of the Commonwealth are confronting rising housing, energy, and healthcare costs even as state government continues to expand. Real affordability starts with slowing state spending, cutting waste, strengthening oversight of government agencies, and redirecting savings to local...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/statement-of-jim-stergios-executive-director-of-pioneer-institute-on-state-of-the-commonwealth-address/"&gt;Statement of Jim Stergios, Executive Director of Pioneer Institute on State of the Commonwealth Address&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 16:43:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Sanctuary by Another Name</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/sanctuary-by-another-name/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I live in a community that, not long ago, was a quiet town outside Austin, Texas—one of many places people fled to in search of safety, order, and a better quality of life. Today, that same community is rapidly transforming into the very version of Austin many residents hoped to escape. Growth is not the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/sanctuary-by-another-name/"&gt;Sanctuary by Another Name&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 16:47:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] New Year, Same Story: Age Verification Measures Distract from Sustainable Solutions</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/age_verification_distract/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;It didn’t take a crystal ball to guess that 2025 would bring a rush of age verification legislation. In our 2025 Tech Policy Forecast, the regulatory tea leaves indicated that app stores would be the new battle ground for pushing age verification, and all of the risks it entails, onto users. 2026 promises to deliver...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/age_verification_distract/"&gt;New Year, Same Story: Age Verification Measures Distract from Sustainable Solutions&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 17:09:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Analysis: Idaho Supreme Court appears likely to uphold parental choice tax credit</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/post/analysis-idaho-supreme-court-appears-likely-to-uphold-parental-choice-tax-credit</link><description>Over and over, justices pressed on two major problems: whether petitioners even have standing to bring the case at all, and whether Idaho’s Constitution truly can be read to prohibit the state from supporting an education policy outside the public school system.</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 18:19:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] 2026 Capitol Chat: Week 3</title><link>https://empowerms.org/2026-capitol-chat-week-3/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Capitol Chat: Week 3 With an ice storm looming and the bill introduction deadline behind them, lawmakers shifted gears during week three of the legislative session. We highlight a few bills drawing early attention and break down this week’s action, including a couple of celebrity appearances and the latest on House Bill 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/2026-capitol-chat-week-3/"&gt;2026 Capitol Chat: Week 3&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 18:23:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Competition Begets Better Banking Data Than Regulation</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/competition-begets-better-banking-data-than-regulation/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As it works to determine how to safeguard the sharing of and access to consumer financial data, the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB) faces a clear choice. It can allow market-based frameworks developed by the private sector to continue evolving, stepping in only where genuine gaps or abuses emerge. Or it can try to revive [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/competition-begets-better-banking-data-than-regulation/"&gt;Competition Begets Better Banking Data Than Regulation&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 18:46:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Understanding welfare work requirements: new eligibility rules for SNAP and Medicaid</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/understanding-snap-and-medicaid-work-requirements/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Big changes are in process for some recipients of Medicaid and Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP or food stamps) benefits and for the state governments that administer the programs. See a breakdown of the changes and who they will actually affect. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/understanding-snap-and-medicaid-work-requirements/"&gt;Understanding welfare work requirements: new eligibility rules for SNAP and Medicaid&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 18:53:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Illinois home prices rising, inventory nearly half</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/illinois-home-prices-rising-inventory-nearly-half/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Since 2019, Illinois home prices have jumped nearly 50% and available houses are down nearly 50%. Blame property taxes and zoning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/illinois-home-prices-rising-inventory-nearly-half/"&gt;Illinois home prices rising, inventory nearly half&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 19:40:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Where are those manufacturing jobs we were promised?</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/manufacturing-jobs-have-fallen-under-trumps-tariff-regime/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Pres. Trump’s on-again, off-again, on-again tariff regime dominated the economic news in 2025. It was kicked off on April 2, a date Trump called “Liberation Day,” when the president announced his executive order imposing baseline tariffs on nearly all U.S. trading partners, supposedly effective in April. The following months saw a near endless stream of...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/manufacturing-jobs-have-fallen-under-trumps-tariff-regime/"&gt;Where are those manufacturing jobs we were promised?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 19:41:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] “Thank God for a place like… the Institute for Reforming Government”</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/thank-god-for-a-place-like-the-institute-for-reforming-government/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;“Thank God for a place like… the Institute for Reforming Government” https://youtu.be/DcogRNr4FGw?si=lzNFpBlVrvFsXQvO&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/thank-god-for-a-place-like-the-institute-for-reforming-government/"&gt;“Thank God for a place like… the Institute for Reforming Government”&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 20:20:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Newsom’s Education Legacy: Rising Costs, Declining Performance</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/newsoms-education-legacy-rising-costs-declining-performance/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=newsoms-education-legacy-rising-costs-declining-performance</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier this month, Governor Gavin Newsom submitted his proposed 2026-27 budget to the legislature, weighing in at nearly $349 billion. His budget plan came one day after he gave the last State of the State address of his term, in which he touted California’s “record-breaking” education spending. Newsom painted California as a model for “nation-leading...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/newsoms-education-legacy-rising-costs-declining-performance/"&gt;Newsom’s Education Legacy: Rising Costs, Declining Performance&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 20:23:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Prospect of open enrollment is already prompting talk of improving public schools’ appeal</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2026/01/prospect-of-open-enrollment-is-already-prompting-talk-of-improving-public-schools-appeal/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A bill to create universal open enrollment for New Hampshire public schools is already prompting school boards to consider marketing their districts to families. And the bill hasn&amp;#8217;t passed either chamber of the Legislature yet. Senate Bill 101, sponsored by Sen. Tim Lang, R-Sanbornton, would require all school districts to &amp;#8220;establish an open enrollment policy [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2026/01/prospect-of-open-enrollment-is-already-prompting-talk-of-improving-public-schools-appeal/"&gt;Prospect of open enrollment is already prompting talk of improving public schools&amp;#8217; appeal&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 20:45:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Winners &amp; Losers: Davos, the Bible, Indiana and More</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/winners-losers-davos-the-bible-indiana-and-more/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Every Friday morning, I join the Cardle &amp;#38; Woolley Show on Talk 1370 Radio in Austin to announce the week’s Winners &amp;#38; Losers. Currently, it feels like we are living in scenes of “Game of Thrones” in which dark, ominous voices keep warning us that “winter is coming.” As we prepare to face down a...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/winners-losers-davos-the-bible-indiana-and-more/"&gt;Winners &amp; Losers: Davos, the Bible, Indiana and More&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 21:07:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] “Islamic Games” are “Identity Sports”</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/islamic-games-are-identity-sports/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;It didn’t take long for Grapevine-Colleyville ISD and Cy-Fair ISD to back off their offer of the use of public school facilities to host the so-called “Islamic Games,” once it was revealed that one of the sponsors was the Council on American-Islamic Relations (CAIR), which Texas Gov. Greg Abbott has linked to foreign terrorists. What’s...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/islamic-games-are-identity-sports/"&gt;“Islamic Games” are “Identity Sports”&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 21:27:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG demands Wisconsin K-12 education authority release records</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-demands-wisconsin-k-12-education-authority-release-records/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;(The Center Square) &amp;#8211; The Institute for Reforming Government is joining a push to get Wisconsin’s Department of Public Instruction to release information related to changes in its benchmarks for the Forward Exam. IRG sent a demand letter related to the request to DPI on Thursday. DPI was found by the Wisconsin Institute for Law [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-demands-wisconsin-k-12-education-authority-release-records/"&gt;IRG demands Wisconsin K-12 education authority release records&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 21:48:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Illinois economy grows 4.3%, riding national trend</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/illinois-economy-grows-4-3-riding-national-trend/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Illinois saw strong economic growth in the third quarter of 2025, largely tracking national trends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/illinois-economy-grows-4-3-riding-national-trend/"&gt;Illinois economy grows 4.3%, riding national trend&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 21:56:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] How do 2026 primary early voting sites compare to 2022?</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/how-do-2026-primary-early-voting-sites-compare-to-2022/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The board of the North Carolina State Board of Elections (SBE) met on January 13 to make final decisions on early voting plans for counties whose boards of elections could not come to a unanimous agreement. The nonunanimous counties and their competing plans are listed in the &amp;#8220;Early Voting Information March 2026 Primary Nonunanimous Plans&amp;#8221;...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/how-do-2026-primary-early-voting-sites-compare-to-2022/"&gt;How do 2026 primary early voting sites compare to 2022?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 22:16:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] House Bill 506 — Sales tax, rebate, developers (-1)</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/house-bill-506-sales-tax-rebate-developers/</link><description>Bill Description:&amp;#160;House Bill 506 would raise the cap on a sales tax rebate incentive program for developers who fund highway improvements while also increasing the minimum commitment to participate in the program. Rating: -1 Does it give government any new, additional, or expanded power to prohibit, restrict, or regulate activities in the free market? Conversely, [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 01:09:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] House Bill 508 — Bike, ped projects, fed funds (-1)</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/house-bill-508-bike-ped-projects-fed-funds/</link><description>Bill Description:&amp;#160;House Bill 508 would allow governments to spend federal funds and grants to improve bike and pedestrian facilities. Rating: -1 Does it increase government spending (for objectionable purposes) or debt? Conversely, does it decrease government spending or debt? Idaho law limits the use of transportation dollars to improve bike and pedestrian facilities unless such [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 01:11:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] House Bill 509 — Vehicle inspections (+1)</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/house-bill-509-vehicle-inspections/</link><description>Bill Description:&amp;#160;House Bill 509 would clarify that large commercial vehicles would not be subject to reinspection for 72 hours following an initial inspection.&amp;#160; Rating: +1 Does it give government any new, additional, or expanded power to prohibit, restrict, or regulate activities in the free market? Conversely, does it eliminate or reduce government intervention in the [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 01:13:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Treating Drug Trafficking Like a Security Threat Matters at Home</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/treating-drug-trafficking-like-a-security-threat-matters-at-home/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For decades, the United States has responded to drug trafficking primarily through domestic law enforcement and public health frameworks. Those approaches matter, but they hit a wall when drug supply chains are protected by political power abroad. At that point, local enforcement is reacting to the problem, not shaping it. Networks that operate across borders, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/treating-drug-trafficking-like-a-security-threat-matters-at-home/"&gt;Treating Drug Trafficking Like a Security Threat Matters at Home&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 11:00:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Rule by judges?</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/rule-by-judges/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Federal district court in Minnesota is open again this weekend, logging more habeas corpus cases seeking to free illegal aliens detained by ICE. I do hope that taxpayers aren&amp;#8217;t paying for overtime. So far this Saturday (January 24), twenty-four (24) new habeas cases have been filed. bringing to 378 the number filed so far in...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/rule-by-judges/"&gt;Rule by judges?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 16:16:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Border Patrol agent reportedly shot man armed with a handgun in Minneapolis</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/ice-agent-reportedly-shot-man-armed-with-a-handgun-in-minneapolis/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This morning at approximately 9 am, near 26th St. and Nicollet Ave South in Minneapolis, federal agents working as part of Operation Metro Surge, attempted to arrest a man who was reportedly armed with a handgun. Video of the incident has surfaced from accross the street from the incident. It only shows about a 44...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/ice-agent-reportedly-shot-man-armed-with-a-handgun-in-minneapolis/"&gt;Border Patrol agent reportedly shot man armed with a handgun in Minneapolis&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 17:24:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Lawfare rages, 24/7</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/lawfare-rages-24-7/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Federal court in Minnesota is working overtime to prevent the enforcement of immigration laws. So far this Sunday (January 25), twelve (12) new habeas corpus cases have been filed, bringing to 389 the number filed so far in 2026, That represents most (61 percent) of all civil cases filed in the district this year. The...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/lawfare-rages-24-7/"&gt;Lawfare rages, 24/7&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 15:58:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Constitutional discrimination: Why voters must get chance to repeal the Blaine Amendment</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/post/constitutional-discrimination-why-voters-must-get-opportunity-to-repeal-the-blaine-amendment</link><description>Idaho’s “Blaine Amendment” — singles out religious institutions and religious schools for unequal treatment. It broadly prohibits public funds from being used “in aid of” any church or religious organization and blocks support for schools controlled by religious denominations.</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 04:41:20 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>