<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>State-Policy Think-Tank Digest</title><link>https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml</link><description>Latest posts from free-market policy institutes across the U.S.</description><atom:link href="https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 04:07:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] New Jersey Policy Institute Announces Inaugural Class of 2026 Junior Fellows</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/11/new-jersey-policy-institute-announces-inaugural-class-of-2026-junior-fellows/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Parsippany, NJ – The New Jersey Policy Institute (NJPI) is proud to announce the inaugural class of its 2026 Junior Fellowship [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/11/new-jersey-policy-institute-announces-inaugural-class-of-2026-junior-fellows/"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute Announces Inaugural Class of 2026 Junior Fellows&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 18:43:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Mississippi is globally recognized!</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/mississippi-is-globally-recognized/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/mississippi-is-globally-recognized/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi is globally recognized!&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 18:55:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Tennessee Tax System &amp; Reform Efforts Webinar</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/tennessee-tax-system-reform-efforts-webinar/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=tennessee-tax-system-reform-efforts-webinar</link><description>Join the Beacon Center for a timely discussion on Tennessee’s tax system, ongoing reform efforts, and how tax policy impacts families, workers, and businesses across the state. We’ll be joined by a panel of experts: Carey Bringle, Nashville business owner Patrick Gleason, Americans for Tax Reform, Beacon Senior Fellow for Tax Policy Justin Owen, CEO,...</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 20:38:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Rifreedom] Center Mourns the Loss of Board Member Michael G. Riley, Civic Leader</title><link>https://rifreedom.org/2025/11/center-mourns-the-loss-of-board-member-michael-g-riley-civic-leader/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org/2025/11/center-mourns-the-loss-of-board-member-michael-g-riley-civic-leader/"&gt;Center Mourns the Loss of Board Member Michael G. Riley, Civic Leader&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org"&gt;RI Center for Freedom and Prosperity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 16:51:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Trouble on the Right – Why Conservatives Need to be Wary</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/trouble-on-the-right-why-conservatives-need-to-be-wary/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I only recently learned what a “groyper” is - you may or may not be familiar with the term?&amp;#160;From what I can tell, a groyper is a hardline white nationalist.&amp;#160; Often anti-Semitic, groypers are hostile to mainstream conservatives.&amp;#160; To the extent they have a coherent agenda, groypers seem more national socialism than free-market capitalism.&amp;#160;Having been [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/trouble-on-the-right-why-conservatives-need-to-be-wary/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Trouble on the Right – Why Conservatives Need to be Wary&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 18:29:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Lowering the bar on proficiency standards is a frightening fad sweeping public education</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/states-lowering-proficiency-standards/</link><description>State education administrators often say,  “It’s all about the kids,” yet their actions suggest it’s more about protecting adult reputations than improving student outcomes. They all want students to do better, but not if it means adults changing their behavior to make it happen. The most recent example of this is lowering the bar on [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 17:21:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Sen. Rod Hickman: Rural revitalization, public safety, and education opportunity</title><link>https://empowerms.org/sen-rod-hickman-rural-revitalization-public-safety-and-education-opportunity/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Sen. Rod Hickman: Rural revitalization, public safety, and education opportunity On this episode of The Empower Podcast, host Grant Callen sits down with Mississippi State Senator Rod Hickman, a lawyer, educator, and public servant representing a stretch of communities across East Mississippi from Macon to Louisville to Meridian. Sen. Hickman shares how growing up in&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/sen-rod-hickman-rural-revitalization-public-safety-and-education-opportunity/"&gt;Sen. Rod Hickman: Rural revitalization, public safety, and education opportunity&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 18:48:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Decoding bureaucracy: how AI could aid regulatory reform</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/decoding-bureaucracy-how-ai-could-aid-regulatory-reform/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For decades, the image of government regulation has been synonymous with dusty, overflowing binders and legal jargon. State regulatory codes tend to accumulate year after year, sometimes contradicting themselves and complicating life for those navigating the process. This accumulation of &amp;#8220;red tape&amp;#8221; creates significant burdens for small business owners trying to remain compliant, citizens trying...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/decoding-bureaucracy-how-ai-could-aid-regulatory-reform/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Decoding bureaucracy: how AI could aid regulatory reform&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 21:18:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] On Thanksgiving, remember that gratitude makes good citizens, heals divisions</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/gratitude-makes-good-citizens-and-heals-divisions/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/gratitude-makes-good-citizens-and-heals-divisions/"&gt;On Thanksgiving, remember that gratitude makes good citizens, heals divisions&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 23:00:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Oregon’s 19th Century Energy Strategy</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/economic-opportunity/oregons-19th-century-energy-strategy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By John A. Charles, Jr. Recently the Oregon Department of Energy (ODOE) published...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/economic-opportunity/oregons-19th-century-energy-strategy/"&gt;Oregon’s 19th Century Energy Strategy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 00:31:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] The War of Visions</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/11/28/the-war-of-visions/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Across the country, Americans are no longer divided simply by policy or party but by rival moral imaginations—two incompatible visions of truth, freedom, and even human nature itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/11/28/the-war-of-visions/"&gt;The War of Visions&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 00:23:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF opinion piece: Federal shutdown highlights New Mexico dependence</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-opinion-piece-federal-shutdown-highlights-new-mexico-dependence/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following appeared in the Santa Fe New Mexican on December 1, 2025. Among other things, the recent federal shutdown highlighted just how dependent New Mexico is on the federal government. According to the website Virtual Capitalist, New Mexico is the most dependent state in the nation on federal dollars. There are some good reasons for this. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-opinion-piece-federal-shutdown-highlights-new-mexico-dependence/"&gt;RGF opinion piece: Federal shutdown highlights New Mexico dependence&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 16:47:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] YAF v SBA</title><link>https://will-law.org/yaf-v-sba/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL and the Center for Individual Rights (CIR) filed a major lawsuit against the Trump Administration today, targeting the foundation for many of the remaining federal DEI programs: the preference for so-called “socially disadvantaged individuals.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/yaf-v-sba/"&gt;YAF v SBA&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 18:10:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] A Very Grateful Immigrant’s Thanksgiving</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/a-very-grateful-immigrants-thanksgiving/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Having just celebrated Thanksgiving across the United States, I’ve been reminded of what makes this holiday truly special.&amp;#160;&amp;#160;If you’re an American who’s grown up with the holiday your whole life, it’s easy to take it for granted. Speaking as an immigrant, let me tell you: there’s something genuinely magical about a country setting aside a [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/a-very-grateful-immigrants-thanksgiving/" rel="nofollow"&gt;A Very Grateful Immigrant’s Thanksgiving&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 21:11:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] New Hampshire ranked freest state in North America for 24th time</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/12/new-hampshire-ranked-freest-state-in-north-america-for-24th-time/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New Hampshire ranks as the freest state in North America, as measured in this year’s Economic Freedom of North America report, released today by the Josiah Bartlett Center for Public Policy in conjunction with Canada’s Fraser Institute. For the 24th time, New Hampshire is the freest state among all U.S. states, having scored 8.34 out [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/12/new-hampshire-ranked-freest-state-in-north-america-for-24th-time/"&gt;New Hampshire ranked freest state in North America for 24th time&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 12:52:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/12/the-outstater-311/</link><description>Keeping the Peace The King’s Peace (pax regis) — Prior to the English Civil War, the common-law concept of&amp;#160;maintaining&amp;#160;public order.&amp;#160; CRIMINOLOGISTS TELL US&amp;#160;that only a sliver of humanity is inherently&amp;#160;“criminal,” that is, persons with a pathological disregard for others or their property. In New York City, for instance, just 327 offenders among 8 million citizens&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/12/the-outstater-311/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 13:43:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] The Holiday Season Is Here — But Affordability Still Isn’t</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/the-holiday-season-is-here/</link><description>If it feels like Christmas keeps getting more expensive, that’s because it is,  and Kansans are feeling it more sharply than policymakers care to admit. The rising cost of living is no longer a blip on a chart; it’s a full-blown pocketbook problem showing up in everything from family grocery runs to holiday gift lists. [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 15:17:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Young v. Lee: Defending Universal School Choice for Tennesseans</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/young-v-lee-defending-universal-school-choice-for-tennesseans/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=young-v-lee-defending-universal-school-choice-for-tennesseans</link><description>Current status: Along with EdChoice, we represent parents who have asked to intervene in defense of Tennessee&amp;#8217;s EFS program in chancery court. A decision on our motion to intervene is expected later this year.  The Beacon Center of Tennessee, along with EdChoice, is intervening to defend Tennessee&amp;#8217;s Education Freedom Scholarship (EFS) Program from legal attack....</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 19:12:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG Polling: April 2025</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-polling-april-2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;April 16, 2025 NEW IRG Poll: Voters Decided Election on Abortion, Musk &amp;#38; Trump’s Agenda Despite all the emphasis on crime, voters were focused elsewhere  Delafield, Wis. –  The Institute for Reforming Government (IRG) is continuing its public polling project with Napolitan News Service and Scott Rasmussen in 2025, with the focus in this poll on Wisconsin’s [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-polling-april-2025/"&gt;IRG Polling: April 2025&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 20:28:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Pioneer New England Legal Foundation Files Lawsuit Challenging Cambridge Inclusionary Zoning Ordinance</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/pioneer-new-england-legal-foundation-files-lawsuit-challenging-cambridge-inclusionary-zoning-ordinance/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Requirement that 20 percent of a housing project remain permanently affordable places burden on developers that should be borne by the public as a whole Cambridge – Pioneer New England Legal Foundation filed a lawsuit in state Land Court against the City...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/pioneer-new-england-legal-foundation-files-lawsuit-challenging-cambridge-inclusionary-zoning-ordinance/"&gt;Pioneer New England Legal Foundation Files Lawsuit Challenging Cambridge Inclusionary Zoning Ordinance&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 11:48:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Book Highlights Advances in Digital Education, Policies to Unlock Its Benefits</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/book-highlights-advances-in-digital-education-policies-to-unlock-its-benefits/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;BOSTON – A new book co-edited by national digital education leader Julie Young draws on best practices and multiple studies published by Pioneer Institute to recount three decades of advances in digital education and highlights the policies necessary for students to fully...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/book-highlights-advances-in-digital-education-policies-to-unlock-its-benefits/"&gt;Book Highlights Advances in Digital Education, Policies to Unlock Its Benefits &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 12:06:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] WILL Moves to Intervene in Wisconsin Redistricting Cases on Behalf of Wisconsin Voters</title><link>https://will-law.org/will-moves-to-intervene-in-wisconsin-redistricting-cases-on-behalf-of-wisconsin-voters/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL filed motions to intervene in two lawsuits seeking to overturn Wisconsin’s Congressional Maps. Seeking again to defend those maps on behalf of a group of Wisconsin voters, WILL argues that these new lawsuits are time-barred, the three-judge panel lacks authority to overrule the Wisconsin Supreme Court, and any attempt to impose new maps in this manner would violate federal law and the U.S. Constitution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/will-moves-to-intervene-in-wisconsin-redistricting-cases-on-behalf-of-wisconsin-voters/"&gt;WILL Moves to Intervene in Wisconsin Redistricting Cases on Behalf of Wisconsin Voters&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 14:16:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] What Key Bills Will Lawmakers Debate in 2026?</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/what-key-bills-will-lawmakers-debate-in-2026/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Maine Legislature meets again in January 2026 and lawmakers have already planned out which bills will be carried over from the 2025 session, and which new legislation will be added to that list. While dozens of bills remain alive, only a small number of them have statewide impact and clear implications for Maine taxpayers, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/what-key-bills-will-lawmakers-debate-in-2026/"&gt;What Key Bills Will Lawmakers Debate in 2026?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 18:37:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Report: New York’s Diminished Population Shows Lasting Damage from Covid-19</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/report-new-yorks-diminished-population-shows-lasting-damage-from-covid-19/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Most parts of New York remained less populated in 2024 than in 2020 as the state struggled to bounce back....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/report-new-yorks-diminished-population-shows-lasting-damage-from-covid-19/"&gt;Report: New York&amp;#8217;s Diminished Population Shows Lasting Damage from Covid-19&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 20:31:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] New Mexico falls to 50th among US states in latest “Index of Economic Freedom”</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/new-mexico-falls-to-50th-among-us-states-in-latest-index-of-economic-freedom/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Rio Grande Foundation has never seen &amp;#8220;eye to eye&amp;#8221; with Gov. Lujan Grisham and the leftists in Santa Fe who have failed to improve New Mexico even with the benefit of billions of dollars in oil and gas revenues. And, while these policy differences and failures may seem trivial to some, they have real [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/new-mexico-falls-to-50th-among-us-states-in-latest-index-of-economic-freedom/"&gt;New Mexico falls to 50th among US states in latest &amp;#8220;Index of Economic Freedom&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 15:40:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] New Revenue Forecast Shows Why Maine Should Cut Taxes, Not Grow Government</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/new-revenue-forecast-shows-why-maine-should-cut-taxes-not-grow-government/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Maine’s latest revenue forecast shows the state will bring in roughly $248 million more than expected over the next two years. However, instead of asking how to give this money back to taxpayers, state leaders are already discussing what government spending to prioritize. This framing is backwards. Maine families are the ones who generated this [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/new-revenue-forecast-shows-why-maine-should-cut-taxes-not-grow-government/"&gt;New Revenue Forecast Shows Why Maine Should Cut Taxes, Not Grow Government&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 16:03:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Nebraska Tax Reform: Why Full Expensing Is the Smart Move</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-tax-reform-why-full-expensing-is-the-smart-move/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The federal One Big Beautiful Bill (OBBB) creates the opportunity for Nebraska to adopt the most “America First” tax reform: full expensing. In an era of reshoring and friend-shoring critical supply chains, full expensing is the tax reform that properly defines “income” and incentivizes production in the U.S.A.   Full expensing is the policy of allowing...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-tax-reform-why-full-expensing-is-the-smart-move/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Nebraska Tax Reform: Why Full Expensing Is the Smart Move&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 16:55:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] Court Watch: Wisconsin Supreme Court Reverses, Consolidates Power Through New Court Management Order</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/court-watch-wisconsin-supreme-court-reverses-consolidates-power-through-new-court-management-order/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Court Watch: Wisconsin Supreme Court Reverses, Consolidates Power Through New Court Management Order Progressive majority reshapes internal court governance to cement its control of the judicial branch Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government’s Court Watch issued the following statement after the Wisconsin Supreme Court quietly issued a new court management order just days [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/court-watch-wisconsin-supreme-court-reverses-consolidates-power-through-new-court-management-order/"&gt;Court Watch: Wisconsin Supreme Court Reverses, Consolidates Power Through New Court Management Order&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 16:58:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] The Hidden Gem: Why Education Freedom is the New Economic Development</title><link>https://empowerms.org/the-hidden-gem-why-education-freedom-is-the-new-economic-development/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Forget industrial parks. The driver for economic growth in rural Mississippi is education freedom, which is the most powerful yet often overlooked tool in our economic development chest. I’ve dedicated my academic research to the topic, stemming from a comment I heard years ago at Starkville City Hall: “Education is the biggest driver of community-economic&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/the-hidden-gem-why-education-freedom-is-the-new-economic-development/"&gt;The Hidden Gem: Why Education Freedom is the New Economic Development&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 17:46:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] A4121 Is a Hatchet When New Jersey Needs a Scalpel</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/12/a4121-is-a-hatchet-when-new-jersey-needs-a-scalpel/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Today, I had the opportunity to testify before the Assembly Education Committee on A4121, a bill that would eliminate New [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/12/a4121-is-a-hatchet-when-new-jersey-needs-a-scalpel/"&gt;A4121 Is a Hatchet When New Jersey Needs a Scalpel&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 21:24:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Working folks get short shrift while city funds vanity streetcar</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/working-folks-get-short-shrift-while-city-funds-vanity-streetcar/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Money wasted on Hop while bus access for people who really need it is at risk Milwaukee County’s bus network has swerved back from the fiscal brink, one tire halfway over the void as officials shuffle money, trim back some routes’ hours and wonder what they’ll do next year. Pay attention, Wisconsin taxpayers: You’re financing [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/working-folks-get-short-shrift-while-city-funds-vanity-streetcar/"&gt;Working folks get short shrift while city funds vanity streetcar&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 22:48:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Portland Public Schools’ Risky Real Estate Gamble</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/education/portland-public-schools-risky-real-estate-gamble/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Eric Fruits, Ph.D. On December 2, Portland Public Schools (PPS) board voted...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/education/portland-public-schools-risky-real-estate-gamble/"&gt;Portland Public Schools’ Risky Real Estate Gamble&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 01:25:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] New Report Confirms Unions Are Lying About Political Spending</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/press-release/new-report-confirms-unions-are-lying-about-political-spending/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Freedom Foundation CEO Aaron Withe today applauded a new Commonwealth Foundation analysis documenting government union political spending, saying it provides further documentation of what both organizations have been exposing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/press-release/new-report-confirms-unions-are-lying-about-political-spending/" rel="nofollow"&gt;New Report Confirms Unions Are Lying About Political Spending&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 16:10:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Debt Is the Fire—And Louisiana Is in the Path</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/tax-budget/debt-is-the-fire-and-louisiana-is-in-the-path/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Federal spending is out of control. Washington is racking up debt faster than at any time outside a world war or national emergency, and the consequences aren’t theoretical. They’re hitting state and local governments hard, especially in Louisiana. The national debt just blew past $38 trillion. This year’s deficit alone will be about $2 trillion,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/tax-budget/debt-is-the-fire-and-louisiana-is-in-the-path/"&gt;Debt Is the Fire—And Louisiana Is in the Path&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 18:16:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Freedom Foundation Helps 50,000 Public Employees Opt Out of Union Membership This Year</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/press-release/freedom-foundation-helps-50000-public-employees-opt-out-of-union-membership-this-year/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Freedom Foundation announced today that it has helped 50,000 public sector employees exercise their First Amendment rights to opt out of union membership in 2025, marking the most successful year since the Supreme Court's landmark Janus v. AFSCME decision in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/press-release/freedom-foundation-helps-50000-public-employees-opt-out-of-union-membership-this-year/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation Helps 50,000 Public Employees Opt Out of Union Membership This Year&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 18:28:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Before Spending Millions to Replace Federal Subsidies, Connecticut Should Audit Its Own Data</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/12/05/before-spending-millions-to-replace-federal-subsidies-connecticut-should-audit-its-own-data/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Access Health CT — the state’s health insurance exchange — recently warned that as many as 30 to 35 percent of its 150,000 marketplace enrollees may lose coverage in the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/12/05/before-spending-millions-to-replace-federal-subsidies-connecticut-should-audit-its-own-data/"&gt;Before Spending Millions to Replace Federal Subsidies, Connecticut Should Audit Its Own Data &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 19:18:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] A ‘Repeal Day’ glance at Liquor Commission revenues</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/12/a-repeal-day-glance-at-liquor-commission-revenues/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;December 5 is neither a federal nor state day of celebration, but it probably should be. On Dec. 5, 1933, Pennsylvania, Ohio and Utah became the final states to ratify the 21st Amendment to the U.S. Constitution.  The night before, toasting your Aunt Gertrude’s 92nd birthday with a glass of champagne was illegal. That evening, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/12/a-repeal-day-glance-at-liquor-commission-revenues/"&gt;A &amp;#8216;Repeal Day&amp;#8217; glance at Liquor Commission revenues&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 22:09:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Small Cost, Big Returns: Technical Schools Building Tennessee</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/small-cost-big-returns-technical-schools-building-tennessee/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=small-cost-big-returns-technical-schools-building-tennessee</link><description>Technical schools may not be the right choice for every high school graduate. Still, for those who have graduated from such programs, data shows they have the potential to make a good living while supporting their local communities, all while avoiding years of student loan payments.</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 22:10:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/12/the-outstater-312/</link><description>THE LEADERSHIP&amp;#160;of my community is excited about a new economic boost that the mayor says is &amp;#8220;too good to pass up.&amp;#8221; Is it a tax break for local businesses? How about zoning reform, or more starter homes for young families? No? Reducing outdated permit requirements and regulations? None of that. They are excited about a&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/12/the-outstater-312/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 14:58:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] The Los Angeles Times Misses the Forest Fire Scandal for the Trees</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/the-los-angeles-times-misse-scandal/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=the-los-angeles-times-misse-scandal</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The real story is not ‘climate change.’ Most good news editors, whether they admit it or not, believe themselves Michelangelo’s heirs — men and women who chisel off the unnecessary bits of a reporter’s copy in order to reveal the angel within. Sadly, the Los Angeles Times often seems bereft of these judicious hacks. Take, for instance, a...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/the-los-angeles-times-misse-scandal/"&gt;The Los Angeles Times Misses the Forest Fire Scandal for the Trees&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 19:42:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] Franke: ‘Listening to the Law’</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/12/franke-listening-to-the-law/</link><description>by Mark Franke Supreme Court nominations are great political theater, great, that is, if you enjoy the spectator sport our uncivil civic discourse has become. But there is an educational aspect to this verbal&amp;#160;sturm und drang. For example we have become educated on the interpretative methodology of originalism, the methodology used by those who look&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/12/franke-listening-to-the-law/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 13:06:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Georgia candidates for governor should make welfare reform a top priority</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/georgia-candidates-for-governor-should-make-welfare-reform-a-top-priority/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/georgia-candidates-for-governor-should-make-welfare-reform-a-top-priority/"&gt;Georgia candidates for governor should make welfare reform a top priority&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 16:58:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] OPINION: New Mexico’s economic freedom is now dead last</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/opinion-new-mexicos-economic-freedom-is-now-dead-last/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following appeared in the Albuquerque Journal  on December 7, 2025. In a study published earlier this year, we highlighted the fact that New Mexico was the only state in the U.S. to have lost economic freedom since 1981. We now know that it is worse than we thought. People are more economically free when [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/opinion-new-mexicos-economic-freedom-is-now-dead-last/"&gt;OPINION: New Mexico&amp;#8217;s economic freedom is now dead last&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 17:53:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Wichita should reallocate spending rather than add a new (rushed?) 1% sales tax</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/sales-tax-proposal-rushed-wichita/</link><description>The Wichita City Council seems poised to rush a proposal to the ballot for a 1-cent sales tax to raise $850 million over seven years for several new projects. That at least implies that imposing a new tax is the only way to fund “public safety projects, property tax relief, and revitalizing Century II and [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 19:55:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Listen: Steve Robinson &amp; Matt Gagnon on WGAN</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/listen-steve-robinson-matt-gagnon-on-wgan/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Steve Robinson from the Maine Wire joins Matt Gagnon to discuss fraud and corruption by the Maine-based Gateway Community Services (GCS). According to reporting by the The Maine Wire, GCS has been found liable for nearly a million dollars worth of erroneous billing to MaineCare, the state’s Medicare agency, in an unsettling precursor to revelations [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/listen-steve-robinson-matt-gagnon-on-wgan/"&gt;Listen: Steve Robinson &amp;amp; Matt Gagnon on WGAN&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 20:37:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] The Data Center Debate Continues in Festus</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/economy/the-data-center-debate-continues-in-festus/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Amidst great debate, a city commission in Festus recently moved forward with plans for a new data center development. Festus [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/economy/the-data-center-debate-continues-in-festus/"&gt;The Data Center Debate Continues in Festus&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 21:07:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Email Confirms Early Contact Between NY Officials and CDPAP Contractor</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/email-confirms-early-contact-between-ny-officials-and-cdpap-contractor/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;State officials met with the ultimate winner of a $1 billion Medicaid contract two weeks before the Legislature authorized bidding....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/email-confirms-early-contact-between-ny-officials-and-cdpap-contractor/"&gt;Email Confirms Early Contact Between NY Officials and CDPAP Contractor&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 14:46:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] Empty Schools, Empty Wallets: How ESSER Pandemic Aid Led to More School Referenda</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/empty-schools-empty-wallets-how-esser-pandemic-aid-led-to-more-school-referenda/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Empty Schools, Empty Wallets: How ESSER Pandemic Aid Led to More School Referenda New IRG analysis reveals hiring sprees and poor financial decisions as Wisconsin schools fall behind national leaders Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government released a new report on Tuesday, “Empty Schools, Empty Wallets: What Happened to $1.49 Billion in ESSER [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/empty-schools-empty-wallets-how-esser-pandemic-aid-led-to-more-school-referenda/"&gt;Empty Schools, Empty Wallets: How ESSER Pandemic Aid Led to More School Referenda&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 15:02:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Why CT’s Treatment of Faith-Based Nonprofits Matters for Its Civic and Fiscal Future</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/12/09/why-cts-treatment-of-faith-based-nonprofits-matters-for-its-civic-and-fiscal-future/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="1890" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/St-Joseph-scaled-e1765295362919.jpeg" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connecticut ranks among the least friendly states for faith-based nonprofit organizations, largely due to restrictive regulatory and tax policies. These rules not only limit religious expression and charitable outreach but also mirror a national trend: as civic associations shutter, governments expand — shifting more costs [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/12/09/why-cts-treatment-of-faith-based-nonprofits-matters-for-its-civic-and-fiscal-future/"&gt;Why CT&amp;#8217;s Treatment of Faith-Based Nonprofits Matters for Its Civic and Fiscal Future&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 16:12:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] SEIU 503 asks members to do its political dirty work</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/oregon/seiu-503-asks-members-to-do-its-political-dirty-work/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;SEIU 503, Oregon’s largest public employee union, has launched its latest campaign — not in the legislature or at the bargaining table, but on the sidewalks asking its own dues-paying members to inform on their neighbors for engaging in the political process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/oregon/seiu-503-asks-members-to-do-its-political-dirty-work/" rel="nofollow"&gt;SEIU 503 asks members to do its political dirty work&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 20:12:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Goldwater Urges Arizona Supreme Court to Protect Right to a Jury Trial</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/goldwater-urges-arizona-supreme-court-to-protect-right-to-a-jury-trial/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Goldwater Institute filed a brief in the Arizona Supreme Court today urging the justices to enforce the state constitution’s..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/goldwater-urges-arizona-supreme-court-to-protect-right-to-a-jury-trial/"&gt;Goldwater Urges Arizona Supreme Court to Protect Right to a Jury Trial&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 20:24:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Massachusetts Subsidized Housing Inventory Update Shows Record Number of Communities Exceed Critical Threshold</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/massachusetts-subsidized-housing-inventory-update-shows-record-number-of-communities-exceed-critical-threshold/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This edition of The House Call explores the 2025 update to Massachusetts&amp;#8217; Subsidized Housing Inventory, showing a spike in the number of communities that have at least 10% of their housing stocks in the Inventory. It also explains the housing-related ballot questions that could...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/massachusetts-subsidized-housing-inventory-update-shows-record-number-of-communities-exceed-critical-threshold/"&gt;Massachusetts Subsidized Housing Inventory Update Shows Record Number of Communities Exceed Critical Threshold&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 20:35:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Commissioner Andy Gipson: Family, Food Security, and Mississippi’s Future</title><link>https://empowerms.org/commissioner-andy-gipson-family-food-security-and-mississippis-future/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Commissioner Andy Gipson: Family, Food Security, and Mississippi’s Future On this episode of The Empower Podcast, host Grant Callen sits down with Commissioner Andy Gipson—Mississippi’s Commissioner of Agriculture and Commerce, former state legislator, Baptist minister, cattleman, and announced candidate for governor. Gipson shares how his journey into public service began with a desire to secure&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/commissioner-andy-gipson-family-food-security-and-mississippis-future/"&gt;Commissioner Andy Gipson: Family, Food Security, and Mississippi’s Future&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:49:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Did Dan Gilbert keep Detroit subsidy promises? The Freep is suing to find out</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/did-dan-gilbert-keep-detroit-subsidy-promises-the-freep-is-suing-to-find-out</link><description>Mackinac Center helps in freedom of information fight</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Does higher spending increase student outcomes?</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/does-higher-spending-increase-student-outcomes</link><description>The American education system is at a crossroads. The rise of AI, student apathy, the literacy crisis and recovery from the global COVID-19 pandemic and lockdowns are looming over the education system. American education is important. Just as low-quality steel will lead to a lower quality chassis of a car, poorly educated American workers will lead to a drop in quality of their respective vocations. At this stage of specialization in the American economy, it is more important than ever to...</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 15:16:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Nebraska Zoning Permitting Process: Recommended Adjustments in Nebraska</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-zoning-permitting-process-recommended-adjustments-in-nebraska/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Nebraska’s zoning and permitting process for livestock operations is inconsistent, unpredictable, and varies widely from county to county. This report examines how Nebraska’s Conditional Use Permit (CUP) system works, the origins and goals of the Livestock Siting Assessment Matrix created under LB106, and why the Matrix remains underused nearly a decade later. Drawing on survey...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-zoning-permitting-process-recommended-adjustments-in-nebraska/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Nebraska Zoning Permitting Process: Recommended Adjustments in Nebraska&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 15:17:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] WILL Hires Associate Counsel to Grow Legal and Policy Capacity in Wisconsin and Beyond</title><link>https://will-law.org/will-hires-associate-counsel-to-grow-legal-and-policy-capacity-in-wisconsin-and-beyond/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL has announced Erin Gamble as our new Associate Counsel. Her hire reflects our organization’s commitment to fighting back against bureaucratic overreach in Wisconsin and across the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/will-hires-associate-counsel-to-grow-legal-and-policy-capacity-in-wisconsin-and-beyond/"&gt;WILL Hires Associate Counsel to Grow Legal and Policy Capacity in Wisconsin and Beyond&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 15:23:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Care is Better When Patients Get a Choice</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/care-is-better-when-patients-get-a-choice/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Put a finger down if you’ve ever 1) had surgery or another medical procedure 2) received unexpected or confusing bills for the service 3) tried to understand the healthcare system to no avail 4) given up and concluded it’s all a racket where everyone but the patient has control over cost and quality.  If you...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/care-is-better-when-patients-get-a-choice/"&gt;Care is Better When Patients Get a Choice&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 16:05:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Texas Has Strengthened Its Grid, But It Is Still Vulnerable to the Next Winter Storm</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/texas-has-strengthened-its-grid-but-it-is-still-vulnerable-to-the-next-winter-storm/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;With Texas experiencing its first significant cold front of the winter season and the five-year anniversary of Winter Storm Uri on the horizon, it&amp;#8217;s worth taking stock of how far Texas has come on grid reliability—and how far it still needs to go. Uri, the disaster that left millions in the dark and claimed over...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/texas-has-strengthened-its-grid-but-it-is-still-vulnerable-to-the-next-winter-storm/"&gt;Texas Has Strengthened Its Grid, But It Is Still Vulnerable to the Next Winter Storm&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 20:00:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Webster Groves Should Not Institute an Economic Development Sales Tax</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/special-taxing-districts/webster-groves-should-not-institute-an-economic-development-sales-tax/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;There is a long list of really dumb taxes in Missouri. The St. Louis and Kansas City earnings taxes are [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/special-taxing-districts/webster-groves-should-not-institute-an-economic-development-sales-tax/"&gt;Webster Groves Should Not Institute an Economic Development Sales Tax&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 20:33:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] It Should Not Be This Difficult to Be Healthy — Especially in Idaho</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/it-should-not-be-this-difficult-to-be-healthy-especially-in-idaho/</link><description>Do you think it has become increasingly difficult to maintain good health in America in 2025? Does it ever feel as if the natural or traditional approaches to wellness — such as using holistic medicine, consuming raw milk, eating chemical-free foods, and toxin-free living — are the most regulated, while allopathic (Western) medicine, highly processed [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 20:43:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Will Advocates for More Water Supply Projects Find Unity?</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/will-advocates-for-more-water-supply-projects-find-unity/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=will-advocates-for-more-water-supply-projects-find-unity</link><description>&lt;p&gt;There’s only one way to restore reliable water allocations to farmers, avoid turning our cities into rationed “xeriscaped” heat islands, and cope with whatever the climate ultimately delivers. That’s to build more infrastructure to safely and sustainably produce millions of acre feet of new fresh water every year. There are many practical ways to accomplish...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/will-advocates-for-more-water-supply-projects-find-unity/"&gt;Will Advocates for More Water Supply Projects Find Unity?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 07:06:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] The choice that will determine Gretchen Whitmer’s future — and Michigan’s</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/the-choice-that-will-determine-gretchen-whitmers-future-and-michigans</link><description>Will the governor move toward the middle or continue moving left?</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Cutting Through the Red Tape — Bringing Personal Accountability Back to Florida</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/cutting-through-the-red-tape-bringing-personal-accountability-back-to-florida/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In his opening address for the 2025 legislative session, Speaker Daniel Perez challenged members to take a hard...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/cutting-through-the-red-tape-bringing-personal-accountability-back-to-florida/"&gt;Cutting Through the Red Tape — Bringing Personal Accountability Back to Florida&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Florida’s Rural Renaissance</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/floridas-rural-renaissance/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I’m a proud son of rural Florida, Florida’s Heartland, six generations deep.&amp;#160; Our small, tight-knit, legacy communities are...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/floridas-rural-renaissance/"&gt;Florida&amp;#8217;s Rural Renaissance&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] The 2025 Journal</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/the-2025-journal/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Click here to read the full version of The Journal. Table of Contents Florida&amp;#8217;s Rural Renaissance Senate Present...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/the-2025-journal/"&gt;The 2025 Journal&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Iowa Needs Stronger Spending Limits to Protect Taxpayers</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/iowa-needs-stronger-spending-limits-to-protect-taxpayers/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Iowa Needs Stronger Spending Limits to Protect Taxpayers" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/iowa-flag-money.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iowa’s current 99% spending limitation helps restrain spending but can be easily bypassed and doesn’t prevent government from growing faster than taxpayers’ ability to pay. Stronger fiscal rules, such as tying spending to population plus inflation, limiting tax increases, or constitutional protections, would build long-term stability and safeguard recent tax reforms. Conservative budgeting has already strengthened Iowa’s finances; maintaining it will protect taxpayers, support continued tax relief, and ensure sustainable budgeting in the future. Iowa has earned a reputation for responsible budgeting and strong fiscal management, especially compared to states facing deep financial trouble. As tax relief continues and our economy grows, Iowa must ensure that future budgets remain just as stable and sustainable as today’s. Strengthening our spending limits is one way to protect taxpayers, preserve Iowa’s fiscal momentum, and keep the state on a path toward long-term prosperity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/iowa-needs-stronger-spending-limits-to-protect-taxpayers/"&gt;Iowa Needs Stronger Spending Limits to Protect Taxpayers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 14:36:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Which states have the most debt? New report shows big divide</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/which-states-have-the-most-debt-new-report-shows-big-divide</link><description>Note: This is a joint op-ed with Mariana Trujillo  of the Reason Foundation. States and local governments across America have collectively accumulated over $6 trillion in liabilities, roughly $5 trillion of which are long-term obligations. These burdens are unevenly distributed. Some states keep a disciplined balance sheet, while others accumulate massive liabilities, requiring payments that crowd out present-day spending—to the detriment of both current taxpayers and future generations. The...</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 14:46:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Sedona’s Home-Sharing Ban Struck Down</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/sedonas-home-sharing-ban-struck-down/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Arizona’s Court of Appeals has delivered a major victory for private property rights, ruling that cities cannot bar homeowners from..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/sedonas-home-sharing-ban-struck-down/"&gt;Sedona’s Home-Sharing Ban Struck Down&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 15:10:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Iowa’s Fiscal Strength Remains If Lawmakers Hold the Line on Spending</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/iowas-fiscal-strength-remains-if-lawmakers-hold-the-line-on-spending/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Iowa’s Fiscal Strength Remains If Lawmakers Hold the Line on Spending" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/iowa-capitol-evening-clouds-1.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iowa, like South Dakota, faces economic uncertainty driven by multi-year weakness in the agricultural sector, with direct impacts on manufacturing, employment, and state tax revenue.&lt;br /&gt;
Despite national headwinds, revised GDP data and December REC estimates show Iowa is performing better than previously reported, offering cautious optimism heading into Fiscal Year 2027.&lt;br /&gt;
To maintain Iowa’s strong fiscal foundation—bolstered by the 3.8% flat tax, full reserve funds, and past conservative budgeting—lawmakers must restrain spending growth and avoid the fiscal pitfalls seen in neighboring high-tax states.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/iowas-fiscal-strength-remains-if-lawmakers-hold-the-line-on-spending/"&gt;Iowa’s Fiscal Strength Remains If Lawmakers Hold the Line on Spending&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 19:29:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Creating links that change lives: Georgia Center for Opportunity partners with Connect to Work GA</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/gco-partners-with-connect-to-work-ga/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This collaboration will help lift job seekers above the poverty line by providing opportunities for successful careers and upward mobility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/gco-partners-with-connect-to-work-ga/"&gt;Creating links that change lives: Georgia Center for Opportunity partners with Connect to Work GA&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 20:09:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Two-thirds of Americans under 30 say people can’t be trusted, Marquette poll finds</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/two-thirds-of-americans-under-30-say-people-cant-be-trusted-marquette-poll-finds/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Two-thirds of Americans under the age of 30 say they believe most people cannot be trusted, according to a recent nationwide Marquette University Law School poll.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/two-thirds-of-americans-under-30-say-people-cant-be-trusted-marquette-poll-finds/"&gt;Two-thirds of Americans under 30 say people can’t be trusted, Marquette poll finds&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 20:33:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Hawaii ‘certificate of need’ laws have ‘chilling effect’ on healthcare access</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/12/hawaii-certificate-of-need-laws-have-chilling-effect-on-healthcare-access/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following was issued as a news release by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii. A new Grassroot Institute of Hawaii white paper highlights the need for&amp;#160;state lawmakers to reform or repeal the state&amp;#8217;s CON regulations HONOLULU, Dec. 11, 2025 &amp;#62;&amp;#62; A new white paper issued by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii outlines specific actions Hawaii [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/12/hawaii-certificate-of-need-laws-have-chilling-effect-on-healthcare-access/"&gt;Hawaii &amp;#8216;certificate of need&amp;#8217; laws have &amp;#8216;chilling effect&amp;#8217; on healthcare access&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 20:38:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] From Promises to Vetoes: Hochul’s Actions Belie Her Commitment to Transparency</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/from-promises-to-vetoes-hochuls-actions-belie-her-commitment-to-transparency/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Governor Kathy Hochul made news this fall when she used her legislative veto power in a way that looked personal.....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/from-promises-to-vetoes-hochuls-actions-belie-her-commitment-to-transparency/"&gt;From Promises to Vetoes: Hochul&amp;#8217;s Actions Belie Her Commitment to Transparency&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 20:54:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Legislature balks as Evers demands millions for more food aid bureaucrats</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/legislature-balks-as-evers-demands-millions-for-more-food-aid-bureaucrats/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Gov. Tony Evers is pressing the Legislature for $70 million to process FoodShare applications to stave off federal penalties that could cost state taxpayers as much as $225 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/legislature-balks-as-evers-demands-millions-for-more-food-aid-bureaucrats/"&gt;Legislature balks as Evers demands millions for more food aid bureaucrats&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 21:58:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Proposal 066: Require fiscal impact assessments for proposed Council legislation and Charter amendments</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/12/proposal-066-require-fiscal-impact-assessments-for-proposed-council-legislation-and-charter-amendments/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii 2025 Honolulu Charter amendment proposal_____________ The following text was submitted recently to the 2025 Honolulu Charter Commission for consideration as an amendment to the Honolulu City Charter, with final approval to be determined by popular vote in the 2026 general election. The questions being answered were posed by the Commission._____________ What [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/12/proposal-066-require-fiscal-impact-assessments-for-proposed-council-legislation-and-charter-amendments/"&gt;Proposal 066: Require fiscal impact assessments for proposed Council legislation and Charter amendments&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 01:33:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Look Up: Your Bodily Autonomy and Property Rights Are Being Attacked From the Sky</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/look-up-your-bodily-autonomy-and-property-rights-are-being-attacked-from-the-sky/</link><description>Want to have some fun at your holiday family gathering this year? Ask your fellow party-goers what they think about cloud seeding. Are those lines in the sky merely contrails, or signs of weather modification, or some sort of atmospheric experimentation? You’ll soon find a variety of answers, speculation, opinion, and theory — from genuine [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 01:40:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Republican aims to take ‘top cop’ job in New York state</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/republican-aims-to-take-top-cop-job-in-new-york-state/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Jon Levine writes for the Washington Free Beacon about an interesting political campaign in a deep blue state. Saritha Komatireddy believes in longshots, she told the Washington Free Beacon. Komatireddy, a 41-year-old mother of four and former federal prosecutor, announced her candidacy for New York attorney general last week as a Republican in a state...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/republican-aims-to-take-top-cop-job-in-new-york-state/"&gt;Republican aims to take &amp;#8216;top cop&amp;#8217; job in New York state&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 10:36:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] State Department makes significanct change on the page</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/state-department-makes-significanct-change-on-the-page/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Elle Purnell of the Federalist explores a recent State Department policy change. The State Department’s rejection of the Biden-era Calibri font for Times New Roman might not be the Trump administration’s most consequential decision, but that doesn’t mean it doesn’t matter. On Tuesday, Secretary of State Marco Rubio circulated a memo declaring the serif font...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/state-department-makes-significanct-change-on-the-page/"&gt;State Department makes significanct change on the page&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 10:39:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Maryland’s governor faces scrutiny for holes in resume</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/marylands-governor-faces-scrutiny-for-holes-in-resume/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Scott Johnson of the Powerline blog ponders questions surrounding a rising star in Democratic politics. Democrat Maryland Governor Wes Moore is an ambitious guy. The Washington Free Beacon now does its thing giving Moore the kind of treatment the New York Times loves to give to Republicans. As always, however, the Free Beacon’s story is...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/marylands-governor-faces-scrutiny-for-holes-in-resume/"&gt;Maryland&amp;#8217;s governor faces scrutiny for holes in resume&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 10:42:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] ‘I truly believe this will transform education’</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/podcasts/the-overton-window/chris-watson-discusses-how-ai-can-help-teachers-improve-student-outcomes</link><description>Chris Waston discusses how AI can help teachers improve student outcomes</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Understanding Iowa’s School Income Surtax</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/understanding-iowas-school-income-surtax/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Understanding Iowa’s School Income Surtax" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/income-surtax.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iowa’s school income surtax, first adopted in 1971, is a district-level tax calculated as a percentage of a taxpayer’s Iowa income tax liability and used to support discretionary school programs.&lt;br /&gt;
Districts may combine the surtax with property taxes to fund the Instructional Support Levy (ISL) and the voter-approved Physical Plant and Equipment Levy (PPEL), adjusting the surtax rate annually to meet budget needs.&lt;br /&gt;
Over the past twenty years, the number of districts not using the surtax has steadily declined, making it an increasingly common but still little-understood part of Iowa’s school finance system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/understanding-iowas-school-income-surtax/"&gt;Understanding Iowa’s School Income Surtax&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 14:07:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Why Missouri Needs Early Literacy Reform with Cory Koedel and Avery Frank</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/education/why-missouri-needs-early-literacy-reform-with-cory-koedel-and-avery-frank/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Susan Pendergrass is joined by Cory Koedel, director of education policy at the Show-Me Institute, and Avery Frank, policy analyst [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/education/why-missouri-needs-early-literacy-reform-with-cory-koedel-and-avery-frank/"&gt;Why Missouri Needs Early Literacy Reform with Cory Koedel and Avery Frank&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 15:16:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] A prescription for fraud? GAO finds serious abuses in Obamacare exchanges</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/a-prescription-for-fraud-gao-finds-serious-abuses-in-obamacare-exchanges</link><description>Remember when Americans were told that the Affordable Care Act (also known as Obamacare) would lower health care costs and that if you liked your doctor, you could keep her? How things have changed over the past 15 years. Health care costs continue to rise faster than inflation and millions of Americans have discovered that their health insurance plans don’t cover their chosen physician. As the saying goes, to add insult to injury, the Government Accountability Office (GAO) recently released...</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 15:21:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Minnesota Man of the Day</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/minnesota-man-of-the-day-10/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Oluwadamilola Ogooluwa Bamigboye is our Minnesota Man of the Day for December 12. He is a Nigerian native but currently resides in Plymouth. Mr. Bamigboye was the subject of those dramatic headlines this week, like this one by KARE-11, FBI investigating after federal agent allegedly kidnapped by detainee in Minnesota According to the federal complaint...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/minnesota-man-of-the-day-10/"&gt;Minnesota Man of the Day&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 16:20:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] GAO Provides Yet More Evidence for Why Enhanced Obamacare Subsidies Must Expire</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/gao-provides-yet-more-evidence-for-why-enhanced-obamacare-subsidies-must-expire/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Defrauding the government through Obamacare&amp;#8217;s insurance exchanges is shockingly easy, per a new government report. The study found that federal insurance subsidies were granted for 90 percent of the fake exchange accounts set up as part of a Government Accountability Office investigation &amp;#8212; at a cost of more than $10,000 a month. Read the entire [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/gao-provides-yet-more-evidence-for-why-enhanced-obamacare-subsidies-must-expire/"&gt;GAO Provides Yet More Evidence for Why Enhanced Obamacare Subsidies Must Expire&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 16:33:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] “Fully Funded Schools” Are a Moving Goal Post</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/education/fully-funded-schools-are-a-moving-goal-post/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Kathryn Hickok How much money does it take to “fully fund” Oregon’s...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/education/fully-funded-schools-are-a-moving-goal-post/"&gt;“Fully Funded Schools” Are a Moving Goal Post&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 17:22:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Winners &amp; Losers: Watching the Data &amp; the History</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/winners-losers-watching-the-data-the-history/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Every Friday morning, I join the Cardle &amp;#38; Woolley Show on Talk 1370 Radio in Austin to announce the week’s Winners &amp;#38; Losers. Amid the joys of this holy season and the machinations of the College Football Playoff bracket, here’s the list for this week: &amp;#160; WINNER: Paying Attention to History White House Chief of...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/winners-losers-watching-the-data-the-history/"&gt;Winners &amp; Losers: Watching the Data &amp; the History&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 17:37:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Taxpayers Asked to Fund a Hospital Takeover They’re Not Allowed to See</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/12/12/taxpayers-asked-to-fund-a-hospital-takeover-theyre-not-allowed-to-see/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Connecticut lawmakers pushed the UConn Health hospital acquisition bill through the November special session — without a public hearing — it was clear transparency was not the priority.   [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/12/12/taxpayers-asked-to-fund-a-hospital-takeover-theyre-not-allowed-to-see/"&gt;Taxpayers Asked to Fund a Hospital Takeover They’re Not Allowed to See&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 18:13:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Federal DOJ sues Minneapolis Public Schools for racial discrimination</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/federal-doj-sues-minneapolis-public-schools-for-racial-discrimination/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The collective bargaining agreement between Minneapolis Public Schools (MPS) and the teacher&amp;#8217;s union, Minneapolis Federation of Educators (MFE) has landed the district in hot water with the federal Department of Justice. The filing claims that the school district is in violation of Title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964, and currently&amp;#160;discriminates against teachers...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/federal-doj-sues-minneapolis-public-schools-for-racial-discrimination/"&gt;Federal DOJ sues Minneapolis Public Schools for racial discrimination&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 18:47:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] San Francisco wants to control what you eat</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/san-francisco-wants-to-control-what-you-eat/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Food choices? Those are for the government to decide. That’s the message behind a lawsuit filed by San Francisco City Attorney David Chiu against &amp;#8220;some of the country’s largest manufacturers of ultra-processed foods.&amp;#8221; It is the first government lawsuit in the nation against food companies. Chiu’s office claims &amp;#8220;the proliferation of ultra-processed foods in the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/san-francisco-wants-to-control-what-you-eat/"&gt;San Francisco wants to control what you eat&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 19:35:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Chicago business activity skid hits two years</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/chicago-business-activity-skid-hits-two-years/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A barometer of business health shows Chicago’s decline worsened in November 2025. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/chicago-business-activity-skid-hits-two-years/"&gt;Chicago business activity skid hits two years&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 19:40:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Why reforming PBMs is the key to lowering drug costs</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/why-reforming-pbms-is-the-key-to-lowering-drug-costs/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;If lawmakers want to make pharmaceuticals more affordable, they should look past populist policies like price controls that will only make matters worse and set their sights on reforming the Pharmacy Benefit Manager market. PBMs manage the drug benefits for insurers and negotiate discounts with drug manufacturers. You probably use one every time you go [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/why-reforming-pbms-is-the-key-to-lowering-drug-costs/"&gt;Why reforming PBMs is the key to lowering drug costs&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 19:43:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] When Past Meets Present: Russian California and the Monroe Doctrine</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/when-past-meets-present/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=when-past-meets-present</link><description>&lt;p&gt;During this week’s Radio Free California podcast, cohosts David Bahnsen and myself discussed the return of the Monroe Doctrine, now offered as the logic behind the Trump administration’s decision to blow up Venezuelan drug boats and to invite that country’s president, Nicolás Maduro, to step outside. It’s unlikely most Americans know that the doctrine, which President James Monroe...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/when-past-meets-present/"&gt;When Past Meets Present: Russian California and the Monroe Doctrine&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 19:46:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Week in Review:  Stamping Out a Trash Monopoly</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-stamping-out-a-trash-monopoly/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The government should not be in the business of protecting preferred service providers from competition—it’s a key principle of economic..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-stamping-out-a-trash-monopoly/"&gt;Week in Review:  Stamping Out a Trash Monopoly&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 20:32:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Most Chicagoans, aldermen oppose Johnson’s 2026 budget</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/most-chicagoans-aldermen-oppose-johnsons-2026-budget/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Most Chicago City Council members and residents oppose Mayor Brandon Johnson’s 2026 budget, especially his plan to tax job creation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/most-chicagoans-aldermen-oppose-johnsons-2026-budget/"&gt;Most Chicagoans, aldermen oppose Johnson’s 2026 budget&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 20:44:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Walz names anti-fraud czar</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/walz-names-anti-fraud-czar/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;From a Tim Walz press release, Governor Tim Walz today announced that Tim O’Malley will join the state as Director of Program Integrity. A judge, former superintendent of the Minnesota Bureau of Criminal Apprehension (BCA), former FBI agent, and reformer in the archdiocese, O’Malley will work across state government to strengthen fraud prevention and protect...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/walz-names-anti-fraud-czar/"&gt;Walz names anti-fraud czar&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 20:54:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Would you invest in Massachusetts or New Hampshire?</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/12/would-you-invest-in-massachusetts-or-new-hampshire/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;If U.S. states were companies that traded on the stock market, the only New England state with a “buy” rating would probably be New Hampshire.  Massachusetts could be called “Big Blue,” the tradition-bound leader cruising on its prior reputation, but falling behind smaller upstarts that have embraced innovation and rapid growth.  New Hampshire would be [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/12/would-you-invest-in-massachusetts-or-new-hampshire/"&gt;Would you invest in Massachusetts or New Hampshire?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 21:10:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Proposal 064: Streamline housing approvals via reform of zoning variance hearing and notice rules</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/12/proposal-064-streamline-housing-approvals-via-reform-of-zoning-variance-hearing-and-notice-rules/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii 2025 Honolulu Charter amendment proposal_____________ The following text was submitted recently to the 2025 Honolulu Charter Commission for consideration as an amendment to the Honolulu City Charter, with final approval to be determined by popular vote in the 2026 general election. The questions being answered were posed by the Commission.______________ What issue or [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/12/proposal-064-streamline-housing-approvals-via-reform-of-zoning-variance-hearing-and-notice-rules/"&gt;Proposal 064: Streamline housing approvals via reform of zoning variance hearing and notice rules&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 21:30:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Report offers $1B in fixes as Chicago budget talks break down</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/report-offers-1b-in-fixes-as-chicago-budget-talks-break-down/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Chicago City Council rejected Mayor Brandon Johnson’s economically harmful tax proposals, but a report offers $1 billion in solutions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/report-offers-1b-in-fixes-as-chicago-budget-talks-break-down/"&gt;Report offers $1B in fixes as Chicago budget talks break down&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 22:31:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Louisiana’s Path to Economic Prosperity and Energy Dominance Runs Through Free Markets</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/energy/pathtoeconomicprosperityandenergydominance/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier this month, Entergy Louisiana broke ground on two of three new gas-fired power plants designed to serve Meta’s $10 billion AI-optimized data center in Richland Parish. That project is just one of more than 200 major industrial investments now in Louisiana’s pipeline—and nearly all have the same top concern: access to reliable, affordable electricity....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/energy/pathtoeconomicprosperityandenergydominance/"&gt;Louisiana’s Path to Economic Prosperity and Energy Dominance Runs Through Free Markets&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 00:34:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Time Is Running Out: Legislature Must Fully Fund LA GATOR to Deliver for Louisiana’s Kids</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/education/time-is-running-out-legislature-must-fully-fund-la-gator-to-deliver-for-louisianas-kids/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As Louisiana lawmakers gear up for the 2026 regular legislative session, one issue stands out as both urgent and transformative: fully funding the Louisiana Giving All True Opportunity to Rise (LA GATOR) program. Enacted in 2024 as one of the nation&amp;#8217;s most comprehensive universal education savings account (ESA) initiatives, LA GATOR promises to empower families...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/education/time-is-running-out-legislature-must-fully-fund-la-gator-to-deliver-for-louisianas-kids/"&gt;Time Is Running Out: Legislature Must Fully Fund LA GATOR to Deliver for Louisiana’s Kids&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 01:01:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] The Battle for Health Freedom Isn’t Over: Let’s Fight for Children</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/the-battle-for-health-freedom-isnt-over-lets-fight-for-children/</link><description>Idaho’s “Medical Freedom Act (MFA)” protects adults from employers, businesses, government agencies, or other entities imposing medical interventions on them, including vaccines. . Enacted this past July, the MFA protects adults from being coerced into using medical products, devices, substances, injections, or any technology, in any form. It’s simple - bodily autonomy is a fundamental, [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 02:39:54 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>