<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>State-Policy Think-Tank Digest</title><link>https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml</link><description>Latest posts from free-market policy institutes across the U.S.</description><atom:link href="https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 09:03:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>[Foropportunity] New Report: Corrections spending rises in Georgia even as prison population declines</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/new-report-corrections-spending-rises-in-georgia/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A new report by Joshua Crawford, Public Safety Fellow at the Georgia Center for Opportunity, shows that the decreasing number of inmates hasn’t translated to meaningful savings or improvements in public safety for Georgians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/new-report-corrections-spending-rises-in-georgia/"&gt;New Report: Corrections spending rises in Georgia even as prison population declines&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 23:02:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Tariffs – why we will hear a lot more about them</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/tariffs-why-we-will-hear-a-lot-more-about-them/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Remember the tariff debates that dominated Washington just a few months ago?&amp;#160; For a while it was the only thing anyone seemed to talk about.&amp;#160;First tariffs were raised by eyewatering amounts.&amp;#160; Then they weren’t.&amp;#160;&amp;#160;Eventually, after all sorts of back and forth, we saw tariffs imposed at the highest rates in decades. Free trade advocates warned [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/tariffs-why-we-will-hear-a-lot-more-about-them/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Tariffs – why we will hear a lot more about them&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 16:00:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF provides comments in support of unlocking new water supplies for New Mexicans</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-provides-comments-in-support-of-unlocking-new-water-supplies-for-new-mexicans/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;They say &amp;#8220;agua es vida&amp;#8221; in New Mexico (water is life). In the desert southwest water is critical to human flourishing and the broader economy of the state and region. So, when we were presented with an opportunity to put water that is produced alongside oil and gas, we had only one question: &amp;#8220;Is it [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-provides-comments-in-support-of-unlocking-new-water-supplies-for-new-mexicans/"&gt;RGF provides comments in support of unlocking new water supplies for New Mexicans&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 16:38:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Accountability and Action: The Path to Safer Communities</title><link>https://empowerms.org/accountability-and-action-the-path-to-safer-communities/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This past weekend, our state was rocked by a wave of violent crime. Over the course of twenty-four hours, five shootings claimed the lives of at least nine Mississippians. While these horrific acts do not appear to be connected, they are alarming nevertheless. Words like horrific, tragic, and avoidable all come to mind. First and&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/accountability-and-action-the-path-to-safer-communities/"&gt;Accountability and Action: The Path to Safer Communities&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 14:16:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] New Statewide Ad Calls Out Governor Shapiro For Budget Impasse</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/10/19/new-statewide-ad-end-the-impasse-governor-shapiro/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Harrisburg, Pa., October 19, 2025 —&amp;#160;The Commonwealth Foundation has launched a new statewide ad calling on Gov. Josh Shapiro to end the state budget impasse by getting to work negotiating a bipartisan, fiscally responsible compromise that protects Pennsylvania taxpayers. Pennsylvania remains the only state in the nation without a state budget. The new ad calls [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/10/19/new-statewide-ad-end-the-impasse-governor-shapiro/"&gt;New Statewide Ad Calls Out Governor Shapiro For Budget Impasse&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 23:35:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] The Federal Shutdown Explained: What it Means for Maine</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/the-federal-shutdown-explained-what-it-means-for-maine/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Congress isn’t known as the place for bipartisan cooperation, but since October 1, inter-party arguing has led to a shutdown of the federal government. This has caused the closing of offices, the suspension of services, and the placing of hundreds of thousands of workers on furlough. The reason, as usual, is infuriating but straightforward: Congress [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/the-federal-shutdown-explained-what-it-means-for-maine/"&gt;The Federal Shutdown Explained: What it Means for Maine&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 19:26:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] Pennsylvania Senate Passes Budget Plan, RGGI Abrogation, Regulatory Reform</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/10/22/pennsylvania-senate-passes-budget-plan/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Harrisburg, Pa., October 22, 2025&amp;#160;— This week, the Pennsylvania Senate advanced legislation, including a spending bill (Senate Bill 160), that protects taxpayers and fosters economic growth. The commonwealth remains the only state in the country without an operating budget or stop gap plan. Now weeks into a federal government shutdown, Pennsylvania’s four-month-long impasse holds the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/10/22/pennsylvania-senate-passes-budget-plan/"&gt;Pennsylvania Senate Passes Budget Plan, RGGI Abrogation, Regulatory Reform&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 18:11:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG CIO Submits Request to DPI Seeking Teacher Licensing and Misconduct Scandal Public Records</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-cio-submits-request-to-dpi-seeking-teacher-licensing-and-misconduct-scandal-public-records/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government’s (IRG) Center for Investigative Oversight (CIO) submitted a public records request to the Wisconsin Department of Public Instruction (DPI), seeking to uncover details surrounding the Department’s handling of teacher licenses for educators accused of misconduct and grooming. Recent reporting by The Capital Times revealed serious concerns surrounding [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-cio-submits-request-to-dpi-seeking-teacher-licensing-and-misconduct-scandal-public-records/"&gt;IRG CIO Submits Request to DPI Seeking Teacher Licensing and Misconduct Scandal Public Records&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 19:07:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] New Jersey’s Bag Ban Backfired. Repeal It—and Cut Waste the Smart Way.</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/10/new-jerseys-bag-ban-backfired-repeal-it-and-cut-waste-the-smart-way/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Wells Winegar, Executive Director, New Jersey Policy Institute (NJPI) &amp;#160; Walk into any New Jersey kitchen and open the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/10/new-jerseys-bag-ban-backfired-repeal-it-and-cut-waste-the-smart-way/"&gt;New Jersey’s Bag Ban Backfired. Repeal It—and Cut Waste the Smart Way.&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 19:51:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] If Lawmakers Are Trying to Defund Public Education, They Aren’t Very Good at It</title><link>https://empowerms.org/if-lawmakers-are-trying-to-defund-public-education-they-arent-very-good-at-it/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;You’ve probably heard the claim that Mississippi’s Republican leaders are “defunding” public education, and that school choice is just another way to siphon dollars away from public schools. But if that’s true, they’re doing a remarkably bad job of it.  Over the past decade, Mississippi has dramatically increased its investment in public education. According to&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/if-lawmakers-are-trying-to-defund-public-education-they-arent-very-good-at-it/"&gt;If Lawmakers Are Trying to Defund Public Education, They Aren’t Very Good at It&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 02:00:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Nebraska’s Tax Treatment of Non-Profits</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/nebraskas-tax-treatment-of-non-profits/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The origins of favorable tax treatment for nonprofit and not-for-profit organizations in the United States were based on the admirable ideals promoting community service and public good.    However, today the United States’ federally tax-exempt economy makes up 15% of gross domestic output (GDP) and spans 1.8 million organizations. A total of $3.3 trillion dollars of...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/nebraskas-tax-treatment-of-non-profits/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Nebraska&amp;#8217;s Tax Treatment of Non-Profits&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 19:37:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Tennessee’s Time for Energy Abundance</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/tennessees-time-for-energy-abundance/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=tennessees-time-for-energy-abundance</link><description>By embracing Tennessee's nuclear roots, small modular reactor and micro modular reactor technologies will have a chance to thrive in a new era of energy independence.</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 19:39:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] The Good, Bad, and Ugly of 2nd Session Bill Requests</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/the-good-bad-and-ugly-of-2nd-session-bill-requests/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Legislative Council has released the list of bill titles under consideration for the Maine Legislature’s 2026 legislative session, and on October 23, the Council met for an initial bill screening. The full list of results is available here.&amp;#160; The Legislative Council is made up of 10 members of legislative leadership. For a bill request [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/the-good-bad-and-ugly-of-2nd-session-bill-requests/"&gt;The Good, Bad, and Ugly of 2nd Session Bill Requests&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 19:40:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] Court ratifies City of Albuquerque donation to Planned Parenthood</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/court-ratifies-city-of-albuquerque-donation-to-planned-parenthood/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In what can only be described as a ruling based on twisted logic a New Mexico District Judge (Denise Barela Shepherd) has decided that it is somehow NOT a violation of New Mexico&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8220;anti-donation clause&amp;#8221; for the City of Albuquerque to explicitly donation $250,000 of our tax dollars to Planned Parenthood.  Our friends at the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/court-ratifies-city-of-albuquerque-donation-to-planned-parenthood/"&gt;Court ratifies City of Albuquerque donation to Planned Parenthood&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 22:24:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Kansas Doesn’t Need Medicaid Expansion — It Needs to Empower Patients</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/kansas-doesnt-need-medicaid-expansion/</link><description>Governor Laura Kelly’s Healthcare Access for Working Kansans (HAWK) Act was sold as a “middle-of-the-road” plan to expand Medicaid to 150,000 more Kansans when it was introduced during the 2025 legislative session. But there’s nothing moderate about growing a failing federal program that already leaves millions of patients nationwide waiting in line for care. Expanding [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 15:00:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] New Video Exposes How Unions Trap Public Employees in Membership</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/press-release/new-video-exposes-how-unions-trap-public-employees-in-membership/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Freedom Foundation today released a new video exposing the deliberate obstacles unions place in front of public employees trying to exercise their constitutional right to leave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/press-release/new-video-exposes-how-unions-trap-public-employees-in-membership/" rel="nofollow"&gt;New Video Exposes How Unions Trap Public Employees in Membership&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 15:22:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Frightfully pricey treats: Why Halloween fun is costing Georgia families more</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/georgia-halloween-candy-prices/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As Halloween approaches, Georgia families look forward to making great memories involving adorable costumes and fun candy hauls. But candy prices have become nothing short of scary for families trying to make ends meet. Here's why prices are on the rise for Georgia's favorite Halloween treats. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/georgia-halloween-candy-prices/"&gt;Frightfully pricey treats: Why Halloween fun is costing Georgia families more&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 16:01:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] PRESS RELEASE: Governor Reeves and Rich Lowry Highlight Mississippi's Success</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/press-release-governor-reeves-and-rich-lowry-highlight-mississippis-success/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASEOctober 28, 2025 Mississippi Center for Public Policy Celebrates Statewide Success with Governor Tate Reeves and National Review Editor Rich Lowry Jackson, Miss. — October 28, 2025 — The Mississippi Center for Public Policy hosted its Celebration of Mississippi Success Gala on Thursday, October 23, at the Country Club of Jackson, honoring the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/press-release-governor-reeves-and-rich-lowry-highlight-mississippis-success/" rel="nofollow"&gt;PRESS RELEASE: Governor Reeves and Rich Lowry Highlight Mississippi&amp;#039;s Success&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 19:43:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Mayor John Horhn: Jackson Rising</title><link>https://empowerms.org/mayor-john-horhn-jackson-rising/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Mayor John Horhn: Jackson Rising What does it take to turn around a city? In this special episode recorded at Jackson City Hall, host Grant Callen talks with Mayor John Horhn about his love for Jackson, the lessons from his childhood and career in public service, and his mission to restore trust, safety, and opportunity&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/mayor-john-horhn-jackson-rising/"&gt;Mayor John Horhn: Jackson Rising&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 01:00:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG Court Watch: Options for Structural Reforms for our Courts</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-court-watch-options-for-structural-reforms-for-our-courts/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;IRG Court Watch: Options for Structural Reforms for our Courts Voters Open to Reform after Multi-Million Dollar, Partisan Judicial Elections Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government’s (IRG)‘s Court Watch initiative released a report, Structural Reform of Judicial Selection in Wisconsin, detailing potential structural reforms to strengthen judicial integrity and public trust in Wisconsin [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-court-watch-options-for-structural-reforms-for-our-courts/"&gt;IRG Court Watch: Options for Structural Reforms for our Courts&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 13:38:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Harvard’s Leo Damrosch on Robert Louis Stevenson &amp; Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/harvards-leo-damrosch-on-robert-louis-stevenson-dr-jekyll-and-mr-hyde/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In this week’s episode of The Learning Curve, co-hosts U-Arkansas Prof. Albert Cheng and Great Hearts Academies’ Dr. Helen Baxendale interview Leo Damrosch, Ernest Bernbaum Professor of Literature Emeritus at Harvard University, and acclaimed biographer of some of the world's greatest literary figures. Prof. Damrosch discusses his newest book Storyteller: The Life of Robert Louis Stevenson. He reflects on Stevenson's childhood in Scotland and the close relationship he maintained with his nanny, Alison Cunningham. He shares how Stevenson lived an adventurous life, with his travel inspiring classics like Treasure Island, Kidnapped, and A Child’s Garden of Verses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/harvards-leo-damrosch-on-robert-louis-stevenson-dr-jekyll-and-mr-hyde/"&gt;Harvard’s Leo Damrosch on Robert Louis Stevenson &amp;#038; Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 15:27:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] New Study Shows Success of School Choice in Action</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/new-study-shows-success-of-school-choice-in-action/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=new-study-shows-success-of-school-choice-in-action</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As California wallows in continued low student performance, a new study shows that school choice is making a positive difference in student outcomes in Arkansas. Recently released scores on California’s state tests in English and math show huge proportions of students failing to achieve proficiency in the basic subjects. More than half of California students...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/new-study-shows-success-of-school-choice-in-action/"&gt;New Study Shows Success of School Choice in Action&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 21:49:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Dear PPS Bond Committee: Please Tell the Taxpayers</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/testimony/testimony-before-the-pps-bond-accountability-committee/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By John A. Charles, Jr. Cascade’s president, John Charles, testified online at the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/testimony/testimony-before-the-pps-bond-accountability-committee/"&gt;Dear PPS Bond Committee: Please Tell the Taxpayers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 23:13:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Nichols v. DOT</title><link>https://will-law.org/nichols-v-dot/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL is challenging a state law that unlawfully restricts Wisconsin drivers’ First Amendment rights. The state uses subjective and arbitrary decisions to decide what drivers can print on their personalized license plates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/nichols-v-dot/"&gt;Nichols v. DOT&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 13:52:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Debunking 2 more property tax myths: setting mill rates and blaming legislators for unfunded mandates</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/2-property-tax-myths-mill-rates-unfunded-mandates/</link><description>Last month, we debunked several property tax myths that some local officials are using to shift the blame for their unaffordable tax increases, and now there are two more excuses to address. For years, many local officials tried to blame County Clerks for setting mill rates, saying something along the lines of ‘we just set [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 15:31:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Killing the I&amp;D Tax leaps N.H. to No. 3 on national tax competitiveness index</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/10/killing-the-id-tax-leaps-n-h-to-no-3-on-national-tax-competitiveness-index/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Killing New Hampshire’s Interest &amp;#38; Dividends Tax has breathed new life into the New Hampshire Advantage. That’s the conclusion from reading the Tax Foundation’s 2026 State Tax Competitiveness Index, released on Oct. 30.  Last year, New Hampshire slipped past Texas to claim the No. 6 spot on the index. Passing the famously conservative and economically [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/10/killing-the-id-tax-leaps-n-h-to-no-3-on-national-tax-competitiveness-index/"&gt;Killing the I&amp;#038;D Tax leaps N.H. to No. 3 on national tax competitiveness index&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 17:51:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Large Scale Desalination Could Transform California</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/large-scale-desalination-could-transform-california/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=large-scale-desalination-could-transform-california</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Why is it axiomatic among California’s water agencies and policymakers that large scale desalination is inconceivable in California? That certainly isn’t the case in other arid locales. In 2024, an estimated 30 million acre feet of fresh water was produced by desalination plants worldwide. On the coast of the Red Sea, about 60 miles south of the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/large-scale-desalination-could-transform-california/"&gt;Large Scale Desalination Could Transform California&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 17:53:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Honoring Courage: Elijah Stacy, Goldwater’s 2025 Freedom Award Winner</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/honoring-courage-elijah-stacy-goldwaters-2025-freedom-award-winner/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Goldwater Institute is proud to honor Elijah Stacy as the recipient of our 2025 Freedom Award. Elijah’s unwavering courage,..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/honoring-courage-elijah-stacy-goldwaters-2025-freedom-award-winner/"&gt;Honoring Courage: Elijah Stacy, Goldwater&amp;#8217;s 2025 Freedom Award Winner&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 19:49:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Parsing the Impact of Mamdani’s Tax Hike Plans</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/parsing-the-impact-of-mamdanis-tax-hike-plans/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The front-running candidate for New York City mayor, Zohran Mamdani, has said he can finance his costly campaign promises –....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/parsing-the-impact-of-mamdanis-tax-hike-plans/"&gt;Parsing the Impact of Mamdani&amp;#8217;s Tax Hike Plans&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 20:28:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Maine’s 2025 Ballot Questions: What Voters Should Know</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/maines-2025-ballot-questions-what-voters-should-know/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As Maine heads into the 2025 election, voters will face two ballot questions that cut to the heart of the state’s debates over election integrity and gun rights. Both questions resurrect legislative fights that failed in Augusta and are now placed directly before the people. Ballot Question 1: Election Integrity Ballot Summary:“Do you want to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/maines-2025-ballot-questions-what-voters-should-know/"&gt;Maine’s 2025 Ballot Questions: What Voters Should Know&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 21:09:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] As hunger looms, Democrats in ‘non-winnable’ situation</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/as-hunger-looms-democrats-in-non-winnable-situation/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;“Democrats put themselves in the situation we’re in, and it’s non-winnable,” says Rachidi, a researcher who has written extensively about FoodShare and SNAP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/as-hunger-looms-democrats-in-non-winnable-situation/"&gt;As hunger looms, Democrats in ‘non-winnable’ situation&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 21:22:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Beacon Wins Final Approval in $1.4 Million Stormwater Settlement, Bringing Justice to Nashville Homeowners</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/beacon-wins-final-approval-in-1-4-million-stormwater-settlement-bringing-justice-to-nashville-homeowners/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=beacon-wins-final-approval-in-1-4-million-stormwater-settlement-bringing-justice-to-nashville-homeowners</link><description>This ruling is a landmark win for property owners and sends a clear message that government overreach will not go unchecked.</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 21:26:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] WI Speaks Polling Results</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/wi-speaks-survey-results/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WI 1023 Toplines (1) WI 1023 Summary of Key Findings (2) WI 1023 Summary of Key Findings (2)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/wi-speaks-survey-results/"&gt;WI Speaks Polling Results&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 00:18:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Virginiainstitute] Examining HJ6007 and Its Implications for Virginia’s Redistricting Process</title><link>https://virginiainstitute.org/examining-hj6007/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=examining-hj6007</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As lawmakers consider HJ6007, Virginians are asking how the proposal aligns with the 2020 constitutional amendment supporting fair maps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org/examining-hj6007/"&gt;Examining HJ6007 and Its Implications for Virginia’s Redistricting Process&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org"&gt;Virginia Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 01:53:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] NYC Employees Receive $300k+ in Overtime</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/nyc-employees-receive-300k-in-overtime/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Two New York City employees received more than $300,000 in overtime payouts, according to fiscal year 2025 payroll data posted....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/nyc-employees-receive-300k-in-overtime/"&gt;NYC Employees Receive $300k+ in Overtime&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 13:20:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Florida Politics: No, Georgia, It’s Not a Trick; Florida Just Wants To Share a Kid-Friendly Treat</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/florida-politics-no-georgia-its-not-a-trick-florida-just-wants-to-share-a-kid-friendly-treat/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As Saturday’s&amp;#160;Georgia-Florida game&amp;#160;approaches, much attention is being paid to the fact that the Gators just fired their head...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/florida-politics-no-georgia-its-not-a-trick-florida-just-wants-to-share-a-kid-friendly-treat/"&gt;Florida Politics: No, Georgia, It’s Not a Trick; Florida Just Wants To Share a Kid-Friendly Treat&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 14:08:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Week in Review: $117K to see what a school is teaching?</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-117k-to-see-what-a-school-is-teaching/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When a Rhode Island teacher made headlines for publishing videos celebrating the assassination of conservative activist Charlie Kirk, one local..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-117k-to-see-what-a-school-is-teaching/"&gt;Week in Review: $117K to see what a school is teaching?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 15:54:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] CT State Police Lieutenant Made $259K Last Year — Half from Overtime He Approved Himself</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/10/31/ct-state-police-lieutenant-made-259k-last-year-half-from-overtime-he-approved-himself/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a law-enforcement agency allows its own managers to approve their own pay, accountability isn’t just missing — it’s broken.  For years, the Connecticut State Police have paid out tens [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/10/31/ct-state-police-lieutenant-made-259k-last-year-half-from-overtime-he-approved-himself/"&gt;CT State Police Lieutenant Made $259K Last Year — Half from Overtime He Approved Himself &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 19:06:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] PRESS RELEASE: MISSISSIPPI CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY HONORS LEGISLATIVE HEROES AT ANNUAL GALA CELEBRATING STATE SUCCESS</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/press-release-mississippi-center-for-public-policy-honors-legislative-heroes-at-annual-gala-celebrating-state-success/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASEOctober 30, 2025 MISSISSIPPI CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY HONORS LEGISLATIVE HEROES AT ANNUAL GALA CELEBRATING STATE SUCCESS JACKSON, MS – October 30, 2025 –Six of Mississippi’s leading lawmakers were presented with award to honor them for championing principled conservative policy. Rich Lowry, editor of the National Review, presented each of the winners. HealthcareRep. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/press-release-mississippi-center-for-public-policy-honors-legislative-heroes-at-annual-gala-celebrating-state-success/" rel="nofollow"&gt;PRESS RELEASE: MISSISSIPPI CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY HONORS LEGISLATIVE HEROES AT ANNUAL GALA CELEBRATING STATE SUCCESS&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 19:21:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Income: You Earned It, You Should Keep It</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/income-you-earned-it-you-should-keep-it/</link><description>Income Taxes: We have options Are you getting the idea that the Idaho Freedom Foundation (IFF) thinks government takes too much in taxes? Good, let’s keep going. By applying our 2026 Freedom and Family Agenda’s strong position on tax cuts, we have proposed eliminating the sales tax on groceries and have offered a plan to [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 23:08:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Virginiainstitute] Press Release – HJ 6007: “one of the worst ideas” passed by the General Assembly</title><link>https://virginiainstitute.org/press-release-hj6007/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=press-release-hj6007</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Virginia Institute for Public Policy has expressed concern over HJ6007, a proposed amendment to Virginia’s Constitution that would alter the state’s current redistricting process. The Institute emphasized that Virginia voters approved a bipartisan approach in 2020 to ensure fair and transparent elections for all citizens. Citing constitutional and procedural issues surrounding HJ6007, the Institute encourages lawmakers to uphold established safeguards that protect the integrity and balance of Virginia’s electoral system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org/press-release-hj6007/"&gt;Press Release – HJ 6007: “one of the worst ideas” passed by the General Assembly&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org"&gt;Virginia Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 00:15:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Tallahassee Democrat: Florida’s Established Approach to Kids’ Online Safety Doesn’t Need Tweaking</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/floridas-established-approach-to-kids-online-safety-doesnt-need-tweaking-opinion/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In the ongoing debate about how to best protect children online, a new proposal gaining traction would force...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/floridas-established-approach-to-kids-online-safety-doesnt-need-tweaking-opinion/"&gt;Tallahassee Democrat: Florida’s Established Approach to Kids’ Online Safety Doesn’t Need Tweaking&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 14:55:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] Average Twin Cities Commuter = 73 Hours Stuck in Traffic</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/average-twin-cities-commuter-73-hours-stuck-in-traffic/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Every year, the Texas A&amp;#38;M Transportation Institute issues a report documenting the price of road congestion on American roads. This 2025 report is notable for Minnesota commuters because it documented that the “average Twin Cities car commuter now spends a record 73 hours a year stuck in traffic.” This is an increase after a COVID-pandemic [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/average-twin-cities-commuter-73-hours-stuck-in-traffic/"&gt;Average Twin Cities Commuter = 73 Hours Stuck in Traffic&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 18:14:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Week in Review: Everything Should Be Smaller in Taxes</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/week-in-review-everything-should-be-smaller-in-taxes/</link><description>That’s right, the title says “Taxes,” not “Texas.” Even in Idaho, taxes are out of control. Please enjoy — if that’s the right word — this mini-series on Idaho taxes. But, before you read, one word of reminder: high taxes are merely the symptom of the true disease: out-of-control government spending. This symptom inflicts real [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 20:04:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] New Pioneer Institute Analysis Finds Proposed Massachusetts Income-Tax Cut Unlikely to Cause Major State Revenue Decline</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/news/2026-tax-cut/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Lessons from the 2000 Massachusetts Income-Tax Rollback: A Reality-Check for the 2025 Ballot Debate is an empirical analysis of Massachusetts revenue data from FY1998–FY2021. The study concludes that a one-point rate reduction is unlikely to produce large, persistent revenue shortfalls, and that long-term fiscal stability depends far more on economic performance than on marginal rate differences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/news/2026-tax-cut/"&gt;New Pioneer Institute Analysis Finds Proposed Massachusetts Income-Tax Cut Unlikely to Cause Major State Revenue Decline&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 15:06:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Why CT’s Special Session Must Be Narrow and Focused</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/11/03/why-cts-special-session-must-be-narrow-and-focused/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="1707" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/shutterstock_2628868481-scaled.jpg" width="2560" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a special session expected in mid-November, progressives are using an emerging funding crisis to revisit Connecticut’s fiscal guardrails and advance other priorities such as health care and affordable housing.   [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/11/03/why-cts-special-session-must-be-narrow-and-focused/"&gt;Why CT&amp;#8217;s Special Session Must Be Narrow and Focused&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 15:15:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] New Report Calls for More Freedom and Consumer Choice in Energy Policy to Lower Costs</title><link>https://will-law.org/new-report-calls-for-more-freedom-and-consumer-choice-in-energy-policy-to-lower-costs/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A new report from WILL, titled “Energy Choice for Wisconsin: A Free-Market Case for Community Solar,” outlines how privately financed community solar projects can expand consumer choice, strengthen the electric grid, preserve farmland, and inject market competition into Wisconsin’s monopoly utility system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/new-report-calls-for-more-freedom-and-consumer-choice-in-energy-policy-to-lower-costs/"&gt;New Report Calls for More Freedom and Consumer Choice in Energy Policy to Lower Costs&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 17:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/11/the-outstater-299/</link><description>Grades: All Rhinestones Now &amp;#8220;Personally, I liked working for the university. They gave us money and facilities. We didn&amp;#8217;t have to produce anything. You&amp;#8217;ve never been out of college. You don&amp;#8217;t know what it&amp;#8217;s like out there. I’ve worked in the private sector — they expect results.”&amp;#160;— Dr. Raymond Stantz (Dan Aykroyd) in the 1984&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/11/the-outstater-299/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 18:43:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Per-Pupil Spending Tells More of the Story</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/per-pupil-spending-tells-more-of-the-story/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Per-Pupil Spending Tells More of the Story" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/school-spending-1200x630-1.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;School bond campaigns often highlight levy rates to suggest affordability, but that figure alone doesn’t reveal how districts spend—or the true cost to taxpayers and students. Looking at districtwide per-student expenditures provides a clearer picture of financial trends and priorities. For instance, Des Moines’ per-student spending is up 24% in five years, and Southeast Polk’s has risen 66%. Districts should routinely publish per-student cost data by program or activity to help voters, taxpayers, and educators evaluate whether new borrowing truly delivers educational value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/per-pupil-spending-tells-more-of-the-story/"&gt;Per-Pupil Spending Tells More of the Story&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 19:16:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF in National Review: New Mexico’s ‘Free’ Child Care an Attempt to Cover for Past Failures</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-in-national-review-new-mexicos-free-child-care-an-attempt-to-cover-for-past-failures/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following appeared at National Review on November 11, 2025. Child care isn’t cheap, especially once the government gets involved. Recently, New Mexico’s Democratic Governor Michelle Lujan Grisham announced a new plan for taxpayers to fund “free” child care for all New Mexicans, regardless of their income levels. The announcement generated favorable news coverage in [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-in-national-review-new-mexicos-free-child-care-an-attempt-to-cover-for-past-failures/"&gt;RGF in National Review: New Mexico’s ‘Free’ Child Care an Attempt to Cover for Past Failures&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 21:15:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] AEA Has Shown Alabamians Who They Are: Believe Them</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/11/04/aea-has-shown-alabamians-who-they-are-believe-them/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;AEA has worked for decades to stop school choice legislation. AEA actively worked against the passage of the AAA Scholarship program, the PRICE Act, and the CHOOSE Act. AEA used political influence and political contributions to people and parties to weaken parental rights in the CHOOSE Act and then tried to kill the CHOOSE Act unless they could “control the spending” with a cap. Further, AEA worked last legislative session to minimize funding for special needs kids, military kids, and kids whose families are living in poverty; they are currently working against future CHOOSE Act schoolchildren. AEA is trying to render void the promises legislators made to Alabama parents when they passed the law in 2024. They are attempting to undercut the work and the word of Governor Kay Ivey, Lt. Governor Will Ainsworth, Speaker Nathaniel Ledbetter, Chairman Danny Garrett, Chairman Arthur Orr, and each of the ninety-two legislators who voted on behalf of the people they represent for universal school choice for Alabama’s children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/11/04/aea-has-shown-alabamians-who-they-are-believe-them/"&gt;AEA Has Shown Alabamians Who They Are: Believe Them&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 05:04:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] McGowan: AI Flunks the Baseball Test</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/11/mcgowan-ai-flunks-the-baseball-test/</link><description>by Richard McGowan, Ph.D. This year’s world series and all the attention paid to Shohei Ohtani reminded me of the way students used to get by when writing papers.&amp;#160;They used CliffsNotes instead of doing research.&amp;#160;Can AI be far behind? I had a bright student who wrote a paper on Plato’s &amp;#8220;Crito&amp;#8221; as explained by every&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/11/mcgowan-ai-flunks-the-baseball-test/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 13:43:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] This bipartisan proposal is a logical step to improve Medicare solvency</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/this-bipartisan-proposal-is-a-logical-step-to-improve-medicare-solvency</link><description>The federal Medicare health insurance program for seniors has been overbudget since its inception in 1965. By 1990, the plan was at least nine times over the original budget  as determined by the Congressional Budget Office (CBO). Eliminating waste, fraud, and abuse in the program would seem to be a noncontroversial first step to decrease the financial burden on taxpayers and guarantee that future generations of seniors have access to Medicare. A bipartisan bill, The No UPCODE Act , has been...</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 15:17:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] SNAP in Nebraska: Current Rules, Economic Impact, and What’s Next</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/snap-in-nebraska-current-rules-economic-impact-and-whats-next/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Program Overview  The Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP), formerly known as the Food Stamp Program, is the most extensive federal nutrition assistance program in the United States. It serves as a &amp;#8220;safety net&amp;#8221; program that helpslow-income individuals and families access and purchase healthy food. The program is funded by the Department of Agriculture (USDA) and...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/snap-in-nebraska-current-rules-economic-impact-and-whats-next/" rel="nofollow"&gt;SNAP in Nebraska: Current Rules, Economic Impact, and What’s Next&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 16:16:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Nebraska lost $300 million from tax migration in 2022</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-lost-300-million-from-tax-migration-in-2022/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Elections occur every other November. But taxpayers vote with their feet every day, and these votes should be counted and tallied just like the votes for a November election.  A “Great Pandemic Wealth Migration” began when the coronavirus pandemic caused Americans to move to work-from-home employment. This meant workers were no longer tied to aphysical...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-lost-300-million-from-tax-migration-in-2022/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Nebraska lost $300 million from tax migration in 2022&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 19:03:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] How Much Tax Support Do Iowa’s County Hospitals Really Need?</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/how-much-tax-support-do-iowas-county-hospitals-really-need/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="How Much Tax Support Do Iowa’s County Hospitals Really Need?" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/da-co-hospital.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Across Iowa, more than 40 county hospitals receive a portion of their funding from local property taxpayers, totaling more than $150 million a year. These facilities are often essential—especially in rural areas where they may be the only source of emergency care. But when public dollars are involved, financial transparency takes on heightened importance. One key question Iowans are always entitled to ask is: How many tax dollars are actually necessary?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/how-much-tax-support-do-iowas-county-hospitals-really-need/"&gt;How Much Tax Support Do Iowa’s County Hospitals Really Need?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 21:21:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Obamacare’s Policy Failures Come To Idaho</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/obamacares-policy-failures-come-to-idaho/</link><description>As the shutdown of the federal government extends beyond 30 days, the key reasons become apparent: it is about healthcare costs and who pays them. The debate over temporarily expanded healthcare premium subsidies and Medicaid eligibility is really about who pays what. You see, the notion that the Affordable Care Act (often referred to as [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 22:45:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] State Board of Education gets bad legal guidance from the Kansas Department of Education</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/state-board-of-education-bad-legal-guidance/</link><description>The October meeting of the Kansas State Board of Education contained another déjà vu moment: attempting to cover up another violation of state laws designed to improve student outcomes (see here and here for past examples.) State Board Chair Cathy Hopkins commented on a Kansas Policy Institute discovery that school districts were not complying with [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 23:33:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Why does it cost so much to build? We’ve lost an abundance mindset</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/why-does-it-cost-so-much-to-build-weve-lost-an-abundance-mindset</link><description>‘Good intentions tell you nothing about the actual consequences’</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] November 2025 Beacon Poll Results</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/november-2025-beacon-poll/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=november-2025-beacon-poll</link><description>Today, we released the latest installment of the Beacon Poll, a statewide survey of 1,200 Tennessee voters featuring questions about voters&amp;#8217; views on socialism versus capitalism, the National Guard in Memphis, political violence, and more. In a surprising result that could have a national impact, a majority of Democrats in Tennessee hold a favorable view...</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 13:00:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] MA Teacher Kelley Brown on Founding Documents, U.S. History, &amp; Civics</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/ma-teacher-kelley-brown-on-founding-documents-u-s-history-civics/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In this week’s episode of The Learning Curve, co-hosts Center for Strong Public Schools’ Alisha Searcy and American Federation for Children’s Walter Blanks interview Kelley Brown, an award-winning civics and government teacher at Easthampton High School and former Massachusetts Teacher of the Year. Ms. Brown discusses her background as an educator, her work with the “We the People": The Citizen and the Constitution program, and how it helps students engage with America’s Founding Documents, U.S. history, and enduring civic ideals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/ma-teacher-kelley-brown-on-founding-documents-u-s-history-civics/"&gt;MA Teacher Kelley Brown on Founding Documents, U.S. History, &amp;#038; Civics&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 14:35:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] MSPC provides digital safety keynote address at Idaho Department of Education conference</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/mspc-provides-digital-safety-keynote-address-at-idaho-department-of-education-conference</link><description>On October 24 th , 2025, I was honored to be a keynote speaker at the Idaho Department of Education’s 10th Annual Family and Community Engagement Conference in Sun Valley, ID. Over 300 teachers, principals, and community leaders came together for this year's event, giving a state-wide perspective on all the things we should be doing to better equip our parents and students with what they need to succeed in educating their youth. The keynote addressed my most recent research project: “ The...</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 15:38:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] The Atlanta Journal-Constitution: Georgia Leaders Should Not Vilify Technology. Social Media and AI Hold Promise.</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/georgia-leaders-should-not-vilify-technology-social-media-and-ai-hold-promise/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In the waning hours of Georgia&amp;#8217;s brief 40-day legislative session this past April, state senators quietly passed Senate...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/georgia-leaders-should-not-vilify-technology-social-media-and-ai-hold-promise/"&gt;The Atlanta Journal-Constitution: Georgia Leaders Should Not Vilify Technology. Social Media and AI Hold Promise.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 16:04:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] California Just Blew Past Last Year’s Record — And We’re Still Climbing</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/california-just-blew-past-last-years-record-and-were-still-climbing/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;California public employees are opting out of their unions in record numbers thanks to the work of the Freedom Foundation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/california-just-blew-past-last-years-record-and-were-still-climbing/" rel="nofollow"&gt;California Just Blew Past Last Year’s Record — And We’re Still Climbing&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 23:30:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Michigan budget deal: two steps forward, one step back</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/michigan-budget-deal-two-steps-forward-one-step-back</link><description>Divided state government managed to agree on some good policy</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] No need for hysteria over federal cuts to homeless housing</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/no-need-for-hysteria-over-federal-cuts-to-homeless-housing/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The usually levelheaded CalMatters reported that the expected deep cuts are the “latest blow in a seemingly endless barrage of bad news for the California agencies tasked with fighting homelessness.” The “news has sent counties throughout California into a panic” and they are “bracing to lose hundreds of millions of dollars,” the publication added. It’s time to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/no-need-for-hysteria-over-federal-cuts-to-homeless-housing/"&gt;No need for hysteria over federal cuts to homeless housing&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 11:00:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] NH’s youngest lawmakers to discuss civility in politics at Civil Discourses kickoff event</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/11/nhs-youngest-lawmakers-to-discuss-civility-in-politics-at-civil-discourses-kickoff-event/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Josiah Bartlett Center for Public Policy will bring a bipartisan group of New Hampshire’s youngest state representatives together on Dec. 1 for a frank and open conversation on the importance of civility in public life.  Josiah Bartlett Center President Andrew Cline will moderate a conversation among:: Rep. Jessica Grill, Democrat of Manchester; Rep. Sam [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/11/nhs-youngest-lawmakers-to-discuss-civility-in-politics-at-civil-discourses-kickoff-event/"&gt;NH&amp;#8217;s youngest lawmakers to discuss civility in politics at Civil Discourses kickoff event&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 13:31:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/11/the-outstater-300/</link><description>The&amp;#160;Mamdani Effect &amp;#8220;It is hard to imagine a more stupid or more dangerous way of making decisions than by putting those decisions in the hands of people who pay no price for being wrong.&amp;#8221; — Thomas Sowell HAVING WORKED with words all my career, I have admired the economists&amp;#8217; turn of phrase. Shakespearean almost, they pack a&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/11/the-outstater-300/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 15:44:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] New Economic Report Details the Cost of Coastal Litigation on  Louisiana Energy Jobs and Investments</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/press-release/new-economic-report-details-the-cost-of-coastal-litigation-on-louisiana-energy-jobs-and-investments/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Pelican Institute for Public Policy today released a chilling new economic impact report, “How Coastal Lawsuit Abuse Undermined Louisiana’s Economy,” detailing how years of coastal lawsuits cast a long shadow over Louisiana’s energy economy. The study conducted by Dr. Gavin Roberts, Ph.D., of Weber State University’s Goddard School of Business and Economics, Department of Economics, provides the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/press-release/new-economic-report-details-the-cost-of-coastal-litigation-on-louisiana-energy-jobs-and-investments/"&gt;New Economic Report Details the Cost of Coastal Litigation on  Louisiana Energy Jobs and Investments&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 15:55:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] CHALKBEAT: Interdistrict Public School Choice Program could expand with bipartisan support amid funding, equity hurdles</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/11/chalkbeat-interdistrict-public-school-choice-program-could-expand-with-bipartisan-support-amid-funding-equity-hurdles/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Interdistrict Public School Choice Program could expand with bipartisan support amid funding, equity hurdles By Jessie Gómez November 3, 2025 [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/11/chalkbeat-interdistrict-public-school-choice-program-could-expand-with-bipartisan-support-amid-funding-equity-hurdles/"&gt;CHALKBEAT: Interdistrict Public School Choice Program could expand with bipartisan support amid funding, equity hurdles&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 16:07:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] ROI-NJ: A blueprint for abundant, affordable energy for New Jersey families | Op-Ed</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/11/roi-nj-a-blueprint-for-abundant-affordable-energy-for-new-jersey-families-op-ed/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A blueprint for abundant, affordable energy for New Jersey families &amp;#124; Op-Ed By Erica Jedynak, New Jersey Policy Institute November [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/11/roi-nj-a-blueprint-for-abundant-affordable-energy-for-new-jersey-families-op-ed/"&gt;ROI-NJ: A blueprint for abundant, affordable energy for New Jersey families | Op-Ed&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 16:11:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] The Long Fight for Educational Freedom with Neal McCluskey and James Shuls</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/education/the-long-fight-for-educational-freedom-with-neal-mccluskey-and-james-shuls/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Learn more about the book here: www.cato.org/books/fighting-freedom-learn Susan Pendergrass speaks with James Shuls, fellow at the Show-Me Institute and head of [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/education/the-long-fight-for-educational-freedom-with-neal-mccluskey-and-james-shuls/"&gt;The Long Fight for Educational Freedom with Neal McCluskey and James Shuls&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 16:28:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] WFSE loses 1,000 members for second consecutive year</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/washington/wfse-loses-1000-members-for-second-consecutive-year/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For the second year in a row, the largest union representing Washington state employees has lost more than 1,000 members, thanks in large part to the ongoing outreach efforts of the Freedom Foundation to help of workers understand their right to opt out of paying union dues.&amp;#160; With annual union dues averaging around $1,000 per [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/washington/wfse-loses-1000-members-for-second-consecutive-year/" rel="nofollow"&gt;WFSE loses 1,000 members for second consecutive year&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 17:55:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] State Tax Competitiveness Index: Minnesota Falls to 44th out of 50!</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/state-tax-competitiveness-index-minnesota-falls-to-44th-out-of-50/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For 20 years, the Tax Foundation has released an annual report evaluating state tax codes – everything from income to property to sales taxes. Each state has its own summary including an interactive map that includes suggestions on how the state could become more competitive. Minnesota state leadership, however appears to be determined for our [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/state-tax-competitiveness-index-minnesota-falls-to-44th-out-of-50/"&gt;State Tax Competitiveness Index: Minnesota Falls to 44th out of 50!&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 19:06:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Support drafting bill that would allow two ADUs per lot in residential zones</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/11/support-drafting-bill-that-would-allow-two-adus-per-lot-in-residential-zones/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Maui County Council on Nov. 7, 2025._____________ Nov. 7, 2025, 9 a.m.Kalana O Maui Building To: Maui County Council&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Alice Lee, Chair&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Yuki Lei Sugimura, Vice-Chair From: Jonathan Helton, Policy Analyst&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Grassroot Institute of Hawaii RE: RESOLUTION 25-203 — A [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/11/support-drafting-bill-that-would-allow-two-adus-per-lot-in-residential-zones/"&gt;Support drafting bill that would allow two ADUs per lot in residential zones&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 19:44:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Extend enterprise zone benefits to incentivize all Maui businesses</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/11/extend-enterprise-zone-benefits-to-incentivize-all-maui-businesses/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Maui County Council on Nov. 7, 2025._____________ Nov. 7, 2025, 9 a.m.Kalana O Maui Building To: Maui County Council       Alice Lee, Chair       Yuki Lei Sugimura, Vice-Chair From: Grassroot Institute of Hawaii            Jonathan Helton, Policy Analyst RE: RESOLUTIONS 25-193 AND 25-194, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/11/extend-enterprise-zone-benefits-to-incentivize-all-maui-businesses/"&gt;Extend enterprise zone benefits to incentivize all Maui businesses&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 19:47:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] ‘Overhead encroachment’ rule blocking restoration of old Lahaina</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/11/overhead-encroachment-rule-blocking-restoration-of-old-lahaina/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Maui County Council on Nov. 7, 2025._____________ Nov. 7, 2025, 9 a.m.Kalana O Maui Building To: Maui County Council       Alice Lee, Chair       Yuki Lei Sugimura, Vice-Chair From: Grassroot Institute of Hawaii            Jonathan Helton, Policy Analyst Re: Bill 156 (2025) — [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/11/overhead-encroachment-rule-blocking-restoration-of-old-lahaina/"&gt;&amp;#8216;Overhead encroachment&amp;#8217; rule blocking restoration of old Lahaina&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 19:52:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Behind the Buzzwords: What Does it Mean to Actually Take “Kids Online Safety” Seriously?</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/behind-the-buzzwords-what-does-it-mean-to-actually-take-kids-online-safety-seriously/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Every few years, there’s a new idea that becomes so trendy, it gets stamped onto everything in sight. For the food industry, protein is currently that magic word. Stroll down any grocery aisle to find foods proudly flaunting bright new “high-protein” labels-even when nothing about the original recipe has changed to merit the rebrand or...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/behind-the-buzzwords-what-does-it-mean-to-actually-take-kids-online-safety-seriously/"&gt;Behind the Buzzwords: What Does it Mean to Actually Take “Kids Online Safety” Seriously?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 19:58:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Rights of nature and the wrongs inflicted on Wisconsinites</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/rights-of-nature-and-the-wrongs-inflicted-on-wisconsinites/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Assembly Democrats intend to introduce a bill to grant Devil’s Lake State Park legal rights, as if it weren’t a set of inanimate rocks, water, trees and lichens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/rights-of-nature-and-the-wrongs-inflicted-on-wisconsinites/"&gt;Rights of nature and the wrongs inflicted on Wisconsinites&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 20:10:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Voters Show Restraint in 2025 Bond Elections</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/voters-show-restraint-in-2025-bond-elections/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Voters Show Restraint in 2025 Bond Elections" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/lcoal-bond-election-results.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iowa voters considered 58 bond proposals totaling more than $1.7 billion in potential new borrowing. A majority (57%) of those proposals failed, with only 25 proposals (43%) gaining approval. Many repeat proposals were rejected again, showing continued taxpayer concern about property taxes and government spending. Just over $1 billion in new debt was approved, with nearly $700 million denied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/voters-show-restraint-in-2025-bond-elections/"&gt;Voters Show Restraint in 2025 Bond Elections&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 20:20:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] UW students turning away from gender and ethnic studies degrees</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/uw-students-turning-away-from-gender-and-ethnic-studies-degrees/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;About half as many students in the Universities of Wisconsin system are getting bachelor’s degrees in ethnic and gender studies as did at their peak in 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/uw-students-turning-away-from-gender-and-ethnic-studies-degrees/"&gt;UW students turning away from gender and ethnic studies degrees&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 20:47:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Madigan’s corruption doesn’t deserve an oil portrait</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/madigans-corruption-doesnt-deserve-an-oil-portrait/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Former Illinois House Speaker Michael Madigan’s corruption conviction means capturing his likeness in a portrait would be tax dollars poorly spent, one lawmaker says.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/madigans-corruption-doesnt-deserve-an-oil-portrait/"&gt;Madigan’s corruption doesn’t deserve an oil portrait&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 21:46:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Want Cheaper Housing? Create More Units, Not More Rules</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/regulation/want-cheaper-housing-create-more-units-not-more-rules/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Recent data from The Wall Street Journal suggest that renters across the country—including in Kansas City—are gaining leverage. Rents are [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/regulation/want-cheaper-housing-create-more-units-not-more-rules/"&gt;Want Cheaper Housing? Create More Units, Not More Rules&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 22:07:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] $2 Trillion and No One Aboard</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/transportation/2-trillion-and-no-one-aboard/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Randal O&amp;#8217;Toole Since 1965, when Congress began subsidizing urban transit, taxpayers have...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/transportation/2-trillion-and-no-one-aboard/"&gt;$2 Trillion and No One Aboard&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 00:20:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Lines for Gas Coming to California</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/lines-for-gas-coming-to-california/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=lines-for-gas-coming-to-california</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Achieving California’s goal of net zero by 2045 requires rapidly transitioning away from combustible fuel. It’s a risky strategy. If the transition happens too fast, Californians confront energy shortages and high prices. When it comes to electricity, Newsom has so far managed to avoid an acute crisis by sensibly prolonging that transition. In 2023, he delayed the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/lines-for-gas-coming-to-california/"&gt;Lines for Gas Coming to California&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 01:24:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Denver wisely repeals its minimum parking mandates</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/denver-wisely-repeals-its-minimum-parking-mandates/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Denver wisely repeals its minimum parking mandates By Sal Rodriguez  &amp;#124;  November 7, 2025 The post-World War II years brought with it many things Americans have taken for granted: economic prosperity, suburban living and minimum parking requirements. Along with the growing prevalence of personal vehicles through the 1950s and 1960s came zoning codes across the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/denver-wisely-repeals-its-minimum-parking-mandates/"&gt;Denver wisely repeals its minimum parking mandates&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 10:00:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Even Van Jones sees red flag with Mamdani victory</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/even-van-jones-sees-red-flag-with-mamdani-victory/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Emily Crane writes for the New York Post about response to this week’s New York mayoral election from a high-profile voice on the political left. Lefty luminary Van Jones was among those raising alarm at Democratic socialist mayor-elect Zohran Mamdani’s rage-filled victory speech, noting his instant “character switch” at winning power. A roaring Mamdani wasted...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/even-van-jones-sees-red-flag-with-mamdani-victory/"&gt;Even Van Jones sees red flag with Mamdani victory&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 10:42:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Traverse City borrows from Peter to pay Paul</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/traverse-city-borrows-from-peter-to-pay-paul</link><description>Troubled city-run internet project taps into funds intended for other purposes</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Cutting through the confusion over AI in education</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/cutting-through-the-confusion-over-ai-in-education/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;How will Artificial Intelligence (AI) impact education? Many articles, books and seminars have sought to address the topic. It’s complicated. Sorting out the valuable from the snake oil only adds to the difficulty. Robert Pondiscio’s insightful op-ed, &amp;#8220;The Illusion of Learning: The Danger of Artificial Intelligence to Education,&amp;#8221; can help bring some much-needed clarity to...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/cutting-through-the-confusion-over-ai-in-education/"&gt;Cutting through the confusion over AI in education&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 14:10:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Budget Update Paints Less Alarming Picture of Federal Health Cuts</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/budget-update-paints-less-alarming-picture/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A new fiscal report from the state Budget Division suggests federal funding cuts will hit New York&amp;#8217;s health-care budget less....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/budget-update-paints-less-alarming-picture/"&gt;Budget Update Paints Less Alarming Picture of Federal Health Cuts&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 14:23:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] The PRI All Stars Election 2025 Wrap Up</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/the-pri-all-stars-election-2025-wrap-up/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Now that the dust has settled, the PRI All Stars are back with their analysis of the 2025 election.  Tim Anaya and Matt Fleming take an in-depth look at the passage of Prop. 50, how its victory will impact the 2026 congressional campaigns in California, and whether Gavin Newsom will get a big national boost. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/the-pri-all-stars-election-2025-wrap-up/"&gt;The PRI All Stars Election 2025 Wrap Up&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 16:21:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] WILL Christmas Open House 2025</title><link>https://will-law.org/christmas2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/christmas2025/"&gt;WILL Christmas Open House 2025&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 16:32:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Housing Help</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/housing-help/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Texas has a big problem: regular folks can’t afford regular homes anymore. The main culprits? Local rules and red tape that make building new houses harder, slower, and way more expensive than it needs to be. So, the 89th Texas Legislature stepped in and passed a batch of reforms to help fix it. Here’s the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/housing-help/"&gt;Housing Help&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 16:54:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Occupational license reform will help the trades in Idaho</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/occupational-license-reform-will-help-the-trades-in-idaho</link><description>The trades, electrical, plumbing, and HVAC (Heating, Ventilation, and Air Conditioning), face a growing concern surrounding what could most accurately be labeled a retirement crisis. Some estimates say that for every five journeyman who retire from the trades , only two apprentices from a younger generation will replace them.  Licensure raises the price of entry into the trades’ labor market, artificially limiting the number of people who can enter it. Given the ever-important need for...</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 16:57:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Week in Review: Exposing School Stonewalling on Fox</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-exposing-school-stonewalling-on-fox/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Rhode Island taxpayers already pay a lot to educate public school students—so, “it’s outrageous” and “completely unreasonable” to expect a..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-exposing-school-stonewalling-on-fox/"&gt;Week in Review: Exposing School Stonewalling on Fox&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 17:08:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Winners &amp; Losers: Texas Wins, Country Loses</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/winners-losers-texas-wins-country-loses/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Every Friday morning, I join the Cardle &amp;#38; Woolley Show on Talk 1370 Radio in Austin to announce the week’s Winners &amp;#38; Losers. The dust is still setting after Tuesday’s election and I’m stuck in an airport dealing with a cancelled flight, so here’s how it looks to me: Election Night: Texas Wins, Country Loses...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/winners-losers-texas-wins-country-loses/"&gt;Winners &amp; Losers: Texas Wins, Country Loses&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 17:28:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Will Concord or Laconia reap the rewards of creating NH’s first social district?</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/11/will-concord-or-laconia-reap-the-rewards-of-creating-nhs-first-social-district/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The term “economic growth” seldom pops up in local news stories. But there it was in the third paragraph of the Concord Monitor’s story on Tuesday’s election results.  After quoting a former teacher who complained about the slow pace of change in Concord due to “a lot of governmental, bureaucratic red tape,” the Monitor described [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/11/will-concord-or-laconia-reap-the-rewards-of-creating-nhs-first-social-district/"&gt;Will Concord or Laconia reap the rewards of creating NH&amp;#8217;s first social district?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 17:30:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Prescription Politics: Understanding PBMs</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/legal-regulatory/prescription-politics-understanding-pbms/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Perhaps you received a text in June from your local CVS Pharmacy alerting you to a big legislative fight? Or maybe you’ve just read about it in the papers. Either way, there’s been a lot of debate over the last few months about “Pharmacy Benefit Managers,” colloquially known as PBMs. But what exactly is a...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/legal-regulatory/prescription-politics-understanding-pbms/"&gt;Prescription Politics: Understanding PBMs&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 18:29:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] Minnesotans Cannot Afford Four More Years of Walz Energy Policy</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/minnesotans-cannot-afford-four-more-years-of-walz-energy-policy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;What happens when working families see electric bills climb to meet the governor’s idealistic demands? By Annette Meeks Gov. Tim Walz officially announced that he wants to serve four more years leading Minnesota. He did not make this announcement in a public meeting, rally or policy speech, but with a carefully crafted video. It was a politically manufactured [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/minnesotans-cannot-afford-four-more-years-of-walz-energy-policy/"&gt;Minnesotans Cannot Afford Four More Years of Walz Energy Policy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 19:02:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Two Missouri Public School Districts Opt into MOScholars</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/school-choice/two-missouri-public-school-districts-opt-into-moscholars/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Two public school districts—Hallsville R-IV and Atlanta C-3—are the first districts in Missouri to participate in MOScholars. MOScholars is Missouri’s [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/school-choice/two-missouri-public-school-districts-opt-into-moscholars/"&gt;Two Missouri Public School Districts Opt into MOScholars&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 19:33:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Examining the ‘too good to be true’ boasts of solar and wind</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/examining-the-too-good-to-be-true-boasts-of-solar-and-wind/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Center of the American Experiment recently posted a short (2:40) video, “Wind &amp;#38; Solar: Too good to be true?” (see below for the embedded video). The video is based on this recent report by Sarah Montalbano, “Shattered Green Dreams: The Environmental Costs of Wind and Solar.” Montalbano analyzes the rarely discussed environmental costs of solar...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/examining-the-too-good-to-be-true-boasts-of-solar-and-wind/"&gt;Examining the &amp;#8216;too good to be true&amp;#8217; boasts of solar and wind&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 20:07:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Illinois drops 6 spots in 6 years for tax competitiveness</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/illinois-drops-6-spots-in-6-years-for-tax-competitiveness/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Illinois’ state tax competitiveness ranking dropped six spots – from 32nd to 38th in the past six years. That’s the worst in the Midwest. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/illinois-drops-6-spots-in-6-years-for-tax-competitiveness/"&gt;Illinois drops 6 spots in 6 years for tax competitiveness&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 20:35:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Chicago budgets $210M for vacant jobs</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/chicago-budgets-210m-for-vacant-jobs/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Chicago has thousands of job vacancies that receive city funding, leaving taxpayers to pay for empty positions that spur massive overtime costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/chicago-budgets-210m-for-vacant-jobs/"&gt;Chicago budgets $210M for vacant jobs&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 20:38:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Over a Decade at the Bottom: Connecticut’s Tax System Still Among America’s Worst</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/11/07/over-a-decade-at-the-bottom-connecticuts-tax-system-still-among-americas-worst/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the eleventh consecutive year, Connecticut has ranked among the worst states in America for tax competitiveness — a streak that’s starting to look less like bad luck and more [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/11/07/over-a-decade-at-the-bottom-connecticuts-tax-system-still-among-americas-worst/"&gt;Over a Decade at the Bottom: Connecticut’s Tax System Still Among America’s Worst&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 21:24:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Harvard’s high grade revelations should cause soul-searching elsewhere</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/harvards-high-grade-revelations-should-cause-soul-searching-elsewhere/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A 25-page report released in late October by Harvard&amp;#8217;s Office of Undergraduate Education revealed that over 60 percent of all undergraduate grades awarded last year were an A. The median GPA at Harvard has been an A since the 2016-2017 academic year. While past years&amp;#8217; reports have blamed the rising grades on COVID-era distractions or...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/harvards-high-grade-revelations-should-cause-soul-searching-elsewhere/"&gt;Harvard&amp;#8217;s high grade revelations should cause soul-searching elsewhere&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 21:31:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Robot and Puppet unlikely to fill $3 billion empty Blue Line train</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/robot-and-puppet-unlikely-to-fill-3-billion-empty-blue-line-train/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Hats off to Eric Rasmussen and 5 INVESTIGATES for exposing the fact that Hennepin County is spending tax dollars on Giganta the dancing robot and Halima the smiling puppet as part of a $2.6 million effort to gather feedback from communities along the proposed Blue Line light-rail extension. That $2.6 million is aix a drop...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/robot-and-puppet-unlikely-to-fill-3-billion-empty-blue-line-train/"&gt;Robot and Puppet unlikely to fill $3 billion empty Blue Line train&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 21:48:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] There Are Better Healthcare Options Out There</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/there-are-better-healthcare-options-out-there/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Open Enrollment Season is upon us. It’s that time of year where employees, self-employed, businesses, and local governments start crunching numbers to see how much health insurance will cost next year—and, surprise of surprises, the answer is almost always “a lot more.” Worse yet, the Federal Budget impasse and Government shutdown over ACA healthcare subsidies...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/there-are-better-healthcare-options-out-there/"&gt;There Are Better Healthcare Options Out There&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 22:05:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] News Release: Cascade Identifies Purchase Risk for PPS One North Building</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/education/news-release-cascade-identifies-purchase-risk-for-pps-one-north-building/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;11/06/2025 FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE Cascade Policy Institute4850 SW Scholls Ferry Rd., Ste 103Portland...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/education/news-release-cascade-identifies-purchase-risk-for-pps-one-north-building/"&gt;News Release: Cascade Identifies Purchase Risk for PPS One North Building&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 23:23:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Minnesota’s Economic News — W/E 11/7/25</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/minnesotas-economic-news-w-e-11-7-25/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;State and local taxes and spending Star Tribune: Ramstad: The next year is going to be tough for Minnesota governments and politics Minn Post: Minnesota has over $5 billion it could spend to make up for lost federal money. Why isn’t the state using it? KAXE: Northern MN voters weigh raising taxes to pay for...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/minnesotas-economic-news-w-e-11-7-25/"&gt;Minnesota’s Economic News — W/E 11/7/25&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 06:01:06 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>