<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>State-Policy Think-Tank Digest</title><link>https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml</link><description>Latest posts from free-market policy institutes across the U.S.</description><atom:link href="https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 00:12:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF in National Review: New Mexico’s ‘Free’ Child Care an Attempt to Cover for Past Failures</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-in-national-review-new-mexicos-free-child-care-an-attempt-to-cover-for-past-failures/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following appeared at National Review on November 11, 2025. Child care isn’t cheap, especially once the government gets involved. Recently, New Mexico’s Democratic Governor Michelle Lujan Grisham announced a new plan for taxpayers to fund “free” child care for all New Mexicans, regardless of their income levels. The announcement generated favorable news coverage in [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-in-national-review-new-mexicos-free-child-care-an-attempt-to-cover-for-past-failures/"&gt;RGF in National Review: New Mexico’s ‘Free’ Child Care an Attempt to Cover for Past Failures&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 21:15:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] AEA Has Shown Alabamians Who They Are: Believe Them</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/11/04/aea-has-shown-alabamians-who-they-are-believe-them/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;AEA has worked for decades to stop school choice legislation. AEA actively worked against the passage of the AAA Scholarship program, the PRICE Act, and the CHOOSE Act. AEA used political influence and political contributions to people and parties to weaken parental rights in the CHOOSE Act and then tried to kill the CHOOSE Act unless they could “control the spending” with a cap. Further, AEA worked last legislative session to minimize funding for special needs kids, military kids, and kids whose families are living in poverty; they are currently working against future CHOOSE Act schoolchildren. AEA is trying to render void the promises legislators made to Alabama parents when they passed the law in 2024. They are attempting to undercut the work and the word of Governor Kay Ivey, Lt. Governor Will Ainsworth, Speaker Nathaniel Ledbetter, Chairman Danny Garrett, Chairman Arthur Orr, and each of the ninety-two legislators who voted on behalf of the people they represent for universal school choice for Alabama’s children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/11/04/aea-has-shown-alabamians-who-they-are-believe-them/"&gt;AEA Has Shown Alabamians Who They Are: Believe Them&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 05:04:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] SNAP in Nebraska: Current Rules, Economic Impact, and What’s Next</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/snap-in-nebraska-current-rules-economic-impact-and-whats-next/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Program Overview  The Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP), formerly known as the Food Stamp Program, is the most extensive federal nutrition assistance program in the United States. It serves as a &amp;#8220;safety net&amp;#8221; program that helpslow-income individuals and families access and purchase healthy food. The program is funded by the Department of Agriculture (USDA) and...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/snap-in-nebraska-current-rules-economic-impact-and-whats-next/" rel="nofollow"&gt;SNAP in Nebraska: Current Rules, Economic Impact, and What’s Next&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 16:16:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Nebraska lost $300 million from tax migration in 2022</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-lost-300-million-from-tax-migration-in-2022/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Elections occur every other November. But taxpayers vote with their feet every day, and these votes should be counted and tallied just like the votes for a November election.  A “Great Pandemic Wealth Migration” began when the coronavirus pandemic caused Americans to move to work-from-home employment. This meant workers were no longer tied to aphysical...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-lost-300-million-from-tax-migration-in-2022/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Nebraska lost $300 million from tax migration in 2022&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 19:03:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] November 2025 Beacon Poll Results</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/november-2025-beacon-poll/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=november-2025-beacon-poll</link><description>Today, we released the latest installment of the Beacon Poll, a statewide survey of 1,200 Tennessee voters featuring questions about voters&amp;#8217; views on socialism versus capitalism, the National Guard in Memphis, political violence, and more. In a surprising result that could have a national impact, a majority of Democrats in Tennessee hold a favorable view...</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 13:00:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] ROI-NJ: A blueprint for abundant, affordable energy for New Jersey families | Op-Ed</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/11/roi-nj-a-blueprint-for-abundant-affordable-energy-for-new-jersey-families-op-ed/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A blueprint for abundant, affordable energy for New Jersey families &amp;#124; Op-Ed By Erica Jedynak, New Jersey Policy Institute November [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/11/roi-nj-a-blueprint-for-abundant-affordable-energy-for-new-jersey-families-op-ed/"&gt;ROI-NJ: A blueprint for abundant, affordable energy for New Jersey families | Op-Ed&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 16:11:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] WFSE loses 1,000 members for second consecutive year</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/washington/wfse-loses-1000-members-for-second-consecutive-year/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For the second year in a row, the largest union representing Washington state employees has lost more than 1,000 members, thanks in large part to the ongoing outreach efforts of the Freedom Foundation to help of workers understand their right to opt out of paying union dues.&amp;#160; With annual union dues averaging around $1,000 per [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/washington/wfse-loses-1000-members-for-second-consecutive-year/" rel="nofollow"&gt;WFSE loses 1,000 members for second consecutive year&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 17:55:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] State Tax Competitiveness Index: Minnesota Falls to 44th out of 50!</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/state-tax-competitiveness-index-minnesota-falls-to-44th-out-of-50/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For 20 years, the Tax Foundation has released an annual report evaluating state tax codes – everything from income to property to sales taxes. Each state has its own summary including an interactive map that includes suggestions on how the state could become more competitive. Minnesota state leadership, however appears to be determined for our [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/state-tax-competitiveness-index-minnesota-falls-to-44th-out-of-50/"&gt;State Tax Competitiveness Index: Minnesota Falls to 44th out of 50!&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 19:06:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Budget Update Paints Less Alarming Picture of Federal Health Cuts</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/budget-update-paints-less-alarming-picture/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A new fiscal report from the state Budget Division suggests federal funding cuts will hit New York&amp;#8217;s health-care budget less....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/budget-update-paints-less-alarming-picture/"&gt;Budget Update Paints Less Alarming Picture of Federal Health Cuts&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 14:23:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Will Concord or Laconia reap the rewards of creating NH’s first social district?</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/11/will-concord-or-laconia-reap-the-rewards-of-creating-nhs-first-social-district/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The term “economic growth” seldom pops up in local news stories. But there it was in the third paragraph of the Concord Monitor’s story on Tuesday’s election results.  After quoting a former teacher who complained about the slow pace of change in Concord due to “a lot of governmental, bureaucratic red tape,” the Monitor described [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/11/will-concord-or-laconia-reap-the-rewards-of-creating-nhs-first-social-district/"&gt;Will Concord or Laconia reap the rewards of creating NH&amp;#8217;s first social district?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 17:30:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] Minnesotans Cannot Afford Four More Years of Walz Energy Policy</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/minnesotans-cannot-afford-four-more-years-of-walz-energy-policy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;What happens when working families see electric bills climb to meet the governor’s idealistic demands? By Annette Meeks Gov. Tim Walz officially announced that he wants to serve four more years leading Minnesota. He did not make this announcement in a public meeting, rally or policy speech, but with a carefully crafted video. It was a politically manufactured [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/minnesotans-cannot-afford-four-more-years-of-walz-energy-policy/"&gt;Minnesotans Cannot Afford Four More Years of Walz Energy Policy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 19:02:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Shutdown Endgame: What the Deal Means for Maine and the Nation</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/shutdown-endgame-what-the-deal-means-for-maine-and-the-nation/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;After more than 40 days, the longest government shutdown in American history appears to be nearing an end. The Senate voted 60–40 on a short-term funding bill that would reopen shuttered federal agencies and extend operations through late January. In a rare show of bipartisanship, eight Democrats, including Senator Angus King, joined Republicans to advance [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/shutdown-endgame-what-the-deal-means-for-maine-and-the-nation/"&gt;Shutdown Endgame: What the Deal Means for Maine and the Nation&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 01:28:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] What You Need To Know For Special Session</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/11/11/what-you-need-to-know-for-special-session/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="1216" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/Screenshot-2025-08-19-134951.jpg" width="1736" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connecticut lawmakers are moving quickly in a special session — tackling housing, emergency spending, and healthcare policy from Nov. 12-13. Some proposals represent steps in the right direction. Others risk [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/11/11/what-you-need-to-know-for-special-session/"&gt;What You Need To Know For Special Session&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 15:50:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] DPI Rates 0 Districts 1 Star, Half of All Schools 4 or 5 Stars on New School Report Cards</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/dpi-rates-0-districts-1-star-half-of-all-schools-4-or-5-stars-on-new-school-report-cards/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;DPI Rates 0 Districts 1 Star, Half of All Schools 4 or 5 Stars on New School Report Cards DPI’s rankings make report cards mostly meaningless  Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government (IRG) released the following statement following the release of 2025 district and school report cards using a lenient formula, resulting in [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/dpi-rates-0-districts-1-star-half-of-all-schools-4-or-5-stars-on-new-school-report-cards/"&gt;DPI Rates 0 Districts 1 Star, Half of All Schools 4 or 5 Stars on New School Report Cards&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 17:31:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] NJBIZ: OPINION: Why New Jersey should repeal its bag ban</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/11/njbiz-opinion-why-new-jersey-should-repeal-its-bag-ban-wells-winegar/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;OPINION: Why New Jersey should repeal its bag ban by Wells Winegar November 10, 2025 &amp;#160; Walk into any New [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/11/njbiz-opinion-why-new-jersey-should-repeal-its-bag-ban-wells-winegar/"&gt;NJBIZ: OPINION: Why New Jersey should repeal its bag ban&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 18:56:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Dr. Brad Wilcox: Get Married</title><link>https://empowerms.org/dr-brad-wilcox-get-married/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Dr. Brad Wilcox: Get Married On this episode of The Empower Podcast, host Grant Callen talks with Dr. Brad Wilcox, Director of the National Marriage Project at the University of Virginia and author of Get Married: Why Americans Must Defy the Elites, Forge Strong Families, and Save Civilization. Dr. Wilcox shares striking research on how&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/dr-brad-wilcox-get-married/"&gt;Dr. Brad Wilcox: Get Married&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 00:00:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] Rio Grande Foundation Soiree a Huge Success!</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rio-grande-foundation-soiree-a-huge-success/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;What do you call 175 freedom loving New Mexicans gathered in one place? A good start! In all seriousness the Rio Grande Foundation hosted its 25th anniversary Laissez Faire Soiree this past Saturday night and we are pleased to report  the event was a smashing success with 175 attendees and lots of fun. Thanks to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rio-grande-foundation-soiree-a-huge-success/"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation Soiree a Huge Success!&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 19:40:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Volunteering for Higher Taxes? Assessing Tennessee’s Uncapped Property Taxes</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/volunteering-for-higher-taxes-assessing-tennessees-uncapped-property-taxes/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=volunteering-for-higher-taxes-assessing-tennessees-uncapped-property-taxes</link><description>If Tennessee wants to protect its residents in all aspects and truly take claim to being a low-tax state, lawmakers should look around the nation and see that we are in the small minority that fails to protect citizens from unjust property tax hikes.</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 19:52:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alaskapolicyforum] Is Anchorage’s New Proposed “Short-Term Rental-Only” Tax Really the Answer?</title><link>https://alaskapolicyforum.org/2025/11/is-anchorages-new-proposed-short-term-rental-only-tax-really-the-answer/#utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=is-anchorages-new-proposed-short-term-rental-only-tax-really-the-answer</link><description>&lt;div style="margin: 5px 5% 10px 5%;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" height="675" src="https://alaskapolicyforum.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/jon-tyson-XS_o-Iuf9Go-unsplash-scaled-e1762980183585.jpg" title="" width="506" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This blog looks at an urgent issue for Anchorage, which is considering a new short-term rental tax next week. That may seem like an easy fix for housing, but in reality, it raises seriousRead More&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alaskapolicyforum.org/2025/11/is-anchorages-new-proposed-short-term-rental-only-tax-really-the-answer/"&gt;Is Anchorage’s New Proposed “Short-Term Rental-Only” Tax Really the Answer?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://alaskapolicyforum.org"&gt;Alaska Policy Forum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 21:06:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Multnomah Audit Finds Fraud in Construction Recycling</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/economic-opportunity/multnomah-audit-finds-fraud-in-construction-recycling/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Naomi Inman What happens to all that construction debris on public works...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/economic-opportunity/multnomah-audit-finds-fraud-in-construction-recycling/"&gt;Multnomah Audit Finds Fraud in Construction Recycling&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 17:13:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] The RGGI trap</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/11/the-rggi-trap/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;According to national media reports, Pennsylvania’s 2025 budget deal caused the state to “exit” RGGI. Media coverage also used the words “leave,” “quit” and “pull out” to describe Pennsylvania’s abandonment of RGGI. Pennsylvania, though, wasn’t actually a member of RGGI.  In 2019, then-Gov. Tom Wolf issued an executive order for his administration to adopt regulations [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/11/the-rggi-trap/"&gt;The RGGI trap&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 20:15:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Before the Ink Dried, the Union Was Already Calling the Shots at Waterbury Hospital</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/11/14/before-the-ink-dried-the-union-was-already-calling-the-shots-at-waterbury-hospital/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bill authorizing UConn Health to purchase Waterbury Hospital wasn’t even written when one of Connecticut’s most politically influential healthcare unions began issuing demands.   On Oct. 17 — weeks before [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/11/14/before-the-ink-dried-the-union-was-already-calling-the-shots-at-waterbury-hospital/"&gt;Before the Ink Dried, the Union Was Already Calling the Shots at Waterbury Hospital&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 20:33:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] A legacy of healing — Documentary tells ReCAST Lawrenceville’s journey through residents’ stories</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/recast-lawrenceville-documentary/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/recast-lawrenceville-documentary/"&gt;A legacy of healing — Documentary tells ReCAST Lawrenceville’s journey through residents’ stories&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:43:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] New Jersey Policy Institute Announces Inaugural Class of 2026 Junior Fellows</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/11/new-jersey-policy-institute-announces-inaugural-class-of-2026-junior-fellows/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Parsippany, NJ – The New Jersey Policy Institute (NJPI) is proud to announce the inaugural class of its 2026 Junior Fellowship [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/11/new-jersey-policy-institute-announces-inaugural-class-of-2026-junior-fellows/"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute Announces Inaugural Class of 2026 Junior Fellows&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 18:43:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Kansas Doesn’t Need to Play Ball With Corporate Welfare</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/kansas-doesnt-need-to-play-ball/</link><description>Taxpayers want markets, not handouts, to drive growth A new SurveyUSA poll of Overland Park and Leawood residents confirms what many Kansans already feel in their gut: people love their teams, but their desire to spend tax dollars on it declines as the taxes hit closer to home.  When asked if the state should use [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 22:00:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Study: Accessory Dwelling Units Now Legal Statewide, but Construction Still Lags</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/economic_opportunity/study-accessory-dwelling-units-now-legal-statewide-but-construction-still-lags/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;BOSTON – Even after statewide legalization in 2024, production of accessory dwelling units (ADUs) in Massachusetts remains far from that of other states due to local zoning and permitting practices that continue to discourage development, according to a new Pioneer Institute study. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/economic_opportunity/study-accessory-dwelling-units-now-legal-statewide-but-construction-still-lags/"&gt;Study: Accessory Dwelling Units Now Legal Statewide, but Construction Still Lags&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 12:51:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Houston Supt. Mike Miles on Urban School District Reform</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/learning-curve/houston-supt-mike-miles-on-urban-school-district-reform/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In this week’s episode of The Learning Curve, co-hosts Great Heart Academies’ Dr. Helen Baxendale and American Federation for Children’s Shaka Mitchell speak with Mike Miles, superintendent of the Houston Independent School District. Miles has devoted his life to public service, starting as a soldier, then as a diplomat in Poland and Russia during the Cold War before moving into K-12 education reform. He discussed how his family background and early educational experiences shaped his commitment to service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/learning-curve/houston-supt-mike-miles-on-urban-school-district-reform/"&gt;Houston Supt. Mike Miles on Urban School District Reform&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 15:29:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Aaron Withe Statement on Trump Administration’s Bold Action to Dismantle Education Bureaucracy</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/education/aaron-withe-statement-on-trump-administrations-bold-action-to-dismantle-education-bureaucracy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Freedom Foundation CEO and Teacher Freedom Alliance President Aaron Withe issued the following statement regarding President Trump’s plans to dismantle the Department of Education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/education/aaron-withe-statement-on-trump-administrations-bold-action-to-dismantle-education-bureaucracy/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Aaron Withe Statement on Trump Administration&amp;#8217;s Bold Action to Dismantle Education Bureaucracy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 16:15:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Congress Must Act: Preempt State AI Patchwork to Fuel America’s—and Louisiana’s—Innovation Fire</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/congress-must-act-preempt-state-ai-patchwork-to-fuel-americas-and-louisianas-innovation-fire/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As the National Defense Authorization Act (NDAA) barrels toward a December showdown, House Republicans, led by Louisiana’s own Speaker Mike Johnson and Majority Leader Steve Scalise, are considering a much-needed moratorium on state AI regulations. This echoes President Donald J. Trump’s urgent X post: “Investment in AI is helping to make the U.S. Economy the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/congress-must-act-preempt-state-ai-patchwork-to-fuel-americas-and-louisianas-innovation-fire/"&gt;Congress Must Act: Preempt State AI Patchwork to Fuel America’s—and Louisiana’s—Innovation Fire&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 18:54:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Mississippi is globally recognized!</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/mississippi-is-globally-recognized/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/mississippi-is-globally-recognized/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi is globally recognized!&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 18:55:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] WILL Applauds Wisconsin Assembly for Passing Important Education Reforms</title><link>https://will-law.org/will-applauds-wisconsin-assembly-for-passing-important-education-reforms/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL applauded the Wisconsin State Assembly for its action in passing two important education reforms: the Wisconsin Teacher Bill of Rights (AB 614) and the Federal Scholarship Tax Credit Opt-in Bill (AB 602).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/will-applauds-wisconsin-assembly-for-passing-important-education-reforms/"&gt;WILL Applauds Wisconsin Assembly for Passing Important Education Reforms&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 21:42:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Wisconsin DPI mired in one scandal after another</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/wisconsin-dpi-mired-in-one-scandal-after-another/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Wisconsin Department of Public Instruction is facing a crisis of confidence after accusations of gutting academic standards, manipulating report cards, slacking on fiscal oversight and bungling oversight of sexual misconduct among teachers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/wisconsin-dpi-mired-in-one-scandal-after-another/"&gt;Wisconsin DPI mired in one scandal after another&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 12:16:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Newly Retired NYPD Retirees Average $100,000+ in Pension</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/newly-retired-nypd-retirees-average-100000-in-pension/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Newly retired1 “full career”2 members of the New York Police Department (NYPD) collected an average of $103,859, according to new....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/newly-retired-nypd-retirees-average-100000-in-pension/"&gt;Newly Retired NYPD Retirees Average $100,000+ in Pension&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 14:07:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] “Inspire Oregon” Tackles Rural Housing Crisis</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/land-use/inspire-oregon-tackles-rural-housing-crisis/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Madilynne Clark The University of Oregon’s Institute for Policy Research and Engagement...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/land-use/inspire-oregon-tackles-rural-housing-crisis/"&gt;“Inspire Oregon” Tackles Rural Housing Crisis&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Maine Human Rights Commission’s New Lawsuit a State-Level Battle in a National Storm</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/maine-human-rights-commissions-new-lawsuit-a-state-level-battle-in-a-national-storm/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On November 17, the Maine Human Rights Commission (MHRC) filed suit against five school systems, MSAD 70, RSU 24, RSU 73, Baileyville and Richmond, arguing that their recently enacted “biological sex” policies violate the Maine Human Rights Act (MHRA). The Commission is suing on its own authority, not through the Attorney General, and its core [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/maine-human-rights-commissions-new-lawsuit-a-state-level-battle-in-a-national-storm/"&gt;Maine Human Rights Commission’s New Lawsuit a State-Level Battle in a National Storm&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 17:27:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] BEAD the Call: What the First Four Years of BEAD can Teach Us</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/bead-the-call-what-the-first-four-years-of-bead-can-teach-us/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Broadband Equity Access and Deployment program (BEAD) has followed a long and winding road since its inception in 2021. Nationally, the final approval process for receiving BEAD funding is still ongoing, but one takeaway has become evident: competition and innovation, not red tape regulations, are the key to unlocking fast and accessible internet. Louisiana...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/bead-the-call-what-the-first-four-years-of-bead-can-teach-us/"&gt;BEAD the Call: What the First Four Years of BEAD can Teach Us&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 17:36:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Tennessee Tax System &amp; Reform Efforts Webinar</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/tennessee-tax-system-reform-efforts-webinar/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=tennessee-tax-system-reform-efforts-webinar</link><description>Join the Beacon Center for a timely discussion on Tennessee’s tax system, ongoing reform efforts, and how tax policy impacts families, workers, and businesses across the state. We’ll be joined by a panel of experts: Carey Bringle, Nashville business owner Patrick Gleason, Americans for Tax Reform, Beacon Senior Fellow for Tax Policy Justin Owen, CEO,...</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 20:38:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Civics Education Update</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/civics-education-update/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=civics-education-update</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The latest news on history, civics, and patriotism in our public schools is a mixed bag. In the early days of our republic, George Washington understood that civic education was essential for preserving freedom. More recently, the late Supreme Court Justice Sandra Day O’Connor reminded us that civic knowledge isn’t inherited genetically but must be...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/civics-education-update/"&gt;Civics Education Update&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 22:24:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] AI Cuts School Paperwork and Puts Time Back Into Teaching</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/ai-cuts-school-paperwork-and-puts-time-back-into-teaching/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Sebastian Girstl Efficiency is a core principle that drives progress, yet this idea has often not received the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/ai-cuts-school-paperwork-and-puts-time-back-into-teaching/"&gt;AI Cuts School Paperwork and Puts Time Back Into Teaching&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 14:31:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Property tax reform won’t reduce student achievement</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/property-tax-reform-student-achievement/</link><description>Kansas Representative Shannon Francis (R-Liberal) told KSNT-TV that he thinks higher property taxes may be bringing people to Kansas. He said higher property taxes have led to investment in schools, and that, as a result, “Kansas schools are a lot better than Oklahoma.” It may be intuitive to think that more spending translates to better [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 16:03:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Grassroot testimonies submitted in November 2025</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/11/grassroot-testimonies-submitted-in-november-2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following are testimonies submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii over the past few weeks for consideration by the Hawai‘i, Honolulu and Maui county councils, plus the state&amp;#8217;s Simplifying Permitting for Enhanced Economic Development Task Force: HAWAI‘I COUNTY &amp;#62;&amp;#62;&amp;#160;Bill 52 (2025)&amp;#160;— “Let household hennery owners sell their produce for extra income” and “Allow Hawaii [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/11/grassroot-testimonies-submitted-in-november-2025/"&gt;Grassroot testimonies submitted in November 2025&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 16:10:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Connecticut Cannot Solve Its Housing Crisis While Ignoring Union-Driven Costs</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/11/21/connecticut-cannot-solve-its-housing-crisis-while-ignoring-union-driven-costs/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Connecticut’s 2025 State of Housing Conference on Nov. 17 and 18, one panel stood out for all the wrong reasons. The session titled “Union-Built Affordable Housing” was billed as [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/11/21/connecticut-cannot-solve-its-housing-crisis-while-ignoring-union-driven-costs/"&gt;Connecticut Cannot Solve Its Housing Crisis While Ignoring Union-Driven Costs&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 19:01:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Winners &amp; Losers: Foreign Terrorists, College Degrees, Texas FEMA &amp; Jelly Roll</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/winners-losers-foreign-terrorists-college-degrees-texas-fema-jelly-roll/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Every Friday morning, I join the Cardle &amp;#38; Woolley Show on Talk 1370 Radio in Austin to announce the week’s Winners &amp;#38; Losers. While the congressional map wars continue and would-be candidates wait for the smoke to clear, here’s who made the list: WINNER: Gov. Greg Abbott Goes After Muslim Extremists in Texas After recent...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/winners-losers-foreign-terrorists-college-degrees-texas-fema-jelly-roll/"&gt;Winners &amp; Losers: Foreign Terrorists, College Degrees, Texas FEMA &amp; Jelly Roll&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 22:25:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Are farm incomes bountiful or withering on the vine?</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/are-farm-incomes-bountiful-or-withering-on-the-vine</link><description>Farmers across the nation are unlikely to be taking a check to the bank at the end of harvest - at least not checks big enough to cover their debt payments. But the government’s so-called remedies are a lesson in contradiction. As statistics refute themselves, regulations harm more than protect, and trade barriers exasperate challenges facing domestic producers, the government’s role in farming is only adding to the red.   Government data ineptly grasps the financial condition facing farmers....</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 15:19:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Trouble on the Right – Why Conservatives Need to be Wary</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/trouble-on-the-right-why-conservatives-need-to-be-wary/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I only recently learned what a “groyper” is - you may or may not be familiar with the term?&amp;#160;From what I can tell, a groyper is a hardline white nationalist.&amp;#160; Often anti-Semitic, groypers are hostile to mainstream conservatives.&amp;#160; To the extent they have a coherent agenda, groypers seem more national socialism than free-market capitalism.&amp;#160;Having been [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/trouble-on-the-right-why-conservatives-need-to-be-wary/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Trouble on the Right – Why Conservatives Need to be Wary&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 18:29:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] State-funded marketing is not the answer to low tourist turnout</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/11/state-funded-marketing-is-not-the-answer-to-low-tourist-turnout/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When you make it difficult for people to visit you, they tend to take the hint and stop coming. That’s a good strategy for dealing with unwanted houseguests, but not the smartest move for a state that depends on visitor dollars to fuel its economy. Hawaii already has some of the highest visitor taxes in [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/11/state-funded-marketing-is-not-the-answer-to-low-tourist-turnout/"&gt;State-funded marketing is not the answer to low tourist turnout&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 20:05:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Parents’ Bill of Rights Ends They/Them Fight</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/parents-bill-of-rights-ends-they-them-fight/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;An enterprising reporter at the New York Post never believed the FBI when it said that Thomas Crooks, the 20-year-old young man who shot President Donald Trump in Butler, Pennsylvania, didn’t have a social media footprint. She kept digging and found that Crooks was hanging out in some dark corners of the Internet and had...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/parents-bill-of-rights-ends-they-them-fight/"&gt;Parents’ Bill of Rights Ends They/Them Fight&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 20:48:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] From Pilgrims to Property Taxes</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/from-pilgrims-to-property-taxes/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="From Pilgrims to Property Taxes" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/plymouth-plantation.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;America’s earliest settlers believed government existed only to protect natural rights—especially property—not to manage society. Families, churches, and communities handled most social needs through voluntary cooperation, cultivating a citizenry capable of self-rule.&lt;br /&gt;
This founding worldview clashes with today’s rising property-tax burdens. Drawing on John Locke’s social-contract theory, the article argues that when government taxes away the fruits of a family’s labor or threatens their ability to stay in their home, it violates the very purpose for which government was created.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/from-pilgrims-to-property-taxes/"&gt;From Pilgrims to Property Taxes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 13:35:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] NEW POLL: Louisiana Voters Call for Fiscal Restraint, Bold Tax Reforms, and Expanded School Choice as Costs Rise; Thanksgiving Traditions Add Flavor to Findings</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/press-release/new-poll-louisiana-voters-call-for-fiscal-restraint-bold-tax-reforms-and-expanded-school-choice-as-costs-rise-thanksgiving-traditions-add-flavor-to-findings/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As families across Louisiana prepare to gather for Thanksgiving, the Pelican Institute for Public Policy today released its latest Pelican Pulse poll, revealing strong voter demand for a leaner state government, deeper tax relief, and greater education options. The statewide survey shows clear support for solutions to curb spending, tackle lawsuit abuse, and empower families—while...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/press-release/new-poll-louisiana-voters-call-for-fiscal-restraint-bold-tax-reforms-and-expanded-school-choice-as-costs-rise-thanksgiving-traditions-add-flavor-to-findings/"&gt;NEW POLL: Louisiana Voters Call for Fiscal Restraint, Bold Tax Reforms, and Expanded School Choice as Costs Rise; Thanksgiving Traditions Add Flavor to Findings&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 13:49:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Our region leads on tax competitiveness, with one glaring exception</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/our-region-leads-on-tax-competitiveness-with-one-glaring-exception</link><description>Our region boasts three states in the top 10 for having the most competitive tax structure, according to the Tax Foundation. The latest numbers show that Wyoming is the most taxpayer-friendly state, Montana is 6th, and Idaho is 9th. While this is impressive, Washington coming in near last at 45th is cause for concern.   The Tax Foundation's  State Competitiveness Index  reveals which states are taxpayer-friendly for both individuals and businesses. States are ranked based on income, sales,...</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 15:14:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Eliminating Missouri’s Income Tax, Subsidies for Gas Stations, and Early Literacy Reform</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/economy/eliminating-missouris-income-tax-subsidies-for-gas-stations-and-early-literacy-reform/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;David Stokes, Elias Tsapelas, and Avery Frank join host Zach Lawhorn to outline what a responsible plan to eliminate Missouri’s [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/economy/eliminating-missouris-income-tax-subsidies-for-gas-stations-and-early-literacy-reform/"&gt;Eliminating Missouri’s Income Tax, Subsidies for Gas Stations, and Early Literacy Reform&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 16:34:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Lowering the bar on proficiency standards is a frightening fad sweeping public education</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/states-lowering-proficiency-standards/</link><description>State education administrators often say,  “It’s all about the kids,” yet their actions suggest it’s more about protecting adult reputations than improving student outcomes. They all want students to do better, but not if it means adults changing their behavior to make it happen. The most recent example of this is lowering the bar on [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 17:21:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Sen. Rod Hickman: Rural revitalization, public safety, and education opportunity</title><link>https://empowerms.org/sen-rod-hickman-rural-revitalization-public-safety-and-education-opportunity/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Sen. Rod Hickman: Rural revitalization, public safety, and education opportunity On this episode of The Empower Podcast, host Grant Callen sits down with Mississippi State Senator Rod Hickman, a lawyer, educator, and public servant representing a stretch of communities across East Mississippi from Macon to Louisville to Meridian. Sen. Hickman shares how growing up in&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/sen-rod-hickman-rural-revitalization-public-safety-and-education-opportunity/"&gt;Sen. Rod Hickman: Rural revitalization, public safety, and education opportunity&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 18:48:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG Expands Oversight and Legal Work with Hire of Kevin Zielinski as Associate Counsel</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-expands-oversight-and-legal-work-with-hire-of-kevin-zielinski-as-associate-counsel/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government (IRG) announced that Kevin Zielinski has joined the organization as Associate Counsel for Legal Reform &amp;#38; Oversight, expanding the IRG team to 9.5 employees. WHY IT MATTERS: In this role, Kevin will support IRG’s work to promote accountable, limited, and effective governance through legal research, oversight initiatives, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-expands-oversight-and-legal-work-with-hire-of-kevin-zielinski-as-associate-counsel/"&gt;IRG Expands Oversight and Legal Work with Hire of Kevin Zielinski as Associate Counsel&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 19:18:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Explainer and Model Policies: Assembly Bill 495 and Parental Rights</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/explainer-and-model-policies-assembly-bill-495-and-parental-rights/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=explainer-and-model-policies-assembly-bill-495-and-parental-rights</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Assembly Bill 495 (Celeste Rodriguez, D &amp;#8211; San Fernando Valley) was passed by the legislature and signed into law by Governor Newsom, over the objections of many parental rights advocates, attorneys, and policy experts. This explainer breaks down the parts of the law that pose a potential threat to parental rights, and presents three model...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/explainer-and-model-policies-assembly-bill-495-and-parental-rights/"&gt;Explainer and Model Policies: Assembly Bill 495 and Parental Rights&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 20:46:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Decoding bureaucracy: how AI could aid regulatory reform</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/decoding-bureaucracy-how-ai-could-aid-regulatory-reform/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For decades, the image of government regulation has been synonymous with dusty, overflowing binders and legal jargon. State regulatory codes tend to accumulate year after year, sometimes contradicting themselves and complicating life for those navigating the process. This accumulation of &amp;#8220;red tape&amp;#8221; creates significant burdens for small business owners trying to remain compliant, citizens trying...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/decoding-bureaucracy-how-ai-could-aid-regulatory-reform/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Decoding bureaucracy: how AI could aid regulatory reform&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 21:18:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] WILL Plans to Protect Lawful Congressional Maps Already in Place</title><link>https://will-law.org/will-plans-to-protect-lawful-congressional-maps-already-in-place/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Wisconsin Supreme Court allowed two new legal challenges to the state’s congressional maps to continue forward by appointing two separate three-judge panels to hear the cases. The Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;#038; Liberty (WILL) had argued against such an appointment as any attempt to redraw the Congressional district lines in this manner would violate the U.S. Constitution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/will-plans-to-protect-lawful-congressional-maps-already-in-place/"&gt;WILL Plans to Protect Lawful Congressional Maps Already in Place&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 21:24:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] NEW YORK: The numbers show workers are done being misled</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/new-york-the-numbers-show-workers-are-done-being-misled/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Something real is happening in New York. Public employees across the state are waking up to the truth. They don’t have to fund a union to keep their job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/new-york-the-numbers-show-workers-are-done-being-misled/" rel="nofollow"&gt;NEW YORK: The numbers show workers are done being misled&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 23:03:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] U-NM’s NYT Bestseller Paul Andrew Hutton on the American Old West</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/u-nms-nyt-bestseller-paul-andrew-hutton-on-the-american-old-west/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In this week’s episode of The Learning Curve, co-hosts U-Ark Prof. Albert Cheng and Dr. Helen Baxendale of Great Hearts Academies speak with Paul Andrew Hutton, Distinguished Professor of History Emeritus at the University of New Mexico and author of the New York Times Bestseller, The Undiscovered Country: Triumph, Tragedy, and the Shaping of the American West. Prof. Hutton discusses the central themes of his new book and explains how the American West became foundational to the nation’s identity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/u-nms-nyt-bestseller-paul-andrew-hutton-on-the-american-old-west/"&gt;U-NM&amp;#8217;s NYT Bestseller Paul Andrew Hutton on the American Old West&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 04:40:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Gratitude for the Forgotten Mayflower Compact</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/gratitude-for-the-forgotten-mayflower-compact/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Gratitude for the Forgotten Mayflower Compact" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/mayflower-compact.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In November 1620, after arriving in Cape Cod, the Pilgrims signed the Mayflower Compact before setting foot on land. Though often overlooked today, the Compact remains a foundational document in the development of American constitutionalism and self-government. Constitutional scholar James McClellan wrote that by adopting the Compact, the Pilgrims brought a contractual theory of government to the New World—an idea that would later influence colonial charters, state constitutions, and even the U.S. Constitution itself.&lt;br /&gt;
This Thanksgiving, remembering the Mayflower Compact highlights the deep historical roots of American freedom and why these early commitments to self-rule remain a blessing worth celebrating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/gratitude-for-the-forgotten-mayflower-compact/"&gt;Gratitude for the Forgotten Mayflower Compact&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 13:48:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/11/the-outstater-309/</link><description>The Star Explores Outstate Indiana THE INDIANAPOLIS STAR &amp;#160;has sent a team of&amp;#160;intrepid&amp;#160;newswomen to the far corners of the state to learn what we are about out here, heavy on those man-on-the-street interviews of hapless “average” Hoosiers. One dispatch from the hinterland began, “The hills of southern Indiana look different than the manufacturing industry-dotted lakeshore&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/11/the-outstater-309/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 14:42:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Rhode Island Supreme Court Should Open the Door to Secret School Meetings</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/rhode-island-supreme-court-should-open-the-door-to-secret-school-meetings/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Do Rhode Islanders have the right to see how school policy is shaped behind the scenes? That’s the simple but..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/rhode-island-supreme-court-should-open-the-door-to-secret-school-meetings/"&gt;Rhode Island Supreme Court Should Open the Door to Secret School Meetings&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 18:03:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] California’s Economy Grows More Dependent on AI</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/californias-economy-grows-more-dependent-on-ai/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=californias-economy-grows-more-dependent-on-ai</link><description>&lt;p&gt;While California’s economy continues to produce some impressive headline numbers, its trajectory is becoming increasingly dependent on the tech sector. And now that tech has gone all in on artificial intelligence, the state’s finances are vulnerable to either a bursting of the “AI Bubble” or an exit of AI innovators to other states. Gov. Gavin...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/californias-economy-grows-more-dependent-on-ai/"&gt;California’s Economy Grows More Dependent on AI&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 18:48:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Support citizen oversight, greater transparency for HART</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/11/support-citizen-oversight-greater-transparency-for-hart/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Honolulu Charter Commission on Nov. 24, 2025._____________ Nov. 24, 2025, 2:30 p.m.Honolulu Hale To: Honolulu Charter Commission       Dawn Szewczyk, Chair       Sommerset Yamamoto, Vice Chair From: Grassroot Institute of Hawaii            Ted Kefalas, Director of Strategic Campaigns RE: P072 — RELATING TO [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/11/support-citizen-oversight-greater-transparency-for-hart/"&gt;Support citizen oversight, greater transparency for HART&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 19:21:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Much of America figuring out how to build more homes</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/much-of-america-figuring-out-how-to-build-more-homes/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The dire need for more houses in America has even regulation heavy cities like Los Angeles, New York City, Minneapolis and St. Paul streamlining rules — and providing a playbook for Wisconsin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/much-of-america-figuring-out-how-to-build-more-homes/"&gt;Much of America figuring out how to build more homes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 19:25:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Madison is a perfect example of why cities should stay out of grocery business</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/madison-perfect-example-of-why-cities-should-stay-out-of-grocery-business/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Plans for a municipally-owned grocery store in Madison is the perfect illustration of why government should stay out of an intensely competitive business it knows nothing about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/madison-perfect-example-of-why-cities-should-stay-out-of-grocery-business/"&gt;Madison is a perfect example of why cities should stay out of grocery business&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 19:58:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Guarding the Guard: Federal vs. State Power</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/guarding-the-guard-federal-vs-state-power/</link><description>The operative word in Idaho National Guard is Idaho. In a time of geopolitical uncertainty and unpredictable decision-making at the federal level, Idaho has a responsibility to ensure its Guard remains under Idaho’s leadership — guided by the priorities of its people rather than the ever-shifting impulses of Washington D.C.&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Do you know the last [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 20:14:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] The safety net ‘system’ that isn’t</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/the-safety-net-system-that-isnt/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/the-safety-net-system-that-isnt/"&gt;The safety net ‘system’ that isn’t&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 21:18:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] On Thanksgiving, remember that gratitude makes good citizens, heals divisions</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/gratitude-makes-good-citizens-and-heals-divisions/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/gratitude-makes-good-citizens-and-heals-divisions/"&gt;On Thanksgiving, remember that gratitude makes good citizens, heals divisions&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 23:00:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Oregon’s 19th Century Energy Strategy</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/economic-opportunity/oregons-19th-century-energy-strategy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By John A. Charles, Jr. Recently the Oregon Department of Energy (ODOE) published...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/economic-opportunity/oregons-19th-century-energy-strategy/"&gt;Oregon’s 19th Century Energy Strategy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 00:31:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Gratitude on Thanksgiving for Freedom’s Defenders</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/gratitude-on-thanksgiving-for-freedoms-defenders/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;At the Goldwater Institute, our work this year has been strengthened by Americans who refuse to surrender their rights. Their..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/gratitude-on-thanksgiving-for-freedoms-defenders/"&gt;Gratitude on Thanksgiving for Freedom’s Defenders&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 07:01:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] The abundance of Thanksgiving hides the challenges in agriculture</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/the-abundance-of-thanksgiving-hides-the-challenges-in-agriculture/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;We are a nation that celebrates with food. Birthdays are synonymous with cake and ice cream. Easter is all about eggs and chocolate. Halloween is everyone’s favorite day for candy. But the ultimate in food-related holidays is Thanksgiving. This Thanksgiving, Americans will consume about 46 million turkeys, 77 million hams, 250 million pounds of potatoes, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/the-abundance-of-thanksgiving-hides-the-challenges-in-agriculture/"&gt;The abundance of Thanksgiving hides the challenges in agriculture&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 11:00:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Entrepreneurs, not the MEDC, will lead Michigan’s recovery</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/entrepreneurs-not-the-medc-will-lead-michigans-recovery</link><description>Lawmakers should focus on strong economy for all, not just favored few</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 12:36:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] The War of Visions</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/11/28/the-war-of-visions/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Across the country, Americans are no longer divided simply by policy or party but by rival moral imaginations—two incompatible visions of truth, freedom, and even human nature itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/11/28/the-war-of-visions/"&gt;The War of Visions&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 00:23:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Week in Review:  We Couldn’t Do It Without You!</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-we-couldnt-do-it-without-you/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The future of freedom in the United States will always rely on courageous individuals willing to defend their individual rights..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-we-couldnt-do-it-without-you/"&gt;Week in Review:  We Couldn’t Do It Without You!&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 07:05:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Scholarships mean bright future for Chicago teen as electrician</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/scholarships-mean-bright-future-for-chicago-teen-as-electrician/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Chicago Public Schools couldn’t give a teen the right education, but scholarships did. Now state leaders can OK a federal program to help every Illinois student.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/scholarships-mean-bright-future-for-chicago-teen-as-electrician/"&gt;Scholarships mean bright future for Chicago teen as electrician&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 10:55:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Vallas: Chicago needs education reform to curb youth violence epidemic</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/vallas-chicago-needs-education-reform-to-curb-youth-violence-epidemic/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Fixing Chicago’s schools is the surest way to stop youth violence. Softening education standards will perpetuate the harm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/vallas-chicago-needs-education-reform-to-curb-youth-violence-epidemic/"&gt;Vallas: Chicago needs education reform to curb youth violence epidemic&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 11:00:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] What was Michigan’s budget fight about?</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/what-was-michigans-budget-fight-about</link><description>Four big controversies that had to get resolved in negotiations</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 12:53:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] NH public schools post nation’s largest enrollment decline and 4th highest per-pupil spending growth</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/11/nh-public-schools-post-nations-largest-enrollment-decline-and-4th-highest-per-pupil-spending-growth/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As New Hampshire’s K-12 public schools experienced the largest enrollment decline of any state this century, they enjoyed the fourth-highest increase in per-pupil spending, according to a new analysis from the Reason Foundation’s K-12 Education Spending Spotlight. Per-pupil public education spending in New Hampshire grew by 60.5% from 2002-2023, the fourth-highest growth rate in the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/11/nh-public-schools-post-nations-largest-enrollment-decline-and-4th-highest-per-pupil-spending-growth/"&gt;NH public schools post nation&amp;#8217;s largest enrollment decline and 4th highest per-pupil spending growth&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 15:55:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/11/the-outstater-310/</link><description>Corporate Media on the Dock HERE&amp;#8217;S AN IDEA:&amp;#160;Ask the Indiana Secretary of State to deny incorporation for newspapers owned by out-of-state entities.&amp;#160; Preposterous? Somewhat. The legal hurdles would be daunting. It might be interesting, though, to hear corporate publishers testify under oath how they are functioning mediums for the First Amendment. If allowed as a friend&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/11/the-outstater-310/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 15:39:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Idaho Lands in Idaho Hands</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/idaho-lands-in-idaho-hands/</link><description>Is Idaho your “adopted” state? If so, why did you move here? Most people list Idaho’s relatively conservative culture, smaller population, and access to public lands among their answers. Idaho is a state renowned for its vast landscapes, rugged mountains, abundant natural resources, and accessible outdoor recreation; however, we have one of the highest percentages [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 20:27:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Week in Review: Make Idaho Sovereign Again</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/week-in-review-make-idaho-sovereign-again/</link><description>State sovereignty is a fundamental principle of Americanism and it should be reclaimed by our executive and legislative branches. The 10th Amendment made this principle unmistakable: powers not explicitly delegated to the federal government were reserved for the states and the people. The Founding Fathers instituted a federal system in which state sovereignty serves as [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 02:09:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Whitmer for president?</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/whitmer-for-president</link><description>A review of her record</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Trucking and Shipping Latest Victims of California’s “Cruelest Law,” AB 5</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/trucking-and-shipping-latest-victims-of-californias-cruelest-law-ab-5/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;If anyone thinks they’re seeing fewer trucks ripping up and down Interstate 5 or slogging through the perpetual 405 gridlock, it might not be their imagination. California law is strangling the freight-hauling business. There has been “a wave of bankruptcies among California trucking companies,” reports Floor Covering News, a trade publication, partially the result of the economic decline of the freight shipping industry. The wretched AB [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/trucking-and-shipping-latest-victims-of-californias-cruelest-law-ab-5/"&gt;Trucking and Shipping Latest Victims of California’s “Cruelest Law,” AB 5&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 11:00:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Nearly 30,000 Chicago teachers are caught in pension trap</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/nearly-30000-chicago-teachers-are-caught-in-pension-trap/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Half of retired Chicago pensioners make more than average working Illinoisans, but nearly 30,000 teachers won’t be eligible for more than a contribution refund.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/nearly-30000-chicago-teachers-are-caught-in-pension-trap/"&gt;Nearly 30,000 Chicago teachers are caught in pension trap&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 11:00:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] Schansberg: ‘Greatness’ — a Biblical Perspective</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/12/schansberg-greatness/</link><description>by Eric Schansberg, Ph.D. Noah is repeatedly commended for his righteousness, and then&amp;#160;for building the Ark in obedience. Not only does he save his family and pairs of each animal,&amp;#160;more broadly&amp;#160;he saves “mankind” and the animal kingdom — in what turns out to be a fresh start, a new beginning, another opportunity for man to&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/12/schansberg-greatness/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 13:39:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Florida Politics: The 340B Drug Program — Accountability Needed To Protect Patients, Taxpayers</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/karen-van-caulil-doug-wheeler-the-340b-drug-program-accountability-needed-to-protect-patients-taxpayers/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The&amp;#160;340B Drug Discount Program&amp;#160;was created to improve access to medications for low-income patients. But, like too many well-intentioned...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/karen-van-caulil-doug-wheeler-the-340b-drug-program-accountability-needed-to-protect-patients-taxpayers/"&gt;Florida Politics: The 340B Drug Program — Accountability Needed To Protect Patients, Taxpayers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 14:49:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Fort Meyers News-Press: Polling Shows Rural Areas More Receptive to Data Centers</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/polling-shows-rural-areas-more-receptive-to-data-centers-opinion/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;November 29, 2025 Late September in Indianapolis, residents filled a city council meeting with applause as Google&amp;#160;withdrew&amp;#160;its planned...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/polling-shows-rural-areas-more-receptive-to-data-centers-opinion/"&gt;Fort Meyers News-Press: Polling Shows Rural Areas More Receptive to Data Centers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 15:12:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Legislators, not judges, should decide school funding</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/legislators-not-judges-should-decide-school-funding</link><description>The Wyoming Supreme Court made the right decision earlier this month to pause education mandates from Laramie District Judge Peter Froelicher that seemed more like royal decrees. Legislators can now wait until the appeal to his February 26 order is decided in the Wyoming Supreme Court, which heard arguments in the case on November 12. Some of the requirements included higher teacher pay, a new computer for every student, a rethinking of the cost of education, school resource officers,...</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 15:14:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF opinion piece: Federal shutdown highlights New Mexico dependence</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-opinion-piece-federal-shutdown-highlights-new-mexico-dependence/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following appeared in the Santa Fe New Mexican on December 1, 2025. Among other things, the recent federal shutdown highlighted just how dependent New Mexico is on the federal government. According to the website Virtual Capitalist, New Mexico is the most dependent state in the nation on federal dollars. There are some good reasons for this. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-opinion-piece-federal-shutdown-highlights-new-mexico-dependence/"&gt;RGF opinion piece: Federal shutdown highlights New Mexico dependence&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 16:47:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Competition, not price controls, just slashed GLP-1 prices</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/competition-not-price-controls-just-slashed-glp-1-prices/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Novo Nordisk just announced price cuts for Ozempic and Wegovy, whose list prices as recently as last year were around $1,000 a month. Patients buying directly from the manufacturer will be able to pay as little as $349 for a monthly dose of these medicines. The company has also dropped prices for new direct-pay customers [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/competition-not-price-controls-just-slashed-glp-1-prices/"&gt;Competition, not price controls, just slashed GLP-1 prices&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 16:52:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] YAF v SBA</title><link>https://will-law.org/yaf-v-sba/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL and the Center for Individual Rights (CIR) filed a major lawsuit against the Trump Administration today, targeting the foundation for many of the remaining federal DEI programs: the preference for so-called “socially disadvantaged individuals.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/yaf-v-sba/"&gt;YAF v SBA&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 18:10:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] The fraud next time</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/the-fraud-next-time/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;That didn’t take long. The employee whistleblower Twitter (X) account @Minnesota_DHS has been suspended. In my last conversation with them (yesterday) they expressed fear over retaliation regarding their explosive post placing the blame for fraud in Minnesota on Gov. Tim Walz. When I last checked that post before the account suspension, it had received more...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/the-fraud-next-time/"&gt;The fraud next time&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 19:37:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] It’s Time We Stop Accepting the EdTech Lie</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/its-time-we-stop-accepting-the-edtech-lie/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;During the pandemic, while Americans were grappling with kitchen table issues such as job security, basic freedoms, the well-being of their loved ones and, importantly, the education of their children, Big Tech silently wrote their ticket to further subsidize their already trillion-dollar industry. And it wasn’t through broadband grants or shadowy back-door-deals tasking Meta or...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/its-time-we-stop-accepting-the-edtech-lie/"&gt;It’s Time We Stop Accepting the EdTech Lie&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 20:22:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] What Should St. Louis County Do about Its Budget Shortfall?</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/budget-and-spending/what-should-st-louis-county-do-about-its-budget-shortfall/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The two largest counties in Missouri are both having difficulties. Over in Jackson County, the assessment system is still a [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/budget-and-spending/what-should-st-louis-county-do-about-its-budget-shortfall/"&gt;What Should St. Louis County Do about Its Budget Shortfall?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 21:05:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] A Very Grateful Immigrant’s Thanksgiving</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/a-very-grateful-immigrants-thanksgiving/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Having just celebrated Thanksgiving across the United States, I’ve been reminded of what makes this holiday truly special.&amp;#160;&amp;#160;If you’re an American who’s grown up with the holiday your whole life, it’s easy to take it for granted. Speaking as an immigrant, let me tell you: there’s something genuinely magical about a country setting aside a [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/a-very-grateful-immigrants-thanksgiving/" rel="nofollow"&gt;A Very Grateful Immigrant’s Thanksgiving&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 21:11:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Retreat toward victory</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/retreat-toward-victory/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As part of the John Locke Foundation’s NC250: Freedom’s Vanguard initiative, this essay contest invited students, scholars, historians, and writers to explore North Carolina’s pivotal role in the American Revolution and the founding of the United States. The project highlights the state’s contributions to independence, liberty, and the shaping of the American Republic. Preamble “Patriotism,”...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/retreat-toward-victory/"&gt;Retreat toward victory&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 21:26:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Guardians of their own liberty</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/guardians-of-their-own-liberty/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As part of the John Locke Foundation’s NC250: Freedom’s Vanguard initiative, this essay contest invited students, scholars, historians, and writers to explore North Carolina’s pivotal role in the American Revolution and the founding of the United States. The project highlights the state’s contributions to independence, liberty, and the shaping of the American Republic. The story...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/guardians-of-their-own-liberty/"&gt;Guardians of their own liberty&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 21:59:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] It’s “data driven” – expect fewer juvenile prosecutions in Hennepin County</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/its-data-driven-expect-fewer-juvenile-prosecutions-in-hennepin-county/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Blame the system, excuse the behavior In 2023, shortly after taking office, Hennepin County Attorney Mary Moriarty hired the University of Minnesota to conduct a study of juvenile justice system interventions in Hennepin County. &amp;#160;The study, entitled “Reimagining Youth Justice in Hennepin County: Modeling the Impact and Effectiveness of Prosecutorial Responses,” sought to determine the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/its-data-driven-expect-fewer-juvenile-prosecutions-in-hennepin-county/"&gt;It’s “data driven” – expect fewer juvenile prosecutions in Hennepin County&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 22:01:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] The Fight Over America’s Institutions is a Test of Our Republic</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/the-fight-over-americas-institutions-is-a-test-of-our-republic/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="The Fight Over America’s Institutions is a Test of Our Republic" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/franklin.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A prediction of Supreme Court expansion sparks a deeper debate about whether sweeping institutional reforms align with or undermine the constitutional framework the Founders designed.&lt;br /&gt;
America was built as a republic, not a pure democracy, with federalism, separation of powers, the Electoral College, and an independent judiciary intentionally structured to restrain majority impulses and protect liberty.&lt;br /&gt;
Modern proposals to reshape long-standing institutions, from court packing to weakening states’ authority, reflect frustration with constitutional guardrails, but those guardrails are essential to preserving the republic “if we can keep it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/the-fight-over-americas-institutions-is-a-test-of-our-republic/"&gt;The Fight Over America’s Institutions is a Test of Our Republic&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 22:31:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Is the federal investment in workforce Pell Grants worth taxpayers’ money?</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/is-the-federal-investment-in-workforce-pell-grants-worth-taxpayers-money/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This summer&amp;#8217;s One Big Beautiful Bill brought an innovative expansion of the federal Pell Grant system. Starting in 2026, Pell Grant eligibility will be expanded to include certain types of short-term career training programs, like construction or welding training programs. What is a Pell Grant? A Pell Grant is a federal grant of funds to...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/is-the-federal-investment-in-workforce-pell-grants-worth-taxpayers-money/"&gt;Is the federal investment in workforce Pell Grants worth taxpayers&amp;#8217; money?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 22:50:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] It’s Time to Hold DESE Accountable</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/accountability/its-time-to-hold-dese-accountable/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A version of the following commentary appeared in the Columbia Missourian. For years, the Show-Me Institute has scrutinized the Missouri Department [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/accountability/its-time-to-hold-dese-accountable/"&gt;It&amp;#8217;s Time to Hold DESE Accountable&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 23:22:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Washington’s tour of North Carolina’s Revolutionary history</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/washingtons-tour-of-north-carolinas-revolutionary-history/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As part of the John Locke Foundation’s NC250: Freedom’s Vanguard initiative, this essay contest invited students, scholars, historians, and writers to explore North Carolina’s pivotal role in the American Revolution and the founding of the United States. The project highlights the state’s contributions to independence, liberty, and the shaping of the American Republic. In Halifax,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/washingtons-tour-of-north-carolinas-revolutionary-history/"&gt;Washington’s tour of North Carolina’s Revolutionary history&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 23:31:41 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>