<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>State-Policy Think-Tank Digest</title><link>https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml</link><description>Latest posts from free-market policy institutes across the U.S.</description><atom:link href="https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 15:03:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG Announces New Leadership</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-announces-new-leadership/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;IRG Announces New Leadership Alison Prange to serve as the next Chair of the Board of Directors  THE NEWS The Board of Directors for the Institute for Reforming Government has elected Alison Prange to serve as the next Chair of the Board. Alison Prange was appointed to IRG’s Board in 2022. THE QUOTES Alison Prange, IRG [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-announces-new-leadership/"&gt;IRG Announces New Leadership&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 15:54:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Three issues Georgia parents are most concerned about</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/georgia-parent-top-concerns/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A new report on child well-being from Emory University reveals the issues that Georgia parents say are impacting kids—and their futures—most. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/georgia-parent-top-concerns/"&gt;Three issues Georgia parents are most concerned about&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 22:42:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Virginiainstitute] The State of Educational Opportunity in Virginia – A Survey of Virginia Parents</title><link>https://virginiainstitute.org/the-state-of-educational-opportunity-in-virginia-a-survey-of-virginia-parents/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=the-state-of-educational-opportunity-in-virginia-a-survey-of-virginia-parents</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 11:07:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Virginiainstitute] Press Release – 50CAN Reveals Call for More Education Choice in Virginia</title><link>https://virginiainstitute.org/press-release-50can-reveals-call-for-more-education-choice-in-virginia/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=press-release-50can-reveals-call-for-more-education-choice-in-virginia</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Summary A recent poll conducted by the Virginia Institute for Public Policy (VIPP) in partnership with 50CAN reveals a strong demand among Virginia parents for expanded educational choices ahead of&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org/press-release-50can-reveals-call-for-more-education-choice-in-virginia/"&gt;Press Release – 50CAN Reveals Call for More Education Choice in Virginia&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org"&gt;Virginia Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 14:47:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] ROI-NJ: New Jersey Policy Institute appoints Unity Bank exec Boyan as board member</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/07/roi-nj-new-jersey-policy-institute-appoints-unity-bank-exec-boyan-as-board-member/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;ROI-NJ recently featured the New Jersey Policy Institute&amp;#8217;s (NJPI) newest board member, George Boyan, Executive Vice President and CFO of [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/07/roi-nj-new-jersey-policy-institute-appoints-unity-bank-exec-boyan-as-board-member/"&gt;ROI-NJ: New Jersey Policy Institute appoints Unity Bank exec Boyan as board member&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 16:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] API Announces Support of the STUDENTS Act</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/08/01/api-announces-support-of-the-students-act/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Alabama Policy Institute (API) announced its endorsement of the federal Stopping Teachers Unions from Damaging Education Needs Today (STUDENTS) Act, which seeks to reform the federal charter of the country’s largest education union, the National Education Association (NEA).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/08/01/api-announces-support-of-the-students-act/"&gt;API Announces Support of the STUDENTS Act&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 01:32:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] New Report Finds Pennsylvania Violating Law, Endangering Students in Dangerous Schools</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/08/05/new-report-finds-pennsylvania-violating-law-endangering-students-in-dangerous-schools/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Harrisburg, Pa., August 5, 2025—The Pennsylvania Department of Education (PDE) is violating state and federal law around “persistently dangerous schools,” endangering the safety of Pennsylvania’s most vulnerable students, and threatening billions in federal funding, according to a groundbreaking analysis from the Commonwealth Foundation.&amp;#160; More than 40 percent of Pennsylvania schools face dangerous incidents, but state [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/08/05/new-report-finds-pennsylvania-violating-law-endangering-students-in-dangerous-schools/"&gt;New Report Finds Pennsylvania Violating Law, Endangering Students in Dangerous Schools&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 14:42:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] OP-ED by Stephanie Smith, API President/CEO and mother of seven</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/08/06/op-ed-by-stephanie-smith-api-president-ceo-and-mother-of-seven/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Fourth Circuit of the U.S. Court of Appeals recently upheld West Virginia’s near-total ban on chemical abortions — a major win for federalism, health safety, and the pro-life movement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/08/06/op-ed-by-stephanie-smith-api-president-ceo-and-mother-of-seven/"&gt;OP-ED by Stephanie Smith, API President/CEO and mother of seven&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 05:47:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Tina Kotek’s Energy Policy: Whichever Way the Wind Blows</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/environment/tina-koteks-energy-policy-whichever-way-the-wind-blows/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Maxwell Powers Governor Tina Kotek has long expressed support for wind power....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/environment/tina-koteks-energy-policy-whichever-way-the-wind-blows/"&gt;Tina Kotek’s Energy Policy: Whichever Way the Wind Blows&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 14:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] DAILY CALLER: Don’t California-Ize The New Jersey Independent Workforce</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/08/daily-caller-dont-california-ize-the-new-jersey-independent-workforce/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Rosemary Becchi, President and Founder of NJPI, co-authored an op-ed in The Daily Caller with Patrice Onwuka, Director of the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/08/daily-caller-dont-california-ize-the-new-jersey-independent-workforce/"&gt;DAILY CALLER: Don’t California-Ize The New Jersey Independent Workforce&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 17:01:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Frontierinstitute] Pro-Density vs. Pro-Freedom: A Look at Bozeman’s Zoning Updates</title><link>https://frontierinstitute.org/pro-density-vs-pro-freedom-a-look-at-bozemans-zoning-updates/</link><description>"The problem isn’t that government is picking the wrong types of housing – the problem is that government is trampling on property rights and making choices that should be left to Montanans."</description><pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 22:49:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] First Statewide Poll Shows Marsha Blackburn as Clear Frontrunner Over John Rose in GOP Primary for Governor</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/blackburn-rose-beaconpoll/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=blackburn-rose-beaconpoll</link><description>In light of Senator Marsha Blackburn&amp;#8217;s recent announcement that she plans to run for governor of Tennessee, Beacon is releasing the poll results of the Republican gubernatorial primary a few days early. In the field before Senator Blackburn’s official announcement, the poll asked Tennesseans who they would support in the 2025 GOP primary for governor, Senator...</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 13:00:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] The Mississippi Center for Public Policy welcomes new Chief Development Officer</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/the-mississippi-center-for-public-policy-welcomes-new-chief-development-officer/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Jackson, MS&amp;#160;— The Mississippi Center for Public Policy (MCPP) is pleased to announce the addition of Richard Wilson as its new Chief Development Officer. With a distinguished background in campaign management, government affairs, and nonprofit fundraising, Wilson brings a wealth of experience and a proven track record of results-driven leadership to MCPP. “We are thrilled [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/the-mississippi-center-for-public-policy-welcomes-new-chief-development-officer/" rel="nofollow"&gt;The Mississippi Center for Public Policy welcomes new Chief Development Officer&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 18:26:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Meet Our New Director of Research</title><link>https://empowerms.org/meet-our-new-director-of-research/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;We’re excited to welcome Dr. Kristin Vance Richards as the new Director of Research at Empower Mississippi. In this role, she will lead our research efforts and help shape data-driven strategies that advance our work in education, work, and criminal justice. Kristin brings deep expertise and a strong commitment to using research to drive meaningful&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/meet-our-new-director-of-research/"&gt;Meet Our New Director of Research&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 06:00:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Competition in education is an opportunity, not a crisis</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/08/competition-in-education-is-an-opportunity-not-a-crisis/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;There’s been a bit of a media freakout this week about the growing popularity of school choice programs nationwide.  The Children’s Scholarship Fund-NH confirmed this week that the Education Freedom Account program hit its 2025-26 enrollment cap of 10,000 students in early August.   “Record number of students matched with their preferred form of education,” [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/08/competition-in-education-is-an-opportunity-not-a-crisis/"&gt;Competition in education is an opportunity, not a crisis&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 16:56:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Welcome Our New Director of Outreach</title><link>https://empowerms.org/welcome-our-new-director-of-outreach/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;We’re excited to welcome Ashley Geen to the Empower Mississippi team as our new Outreach Director. In this role, Ashley will lead our efforts to connect with individuals most impacted by public policy in education, work, and criminal justice. Her work will focus on elevating community voices and ensuring those directly affected have a platform&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/welcome-our-new-director-of-outreach/"&gt;Welcome Our New Director of Outreach&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 01:42:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] August 2025 Beacon Poll Results</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/august-2025-beacon-poll-results/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=august-2025-beacon-poll-results</link><description>A majority of Tennesseans, 56% of voters, believe the cap on Education Freedom Scholarships should be lifted from where it currently sits at 20,000 so that all eligible families who applied this year can use the program, while 30% of Tennesseans disagree and believe the cap should remain where it is. Polling has shown consistent support...</description><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 12:45:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] WTOK looks at what School Choice might mean for Mississippi</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/wtok-looks-at-what-school-choice-might-mean-for-mississippi/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I’m thrilled to share that momentum for School Choice in Mississippi is growing!&amp;#160;Governor Tate Reeves, Speaker Jason White, and even the White House are championing this transformative opportunity to empower parents and enhance education for our children. This week, WTOK TV aired an in-depth segment exploring how School Choice could benefit families across our state.&amp;#160;I [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/wtok-looks-at-what-school-choice-might-mean-for-mississippi/" rel="nofollow"&gt;WTOK looks at what School Choice might mean for Mississippi&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 16:08:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Who protects the protectors? The harsh reality for Kansas prison staff</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/kansas/who-protects-the-protectors/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Americans working in the Department of Corrections (DOC) are overworked, understaffed and, simply put, underrepresented. Correction Officers (COs) and other DOC employees are often represented by unions that include a wide range of state employees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/kansas/who-protects-the-protectors/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Who protects the protectors? The harsh reality for Kansas prison staff&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 16:27:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Iowa Mom Threatened with Lawsuit for Criticizing Curriculum at School Board Meeting</title><link>https://will-law.org/iowa-mom-threatened-with-lawsuit-for-criticizing-curriculum-at-school-board-meeting/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;#038; Liberty (WILL) is representing an Iowa parent with respect to a potential defamation lawsuit after she, a newly naturalized citizen from the Dominican Republic, spoke at a public school board meeting about her concerns regarding certain curricula and instructional materials used in her son’s classroom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/iowa-mom-threatened-with-lawsuit-for-criticizing-curriculum-at-school-board-meeting/"&gt;Iowa Mom Threatened with Lawsuit for Criticizing Curriculum at School Board Meeting&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 13:59:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Texas Pursues Property Tax Reforms in Special Session</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/texas-pursues-property-tax-reforms-in-special-session/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Texas Governor Greg Abbott called lawmakers back for a special session to address Texas’ property tax burden. In his special session proclamation, Abbott has asked lawmakers to focus on two complementary items. The first is allocating more state money to reduce property taxes, and the second is to impose more strict spending restraints on local...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/texas-pursues-property-tax-reforms-in-special-session/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Texas Pursues Property Tax Reforms in Special Session&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 19:10:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] What to know about education in Georgia as students go back to school</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/what-to-know-about-education-in-georgia/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As August ushers in a new school year in Georgia, nearly two million students are headed back to our states 2,300 public schools. How are Georgia schools doing when it comes to preparing kids for work and life? Here's a look at some key measures. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/what-to-know-about-education-in-georgia/"&gt;What to know about education in Georgia as students go back to school&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 22:26:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] Pa. Senate Passes Budget Protecting Taxpayers, as Shapiro, House Democrats Continue Gridlock</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/08/12/pa-senate-passes-budget-protecting-taxpayers-as-shapiro-house-democrats-continue-gridlock/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Harrisburg, Pa., August 12, 2025&amp;#160;— Today, the Pennsylvania Senate is advancing a spending bill that provides the clearest path forward in months toward a sustainable state budget. The commonwealth is now well into the second month of a protracted impasse, operating without a state budget in place. Despite Gov. Josh Shapiro declaring in June that [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/08/12/pa-senate-passes-budget-protecting-taxpayers-as-shapiro-house-democrats-continue-gridlock/"&gt;Pa. Senate Passes Budget Protecting Taxpayers, as Shapiro, House Democrats Continue Gridlock&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 23:11:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Nebraska’s Top Property Tax Targets</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/nebraskas-top-property-tax-targets/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Property tax relief is always top of the agenda in Lincoln, as Nebraskans struggle under the weight of one of the nation’s heaviest property tax burdens. Nebraska should target two taxes to take off the rolls, and two technical changes to restructure the property tax system to deliver better relief.   Currently, Nebraska puts $1 billion...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/nebraskas-top-property-tax-targets/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Nebraska’s Top Property Tax Targets&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 13:50:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] New WILL Report: Trump Tax Bill Creates Major Opportunity to Expand Educational Opportunities for Wisconsin Families</title><link>https://will-law.org/new-will-report-trump-tax-bill-creates-major-opportunity-to-expand-educational-opportunities-for-wisconsin-families/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL unveiled a new report detailing how Wisconsin can unlock a major stream of education funding for Wisconsin families – all at no expense to the state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/new-will-report-trump-tax-bill-creates-major-opportunity-to-expand-educational-opportunities-for-wisconsin-families/"&gt;New WILL Report: Trump Tax Bill Creates Major Opportunity to Expand Educational Opportunities for Wisconsin Families&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 17:35:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Average New NYC Fire Pensions Surpass $170K</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/average-new-nyc-fire-pensions-surpass-170k/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New York City firefighters and fire officers retiring last year after full careers were entitled to average annual pension benefits....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/average-new-nyc-fire-pensions-surpass-170k/"&gt;Average New NYC Fire Pensions Surpass $170K&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 18:25:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Special Session Should Use Emergency Funds, Not Punish Oregonians</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/transportation/special-session-should-use-emergency-funds-not-punish-oregonians/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Connor Roberts The Oregon Department of Transportation (ODOT) has a $350 million...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/transportation/special-session-should-use-emergency-funds-not-punish-oregonians/"&gt;Special Session Should Use Emergency Funds, Not Punish Oregonians&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 21:30:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] The Case for Carbon Sequestration via Natural Gas Power Plants</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/the-case-for-carbon-sequestration-via-natural-gas-power-plants/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=the-case-for-carbon-sequestration-via-natural-gas-power-plants</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In the case Massachusetts v. EPA in 2007, the U.S. Supreme Court ruled that the Environmental Protection Agency can regulate greenhouse gases because they qualify as air pollutants. And ever since, electric power plants using “thermal” fuels have faced escalating regulatory pressure. How this has played out for coal fired power plants in the Western United States is summarized...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/the-case-for-carbon-sequestration-via-natural-gas-power-plants/"&gt;The Case for Carbon Sequestration via Natural Gas Power Plants&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 23:16:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Get to Know Kathryn Beale, Beacon’s New Director of Development</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/get-to-know-kat-beale-beacons-new-director-of-development/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=get-to-know-kat-beale-beacons-new-director-of-development</link><description>Tell us about you—where you’re from, any fun facts about yourself, and where you spent your career prior to Beacon. I’m originally from Benton, Kentucky, a small town in the very western corner of the Bluegrass State. But, important to my upbringing, I am not a Wildcat! I spent four years in Nashville at Lipscomb...</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 15:13:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] Justin Bogie: Alabama’s grocery tax cut is a win – but lawmakers should finish the job</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/08/14/justin-bogie-alabamas-grocery-tax-cut-is-a-win-but-lawmakers-should-finish-the-job/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On September 1st, Alabama families will receive another dose of relief at the checkout line. The state’s sales tax on groceries will drop from 3% to 2%, continuing a rollback that began in 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/08/14/justin-bogie-alabamas-grocery-tax-cut-is-a-win-but-lawmakers-should-finish-the-job/"&gt;Justin Bogie: Alabama’s grocery tax cut is a win – but lawmakers should finish the job&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 17:41:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Kansas Can’t Afford to Lose Trust in the Jobs Numbers</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/kansas-lose-trust-in-the-jobs-numbers/</link><description>The latest Bureau of Labor Statistics (BLS) jobs report landed like a thunderclap in Washington — and it could send shockwaves to Topeka. For July, the BLS reported 73,000 net new jobs nationwide, 83,000 in the private sector, offset by a loss of 10,000 in government jobs. The unemployment rate ticked up to 4.2%, and [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 18:18:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] New York’s Hospital Quality Remains Among the Worst in the U.S.</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/new-yorks-hospital-quality-remains-among-the-worst-in-the-u-s/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The federal government recently updated its hospital quality ratings, and New York once again fell near the bottom. Among 132....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/new-yorks-hospital-quality-remains-among-the-worst-in-the-u-s/"&gt;New York&amp;#8217;s Hospital Quality Remains Among the Worst in the U.S.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 18:44:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] NJ ED REPORT: Amplifying Student Voices: Advocating for Younger and More Inclusive Representation in IEP Meetings</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/08/nj-ed-report-amplifying-student-voices-advocating-for-younger-and-more-inclusive-representation-in-iep-meetings/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;NJPI policy research intern David Fishkin, a Political Science student at Rutgers University – New Brunswick, has published an op-ed [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/08/nj-ed-report-amplifying-student-voices-advocating-for-younger-and-more-inclusive-representation-in-iep-meetings/"&gt;NJ ED REPORT: Amplifying Student Voices: Advocating for Younger and More Inclusive Representation in IEP Meetings&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 18:52:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Private schools in Wisconsin’s choice programs prove far more effective with taxpayer money</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/private-schools-in-wisconsins-choice-programs-prove-far-more-effective-with-taxpayer-money/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;School choice is 41 percent more effective in Racine, and in the rest of Wisconsin, money going to choice is spent 33 percent more effectively than in district schools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/private-schools-in-wisconsins-choice-programs-prove-far-more-effective-with-taxpayer-money/"&gt;Private schools in Wisconsin’s choice programs prove far more effective with taxpayer money&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 22:03:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] New, Flawed Rating Changes Cover Up for Underperforming Schools, Again</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/new-flawed-rating-changes-cover-up-for-underperforming-schools-again/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New, Flawed Rating Changes Cover Up for Underperforming Schools, Again IRG uncovers changes that hide low-performing districts from parents Delafield, Wis. — The Institute for Reforming Government (IRG) issued a statement after the Wisconsin DPI again changed its 1–5 star school ratings at an August 12–14 Madison meeting, leaving parents unclear on local school performance. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/new-flawed-rating-changes-cover-up-for-underperforming-schools-again/"&gt;New, Flawed Rating Changes Cover Up for Underperforming Schools, Again&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 16:17:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] State Board of Ed votes to reduce proficiency standards; legislators should implement a different state assessment</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/state-board-of-ed-reduces-proficiency-standards/</link><description>The Kansas State Board of Education voted 7-3 this week to accept new cut scores for determining proficiency levels on the state assessment test, setting the stage for the Kansas Legislature to hopefully halt the imposition of less rigorous performance standards. More on that shortly after a brief recap of the fraud being perpetrated on [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 18:03:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Governor Little: “Idaho will further improve government efficiency and reduce government spending”</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/governor-little-idaho-will-further-improve-government-efficiency-and-reduce-government-spending</link><description>Changes are coming to Idaho’s current budget with Governor Little acting swiftly to focus on government efficiencies in response to...</description><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 20:10:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] A Risky Proposal to Divert Connecticut’s Surplus</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/08/15/a-risky-proposal-to-divert-connecticuts-surplus/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connecticut&amp;#8217;s budget surplus presents a critical choice: use the one-time windfall to address the state&amp;#8217;s deep-rooted financial problems or spend it on new, permanent government programs. Progressive activists are pushing [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/08/15/a-risky-proposal-to-divert-connecticuts-surplus/"&gt;A Risky Proposal to Divert Connecticut&amp;#8217;s Surplus&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 20:11:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] State financial inputs aren’t the measure of a university system</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/08/state-financial-inputs-arent-the-measure-of-a-university-system/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;How do you measure the success of a business? You might look at financial measures such as profits, dividends or share price, industry dominance such as market share, or how well it achieves its mission. A law firm could measure success in client wins, a sports team in championships.  What do all of those measures [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/08/state-financial-inputs-arent-the-measure-of-a-university-system/"&gt;State financial inputs aren&amp;#8217;t the measure of a university system&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 20:17:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] The Cost of Transit in California</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/the-cost-of-transit-in-california/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=the-cost-of-transit-in-california</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This study analyzes the financial performance of 85 California transit operators for fiscal year 2023, revealing a significant gap between revenue and expenses that necessitates over $10 billion in annual taxpayer subsidies. The report identifies long-term cost escalation, driven by what economist William Baumol termed “Cost Disease,” as a core issue. It concludes that without...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/the-cost-of-transit-in-california/"&gt;The Cost of Transit in California&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 21:02:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Nampans Are Speaking. Will the Mayor and City Council Listen?</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/nampans-are-speaking-will-the-mayor-and-city-council-listen/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/nampans-are-speaking-will-the-mayor-and-city-council-listen/" rel="nofollow" title="Nampans Are Speaking. Will the Mayor and City Council Listen?"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/Article-Headers-2025-08-15T172539.543.png" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Since our last article, criticism of the proposed transfer of the Ford Idaho Center (FIC) to the College of Western Idaho (CWI) has escalated monumentally. Nampans are speaking out to express their disapproval — and they are not being quiet about it.&amp;#160; At the August 11, 2025, “listening” town hall, the Mayor and members of [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2025 01:00:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Listen: Skyrocketing Energy Costs on Inside Maine</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/listen-skyrocketing-energy-costs-on-inside-maine/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Policy analyst, Harris Van Pate, joined Inside Maine on WGAN to discuss new data from the U.S. Energy Information Administration showing steep electricity price increases in Maine, price increases which far outpace the rest of the country. Van Pate diagnoses the problem, explains what is driving costs in Maine, and outlines a better path forward. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/listen-skyrocketing-energy-costs-on-inside-maine/"&gt;Listen: Skyrocketing Energy Costs on Inside Maine&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2025 20:38:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] WHITE PAPER: Financing Hoosier Healthcare</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/08/white-paper-financing-hoosier-healthcare/</link><description>The foundation&amp;#8217;s white papers are intended to make scholarly research on Indiana issues more widely available to policy analysts and researchers. White Papers represent research in progress and are published to invite comment and discussion as preparation for their submission to academic journals and other professional publications. by Maryann O. Keating, Ph.D. Shuffling through&amp;#160; health&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/08/white-paper-financing-hoosier-healthcare/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2025 12:10:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] Albuquerque Mayoral candidate information: surveys and conversations</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/albuquerque-mayoral-candidate-information-surveys-and-conversations/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;There are seven candidates on the ballot this fall for mayor of Albuquerque. The Rio Grande Foundation invited all of them to complete candidate surveys and come on our podcast, Tipping Point New Mexico. The election is Tuesday, November 4 (with a runoff likely to follow). In alphabetical order by last name here are the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/albuquerque-mayoral-candidate-information-surveys-and-conversations/"&gt;Albuquerque Mayoral candidate information: surveys and conversations&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 15:16:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Shenna Bellows’ Response to DOJ Misses the Mark on Election Law</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/shenna-bellows-response-to-doj-misses-the-mark-on-election-law/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier this month, U.S. Department of Justice officials requested an electronic copy of Maine’s statewide voter registration list under the National Voter Registration Act (NVRA). In her official reply, Secretary of State Shenna Bellows rejected the request, citing state law and concerns about personal information. Unfortunately, her memo misstates constitutional authority, misapplies case law, misinterprets [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/shenna-bellows-response-to-doj-misses-the-mark-on-election-law/"&gt;Shenna Bellows’ Response to DOJ Misses the Mark on Election Law&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 16:52:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] School Choice is Coming to Mississippi!</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/school-choice-is-coming-to-mississippi/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;What would it take for Mississippi to embrace School Choice?&amp;#160;How can we join our neighboring states in empowering families to control their child's share of the education budget? For School Choice to happen, we would need to see several steps.&amp;#160; &amp;#160;&amp;#160;Number one, we would need a committed Governor, ready to invest his political capital in [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/school-choice-is-coming-to-mississippi/" rel="nofollow"&gt;School Choice is Coming to Mississippi!&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 17:23:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Rifreedom] Center Cosigns Letter Supporting Seafreeze Petition to Suspend VINEYARD WIND Construction</title><link>https://rifreedom.org/2025/08/center-cosigns-letter-supporting-seafreeze-petition-to-suspend-vineyard-wind-construction/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Today, CEO for the Rhode Island Center for Freedom &amp;#038; Prosperity, Mike Stenhouse, co-signed a letter, along with national energy expert, G. Allen Brooks, requesting Doug Brugum, Secretary of the US Department Of the Interior (DOI), and other federal officials to accept the formal petition previously filed Seafreeze Inc (and others) that calls upon the government to immediately suspend "further construction and energy generation activity" of the near-completed Vineyard Wind off-shore wind project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org/2025/08/center-cosigns-letter-supporting-seafreeze-petition-to-suspend-vineyard-wind-construction/"&gt;Center Cosigns Letter Supporting Seafreeze Petition to Suspend VINEYARD WIND Construction&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org"&gt;RI Center for Freedom and Prosperity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 17:38:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Idaho’s DOGE wants efficiency? This proposal checks all the boxes</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/idahos-doge-wants-efficiency-this-proposal-checks-all-the-boxes/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/idahos-doge-wants-efficiency-this-proposal-checks-all-the-boxes/" rel="nofollow" title="Idaho’s DOGE wants efficiency? This proposal checks all the boxes"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/Cream-Neutral-Minimalist-New-Business-Pitch-Deck-Presentation-5.jpg" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I have, so far, sent one and only one recommendation to the Idaho Legislature’s new DOGE task force that is supposed to be on the hunt for efficiencies in government. I could send more, but I wanted to offer something that checks all the boxes for legislators who want to: Make government more efficient. Save [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 19:16:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/08/the-outstater-283/</link><description>Cracking Down on Crime “Your race card has been denied, do you have another form of argument?” — anonymous. WE CAN HOPE that our city is learning something from the crime crackdown in Washington, D.C. It turns out that if you arrest people for breaking the law, other people, regardless of their background or upbringing, decide&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/08/the-outstater-283/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 19:40:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] KING NEWSOM DRAWS HIS DISTRICTS</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/king-newsom-district/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=king-newsom-district</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Newsom’s gerrymandering scheme not only disenfranchises independent and conservative voters in California, but all citizens of this State. The California Constitution guarantees citizens the right to meaningfully participate in the democratic process and be informed regarding legislation. In order to effectuate this guarantee, the people of California insisted on a minimum 30-day waiting period between...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/king-newsom-district/"&gt;KING NEWSOM DRAWS HIS DISTRICTS&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 21:55:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Florida’s Election Reform Sets the Standard Nationwide</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/floridas-election-reform-sets-the-standard-nationwide/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE August 19, 2025 CONTACT Logan Elizabeth Padgett 850-386-3131 Florida’s Election Reform Sets the Standard Nationwide...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/floridas-election-reform-sets-the-standard-nationwide/"&gt;Florida’s Election Reform Sets the Standard Nationwide &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 04:01:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Florida: The Gold Standard in Elections Administration From Bush v. Gore to Present 2000-2025</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/florida-the-gold-standard-in-elections-administration-from-bush-v-gore-to-present-2000-2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Ben Gibson — Senior Fellow, The James Madison Institute Doug Wheeler — Director, George Gibbs Center for Economic...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/florida-the-gold-standard-in-elections-administration-from-bush-v-gore-to-present-2000-2025/"&gt;Florida: The Gold Standard in Elections Administration From Bush v. Gore to Present 2000-2025&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 04:01:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Trump artificial intelligence plan a good start</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/trump-artificial-intelligence-plan-a-good-start</link><description>Order includes more than 90 policy changes</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Idaho landowners fight federal power grab</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/idaho-landowners-fight-federal-power-grab</link><description>Note: This is a guest op-ed by Louis Villacci of the Pacific Legal Foundation. When the Supreme Court issues a ruling, whose job is it to...</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 14:14:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] WILL Calls on USDOJ to Probe Wisconsin Election Integrity</title><link>https://will-law.org/will-calls-on-usdoj-to-probe-wisconsin-election-integrity/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In a new letter to the United States Department of Justice, WILL outlines potential concerns with the Wisconsin Election Commission’s (WEC) maintenance of the statewide voter registration list and suggests follow-up questions to be posed to WEC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/will-calls-on-usdoj-to-probe-wisconsin-election-integrity/"&gt;WILL Calls on USDOJ to Probe Wisconsin Election Integrity&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 14:26:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] The Great Smoot-Hawley Myth Persists</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/the-great-smoot-hawley-myth-persists/</link><description>&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1180" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/Screenshot-2025-08-19-at-11.32.03-AM.png" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;" width="1576" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Great Smoot-Hawley Myth Persists" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/Screenshot-2025-08-19-at-11.32.03-AM-534x400.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nearly a century after they were fresh on the American scene, President Herbert Hoover and the infamous Smoot-Hawley Tariff he signed into law in 1930 are back in the headlines. Making a comparison to President Donald Trump’s protectionist tariffs, critics invoke a common wisdom that deserves reevaluation.&lt;br /&gt;
The Smoot-Hawley Tariff is blamed for deepening the Great Depression, destroying international trade, and planting the seeds of World War II. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/the-great-smoot-hawley-myth-persists/"&gt;The Great Smoot-Hawley Myth Persists&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 16:57:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Connecting Nuclear Energy’s Past and Present: Guiding Missouri’s Future</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/economy/connecting-nuclear-energys-past-and-present-guiding-missouris-future/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Nuclear power provides nearly 20% of electricity in the United States, yet new construction has stalled even as demand rises. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/economy/connecting-nuclear-energys-past-and-present-guiding-missouris-future/"&gt;Connecting Nuclear Energy’s Past and Present: Guiding Missouri’s Future&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 17:23:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Connecticut Union Raises. Incompetence or Worse?</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/08/19/connecticut-union-raises-incompetence-or-worse/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="1216" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/Screenshot-2025-08-19-134951.jpg" width="1736" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Editor&amp;#8217;s Note: This article was originally published by The Hartford Courant. *** Connecticut Gov. Ned Lamont’s promise to grant state employee unions raises every year of his term is either a stunning [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/08/19/connecticut-union-raises-incompetence-or-worse/"&gt;Connecticut Union Raises. Incompetence or Worse?  &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 17:51:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Goldwater Puts University of Kentucky on Notice: Comply with DEI Ban</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/goldwater-puts-university-of-kentucky-on-notice-comply-with-dei-ban/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The University of Kentucky just can’t quit its devotion to Diversity, Equity, and Inclusion (DEI), even though a new law..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/goldwater-puts-university-of-kentucky-on-notice-comply-with-dei-ban/"&gt;Goldwater Puts University of Kentucky on Notice: Comply with DEI Ban&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 19:09:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] What’s at stake in Albuquerque’s City Elections?</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/whats-at-stake-in-albuquerques-city-elections/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Paul recently sat down with Diane Kinderwater for an episode of &amp;#8220;Issues and Answers&amp;#8221; on KCHF TV. The show airs statewide and can be streamed live right here. In a recent conversation Paul had a chance to discuss what&amp;#8217;s at stake in the City of Albuquerque elections this fall. We discuss crime, homelessness, the economy, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/whats-at-stake-in-albuquerques-city-elections/"&gt;What&amp;#8217;s at stake in Albuquerque&amp;#8217;s City Elections?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 19:34:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Nebraska’s State Funding for K-12 Education Has Doubled Since 2020</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/nebraskas-state-funding-for-k-12-education-has-doubled-since-2020/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Nebraska’s education funding has historically been heavily weighted on the property tax, but that is beginning to change. Through new sources of funding and property tax offsets, the implicit state funding of education is growing rapidly.  Over the last decade, state aid through the TEEOSA formula has increased by $200 million. Meanwhile, property tax funding...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/nebraskas-state-funding-for-k-12-education-has-doubled-since-2020/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Nebraska’s State Funding for K-12 Education Has Doubled Since 2020 &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 19:56:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Deficits on the horizon as state spending explodes</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/state-spending-explodes-deficits/</link><description>How do you go from having a $3 billion budget surplus and stable tax revenue to broke in just a few years? By repeatedly spending more than you take in. General Fund spending has pretty much been out of control since 2018, the year after the Legislature passed the largest tax increase in state history. [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 20:51:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] WASHINGTON: Helping workers gain independence in record numbers</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/washington-helping-workers-gain-independence-in-record-numbers/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;During the month we were celebrating this nation’s 249 years of independence, the Freedom Foundation helped free well over 500 public employees from union tyranny in the state named for its first president.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/washington-helping-workers-gain-independence-in-record-numbers/" rel="nofollow"&gt;WASHINGTON: Helping workers gain independence in record numbers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 21:45:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Mike Hurst: School Choice Showdown</title><link>https://empowerms.org/mike-hurst-school-choice-showdown/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Mike Hurst: School Choice Showdown With Speaker Jason White and Governor Tate Reeves signaling school choice as the top priority for the 2026 legislative session, momentum is building—but so is the opposition. On this episode, host Grant Callen sits down with the Chairman of the Mississippi Republican Party for a deep dive into the heated&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/mike-hurst-school-choice-showdown/"&gt;Mike Hurst: School Choice Showdown&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 01:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Let the Line 5 Tunnel project go ahead</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/let-the-line-5-tunnel-project-go-ahead</link><description>Comments submitted to the Michigan Department of Environment, Great Lakes, and Energy</description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] Snow: An Avian Parable on Polarization</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/08/snow-an-avian-parable-on-polarization/</link><description>by Nathanael&amp;#160;Snow, Ph.D. Over the White River on the east side of Muncie a bridge spans connecting the Kitselman Trail to the Cardinal Greenway. The Canada geese below responded with some interest to the first bits of stale bread I tossed down. As I manifested as the source of manna by throwing more morsels to&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/08/snow-an-avian-parable-on-polarization/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 11:45:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] The Tapeworm Eating ODOT’s Record Gas Tax Revenue</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/tax-and-budget/simple-solutions-for-the-odot-funding-crisis/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By John A. Charles, Jr. Governor Tina Kotek has called a special session...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/tax-and-budget/simple-solutions-for-the-odot-funding-crisis/"&gt;The Tapeworm Eating ODOT’s Record Gas Tax Revenue&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 14:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Banking on Freedom: Executive Order Takes Aim at Reputational Debanking</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/tax-budget/banking-on-freedom-executive-order-takes-aim-at-reputational-debanking/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The free market necessitates voluntary exchange, free from government coercion. Mutual cooperation through this socio-economic structure once propelled America from a fledgling nation into a global leader in innovation and prosperity. However, in recent years, government-driven debanking has undermined this system—cutting off individuals and businesses from basic financial services based on subjective judgments about their...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/tax-budget/banking-on-freedom-executive-order-takes-aim-at-reputational-debanking/"&gt;Banking on Freedom: Executive Order Takes Aim at Reputational Debanking&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 14:50:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Illinois adds 20,300 jobs in a year, but 301,000 seek work in July</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/illinois-adds-20300-jobs-in-a-year-but-301000-seek-work-in-july/</link><description>Illinois continues to be one of the slowest growing economies in the nation, ranking 46th in post-pandemic job recovery and adding just 20,300 jobs in the past year. Unemployment remained above the national average.</description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 15:33:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] BU Law’s Keith Hylton on Intellectual Property, Patents, &amp; the Law</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/bu-laws-keith-hylton-on-intellectual-property-patents-the-law/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This week on The Learning Curve, co-hosts U-Arkansas Prof. Albert Cheng and Ret. MN Supreme Court Justice Barry Anderson interview Prof. Keith Hylton, William Fairfield Warren Distinguished Professor and Professor of Law at Boston University. Prof. Hylton shares insights from his academic career and the book Laws of Creation: Property Rights in the World of Ideas, which he co-authored. The discussion explores how Enlightenment thinkers like John Locke and Adam Smith helped shape the legal framework for property rights and the free market in the U.S., and how these ideas are central to understanding our modern economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/bu-laws-keith-hylton-on-intellectual-property-patents-the-law/"&gt;BU Law&amp;#8217;s Keith Hylton on Intellectual Property, Patents, &amp;#038; the Law&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 16:06:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cardinalinstitute] West Virginia’s Certificate of Need Laws Are Failing You</title><link>https://cardinalinstitute.com/west-virginias-certificate-of-need-laws-are-failing-you/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;West Virginia’s Certificate of Need Laws Are Failing You The West Virginia Hospital Association’s recent op-ed defending West Virginia’s Certificate of Need (CON) laws is a masterclass in elite protectionism, dressed in concern, framed as a noble stand for community health. Make no mistake—the heart of the piece is about hospital bottom lines rather than how [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com/west-virginias-certificate-of-need-laws-are-failing-you/"&gt;West Virginia’s Certificate of Need Laws Are Failing You&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com"&gt;Cardinal Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 16:22:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Vouchers, ducks and the need to be honest</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/vouchers-ducks-and-the-need-to-be-honest</link><description>Opponents of parental choice in education are reviving their favorite scare tactic: the "voucher" boogeyman.</description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 16:30:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] NEW YORK: Opt-outs up by 63 percent</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/new-york-opt-outs-up-by-63-percent/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Public employees in New York are walking away from their unions at record speed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/new-york-opt-outs-up-by-63-percent/" rel="nofollow"&gt;NEW YORK: Opt-outs up by 63 percent&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 17:27:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Missouri’s Stagnant Reading Scores</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/performance/missouris-stagnant-reading-scores/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The COVID-19 pandemic began over five years ago. Students in 7th grade during the initial phase of remote learning are [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/performance/missouris-stagnant-reading-scores/"&gt;Missouri’s Stagnant Reading Scores&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 18:59:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] How Massachusetts Let School Accountability Slip—and Student Achievement with It</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/academic-standards/how-massachusetts-let-school-accountability-slip-and-student-achievement-with-it/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Commonwealth’s enormous investments in its schools—over 100 billion dollars since MERA was enacted—have continued to this day, but basic accountability has not. It is time to honor the original bargain. Massachusetts must once again couple its record-high investments with the same uncompromising scrutiny that made our schools the envy of the nation. That means prying accountability out of the foxes’ paws and restoring it to a truly independent watchdog—an EQA reborn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/academic-standards/how-massachusetts-let-school-accountability-slip-and-student-achievement-with-it/"&gt;How Massachusetts Let School Accountability Slip—and Student Achievement with It&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 20:24:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Frontierinstitute] The Character of Montana</title><link>https://frontierinstitute.org/the-character-of-montana/</link><description>"The world needs more men and women unafraid to take responsibility, adult enough to accept accountability, courageous enough to speak truth to power, and smart enough to express gratitude to others when they deserve it."</description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 21:28:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Updated Revenue Numbers Expose Idaho’s Spending Problem</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/updated-revenue-numbers-expose-idahos-spending-problem/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/updated-revenue-numbers-expose-idahos-spending-problem/" rel="nofollow" title="Updated Revenue Numbers Expose Idaho’s Spending Problem"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/Article-Headers-2025-08-20T144232.311.png" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;REVISION (August 21, 2025): Due to inconsistent reporting between the Division of Financial Management and Legislative Service Office, this article has been updated. The article now reflects the data that was provided by the LSO following the article's publication. For several years, the Idaho Freedom Foundation (IFF) has been sounding warnings about Idaho's excessive spending [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 22:10:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Frontierinstitute] Montana Data Centers: Separating Fact From Fiction</title><link>https://frontierinstitute.org/montana-data-centers-separating-fact-from-fiction/</link><description>Montana can lead the economy of the future, but only if we allow it.</description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 22:20:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Let homeowners below age 65 benefit from lowered property tax as well</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/08/let-homeowners-below-age-65-benefit-from-lowered-property-tax-as-well/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Honolulu City Council Committee on Budget on August 19, 2025._____________ Aug. 19, 2025, 9 a.m.Honolulu Hale To: Honolulu City Council Committee on Budget&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Val Okimoto, Chair&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Scott Nishimoto, Vice Chair From: Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Ted Kefalas, Director of Strategic [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/08/let-homeowners-below-age-65-benefit-from-lowered-property-tax-as-well/"&gt;Let homeowners below age 65 benefit from lowered property tax as well&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:37:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Help homeowners over age 65 cope with higher property assessments</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/08/help-homeowners-over-age-65-cope-with-higher-property-assessments/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Honolulu City Council Committee on Budget on August 19, 2025_____________ Aug. 19, 2025, 9 a.m.Honolulu Hale To: Honolulu City Council Committee on Budget       Val Okimoto, Chair       Scott Nishimoto, Vice Chair From: Grassroot Institute of Hawaii            Ted Kefalas, Director of Strategic [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/08/help-homeowners-over-age-65-cope-with-higher-property-assessments/"&gt;Help homeowners over age 65 cope with higher property assessments&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:39:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Historic Preservation Commissions Tread on Property Rights</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/historic-preservation-commissions-tread-on-property-rights/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;John Mark Slack wanted to restore his historic San Marcos home for livability. But San Marcos’ Historic Preservation Commission demanded that in order to get a Certificate of Appropriateness—its stamp of approval—he must replace  the roof, siding and doors; broaden the front porch, and add skirting. But commissioners didn’t stop there. In a recent Commission...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/historic-preservation-commissions-tread-on-property-rights/"&gt;Historic Preservation Commissions Tread on Property Rights&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 01:46:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Newsom: Green For Some, Not For All</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/newsom-green-for-some-not-for-all/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;California Gov. Gavin Newsom has a lot to say about the environment and also about government-funded high-speed rail in his state. As usual, he leaves out a lot of important context. In the third and final part of our look at Shawn Ryan’s marathon mid-July podcast with Newsom, we share what Newsom won’t. In the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/newsom-green-for-some-not-for-all/"&gt;Newsom: Green For Some, Not For All&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 10:34:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] As Math and Reading Proficiency Went Up, ‘Cut Scores’ Went Down</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/as-math-and-reading-proficiency-went-up-cut-scores-went-down/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This month&amp;#8217;s release of 2024-25 math and reading test results from the Education Department reopened a nagging question: Why are....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/as-math-and-reading-proficiency-went-up-cut-scores-went-down/"&gt;As Math and Reading Proficiency Went Up, &amp;#8216;Cut Scores&amp;#8217; Went Down&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 13:46:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Colorado’s AI Catastrophe: A Cautionary Tale</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/colorados-ai-catastrophe-a-cautionary-tale/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On May 27, 2024, Colorado became the unfortunate pioneer in a troubling new frontier of government overreach. The...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/colorados-ai-catastrophe-a-cautionary-tale/"&gt;Colorado&amp;#8217;s AI Catastrophe: A Cautionary Tale&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 15:20:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] The Inflationary Effect of Drug Price Controls</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/the-inflationary-effect-of-drug-price-controls/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In a bill chock full of bad policies, the drug pricing provision of the Inflation Reduction Act stands out as particularly troubling. This provision establishes a negotiation process to set a Maximum Fair Price (MFP) on selected drugs for Medicare patients. Because the legislation calls the MFP a negotiation doesn’t make it so. By statute, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/the-inflationary-effect-of-drug-price-controls/"&gt;The Inflationary Effect of Drug Price Controls&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] School Choice is Expanding like Never Before—Now Comes the Real Test</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/news/school-choice-is-expanding-like-never-before-now-comes-the-real-test/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;School choice is sometimes sold as a cure-all for underperforming public schools, other times it is deemed ineffective and a siphon of public resources. Both can be true, but this debate misses the point: school choice is not a guarantor of student success, nor was it ever intended to be. Its purpose is to provide choices, and most agree that choice is good. Not all choices will be good, to be sure. Indeed, there are poor-performing charter and private schools, just as there are ineffective district schools. When systems with school choice features fail, we ought to blame and reform the choices—they are clearly of poor quality—not ban the freedom to choose. It is grossly undemocratic to suggest otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/news/school-choice-is-expanding-like-never-before-now-comes-the-real-test/"&gt;School Choice is Expanding like Never Before—Now Comes the Real Test&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 16:05:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Federal Spending Cuts and the Real Threat to Liberty</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/federal-spending-cuts-and-the-real-threat-to-liberty/</link><description>&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1707" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/AdobeStock_404167062-scaled.jpeg" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;" width="2560" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Federal Spending Cuts and the Real Threat to Liberty" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/AdobeStock_404167062-500x333.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of his effort to reduce federal spending, President Donald Trump directed his administration to scrutinize budgets and cut unnecessary programs. Secretary of State Marco Rubio recommended eliminating $1 million in grant funding for the University of Iowa’s International Writing Program (IWP), which had received federal support for more than 58 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The IWP is described “the oldest and largest multicultural writing residency in the world.” With federal funds eliminated, the University turned to private donations, grants, gifts, and even foreign support to keep the program alive, ultimately sponsoring 23 international writers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/federal-spending-cuts-and-the-real-threat-to-liberty/"&gt;Federal Spending Cuts and the Real Threat to Liberty&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 16:58:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] In child care, as in housing, maybe the government’s doing a bit too much?</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/08/in-child-care-as-in-housing-maybe-the-governments-doing-a-bit-too-much/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Surging child care prices have grabbed the media’s attention here in New Hampshire, and rightly so. The price of full-time care in a licensed center “jumped 48 percent between 2013 and 2023,” landing at nearly $32,000 a year, according to an analysis last year by the Carsey School of Public Policy at UNH.   Child [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/08/in-child-care-as-in-housing-maybe-the-governments-doing-a-bit-too-much/"&gt;In child care, as in housing, maybe the government’s doing a bit too much?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 17:00:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] The environment is getting better — why aren’t kids being taught that?</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/the-environment-is-getting-better-why-arent-kids-being-taught-that/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;If you ask a Minnesota student about the environment, you’re likely to hear about crises, collapses, and catastrophes. The truth is that the environment has been steadily improving and that human life is overwhelmingly better with modern energy, spurred by innovation. Worry about the Earth’s environment is pervasive among Americans and young people writ large....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/the-environment-is-getting-better-why-arent-kids-being-taught-that/"&gt;The environment is getting better — why aren’t kids being taught that?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 17:37:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] The Perils of Populism: A Free Market Warning for Louisiana</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/tax-budget/the-perils-of-populism-a-free-market-warning-for-louisiana/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In an era where political rhetoric often pits the “little guy” against the “big guy,” populism has resurfaced as a potent force, captivating voters with promises of empowerment and justice. From a free market perspective, however, populism is not a savior but a siren song that leads economies astray. As Louisiana experienced with Huey Long,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/tax-budget/the-perils-of-populism-a-free-market-warning-for-louisiana/"&gt;The Perils of Populism: A Free Market Warning for Louisiana&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 17:47:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF in National Review: The Return of Car Choice, Hopefully</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-in-national-review-the-return-of-car-choice-hopefully/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following appeared in National Review&amp;#8217;s Capital Matters on August 20, 2025. Whatever happens to the future of EVs, they should compete on an even playing field with other vehicles. While the courts have yet to have their say, one of the Trump administration’s most important accomplishments, perhaps second only to his successful crackdown on illegal [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-in-national-review-the-return-of-car-choice-hopefully/"&gt;RGF in National Review: The Return of Car Choice, Hopefully&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 17:56:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] New Hampshire Becomes the 16th State to Expand Right to Try for Individualized Treatments</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/new-hampshire-becomes-the-16th-state-to-expand-right-to-try-for-individualized-treatments/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In another victory for rare-disease patients, New Hampshire Gov. Kelly Ayotte signed legislation this week expanding the state’s Right to..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/new-hampshire-becomes-the-16th-state-to-expand-right-to-try-for-individualized-treatments/"&gt;New Hampshire Becomes the 16th State to Expand Right to Try for Individualized Treatments&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 18:16:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] A Trio of New Transparency Laws: Examining the Open Government Reforms Instituted by SB 843, HB 103, &amp; HB 3526</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/a-trio-of-new-transparency-laws-examining-the-open-government-reforms-instituted-by-sb-843-hb-103-hb-3526/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;During the Regular Session, the 89th Texas Legislature passed three key measures to meaningfully improve fiscal transparency and cultivate a more informed decision-making environment. These well-intentioned measures include: • HB 103 (2025), relating to the creation and maintenance of a database of taxing unit bond, tax, and bond-related project information; providing a civil penalty; •...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/a-trio-of-new-transparency-laws-examining-the-open-government-reforms-instituted-by-sb-843-hb-103-hb-3526/"&gt;A Trio of New Transparency Laws: Examining the Open Government Reforms Instituted by SB 843, HB 103, &amp; HB 3526&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 18:18:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Chicago Public Schools has same credit rating as Colombia, Vietnam</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/chicago-public-schools-has-same-credit-rating-as-colombia-vietnam/</link><description>The Chicago Public Schools board is set to vote on the district’s 2025-2026 budget on Aug. 28. It must close a $734 million budget hole, but the district’s finances are a mess.</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 18:34:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Portland’s Social Housing Task Force: Another Wrong Turn for Housing Policy</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/portlands-social-housing-task-force-another-wrong-turn-for-housing-policy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Portland officials are once again reaching for the wrong tool to solve Maine’s housing crisis. In March, the City Council voted to create a “Social Housing Task Force” with the stated goal of exploring a system where the government owns, develops, and manages housing for residents. At first glance, this may sound like a bold [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/portlands-social-housing-task-force-another-wrong-turn-for-housing-policy/"&gt;Portland’s Social Housing Task Force: Another Wrong Turn for Housing Policy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Does Democratic Accountability Work in Public Education?</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/accountability/does-democratic-accountability-work-in-public-education/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I used to believe that local school board elections were an effective tool for holding public schools accountable, but I [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/accountability/does-democratic-accountability-work-in-public-education/"&gt;Does Democratic Accountability Work in Public Education?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 19:10:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Spotlight on Iowa’s September 9, 2025 Special Elections</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/spotlight-on-iowas-september-9-2025-special-elections/</link><description>&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="521" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/vote.jpg" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Spotlight on Iowa’s September 9, 2025 Special Elections" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/vote-500x217.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On September 9, Iowans will head to the polls for a series of important—though often overlooked—special elections. Unlike last year, when 21 local governments had property tax questions on the ballot, this year’s special elections are significantly less. Only three school districts—West Delaware County, Carlisle, and Sheldon—are asking voters to renew a property tax levy dedicated to school infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/spotlight-on-iowas-september-9-2025-special-elections/"&gt;Spotlight on Iowa’s September 9, 2025 Special Elections&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 20:03:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Will batteries save clean energy?</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/will-batteries-save-clean-energy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Probably not. Last week, the state Public Utilities Commission (MPUC) announced that it approved &amp;#8220;Minnesota’s first stand-alone battery storage project.&amp;#8221; The details of the 150 MW project: Located in Olmsted County between Byron and Rochester, the facility will store excess electricity from the grid for up to four hours and discharge it during times of...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/will-batteries-save-clean-energy/"&gt;Will batteries save clean energy?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 20:23:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Financially illiterate high schoolers about to be taught a lesson</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/financially-illiterate-high-schoolers-about-to-be-taught-a-lesson/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Overwhelmingly popular new mandate spurs action from nonprofits Editor’s note: Fourteen years ago, the Badger Institute (then known as WPRI) issued a paper by Scott Niederjohn calling on the State of Wisconsin to require that all high school students take a course in economics and personal finance before graduating. Only 19 percent of high school [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/financially-illiterate-high-schoolers-about-to-be-taught-a-lesson/"&gt;Financially illiterate high schoolers about to be taught a lesson&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 20:34:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Minnesota ranks highest in the nation on state support for immigrant students</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/minnesota-ranks-highest-in-the-nation-on-state-support-for-immigrant-students/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A recently released report from progressive institute The Century Foundation ranked Minnesota number one in the nation for immigrant student support.&amp;#160; The report judged states on three primary factors; (1) how specific the language used by the state government surrounding immigrant students was, with the preferred term being “newcomers” for its broad applicability to migrants,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/minnesota-ranks-highest-in-the-nation-on-state-support-for-immigrant-students/"&gt;Minnesota ranks highest in the nation on state support for immigrant students&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 21:07:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Wisconsin breweries no longer chugging along</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/wisconsin-breweries-no-longer-chugging-along/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Beer production in Wisconsin, a state that prides itself on its brewing heritagen is down more than 15 percent in just the last four years, a victim of a confluence of local and national drinking trends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/wisconsin-breweries-no-longer-chugging-along/"&gt;Wisconsin breweries no longer chugging along&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 21:09:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Generics Must Compete On Price, Not Safety</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/generics-must-compete-on-price-not-safety/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;America’s generic drug market is one of our greatest health policy successes. Today, 91% of all prescriptions in the U.S. are filled with generics. That dominance saves patients and taxpayers hundreds of billions of dollars every year—and it also drives innovation. Drugmakers know their monopoly on a new treatment will be temporary—typically only enjoying about [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/generics-must-compete-on-price-not-safety/"&gt;Generics Must Compete On Price, Not Safety&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 22:01:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Don’t add more tax tiers, but if you do, be sure to index them</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/08/dont-add-more-tax-tiers-but-if-you-do-be-sure-to-index-them/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Honolulu City Council Committee on Budget on August 19, 2025._____________ Aug. 19, 2025, 9 a.m.Honolulu Hale To: Honolulu City Council Committee on Budget       Val Okimoto, Chair       Scott Nishimoto, Vice Chair From: Grassroot Institute of Hawaii            Ted Kefalas, Director of Strategic [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/08/dont-add-more-tax-tiers-but-if-you-do-be-sure-to-index-them/"&gt;Don&amp;#8217;t add more tax tiers, but if you do, be sure to index them&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 23:40:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] After reforms, Casitas quietly are reshaping California’s cities</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/after-reforms-casitas-quietly-are-reshaping-californias-cities/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;After reforms, Casitas quietly are reshaping California’s cities By John Seiler &amp;#124; August 22, 2025 Although I now live in Irvine, a highly planned community, I weekly drive to Huntington Beach. For most of the 38 years since I came to California, I lived near the power plant now called the Huntington Beach Energy Project. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/after-reforms-casitas-quietly-are-reshaping-californias-cities/"&gt;After reforms, Casitas quietly are reshaping California’s cities&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 09:11:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] California Dems won’t say who drew ‘transparent’ election maps</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/california-dems-wont-say-who-drew-transparent-election-maps/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Meghan Blonder and Thaleigha Rampersad of the Washington Free Beacon document California Democrats’ dishonest take on gerrymandering. Top California legislators are touting their &amp;#8220;transparent&amp;#8221; process to gerrymander the state&amp;#8217;s congressional map—while refusing to say who is responsible for drawing it. &amp;#8220;Who exactly is responsible for the maps?&amp;#8221; KCRA 3 California capitol correspondent Ashley Zavala repeatedly...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/california-dems-wont-say-who-drew-transparent-election-maps/"&gt;California Dems won’t say who drew ‘transparent’ election maps&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 09:36:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Exposing unacceptable ideas of ‘toxic black radicals’</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/exposing-unacceptable-ideas-of-toxic-black-radicals/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Mark Hemingway of the Federalist highlights one of the worst aspects of today’s American political discourse. Since being dumped from MSNBC, [Joy] Reid has been making the podcast rounds. And the 40-second clip is vintage Reid; she accuses white people writ large of not being able to invent anything, rewriting history, and caps it off...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/exposing-unacceptable-ideas-of-toxic-black-radicals/"&gt;Exposing unacceptable ideas of ‘toxic black radicals’&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 09:39:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Trump seeks review of museums’ ‘woke’ content</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/trump-seeks-review-of-museums-woke-content/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Savannah Hulsey Pointer writes for the Epoch Times about a Trump administration focus on government-run museums. President Donald Trump has instructed legal experts to review “woke” installations in museums nationwide. According to an Aug. 19 post on Truth Social, the president believes that museums are the “last remaining segment of ‘WOKE,’” and he wants to...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/trump-seeks-review-of-museums-woke-content/"&gt;Trump seeks review of museums’ ‘woke’ content&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 09:42:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] ‘It’s unlikely they’ll be able to stop tidal waves of cigarettes’</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/podcasts/the-overton-window/todd-nesbit-and-mike-lafaive-break-down-their-data-on-rising-taxes-and-cigarette-smuggling</link><description>Todd Nesbit and Mike LaFaive break down their data on rising taxes and cigarette smuggling</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] How Chicago Teachers Union acts like Illinois’ newest political party</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/how-chicago-teachers-union-acts-like-illinois-newest-political-party/</link><description>The Chicago Teachers Union and its president want a say about fixing Chicago’s transit and health care problems, rather than focusing on its education problem. CTU’s answer to every problem? More taxes from Chicagoans and the rest of the state.</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 10:00:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] New TV/Digital Ad: Shapiro’s Budget Impasse is Failing Kids &amp; Families</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/08/22/new-tv-digital-ad-shapiros-budget-impasse-is-failing-kids-families/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Harrisburg, Pa., August 22, 2025 — Today, the Commonwealth Foundation launched a new ad, calling for Gov. Josh Shapiro to end the budget impasse with a compromise that protects families from tax hikes and offers educational choice. The ad is running statewide on digital beginning this weekend, and will air on TV from Sunday, August [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/08/22/new-tv-digital-ad-shapiros-budget-impasse-is-failing-kids-families/"&gt;New TV/Digital Ad: Shapiro’s Budget Impasse is Failing Kids &amp;#038; Families&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 13:32:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] CT’s Low “Fun” Rank Linked to High Taxes, Strict Regulations</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/08/22/cts-low-fun-rank-linked-to-high-taxes-strict-regulations/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="1709" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/shutterstock_1487599832-scaled.jpg" width="2560" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connecticut is not considered a “fun” state, ranking 43rd overall in a new WalletHub report. This quirky detail reveals a deeper problem plaguing the state: that high taxes and burdensome [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/08/22/cts-low-fun-rank-linked-to-high-taxes-strict-regulations/"&gt;CT’s Low “Fun” Rank Linked to High Taxes, Strict Regulations&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 13:49:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] BEAD for Speed: Louisiana’s Broadband Efforts Lead Once Again</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/bead-for-speed-louisianas-broadband-efforts-lead-once-again/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When the National Telecommunications and Information Administration announced an overhaul of the $42.45 billion Broadband Equity, Access, and  Deployment (BEAD) program that had been slowly unrolling since 2021, broadband offices across the country were tasked with revising years of work under tight deadlines. Louisiana’s ConnectLA rose to the occasion and executed a revised plan with swift determination,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/bead-for-speed-louisianas-broadband-efforts-lead-once-again/"&gt;BEAD for Speed: Louisiana’s Broadband Efforts Lead Once Again&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 14:20:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Yuma County Refunding Illegal Property Tax after Goldwater Legal Challenge</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/yuma-county-hospital-district-treasurer-refunding-illegal-property-tax-after-goldwater-legal-challenge/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In a win for taxpayers, the Yuma County government in Arizona has agreed to refund over $4 million it unlawfully..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/yuma-county-hospital-district-treasurer-refunding-illegal-property-tax-after-goldwater-legal-challenge/"&gt;Yuma County Refunding Illegal Property Tax after Goldwater Legal Challenge&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 14:53:39 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>