<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>State-Policy Think-Tank Digest</title><link>https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml</link><description>Latest posts from free-market policy institutes across the U.S.</description><atom:link href="https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 01:31:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>[Beacontn] Freedom Wins: The Future of Education is Here</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/freedom-wins-the-future-of-education-is-here/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=freedom-wins-the-future-of-education-is-here</link><description>While the EFS success is a great reason to celebrate, there is more work to be done to unlock education freedom for all Tennesseans.</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 16:17:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Mississippi Leadership Academy Kicks Off 2025 Program with State Leaders</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/mississippi-leadership-academy-kicks-off-2025-program-with-state-leaders/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For Immediate Release Jackson, MS – September 23, 2025&amp;#160;— Students from across Mississippi gathered in Jackson on Saturday for the&amp;#160;opening session of the 2025 Mississippi Leadership Academy, a program that equips high school and college students with leadership training, civic knowledge, and direct access to state leaders. This year’s kickoff featured&amp;#160;State Auditor Shad White, Representative [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/mississippi-leadership-academy-kicks-off-2025-program-with-state-leaders/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Leadership Academy Kicks Off 2025 Program with State Leaders&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 20:50:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Nebraskanomics: Governor Jim Pillen on Moving Nebraska Forward</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/nebraskanomics-governor-jim-pillen-on-moving-nebraska-forward/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Tune in to the latest episode of Nebraskanomics as we welcome the 41st Governor of the State of Nebraska, Governor Jim Pillen. During the episode Governor Pillen and Platte Institute Chief Executive Officer Jim Vokal discuss how we provide property tax reform for Nebraskans, the importance of making the most of federal funds, and what’s...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/nebraskanomics-governor-jim-pillen-on-moving-nebraska-forward/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Nebraskanomics: Governor Jim Pillen on Moving Nebraska Forward&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 14:43:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Nebraska Property Taxes Keep Rising Despite Tax Caps</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-property-taxes-keep-rising-despite-tax-caps/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Nebraska’s Truth-in-Taxation season brings surprises each year, shining a light on local government tax increases. That’s because Nebraska’s Truth-in-Taxation law requires local governments to notify property owners of proposed tax increases as a prelude to public hearings about the tax proposals.  Residents of Omaha were hit with another set of unsustainable tax increases in 2025, as...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-property-taxes-keep-rising-despite-tax-caps/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Nebraska Property Taxes Keep Rising Despite Tax Caps&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 15:30:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] Test Scores Changes Backfire on Education Establishment</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/test-scores-changes-backfire-on-education-establishment/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Test Scores Changes Backfire on Education Establishment Test score changes display widening gaps Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government (IRG) released the following statement following the release of Forward Exam and ACT test scores on Thursday showing mixed performance of K-12 schools in Wisconsin.  WHAT HAPPENED: Under Superintendent of Public Instruction Jill Underly’s [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/test-scores-changes-backfire-on-education-establishment/"&gt;Test Scores Changes Backfire on Education Establishment&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 17:52:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Idaho’s Parental Choice Tax Credit Is Constitutional</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/idahos-parental-choice-tax-credit-is-constitutional/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/idahos-parental-choice-tax-credit-is-constitutional/" rel="nofollow" title="Idaho’s Parental Choice Tax Credit Is Constitutional"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Article-Headers-2025-09-26T132715.417.png" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;A coalition of Leftist activists, including the Idaho Education Association, the Moscow School District, and Rep. Stephanie Mickelsen (R), has filed a challenge to block the implementation of Idaho’s parental choice tax credit. However, petitioners’ frivolous claims lack any basis in either our state constitution or Idaho Supreme Court precedent. Idaho’s school choice program is [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 19:54:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Why Affordable Housing is Unaffordable</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/land-use/why-affordable-housing-is-unaffordable/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Randal O’Toole Last week KGW news reported that Portland area rents are...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/land-use/why-affordable-housing-is-unaffordable/"&gt;Why Affordable Housing is Unaffordable&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 12:48:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Jere Nash: Reconstruction in Mississippi</title><link>https://empowerms.org/jere-nash-reconstruction-in-mississippi/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Jere Nash: Reconstruction in Mississippi On this episode, host Grant Callen sits down with historian Jere Nash, a Greenville native, retired political consultant, and co-author of award-winning books. Jere’s latest work, Reconstruction in Mississippi, 1862-1877, offers a definitive look at a pivotal era. We discuss why Jere chose to explore Reconstruction, debunk common myths, and examine&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/jere-nash-reconstruction-in-mississippi/"&gt;Jere Nash: Reconstruction in Mississippi&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 22:00:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Recasting Lawrenceville as a resilient, connected community</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/recast-lawrenceville-josiah-story/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Through our partnership with the ReCAST initiative, residents in Lawrenceville are finding purpose, hope, and connection through employment.   One powerful example is Josiah, who found a path forward by participating in our Jobs for Life class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/recast-lawrenceville-josiah-story/"&gt;Recasting Lawrenceville as a resilient, connected community&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:04:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] Hours Away from Federal Government Shutdown, Pennsylvania Remains Vulnerable</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/09/30/governor-shapiros-failed-leadership-resulting-in-a-monthslong-state-budget-impasse-has-left-pennsylvanians-more-vulnerable-in-the-event-of-a-federal-shutdown/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Harrisburg, Pa., September 30, 2025 —&amp;#160;A federal government shutdown is set to begin at midnight, barring a last-minute deal.&amp;#160;For Pennsylvania residents, the commonwealth remains in a dangerously precarious position, with a looming federal shutdown overlapping with its four-month-long state budget impasse. Despite reporting that a budget deal was “very, very close” in June, Gov. Josh [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/09/30/governor-shapiros-failed-leadership-resulting-in-a-monthslong-state-budget-impasse-has-left-pennsylvanians-more-vulnerable-in-the-event-of-a-federal-shutdown/"&gt;Hours Away from Federal Government Shutdown, Pennsylvania Remains Vulnerable &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 01:50:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Nebraska Property Taxes Now 4th Highest Nationwide</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-property-taxes-now-4th-highest-nationwide/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Nebraska’s property taxes have risen to fourth highest in the United States, according to a 2025 study from the Tax Foundation using 2023 tax data. Illinois (1.83%) has the highest taxes as a share of home value, followed closely by New Jersey (1.77%). Following New Jersey is Connecticut (1.48%) which is only slightly higher than...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-property-taxes-now-4th-highest-nationwide/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Nebraska Property Taxes Now 4th Highest Nationwide&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 13:48:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] First Principles Series: The Importance of Protecting our First Amendment Rights</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/first-amendment-fp/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=first-amendment-fp</link><description>Beacon tirelessly advocates for the principles of liberty whether government officials like them or not. Thanks to the First Amendment, all Americans are free to do the same.</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 18:16:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] Alabama Fights for Freedom</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/10/02/alabama-fights-for-freedom/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Defending higher education means defending SB 129. The core of SB 129 is not to censor but to restore balance between individual liberty and government overreach in education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/10/02/alabama-fights-for-freedom/"&gt;Alabama Fights for Freedom&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 16:48:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] BERGEN RECORD: The NJEA’s funding of Sean Spiller’s campaign was wrong. We need accountability | Opinion</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/10/bergen-record-the-njeas-funding-of-sean-spillers-campaign-was-wrong-we-need-accountability-opinion/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The NJEA&amp;#8217;s funding of Sean Spiller&amp;#8217;s campaign was wrong. We need accountability &amp;#124; Opinion &amp;#160; By: Rosemary Becchi October 2, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/10/bergen-record-the-njeas-funding-of-sean-spillers-campaign-was-wrong-we-need-accountability-opinion/"&gt;BERGEN RECORD: The NJEA’s funding of Sean Spiller’s campaign was wrong. We need accountability | Opinion&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 18:19:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] SPOTLIGHT NJ: NJ teachers sue over $40 million campaign boost for union president</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/10/spotlight-nj-nj-teachers-sue-over-40-million-campaign-boost-for-union-president/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;NJ teachers sue over $40 million campaign boost for union president NJEA used member dues to get its president elected [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/10/spotlight-nj-nj-teachers-sue-over-40-million-campaign-boost-for-union-president/"&gt;SPOTLIGHT NJ: NJ teachers sue over $40 million campaign boost for union president&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 18:24:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] First Principles Series: The Practical Case for Protecting Free Speech</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/free-speech-fp/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=free-speech-fp</link><description>Our “First Principles Series” is an ongoing awareness effort by Beacon to restore our nation’s commitment to those principles of free markets, individual liberty, and limited government that have made America the best nation in the history of the world. Often, politicians eager to appease constituents can stray from these principles. And voters can be misled...</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 19:21:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] New York’s Immigrant Health Coverage Becomes a National Flash Point</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/new-yorks-immigrant-health-coverage-becomes-a-national-flash-point/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A little-noticed New York program that provides Medicaid coverage to elderly undocumented immigrants was thrust onto the national stage this....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/new-yorks-immigrant-health-coverage-becomes-a-national-flash-point/"&gt;New York&amp;#8217;s Immigrant Health Coverage Becomes a National Flash Point&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 17:22:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Unleash home builders to fight socialism</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/10/unleash-home-builders-to-fight-socialism/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On Monday, a young woman from New Hampshire was featured prominently in a front-page Wall Street Journal story. She didn’t found a company or create a valuable new product. Quite the opposite; she spent the summer canvassing for the Democratic Socialists of America in New York City, where she hopes to get socialist Zohran Mamdani [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/10/unleash-home-builders-to-fight-socialism/"&gt;Unleash home builders to fight socialism&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 20:36:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cardinalinstitute] One Big Beautiful Opportunity to Reconnect West Virginians with Stable Work</title><link>https://cardinalinstitute.com/one-big-beautiful-opportunity-to-reconnect-west-virginians-with-work/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;One Big Beautiful Bill is One Big Beautiful Opportunity to Reconnect West Virginians with Stable Work On July 4, President Donald Trump signed the latest congressional reconciliation package, known colloquially as the One Big Beautiful Bill Act (OBBB), a sweeping package of federal budget measures including extension of the 2017 tax cuts, spending cuts and [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com/one-big-beautiful-opportunity-to-reconnect-west-virginians-with-work/"&gt;One Big Beautiful Opportunity to Reconnect West Virginians with Stable Work&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com"&gt;Cardinal Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 17:57:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Stueland v. Cullen</title><link>https://will-law.org/stueland-v-cullen/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL has filed a new lawsuit against Milwaukee County to end an unconstitutional carve out allowing Milwaukee County to withhold millions from Wisconsin’s Common School Fund. This fund, mandated by the Wisconsin Constitution, supports libraries in schools and communities across Wisconsin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/stueland-v-cullen/"&gt;Stueland v. Cullen&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 14:45:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG Report: Federal Bureaucrats Are Quietly Shaping Wisconsin Policy</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-report-federal-bureaucrats-are-quietly-shaping-wisconsin-policy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;IRG Report: Federal Bureaucrats Are Quietly Shaping Wisconsin Policy Guidance documents bypass legislature and voters, change state policy &amp;#160; Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government (IRG) released a new report on Wednesday detailing how federal agencies are quietly steering Wisconsin policy through informal “guidance documents,” often bypassing state legislative oversight. &amp;#160; READ THE [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-report-federal-bureaucrats-are-quietly-shaping-wisconsin-policy/"&gt;IRG Report: Federal Bureaucrats Are Quietly Shaping Wisconsin Policy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 15:11:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Give Me Your Innovators, Your AI: The Promise of America for European Technology</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/give-me-your-innovators-your-ai-the-promise-of-america-for-european-technology/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;There is a growing disconnect between America’s technology industry and America’s technology legislation. The dissonance between a culture where competition is driving profound feats of innovation and one wherein risk-aversion trumps all has become more pronounced with the proliferation of artificial intelligence (AI). Uniting policy and practice will be essential to maintaining American leadership in...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/give-me-your-innovators-your-ai-the-promise-of-america-for-european-technology/"&gt;Give Me Your Innovators, Your AI: The Promise of America for European Technology&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 16:30:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] In the Fight Over ACA Tax Credits, the Stakes Are Lowest for New York</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/in-the-fight-over-aca-tax-credits-the-stakes-are-lowest-for-new-york/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As Washington skirmishes over the future of enhanced tax credits under the Affordable Care Act, New York has relatively little....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/in-the-fight-over-aca-tax-credits-the-stakes-are-lowest-for-new-york/"&gt;In the Fight Over ACA Tax Credits, the Stakes Are Lowest for New York&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 18:14:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] Day 100 of State Budget Impasse</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/10/08/day-100-of-state-budget-impasse/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On Hundredth Day of the Shapiro Shutdown, PA Democrats Push Spending &amp;#38; Tax Hikes  Harrisburg, Pa., October 8, 2025 — Day 100 of the state budget shutdown brought chaos to the Capitol rotunda, with partisan political theater from Pennsylvania House and Senate Democrats placing parties even farther apart at the negotiating&amp;#160;table.&amp;#160; After previously rejecting and [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/10/08/day-100-of-state-budget-impasse/"&gt;Day 100 of State Budget Impasse&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 00:25:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Decarceration’s Disconnect: Corrections spending rises in Georgia even as prison population declines</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/georgia-prison-spending-and-reform/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Prison reform debates often focus on reducing prison populations to save taxpayers money. But is that actually possible? In a new report for the Manhattan Institute, Joshua Crawford, Public Safety Fellow at the Georgia Center for Opportunity, reveals some surprising answers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/georgia-prison-spending-and-reform/"&gt;Decarceration’s Disconnect: Corrections spending rises in Georgia even as prison population declines&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 04:09:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] VIDEO: California Caregiver Exposes SEIU 2015 for Coercion and Silencing Members</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/litigation/video-california-caregiver-exposes-seiu-2015-for-coercion-and-silencing-members/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In a video released today by the Freedom Foundation, Chaquan May, a California mother and in-home healthcare provider for her medically fragile daughter, exposes how SEIU 2015 has ignored, coerced, and trapped her in union membership against her will.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/litigation/video-california-caregiver-exposes-seiu-2015-for-coercion-and-silencing-members/" rel="nofollow"&gt;VIDEO: California Caregiver Exposes SEIU 2015 for Coercion and Silencing Members &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 20:19:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Fixing regulatory rampage will require amendment, say observers</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/fixing-regulatory-rampage-will-require-amendment-say-observers/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;But reforms via statute might help Wisconsin avoid a still more onerous environment Fixing the damage wreaked by the Wisconsin Supreme Court when it stripped the Legislature of its power to halt bureaucrats’ regulations will take a constitutional amendment, say legal experts — though reforms in statute can help in the interim. That damage so [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/fixing-regulatory-rampage-will-require-amendment-say-observers/"&gt;Fixing regulatory rampage will require amendment, say observers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 22:09:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] The Center for Black Student Excellence Should Be a Private Venture</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/education/the-center-for-black-student-excellence-should-be-a-private-venture/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By John A. Charles, Jr. In September, the Portland Public Schools Board voted...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/education/the-center-for-black-student-excellence-should-be-a-private-venture/"&gt;The Center for Black Student Excellence Should Be a Private Venture&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 07:06:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] WILL Urges Dismissal of New Attempt to Overturn Congressional Maps</title><link>https://will-law.org/will-urges-dismissal-of-new-attempt-to-overturn-congressional-maps/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The News: WILL is once again defending Wisconsin’s congressional maps, filing briefs in opposition to an overtly political, nonsensical, and last-minute attempt to redraw Wisconsin’s maps on the eve of the midterm election.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/will-urges-dismissal-of-new-attempt-to-overturn-congressional-maps/"&gt;WILL Urges Dismissal of New Attempt to Overturn Congressional Maps&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 14:35:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF discusses opposition to Albuquerque Public Schools’ $350 million bond with KOAT 7</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-discusses-opposition-to-albuquerque-public-schools-350-million-bond-with-koat-7/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As noted in a recent post on Errors of Enchantment.com Albuquerque Public Schools is looking for a $350 million bond on this fall&amp;#8217;s ballot. While RGF doesn&amp;#8217;t necessarily oppose the uses of the bond we have looked closely at the APS budget and have seen a steep decline in the student population while the District&amp;#8217;s [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-discusses-opposition-to-albuquerque-public-schools-350-million-bond-with-koat-7/"&gt;RGF discusses opposition to Albuquerque Public Schools&amp;#8217; $350 million bond with KOAT 7&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 15:15:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Avery Nichols named 2025 Sawtooth Leadership Academy scholarship recipient</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/avery-nichols-named-2025-sawtooth-leadership-academy-scholarship-recipient</link><description>After months of rigorous coursework, mentorship, and public voting, Avery Nichols has been selected as the first-place scholar, earning the $5,000 Tim Hennessey &amp;#38; Holly Harrison Scholarship.</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 17:36:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Among Large Massachusetts Cities, Lawrence Had the Highest Home Value to Income Ratio in 2024</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/among-large-massachusetts-cities-lawrence-had-the-highest-home-value-to-income-ratio-in-2024/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This edition of The House Call explores new American Community Survey data comparing home values and rents to household incomes in Massachusetts cities. It also discusses a proposed rezoning in Boston that would allow for taller buildings downtown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/among-large-massachusetts-cities-lawrence-had-the-highest-home-value-to-income-ratio-in-2024/"&gt;Among Large Massachusetts Cities, Lawrence Had the Highest Home Value to Income Ratio in 2024&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 19:48:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] New Report: Corrections spending rises in Georgia even as prison population declines</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/new-report-corrections-spending-rises-in-georgia/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A new report by Joshua Crawford, Public Safety Fellow at the Georgia Center for Opportunity, shows that the decreasing number of inmates hasn’t translated to meaningful savings or improvements in public safety for Georgians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/new-report-corrections-spending-rises-in-georgia/"&gt;New Report: Corrections spending rises in Georgia even as prison population declines&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 23:02:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Progressive Bills Youngkin Vetoed Will Kickstart Agenda if Spanberger Wins</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/progressive-bills-youngkin-vetoed-will-kickstart-agenda-if-spanberger-wins/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="630" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/Spanberger-erasing-Youngkin-Vetoes.jpg" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Predicting how Democrats will transform Virginia should they gain full control of state government in November’s election is easy. Just look through the list of 400 plus bills vetoed by Republican Governor Glenn Youngkin, most of them from 2024 and 2025. The progressive bills which reached Youngkin’s desk with unanimous or near unanimous Democratic votes and then died will [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/progressive-bills-youngkin-vetoed-will-kickstart-agenda-if-spanberger-wins/"&gt;Progressive Bills Youngkin Vetoed Will Kickstart Agenda if Spanberger Wins&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Gov. Mills exaggerates the ‘cost’ of federal tax conformity</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/gov-mills-exaggerates-the-cost-of-federal-tax-conformity/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Governor Janet Mills has claimed that conforming Maine’s laws to tax changes passed in the federal One Big Beautiful Bill Act (OBBBA) would “cost the state over $400 million.” A new 2025 Maine law empowered her to proactively comply with federal tax changes this year before the legislature reconvenes in January, but Gov. Mills has [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/gov-mills-exaggerates-the-cost-of-federal-tax-conformity/"&gt;Gov. Mills exaggerates the &amp;#8216;cost&amp;#8217; of federal tax conformity&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 13:29:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Shasta County Board of Supervisors to Appeal Ruling in Free Speech Case Against California Public Employment Relations Board</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/press-release/shasta-county-board-of-supervisors-to-appeal-ruling-in-free-speech-case-against-california-public-employment-relations-board/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Shasta County Board of Supervisors will appeal a recent court ruling against the California Public Employment Relations Board (PERB), continuing its fight to defend free speech rights for public employers and employees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/press-release/shasta-county-board-of-supervisors-to-appeal-ruling-in-free-speech-case-against-california-public-employment-relations-board/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Shasta County Board of Supervisors to Appeal Ruling in Free Speech Case Against California Public Employment Relations Board&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 14:12:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Tariffs – why we will hear a lot more about them</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/tariffs-why-we-will-hear-a-lot-more-about-them/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Remember the tariff debates that dominated Washington just a few months ago?&amp;#160; For a while it was the only thing anyone seemed to talk about.&amp;#160;First tariffs were raised by eyewatering amounts.&amp;#160; Then they weren’t.&amp;#160;&amp;#160;Eventually, after all sorts of back and forth, we saw tariffs imposed at the highest rates in decades. Free trade advocates warned [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/tariffs-why-we-will-hear-a-lot-more-about-them/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Tariffs – why we will hear a lot more about them&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 16:00:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Over-Sized, Over-Priced Schools Accelerate PPS’ Fiscal Crisis</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/reports/over-sized-over-priced-schools-accelerate-pps-fiscal-crisis/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Naomi Inman Cascade&amp;#8217;s President and CEO, John Charles, emailed a&amp;#160;Memo&amp;#160;on Monday to...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/reports/over-sized-over-priced-schools-accelerate-pps-fiscal-crisis/"&gt;Over-Sized, Over-Priced Schools Accelerate PPS’ Fiscal Crisis&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 16:57:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Moody’s reaffirms Idaho’s strong credit rating</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/moody-s-reaffirms-idaho-s-strong-credit-rating</link><description>Moody’s Ratings, one of the major global credit review companies, has reaffirmed its highest credit rating for Idaho while saying the state’s credit “outlook remains stable.” This good fiscal news is a reflection of Idaho’s sound fiscal management and helps save money for taxpayers by keeping government borrowing costs low with favorable terms. According to Moody’s October 9 update : “Idaho's Aaa issuer rating reflects its strong credit position supported by continued higher than average...</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 18:03:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF opinion piece: Voters should be skeptical of $350 million bond for APS</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-opinion-piece-voters-should-be-skeptical-of-350-million-bond-for-aps/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following appeared in the Albuquerque Journal on Sunday October 12, 2025. On this fall’s ballots in addition to votes for mayor, city council and school board, local voters will be asked to decide on a $350 million bond for Albuquerque Public Schools. These bonds (another name for debt which is typically used to pay [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-opinion-piece-voters-should-be-skeptical-of-350-million-bond-for-aps/"&gt;RGF opinion piece: Voters should be skeptical of $350 million bond for APS&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 18:49:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Political Targeting? The Valley School District’s Purported Vendetta Against Levy Opponents</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/political-targeting-the-valley-school-districts-purported-vendetta-against-levy-opponents/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/political-targeting-the-valley-school-districts-purported-vendetta-against-levy-opponents/" rel="nofollow" title="Political Targeting? The Valley School District’s Purported Vendetta Against Levy Opponents"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/Article-Headers-2025-10-13T182323.858.png" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Nothing says small-town charm quite like political retaliation. On one side, we have the Valley School District #262 trying to pass a $600,000 levy in the May 2025 election. On the other is a local farmer who dared to oppose it. When the levy failed by a mere seven votes, things escalated quickly. Cue a [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 19:17:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Meet the Leftist Organization That’s Been Influencing Texas History Courses</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/meet-the-leftist-organization-thats-been-influencing-texas-history-courses/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Great news! The State Board of Education voted this September to teach students history in grades 3-8. You would think that Texas schools are teaching history now, but, sadly, you would be mistaken: the current Texas framework only contains two years of actual history content in Kindergarten through 8th grade. One would think that a...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/meet-the-leftist-organization-thats-been-influencing-texas-history-courses/"&gt;Meet the Leftist Organization That’s Been Influencing Texas History Courses&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 21:26:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Lower proficiency standards lead to phony student achievement gains</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/lower-proficiency-standards-phony-gains/</link><description>In the fable of the Emperor’s New Clothes, two con men convinced the Emperor they had woven a magnificent set of clothes that were invisible to incompetent people. Everyone went along with the ruse to avoid being considered stupid, but they knew he was naked. A similar con is being pulled by the Kansas State Board [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 22:02:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Dr. Steven Skultety: Freedom, Rights, and Civil Disagreement</title><link>https://empowerms.org/dr-steven-skultety-freedom-rights-and-civil-disagreement/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Dr. Steven Skultety: Freedom, Rights, and Civil Disagreement On this episode of the Empower Podcast, Grant Callen sits down with Dr. Steven Skultety, Director of the Declaration of Independence Center for the Study of American Freedom at the University of Mississippi. They explore the foundations of American democracy, the origins of rights, and why civil disagreement&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/dr-steven-skultety-freedom-rights-and-civil-disagreement/"&gt;Dr. Steven Skultety: Freedom, Rights, and Civil Disagreement&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 23:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Michigan bill would make it easier to be a school librarian</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/michigan-bill-would-make-it-easier-to-be-a-school-librarian</link><description>Help schools carry their books</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] JMI Releases New Property Tax Reform Study</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/jmi-releases-new-property-tax-reform-study/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE October 15, 2025 CONTACT Logan Elizabeth Padgett lpadgett@jamesmadison.org (850) 386-3131 JMI Releases New Property Tax...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/jmi-releases-new-property-tax-reform-study/"&gt;JMI Releases New Property Tax Reform Study&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Listen: Gov. Mills Announces for Senate</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/listen-gov-mills-announces-for-senate/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Policy analyst, Harris Van Pate, joined the WGAN Morning News to discuss Gov. Janet Mills&amp;#8217; announcement to run for the Senate against Sen. Susan Collins and what the path forward looks like for Mills in the democratic primary. He also talked about CMP&amp;#8217;s most recent rate hike proposal and shared some insights on Maine Policy&amp;#8217;s [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/listen-gov-mills-announces-for-senate/"&gt;Listen: Gov. Mills Announces for Senate&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 12:31:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] New Report Finds Most New Jersey School Districts Lack  Clear Academic Goals or Accountability in Strategic Plans</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/10/new-report-finds-most-new-jersey-school-districts-lack-clear-academic-goals-or-accountability-in-strategic-plans/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 14:52:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] AZ Trinity Arch Prep’s Jack Johnson Pannell on Educating Boys</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/az-trinity-arch-preps-jack-johnson-pannell-on-educating-boys/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In this week’s episode of The Learning Curve, co-hosts U-Arkansas Prof. Albert Cheng and Center for Public Schools’ Alisha Searcy interview Jack Johnson Pannell, founder and head of Trinity Arch Preparatory School for Boys in Phoenix. Mr. Pannell discusses his career as an educational leader, including founding a nationally recognized charter school in Baltimore, and shares how his background in the liberal arts and law has informed his approach to schooling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/az-trinity-arch-preps-jack-johnson-pannell-on-educating-boys/"&gt;AZ Trinity Arch Prep&amp;#8217;s Jack Johnson Pannell on Educating Boys&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 15:48:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Legal Advocates Ask Supreme Court to End Home Equity Seizures in Tax Foreclosures</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/legal-advocates-ask-supreme-court-to-end-home-equity-seizures-in-tax-foreclosures/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;BOSTON, MA — The Pioneer New England Legal Foundation (Legal Foundation), Greater Boston Legal Services (GBLS), and law firm Greenberg Traurig filed an amicus brief with the U.S. Supreme Court in support of homeowners in two Michigan cases that could determine how far governments can go in taking property for unpaid taxes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/legal-advocates-ask-supreme-court-to-end-home-equity-seizures-in-tax-foreclosures/"&gt;Legal Advocates Ask Supreme Court to End Home Equity Seizures in Tax Foreclosures &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 16:12:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] American Independence = Financial Independence</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/tax-budget/american-independence-financial-independence/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When America declared its independence nearly 250 years ago, it was not only a political revolution but also an assertion of self-reliance. The Founders of our country believed that Americans ought to be able to self-govern without dependence on a distant power. Today, that spirit of independence is under strain—not from a foreign monarch, but...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/tax-budget/american-independence-financial-independence/"&gt;American Independence = Financial Independence&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 16:31:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] 2026 Naples Annual Dinner</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/naples/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Join The James Madison Institute (JMI) in Naples, Florida, on February 17th, 2026, for the 2026 Naples Annual...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/naples/"&gt;2026 Naples Annual Dinner&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 16:34:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Red, White, &amp; Bluegrass</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/tallahassee/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Mark your calendars for our 2026 Red, White, &amp;#38; Bluegrass event in Tallahassee. Join us January 14, 2025...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/tallahassee/"&gt;Red, White, &amp;amp; Bluegrass&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 16:38:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF provides comments in support of unlocking new water supplies for New Mexicans</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-provides-comments-in-support-of-unlocking-new-water-supplies-for-new-mexicans/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;They say &amp;#8220;agua es vida&amp;#8221; in New Mexico (water is life). In the desert southwest water is critical to human flourishing and the broader economy of the state and region. So, when we were presented with an opportunity to put water that is produced alongside oil and gas, we had only one question: &amp;#8220;Is it [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-provides-comments-in-support-of-unlocking-new-water-supplies-for-new-mexicans/"&gt;RGF provides comments in support of unlocking new water supplies for New Mexicans&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 16:38:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Jefferson City Residents Should Be Skeptical of Conference Center Project</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/subsidies/jefferson-city-residents-should-be-skeptical-of-conference-center-project/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A version of this commentary appeared in the News-Tribune. On November 4, Jefferson City voters will decide on a proposal to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/subsidies/jefferson-city-residents-should-be-skeptical-of-conference-center-project/"&gt;Jefferson City Residents Should Be Skeptical of Conference Center Project&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 18:01:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] The $8.25 Billion San Francisco Train that Couldn’t (or at least Shouldn’t)</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/the-8-25-billion-san-francisco-train-that-couldnt-or-at-least-shouldnt/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=the-8-25-billion-san-francisco-train-that-couldnt-or-at-least-shouldnt</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The California High-Speed Rail Authority has finally recognized the obvious: there is no path to connecting Los Angeles and San Francisco with trains running at 220mph. With state rail officials now accepting reality, the question is whether northern California transit planners will do so as well by cancelling their plan to extend California High-Speed Rail...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/the-8-25-billion-san-francisco-train-that-couldnt-or-at-least-shouldnt/"&gt;The $8.25 Billion San Francisco Train that Couldn’t (or at least Shouldn’t)&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 19:42:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG: New School Choice Enrollment Numbers Show Growth Slowing Statewide</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-new-school-choice-enrollment-numbers-show-growth-slowing-statewide/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;IRG: New School Choice Enrollment Numbers Show Growth Slowing Statewide Baby bust rears its head in school enrollment numbers Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government (IRG) released the following statement following the Department of Public Instruction’s release of 2025-2026 school choice and charter enrollment numbers. WHY IT MATTERS: While traditional schools continue to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-new-school-choice-enrollment-numbers-show-growth-slowing-statewide/"&gt;IRG: New School Choice Enrollment Numbers Show Growth Slowing Statewide&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 19:51:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] It Is Time to Tackle Idaho’s Public Spending Addiction</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/it-is-time-to-tackle-idahos-public-spending-addiction/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/it-is-time-to-tackle-idahos-public-spending-addiction/" rel="nofollow" title="It Is Time to Tackle Idaho’s Public Spending Addiction"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/Article-Headers-2025-10-15T135522.813.png" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Idaho officials are addicted. The standard dictionary definition of addiction is “a strong inclination to do, use, or indulge in something repeatedly,” and there is nothing that matches this description more than the Idaho state government’s inability to curb the growth of spending.&amp;#160; Mind you, it is not just Idaho. The shutdown of the federal [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 20:19:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Considering Coal-to-Nuclear Transitions in Missouri</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/energy/considering-coal-to-nuclear-transitions-in-missouri/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Kansas’s Department of Commerce and Evergy (the state’s largest utility) are partnering with TerraPower, a leading nuclear developer, to explore [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/energy/considering-coal-to-nuclear-transitions-in-missouri/"&gt;Considering Coal-to-Nuclear Transitions in Missouri&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 21:30:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Farewell to a founding father of the liberty movement</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/farewell-to-a-founding-father-of-the-liberty-movement</link><description>Edwin J. Feulner, R.I.P.</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Naval strikes on drug rings may bring cases of “Smuggler’s Blues” and “Sugar Highs”</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/naval-strikes-on-drug-rings-may-bring-cases-of-smugglers-blues-and-sugar-highs/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In 1999, just 703 people died from fentanyl overdoses. For the next ten years, those deaths remained relatively low. hitting 2,628 in 2012. Yet from 2013 to 2023, fentanyl killed 376,197 Americans – a number roughly equivalent to the entire population of Cleveland Ohio. This doesn’t factor in the over 1.3 million overdose victims who [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/naval-strikes-on-drug-rings-may-bring-cases-of-smugglers-blues-and-sugar-highs/"&gt;Naval strikes on drug rings may bring cases of “Smuggler’s Blues” and “Sugar Highs”&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 10:00:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Randy Watson’s legacy: 10 years of declining college readiness on ACT</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/watson-10-years-declining-college-readiness-act/</link><description>Kansas Education Commissioner Randy Watson took office in July of 2015 and immediately began de-emphasizing academic improvement in favor of social-emotional learning (SEL). He convinced the State Board of Education to adopt his gimmicky “Kansans Can” program, featuring a tagline of “Kansas leads the world in the success of each student.” At the time of [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 12:06:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Why we focus on economic growth</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/10/why-we-focus-on-economic-growth/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When testifying at the Statehouse, Josiah Bartlett Center staff are sometimes surprised by questions legislators ask. We don’t expect lawmakers to know the research on how certain policies worked or didn’t work in other states. Finding and presenting that information is our job. The surprises come when lawmakers ask more basic questions. We are fairly [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/10/why-we-focus-on-economic-growth/"&gt;Why we focus on economic growth&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 13:48:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Accountability and Action: The Path to Safer Communities</title><link>https://empowerms.org/accountability-and-action-the-path-to-safer-communities/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This past weekend, our state was rocked by a wave of violent crime. Over the course of twenty-four hours, five shootings claimed the lives of at least nine Mississippians. While these horrific acts do not appear to be connected, they are alarming nevertheless. Words like horrific, tragic, and avoidable all come to mind. First and&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/accountability-and-action-the-path-to-safer-communities/"&gt;Accountability and Action: The Path to Safer Communities&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 14:16:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Wisconsin Artist Battles Utility in Landmark Property Rights Case</title><link>https://will-law.org/wisconsin-artist-battles-utility-in-landmark-property-rights-case/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL issued a warning to the American Transmission Company (ATC) regarding its plan to build a massive new transmission line across the property of Tom and Mary Uttech in Saukville, WI, for the sole benefit of a new AI data center in Port Washington, WI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/wisconsin-artist-battles-utility-in-landmark-property-rights-case/"&gt;Wisconsin Artist Battles Utility in Landmark Property Rights Case&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 14:46:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] How to reform the property tax to protect taxpayers and services</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/how-to-reform-wyoming-s-property-tax-to-protect-taxpayers-and-services</link><description>Calls to abolish the property tax are growing louder across the country as elected representatives respond to constituents' increasing concerns about rising property assessments and tax bills. Wyoming is one of the states currently having this debate. What happens there next could be a lesson for lawmakers in other states. In the last year, Wyoming legislators passed stopgap measures to lower residents’ bills in the short term. The lack of meaningful and long-term reform, plus increasing...</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 15:55:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Steps Toward Water Abundance</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/steps-toward-water-abundance/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=steps-toward-water-abundance</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier this month a letter was sent to Governor Newsom from the State Water Contractors, an association of 27 water agencies that together deliver water to nearly 30 million Californians and irrigate nearly one million acres of farmland. This letter is a document of extraordinary importance to the future of California’s water supply. It summarizes several significant reasons...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/steps-toward-water-abundance/"&gt;Steps Toward Water Abundance&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 16:08:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] A Winning Playbook: How Louisiana can Continue to Attract the Tech Industry</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/a-winning-playbook-how-louisiana-can-continue-to-attract-the-tech-industry/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Anyone following the drama of football season can attest to the fact that recruiting never stops. Savvy coaches and general managers understand that every game, press conference, and handshake is helping potential players answer the question of “which team do I want to play for?” In Louisiana, a state known for championship football teams and...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/a-winning-playbook-how-louisiana-can-continue-to-attract-the-tech-industry/"&gt;A Winning Playbook: How Louisiana can Continue to Attract the Tech Industry&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 17:11:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] The Up-Down Coalition Is Turning Red</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/the-up-down-coalition-is-turning-red/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=the-up-down-coalition-is-turning-red</link><description>&lt;p&gt;While the progressive candidates in America rely on millions of college-educated liberals as its base, it depends on two additional sources of political power. The loss of either one could be fatal to the party’s ability to win elections. The first is America’s financial elites, providing money and institutional support. The second is America’s low-income...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/the-up-down-coalition-is-turning-red/"&gt;The Up-Down Coalition Is Turning Red&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 17:36:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Podcast: DEI Is Destroying Our Universities</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/podcast-dei-is-destroying-our-universities/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;What happens when America’s most prestigious universities stop educating and start indoctrinating? In the latest episode of the Goldwater Institute’s..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/podcast-dei-is-destroying-our-universities/"&gt;Podcast: DEI Is Destroying Our Universities&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 19:00:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Reform First, Dollars Second</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/free-market-reform/reform-first-dollars-second/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;If policymakers were worried about the One Big Beautiful Bill’s impact on healthcare in Missouri, they may soon find it’s [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/free-market-reform/reform-first-dollars-second/"&gt;Reform First, Dollars Second&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 19:45:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Arkansas teachers union’s dues revenue drops 36 percent in one year</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/labor/arkansas-teachers-unions-dues-revenue-drops-36-percent-in-one-year/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A new Freedom Foundation analysis shows the Arkansas Education Association's annual revenue from member dues plummeted 36 percent after school districts stopped deducting dues from teachers' paychecks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/labor/arkansas-teachers-unions-dues-revenue-drops-36-percent-in-one-year/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Arkansas teachers union’s dues revenue drops 36 percent in one year&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 19:50:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] DOH Ducks a Simple Question on Covid in Nursing Homes</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/doh-ducks-a-simple-question-on-covid-in-nursing-homes/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Five years after the coronavirus pandemic, the state Department of Health is pleading ignorance about one of its most hotly....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/doh-ducks-a-simple-question-on-covid-in-nursing-homes/"&gt;DOH Ducks a Simple Question on Covid in Nursing Homes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 20:05:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Bill would use tax credit to lower cost barrier to new nuclear in Wisconsin</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/bill-would-use-tax-credit-to-lower-cost-barrier-to-new-nuclear-in-wisconsin/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New nuclear measure in Wisconsin includes shifts in state’s priorities in law for ‘only way we keep lights on.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/bill-would-use-tax-credit-to-lower-cost-barrier-to-new-nuclear-in-wisconsin/"&gt;Bill would use tax credit to lower cost barrier to new nuclear in Wisconsin&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 22:06:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Claims of data center water use are laughably wrong</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/claims-of-data-center-water-use-are-laughably-wrong/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The biggest data centers planned for Wisconsin are not a threat to local water systems or to Lake Michigan — a fact opponents either can’t believe or won’t admit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/claims-of-data-center-water-use-are-laughably-wrong/"&gt;Claims of data center water use are laughably wrong&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 22:06:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] If you build it, they will socialize? Public spaces and loneliness</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/if-you-build-it-they-will-socialize-public-spaces-and-loneliness/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;If you build it, they will socialize? Public spaces and loneliness By D. Dowd Muska  &amp;#124; October 17, 2025 Urbanists have a new item for cities’ to-do lists: Fix America’s loneliness crisis. And their preferred tool? Public spaces. The William Penn Foundation’s Shawn McCaney is typical. He believes the nation’s “lack of social connection” is [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/if-you-build-it-they-will-socialize-public-spaces-and-loneliness/"&gt;If you build it, they will socialize? Public spaces and loneliness&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 09:00:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] ‘We are failing in public education’</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/podcasts/the-overton-window/kevin-rinke-discusses-literacy-leadership-and-lessons-from-politics</link><description>Kevin Rinke discusses literacy, leadership and lessons from politics</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Chicago park pension remains underfunded despite reforms</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/chicago-park-pension-remains-underfunded-despite-reforms/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Despite a 2021 law meant to improve the funding ratio of Chicago’s park pension, the amount of money the system has on hand to pay out benefits remains low. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/chicago-park-pension-remains-underfunded-despite-reforms/"&gt;Chicago park pension remains underfunded despite reforms&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 10:00:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] NH voters want to cut regulations to build more housing, polling confirms</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/10/nh-voters-want-to-cut-regulations-to-build-more-housing-polling-confirms/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On New Hampshire’s top economic issue, a broad consensus has formed. Voters want more housing, and they want government to make it easier to build, according to new polling. St. Anselm College’s 2025 statewide housing survey, released this week, shows that opinions have settled overwhelmingly in favor of deregulating the housing market to let builders [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/10/nh-voters-want-to-cut-regulations-to-build-more-housing-polling-confirms/"&gt;NH voters want to cut regulations to build more housing, polling confirms&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 11:30:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Government Shouldn’t Pick Winners and Losers—Especially on Your Utility Bill</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/government-shouldnt-pick-winners-and-losers/</link><description>Panasonic’s special rate deal shows how corporate favoritism quietly shifts costs onto Kansans &amp;#160; Kansas taxpayers have already given Panasonic nearly $829 million in incentives to build its massive electric-vehicle battery plant in De Soto—the largest economic-development deal in state history. Now, as Sunflower State Journal reports, Kansans could soon be paying again—this time through [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 15:00:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Listen: Charter school analysis on WGAN</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/listen-charter-school-analysis-on-wgan/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Policy analyst, Harris Van Pate, joined the WGAN Morning News to discuss Maine Policy&amp;#8217;s new report, Accountability Gap, which measures charter schools and public schools using the accountability metrics used to judge the success of charter schools and renew their charters. The report found that if all public schools had to abide by the standards [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/listen-charter-school-analysis-on-wgan/"&gt;Listen: Charter school analysis on WGAN&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 15:54:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Lawmakers push DoorDash, Uber Eats delivery tax statewide for Chicago transit</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/lawmakers-push-doordash-uber-eats-delivery-tax-statewide-for-chicago-transit/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Lawmakers may approve a statewide delivery tax on Doordash and Uber Eats to fund Chicago transit, hitting all Illinoisans who shop online, even those who don’t use CTA, Metra or Pace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/lawmakers-push-doordash-uber-eats-delivery-tax-statewide-for-chicago-transit/"&gt;Lawmakers push DoorDash, Uber Eats delivery tax statewide for Chicago transit&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 17:04:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] The Most Watched AG Debate in History?</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/the-most-watched-ag-debate-in-history/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="720" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/Virgina-AG-Debate.jpg" width="1280" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last night’s only debate for Attorney General of Virginia between incumbent AG Jason Miyares and Delegate Jay Jones was spirited, well-moderated, and covered dozens of key topics. Sadly, the debate occurred after over 600,000 Virginians had already cast their ballots and before over half of those early voters had heard of the news of the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/the-most-watched-ag-debate-in-history/"&gt;The Most Watched AG Debate in History?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 18:16:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] The Compounding Pharmacy Loophole Threatens Safety And Innovation</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/the-compounding-pharmacy-loophole-threatens-safety-and-innovation/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The new class of GLP-1 medicines exemplifies both the potential of pharmaceutical innovation and the risks to future advancements from ill-considered government policies. The incredible benefits from GLP-1’s are clear – they significantly improve our health and well-being. Risks arise because current federal policies enable activities that jeopardize patient safety and undermine innovators’ ability to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/the-compounding-pharmacy-loophole-threatens-safety-and-innovation/"&gt;The Compounding Pharmacy Loophole Threatens Safety And Innovation&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 18:24:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Teaching the Teachers</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/teaching-the-teachers/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;What are we teaching the teachers? “During my time in the master’s program at Stanford’s Graduate School of Education, we were taught to teach children,” writes my colleague Kate Bierly, “But first, we were taught to dismantle ‘harmful’ stereotypes and to teach our students to see the world through the lens of the ‘oppressed.’” “Every...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/teaching-the-teachers/"&gt;Teaching the Teachers&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 19:03:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Minnesota’s 2024 Violent Crime Data: a focused brief</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/minnesotas-2024-violent-crime-data-a-focused-brief/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On October 16, the Minnesota Bureau of Criminal Apprehension (BCA) released its annual Legislative Report highlighting 2024 crime data. The following is a short summary of the report focusing on violent crime data —– Murder, Aggravated Assault, Robbery, and Rape. Statewide Violent crime levels statewide remained steady. The number of violent crimes dropped slightly from...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/minnesotas-2024-violent-crime-data-a-focused-brief/"&gt;Minnesota’s 2024 Violent Crime Data: a focused brief&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 19:47:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Essential civic institutions: are school boards fulfilling their purpose?</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/essential-civic-institutions-are-school-boards-fulfilling-their-purpose/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;School boards &amp;#8212; an elected group of community members that sets policy, approves the yearly budget, and establishes a vision for a school district &amp;#8212; haven&amp;#8217;t been around forever. In fact, school boards are a profoundly American invention. Puritans first passed the Massachusetts Law of 1647, which established the first public school system in America...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/essential-civic-institutions-are-school-boards-fulfilling-their-purpose/"&gt;Essential civic institutions: are school boards fulfilling their purpose?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 21:21:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Chicago Mayor Brandon Johnson proposes $21 per employee corporate “head tax”</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/chicago-mayor-brandon-johnson-proposes-21-per-employee-corporate-head-tax/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Chicago Mayor Brandon Johnson proposed a $21-per-employee monthly tax on large companies to help fill a nearly $1.2 billion shortfall. Business leaders and even a former mayor say the “head tax” could kill job creation and new investment.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/chicago-mayor-brandon-johnson-proposes-21-per-employee-corporate-head-tax/"&gt;Chicago Mayor Brandon Johnson proposes $21 per employee corporate “head tax”&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 21:33:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Schatz praises working together to address Hawaii’s housing crisis</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/10/schatz-praises-working-together-to-address-hawaiis-housing-crisis/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;“We all say we want housing, but we make it almost impossible to build, by enacting thickets of regulations and requirements, and reviews.” So said Hawaii U.S. Sen. Brian Schatz in brief, prerecorded remarks for&amp;#160;a special Oct. 15 housing event at the Japanese Cultural Center of Hawai‘i hosted by Grassroot Institute of Hawaii and Hawai’i [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/10/schatz-praises-working-together-to-address-hawaiis-housing-crisis/"&gt;Schatz praises working together to address Hawaii&amp;#8217;s housing crisis&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 21:53:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Winners &amp; Losers: Peacemaker, Icebreakers &amp; Ballot Bans</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/winners-losers-peacemaker-icebreakers-ballot-bans/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Every Friday morning, I join the Cardle &amp;#38; Wooley Show on Talk 1370 Radio in Austin to announce the week’s Winners &amp;#38; Losers. In a week marked by an historic peace accord in the Middle East and Portland, Oregon’s naked bike ride to protest the National Guard in their city, here’s who made the list: WINNER:...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/winners-losers-peacemaker-icebreakers-ballot-bans/"&gt;Winners &amp; Losers: Peacemaker, Icebreakers &amp; Ballot Bans &lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 21:56:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Goldwater 2025 Freedom Gala: Trailblazing for Liberty</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/goldwater-2025-freedom-gala-trailblazing-for-liberty/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Challenging illegal taxes and government censorship in court. Backing free-market housing reforms. Breaking down barriers to work. Standing up for..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/goldwater-2025-freedom-gala-trailblazing-for-liberty/"&gt;Goldwater 2025 Freedom Gala: Trailblazing for Liberty &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 04:33:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Week in Review: Trailblazing for Liberty</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-trailblazing-for-liberty/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Goldwater Institute continues to blaze trails for liberty in courtrooms, classrooms, and statehouses, fighting for freedom and against government..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-trailblazing-for-liberty/"&gt;Week in Review: Trailblazing for Liberty&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 04:44:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Minnesota’s Economic News — W/E 10/17/25</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/minnesotas-economic-news-w-e-10-17-25/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;State and local taxes and spending Alpha News: Bloomington looking at property tax increase of 9.44%, building $100 million complex Economic growth Minnesota Reformer: Minnesota exports down 19% from this time last year MPR News: Minnesota lost over $1 billion in exports in second quarter of the year Fox 9: Minnesota exports drop $1.3 billion...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/minnesotas-economic-news-w-e-10-17-25/"&gt;Minnesota’s Economic News — W/E 10/17/25&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 05:01:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Exempt fire-destroyed properties from street-improvement costs</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/10/exempt-fire-destroyed-properties-from-street-improvement-costs/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Maui County Council Committee on Oct. 21, 2025._____________ Oct. 21, 2025, 1:30 p.m.Kalana O Maui Building To: Maui County Council&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Tom Cook, Chair&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Yuki Lei Sugimura, Vice-Chair From: Jonathan Helton, Policy Analyst&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Grassroot Institute of Hawaii RE: Bill 110 — [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/10/exempt-fire-destroyed-properties-from-street-improvement-costs/"&gt;Exempt fire-destroyed properties from street-improvement costs&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 13:43:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Waive rules for encroachments so Lahaina charm can be restored</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/10/waive-rules-for-encroachments-so-lahaina-charm-can-be-restored/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Maui County Council Committee on Water and Infrastructure on Oct. 21, 2025._____________ Oct. 21, 2025, 1:30 p.m.Kalana O Maui Building To: Maui County Council Committee on Water and Infrastructure       Tom Cook, Chair       Yuki Lei Sugimura, Vice Chair From: Grassroot Institute [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/10/waive-rules-for-encroachments-so-lahaina-charm-can-be-restored/"&gt;Waive rules for encroachments so Lahaina charm can be restored&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 13:50:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Behind the Rallies, Slogans and Rhetoric, Clean Virginia Pushes Its Energy Agenda with Voters</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/behind-the-rallies-slogans-and-rhetoric-clean-virginia-pushes-its-energy-agenda-with-voters/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="720" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/Energy-Bills.jpg" width="1280" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The energy bills are…” shouts the emcee on the stage. “Too damn high,” comes the immediate response from a crowded meeting room in the east end of Richmond, October 16. That call and response mantra constantly punctuated a long and creative presentation on Virginia’s energy dilemma from the point of view of the activist group Clean Virginia. The point of view [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/behind-the-rallies-slogans-and-rhetoric-clean-virginia-pushes-its-energy-agenda-with-voters/"&gt;Behind the Rallies, Slogans and Rhetoric, Clean Virginia Pushes Its Energy Agenda with Voters&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 21:22:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] New Statewide Ad Calls Out Governor Shapiro For Budget Impasse</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/10/19/new-statewide-ad-end-the-impasse-governor-shapiro/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Harrisburg, Pa., October 19, 2025 —&amp;#160;The Commonwealth Foundation has launched a new statewide ad calling on Gov. Josh Shapiro to end the state budget impasse by getting to work negotiating a bipartisan, fiscally responsible compromise that protects Pennsylvania taxpayers. Pennsylvania remains the only state in the nation without a state budget. The new ad calls [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/10/19/new-statewide-ad-end-the-impasse-governor-shapiro/"&gt;New Statewide Ad Calls Out Governor Shapiro For Budget Impasse&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 23:35:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>