<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>State-Policy Think-Tank Digest</title><link>https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml</link><description>Latest posts from free-market policy institutes across the U.S.</description><atom:link href="https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 17:03:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>[Cardinalinstitute] One Big Beautiful Opportunity to Reconnect West Virginians with Stable Work</title><link>https://cardinalinstitute.com/one-big-beautiful-opportunity-to-reconnect-west-virginians-with-work/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;One Big Beautiful Bill is One Big Beautiful Opportunity to Reconnect West Virginians with Stable Work On July 4, President Donald Trump signed the latest congressional reconciliation package, known colloquially as the One Big Beautiful Bill Act (OBBB), a sweeping package of federal budget measures including extension of the 2017 tax cuts, spending cuts and [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com/one-big-beautiful-opportunity-to-reconnect-west-virginians-with-work/"&gt;One Big Beautiful Opportunity to Reconnect West Virginians with Stable Work&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com"&gt;Cardinal Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 17:57:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] Day 100 of State Budget Impasse</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/10/08/day-100-of-state-budget-impasse/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On Hundredth Day of the Shapiro Shutdown, PA Democrats Push Spending &amp;#38; Tax Hikes  Harrisburg, Pa., October 8, 2025 — Day 100 of the state budget shutdown brought chaos to the Capitol rotunda, with partisan political theater from Pennsylvania House and Senate Democrats placing parties even farther apart at the negotiating&amp;#160;table.&amp;#160; After previously rejecting and [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/10/08/day-100-of-state-budget-impasse/"&gt;Day 100 of State Budget Impasse&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 00:25:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Decarceration’s Disconnect: Corrections spending rises in Georgia even as prison population declines</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/georgia-prison-spending-and-reform/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Prison reform debates often focus on reducing prison populations to save taxpayers money. But is that actually possible? In a new report for the Manhattan Institute, Joshua Crawford, Public Safety Fellow at the Georgia Center for Opportunity, reveals some surprising answers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/georgia-prison-spending-and-reform/"&gt;Decarceration’s Disconnect: Corrections spending rises in Georgia even as prison population declines&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 04:09:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] New Report: Corrections spending rises in Georgia even as prison population declines</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/new-report-corrections-spending-rises-in-georgia/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A new report by Joshua Crawford, Public Safety Fellow at the Georgia Center for Opportunity, shows that the decreasing number of inmates hasn’t translated to meaningful savings or improvements in public safety for Georgians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/new-report-corrections-spending-rises-in-georgia/"&gt;New Report: Corrections spending rises in Georgia even as prison population declines&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 23:02:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Tariffs – why we will hear a lot more about them</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/tariffs-why-we-will-hear-a-lot-more-about-them/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Remember the tariff debates that dominated Washington just a few months ago?&amp;#160; For a while it was the only thing anyone seemed to talk about.&amp;#160;First tariffs were raised by eyewatering amounts.&amp;#160; Then they weren’t.&amp;#160;&amp;#160;Eventually, after all sorts of back and forth, we saw tariffs imposed at the highest rates in decades. Free trade advocates warned [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/tariffs-why-we-will-hear-a-lot-more-about-them/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Tariffs – why we will hear a lot more about them&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 16:00:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF opinion piece: Voters should be skeptical of $350 million bond for APS</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-opinion-piece-voters-should-be-skeptical-of-350-million-bond-for-aps/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following appeared in the Albuquerque Journal on Sunday October 12, 2025. On this fall’s ballots in addition to votes for mayor, city council and school board, local voters will be asked to decide on a $350 million bond for Albuquerque Public Schools. These bonds (another name for debt which is typically used to pay [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-opinion-piece-voters-should-be-skeptical-of-350-million-bond-for-aps/"&gt;RGF opinion piece: Voters should be skeptical of $350 million bond for APS&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 18:49:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF provides comments in support of unlocking new water supplies for New Mexicans</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-provides-comments-in-support-of-unlocking-new-water-supplies-for-new-mexicans/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;They say &amp;#8220;agua es vida&amp;#8221; in New Mexico (water is life). In the desert southwest water is critical to human flourishing and the broader economy of the state and region. So, when we were presented with an opportunity to put water that is produced alongside oil and gas, we had only one question: &amp;#8220;Is it [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-provides-comments-in-support-of-unlocking-new-water-supplies-for-new-mexicans/"&gt;RGF provides comments in support of unlocking new water supplies for New Mexicans&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 16:38:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Accountability and Action: The Path to Safer Communities</title><link>https://empowerms.org/accountability-and-action-the-path-to-safer-communities/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This past weekend, our state was rocked by a wave of violent crime. Over the course of twenty-four hours, five shootings claimed the lives of at least nine Mississippians. While these horrific acts do not appear to be connected, they are alarming nevertheless. Words like horrific, tragic, and avoidable all come to mind. First and&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/accountability-and-action-the-path-to-safer-communities/"&gt;Accountability and Action: The Path to Safer Communities&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 14:16:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] NH voters want to cut regulations to build more housing, polling confirms</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/10/nh-voters-want-to-cut-regulations-to-build-more-housing-polling-confirms/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On New Hampshire’s top economic issue, a broad consensus has formed. Voters want more housing, and they want government to make it easier to build, according to new polling. St. Anselm College’s 2025 statewide housing survey, released this week, shows that opinions have settled overwhelmingly in favor of deregulating the housing market to let builders [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/10/nh-voters-want-to-cut-regulations-to-build-more-housing-polling-confirms/"&gt;NH voters want to cut regulations to build more housing, polling confirms&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 11:30:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Government Shouldn’t Pick Winners and Losers—Especially on Your Utility Bill</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/government-shouldnt-pick-winners-and-losers/</link><description>Panasonic’s special rate deal shows how corporate favoritism quietly shifts costs onto Kansans &amp;#160; Kansas taxpayers have already given Panasonic nearly $829 million in incentives to build its massive electric-vehicle battery plant in De Soto—the largest economic-development deal in state history. Now, as Sunflower State Journal reports, Kansans could soon be paying again—this time through [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 15:00:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Listen: Charter &amp; Public School Standards on WVOM</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/listen-charter-public-school-standards-on-wvom/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Policy analyst, Harris Van Pate, joined the George Hale Ric Tyler Show on WVOM to discuss the double standard in accountability for charter schools and public schools as identified in Maine Policy&amp;#8217;s new research, Accountability Gap. Listen to the full segment below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/listen-charter-public-school-standards-on-wvom/"&gt;Listen: Charter &amp;amp; Public School Standards on WVOM&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 19:10:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Behind the Rallies, Slogans and Rhetoric, Clean Virginia Pushes Its Energy Agenda with Voters</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/behind-the-rallies-slogans-and-rhetoric-clean-virginia-pushes-its-energy-agenda-with-voters/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="720" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/Energy-Bills.jpg" width="1280" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The energy bills are…” shouts the emcee on the stage. “Too damn high,” comes the immediate response from a crowded meeting room in the east end of Richmond, October 16. That call and response mantra constantly punctuated a long and creative presentation on Virginia’s energy dilemma from the point of view of the activist group Clean Virginia. The point of view [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/behind-the-rallies-slogans-and-rhetoric-clean-virginia-pushes-its-energy-agenda-with-voters/"&gt;Behind the Rallies, Slogans and Rhetoric, Clean Virginia Pushes Its Energy Agenda with Voters&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 21:22:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] New Statewide Ad Calls Out Governor Shapiro For Budget Impasse</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/10/19/new-statewide-ad-end-the-impasse-governor-shapiro/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Harrisburg, Pa., October 19, 2025 —&amp;#160;The Commonwealth Foundation has launched a new statewide ad calling on Gov. Josh Shapiro to end the state budget impasse by getting to work negotiating a bipartisan, fiscally responsible compromise that protects Pennsylvania taxpayers. Pennsylvania remains the only state in the nation without a state budget. The new ad calls [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/10/19/new-statewide-ad-end-the-impasse-governor-shapiro/"&gt;New Statewide Ad Calls Out Governor Shapiro For Budget Impasse&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 23:35:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Time to Rely Less on D.C.? Nebraska’s Path to Independence</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/time-to-rely-less-on-d-c-nebraskas-path-to-independence/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As the federal debt approaches $38 trillion, the federal government is shut down, and some states are asking whether it might be time to get control of their dependence on federal funding and declare a greater level of independence.  &amp;#8220;Federalism&amp;#8221; is the foundation of our system of government, establishing a multi-layered approach to divided and...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/time-to-rely-less-on-d-c-nebraskas-path-to-independence/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Time to Rely Less on D.C.? Nebraska’s Path to Independence&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 12:54:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] NJ ED REPORT: New Report: Most NJ School Districts Lack Smart Student-Centered Strategic Plans</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/10/nj-ed-report-new-report-most-nj-school-districts-lack-smart-student-centered-strategic-plans/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New Report: Most NJ School Districts Lack Smart Student-Centered Strategic Plans By  NJER Newsroom  October 15, 2025 Study of 50 district [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/10/nj-ed-report-new-report-most-nj-school-districts-lack-smart-student-centered-strategic-plans/"&gt;NJ ED REPORT: New Report: Most NJ School Districts Lack Smart Student-Centered Strategic Plans&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 13:12:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] WALL STREET JOURNAL: A Teachers Union Candidate Took My Money and Ran for Office</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/10/wall-street-journal-a-teachers-union-candidate-took-my-money-and-ran-for-office/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A Teachers Union Candidate Took My Money and Ran for Office By Marie Dupont Oct. 17, 2025 As the New [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/10/wall-street-journal-a-teachers-union-candidate-took-my-money-and-ran-for-office/"&gt;WALL STREET JOURNAL: A Teachers Union Candidate Took My Money and Ran for Office&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 13:16:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Decision Time for TriMet’s 82nd Ave. Road Diet</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/transportation/decision-time-for-trimets-82nd-ave-road-diet/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By John A. Charles, Jr. TriMet’s “Road Diet” planned for 82nd Avenue is...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/transportation/decision-time-for-trimets-82nd-ave-road-diet/"&gt;Decision Time for TriMet’s 82nd Ave. Road Diet&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 17:34:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] UC Unions Exposed: Fear, Intimidation, and a Growing Antisemitism Problem</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/uc-unions-exposed-fear-intimidation-and-a-growing-antisemitism-problem/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Freedom Foundation canvassers have been on University of California-Los Angeles (UCLA) campuses talking with employees about their rights, and what we’ve seen from union leadership is disturbing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/uc-unions-exposed-fear-intimidation-and-a-growing-antisemitism-problem/" rel="nofollow"&gt;UC Unions Exposed: Fear, Intimidation, and a Growing Antisemitism Problem&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 18:28:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] The Federal Shutdown Explained: What it Means for Maine</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/the-federal-shutdown-explained-what-it-means-for-maine/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Congress isn’t known as the place for bipartisan cooperation, but since October 1, inter-party arguing has led to a shutdown of the federal government. This has caused the closing of offices, the suspension of services, and the placing of hundreds of thousands of workers on furlough. The reason, as usual, is infuriating but straightforward: Congress [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/the-federal-shutdown-explained-what-it-means-for-maine/"&gt;The Federal Shutdown Explained: What it Means for Maine&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 19:26:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Empire Center Calls for Release of PPL Records</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/empire-center-calls-for-release-of-ppl-records/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Empire Center is calling on the Hochul administration to promptly release records of its spring 2024 communications with Public....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/empire-center-calls-for-release-of-ppl-records/"&gt;Empire Center Calls for Release of PPL Records&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 15:03:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Stanford’s Anna Lembke, MD, on Dopamine Nation &amp; Addiction</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/stanfords-anna-lembke-md-on-dopamine-nation-addiction/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In this week’s episode of The Learning Curve, co-hosts U-Arkansas Prof. Albert Cheng and Center for Public Schools’ Alisha Searcy interview Dr. Anna Lembke, MD, professor of psychiatry at the Stanford University School of Medicine, chief of the Stanford Addiction Medicine Dual Diagnosis Clinic, and author of the NYT bestselling book, Dopamine Nation: Finding Balance in the Age of Indulgence. Dr. Lembke explains how dopamine functions in the human brain and contributes to addictive behaviors. She explores how modern American life fuels a culture of addiction, drawing parallels between past waves of opioid and alcohol abuse and today’s dependence on the internet and smart phones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/stanfords-anna-lembke-md-on-dopamine-nation-addiction/"&gt;Stanford&amp;#8217;s Anna Lembke, MD, on Dopamine Nation &amp;#038; Addiction&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 16:16:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] Pennsylvania Senate Passes Budget Plan, RGGI Abrogation, Regulatory Reform</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/10/22/pennsylvania-senate-passes-budget-plan/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Harrisburg, Pa., October 22, 2025&amp;#160;— This week, the Pennsylvania Senate advanced legislation, including a spending bill (Senate Bill 160), that protects taxpayers and fosters economic growth. The commonwealth remains the only state in the country without an operating budget or stop gap plan. Now weeks into a federal government shutdown, Pennsylvania’s four-month-long impasse holds the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/10/22/pennsylvania-senate-passes-budget-plan/"&gt;Pennsylvania Senate Passes Budget Plan, RGGI Abrogation, Regulatory Reform&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 18:11:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG CIO Submits Request to DPI Seeking Teacher Licensing and Misconduct Scandal Public Records</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-cio-submits-request-to-dpi-seeking-teacher-licensing-and-misconduct-scandal-public-records/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government’s (IRG) Center for Investigative Oversight (CIO) submitted a public records request to the Wisconsin Department of Public Instruction (DPI), seeking to uncover details surrounding the Department’s handling of teacher licenses for educators accused of misconduct and grooming. Recent reporting by The Capital Times revealed serious concerns surrounding [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-cio-submits-request-to-dpi-seeking-teacher-licensing-and-misconduct-scandal-public-records/"&gt;IRG CIO Submits Request to DPI Seeking Teacher Licensing and Misconduct Scandal Public Records&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 19:07:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] New Jersey’s Bag Ban Backfired. Repeal It—and Cut Waste the Smart Way.</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/10/new-jerseys-bag-ban-backfired-repeal-it-and-cut-waste-the-smart-way/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Wells Winegar, Executive Director, New Jersey Policy Institute (NJPI) &amp;#160; Walk into any New Jersey kitchen and open the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/10/new-jerseys-bag-ban-backfired-repeal-it-and-cut-waste-the-smart-way/"&gt;New Jersey’s Bag Ban Backfired. Repeal It—and Cut Waste the Smart Way.&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 19:51:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] If Lawmakers Are Trying to Defund Public Education, They Aren’t Very Good at It</title><link>https://empowerms.org/if-lawmakers-are-trying-to-defund-public-education-they-arent-very-good-at-it/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;You’ve probably heard the claim that Mississippi’s Republican leaders are “defunding” public education, and that school choice is just another way to siphon dollars away from public schools. But if that’s true, they’re doing a remarkably bad job of it.  Over the past decade, Mississippi has dramatically increased its investment in public education. According to&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/if-lawmakers-are-trying-to-defund-public-education-they-arent-very-good-at-it/"&gt;If Lawmakers Are Trying to Defund Public Education, They Aren’t Very Good at It&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 02:00:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Acton Dinner: “The Future of Faith and Freedom” with Rev. Robert A. Sirico</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/economic-opportunity/acton-dinner-the-future-of-faith-and-freedom-with-rev-robert-a-sirico/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Naomi Inman On October 21, the Acton Institute held its Portland Dinner...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/economic-opportunity/acton-dinner-the-future-of-faith-and-freedom-with-rev-robert-a-sirico/"&gt;Acton Dinner: “The Future of Faith and Freedom” with Rev. Robert A. Sirico&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 22:36:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Feds to New Hampshire: Snip SNAP or pay us back</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/10/feds-to-new-hampshire-snip-snap-or-pay-us-back/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On Thursday, the state Department of Health and Human Services (DHHS) announced a plan to deliver food to New Hampshire food stamp recipients should the federal government shutdown continue into November.  The partnership with the New Hampshire Food Bank was announced just 13 days after the U.S. Department of Agriculture warned states that funding for [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/10/feds-to-new-hampshire-snip-snap-or-pay-us-back/"&gt;Feds to New Hampshire: Snip SNAP or pay us back&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 15:15:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Freedom Foundation Backs 51 Cities Fighting California’s Housing Speech Mandate</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/press-release/freedom-foundation-backs-51-cities-fighting-californias-housing-speech-mandate/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Freedom Foundation is joining an amicus brief with 51 cities supporting Huntington Beach's Petition for Writ of Certiorari to the United States Supreme Court in City of Huntington Beach v. Newsom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/press-release/freedom-foundation-backs-51-cities-fighting-californias-housing-speech-mandate/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation Backs 51 Cities Fighting California’s Housing Speech Mandate&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 15:58:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Judge Certifies Class Action for Parents and Teachers in Lawsuit Challenging California’s Gender Secrecy Rules</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/judge-certifies-class-action/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=judge-certifies-class-action</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A federal judge has certified a landmark class action lawsuit that could finally bring an end to California’s state-sanctioned “Parental Exclusion Policies” that order teachers to hide a child’s gender transition at school from their own parents. U.S. District Judge Roger Benitez of the Southern District of California issued the October 15 order in Mirabelli v. Olson, a lawsuit...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/judge-certifies-class-action/"&gt;Judge Certifies Class Action for Parents and Teachers in Lawsuit Challenging California’s Gender Secrecy Rules&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 21:43:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Don’t Bet Against Virginia: Why the State’s Economy Is Stronger Than the Headlines Suggest and Progressives Shout</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/dont-bet-against-virginia-why-the-states-economy-is-stronger-than-the-headlines-suggest-and-progressives-shout/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="720" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/Virginia-Economy.jpg" width="1280" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you only read the headlines, you might think Virginia’s economy is teetering on the brink. A recent Cardinal News story declared that the Commonwealth’s GDP growth has fallen from 6.2 percent to 1.7 percent, and touted warning signs spelled out in “three new (economic) reports” that claim to show serious trouble ahead. Setting aside the fact [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/dont-bet-against-virginia-why-the-states-economy-is-stronger-than-the-headlines-suggest-and-progressives-shout/"&gt;Don’t Bet Against Virginia: Why the State’s Economy Is Stronger Than the Headlines Suggest and Progressives Shout&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 04:03:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Destroying Democracy: Will Dems Trample on Voters’ Will?</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/destroying-democracy-will-dems-trample-on-voters-will/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="720" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/IMG_4669.jpeg" width="1280" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have to be pretty confident – no, read that “arrogant” – to tell 2.7 million Virginia voters that you’re willing to stick it to them. But that’s exactly what Virginia House and Senate Democratic leaders appear ready to do at 4:00 pm on Monday, all in the cause of enhancing political power and rejecting the voters’ [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/destroying-democracy-will-dems-trample-on-voters-will/"&gt;Destroying Democracy: Will Dems Trample on Voters’ Will?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 16:43:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Free Market Concerns—Argentinian Beef Imports</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/free-market-concerns-argentinian-beef-imports/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Based on free-market principles, President Trump&amp;#8217;s proposal to increase Argentine beef imports to lower domestic prices is problematic for several reasons.   Market Distortion and Unintended Consequences.  In the free market, prices are determined by the natural forces of supply and demand, which convey important information to producers and consumers about what the market will tolerate. ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/free-market-concerns-argentinian-beef-imports/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Free Market Concerns—Argentinian Beef Imports&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 13:26:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Nebraska’s Tax Treatment of Non-Profits</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/nebraskas-tax-treatment-of-non-profits/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The origins of favorable tax treatment for nonprofit and not-for-profit organizations in the United States were based on the admirable ideals promoting community service and public good.    However, today the United States’ federally tax-exempt economy makes up 15% of gross domestic output (GDP) and spans 1.8 million organizations. A total of $3.3 trillion dollars of...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/nebraskas-tax-treatment-of-non-profits/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Nebraska&amp;#8217;s Tax Treatment of Non-Profits&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 19:37:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Tennessee’s Time for Energy Abundance</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/tennessees-time-for-energy-abundance/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=tennessees-time-for-energy-abundance</link><description>By embracing Tennessee's nuclear roots, small modular reactor and micro modular reactor technologies will have a chance to thrive in a new era of energy independence.</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 19:39:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] The Good, Bad, and Ugly of 2nd Session Bill Requests</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/the-good-bad-and-ugly-of-2nd-session-bill-requests/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Legislative Council has released the list of bill titles under consideration for the Maine Legislature’s 2026 legislative session, and on October 23, the Council met for an initial bill screening. The full list of results is available here.&amp;#160; The Legislative Council is made up of 10 members of legislative leadership. For a bill request [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/the-good-bad-and-ugly-of-2nd-session-bill-requests/"&gt;The Good, Bad, and Ugly of 2nd Session Bill Requests&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 19:40:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] Court ratifies City of Albuquerque donation to Planned Parenthood</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/court-ratifies-city-of-albuquerque-donation-to-planned-parenthood/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In what can only be described as a ruling based on twisted logic a New Mexico District Judge (Denise Barela Shepherd) has decided that it is somehow NOT a violation of New Mexico&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8220;anti-donation clause&amp;#8221; for the City of Albuquerque to explicitly donation $250,000 of our tax dollars to Planned Parenthood.  Our friends at the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/court-ratifies-city-of-albuquerque-donation-to-planned-parenthood/"&gt;Court ratifies City of Albuquerque donation to Planned Parenthood&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 22:24:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Kansas Doesn’t Need Medicaid Expansion — It Needs to Empower Patients</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/kansas-doesnt-need-medicaid-expansion/</link><description>Governor Laura Kelly’s Healthcare Access for Working Kansans (HAWK) Act was sold as a “middle-of-the-road” plan to expand Medicaid to 150,000 more Kansans when it was introduced during the 2025 legislative session. But there’s nothing moderate about growing a failing federal program that already leaves millions of patients nationwide waiting in line for care. Expanding [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 15:00:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] New Video Exposes How Unions Trap Public Employees in Membership</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/press-release/new-video-exposes-how-unions-trap-public-employees-in-membership/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Freedom Foundation today released a new video exposing the deliberate obstacles unions place in front of public employees trying to exercise their constitutional right to leave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/press-release/new-video-exposes-how-unions-trap-public-employees-in-membership/" rel="nofollow"&gt;New Video Exposes How Unions Trap Public Employees in Membership&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 15:22:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Frightfully pricey treats: Why Halloween fun is costing Georgia families more</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/georgia-halloween-candy-prices/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As Halloween approaches, Georgia families look forward to making great memories involving adorable costumes and fun candy hauls. But candy prices have become nothing short of scary for families trying to make ends meet. Here's why prices are on the rise for Georgia's favorite Halloween treats. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/georgia-halloween-candy-prices/"&gt;Frightfully pricey treats: Why Halloween fun is costing Georgia families more&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 16:01:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Moms For Liberty Activist Scarlett Johnson Wins Her Appeal</title><link>https://will-law.org/moms-for-liberty-activist-scarlett-johnson-wins-her-appeal/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Wisconsin Court of Appeals ruled in favor of WILL’s client, Scarlett Johnson, a Wisconsin Moms for Liberty activist sued for defamation for criticizing her school district. The Court agreed with WILL’s argument that Scarlett’s posts were statements of opinion that are not provably false and therefore cannot be defamatory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/moms-for-liberty-activist-scarlett-johnson-wins-her-appeal/"&gt;Moms For Liberty Activist Scarlett Johnson Wins Her Appeal&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 17:35:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] PRESS RELEASE: Governor Reeves and Rich Lowry Highlight Mississippi's Success</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/press-release-governor-reeves-and-rich-lowry-highlight-mississippis-success/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASEOctober 28, 2025 Mississippi Center for Public Policy Celebrates Statewide Success with Governor Tate Reeves and National Review Editor Rich Lowry Jackson, Miss. — October 28, 2025 — The Mississippi Center for Public Policy hosted its Celebration of Mississippi Success Gala on Thursday, October 23, at the Country Club of Jackson, honoring the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/press-release-governor-reeves-and-rich-lowry-highlight-mississippis-success/" rel="nofollow"&gt;PRESS RELEASE: Governor Reeves and Rich Lowry Highlight Mississippi&amp;#039;s Success&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 19:43:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Mayor John Horhn: Jackson Rising</title><link>https://empowerms.org/mayor-john-horhn-jackson-rising/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Mayor John Horhn: Jackson Rising What does it take to turn around a city? In this special episode recorded at Jackson City Hall, host Grant Callen talks with Mayor John Horhn about his love for Jackson, the lessons from his childhood and career in public service, and his mission to restore trust, safety, and opportunity&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/mayor-john-horhn-jackson-rising/"&gt;Mayor John Horhn: Jackson Rising&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 01:00:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Kent visits with Johny and Steezy, touts potential of Open Hearings</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/10/kent-visits-again-johny-and-steezy-touts-potential-of-open-hearings/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Virtually nothing was off-limits during Joe Kent’s recent podcast appearance on “The Aloha Hour with Johny and Steezy.”  Kent, executive vice president of the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii, discussed financial boondoggles such as Honolulu’s rail project and the state’s new Aloha Stadium; the high cost of housing and living in Hawaii; the slow pace of [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/10/kent-visits-again-johny-and-steezy-touts-potential-of-open-hearings/"&gt;Kent visits with Johny and Steezy, touts potential of Open Hearings&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 01:43:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG Court Watch: Options for Structural Reforms for our Courts</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-court-watch-options-for-structural-reforms-for-our-courts/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;IRG Court Watch: Options for Structural Reforms for our Courts Voters Open to Reform after Multi-Million Dollar, Partisan Judicial Elections Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government’s (IRG)‘s Court Watch initiative released a report, Structural Reform of Judicial Selection in Wisconsin, detailing potential structural reforms to strengthen judicial integrity and public trust in Wisconsin [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-court-watch-options-for-structural-reforms-for-our-courts/"&gt;IRG Court Watch: Options for Structural Reforms for our Courts&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 13:38:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Harvard’s Leo Damrosch on Robert Louis Stevenson &amp; Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/harvards-leo-damrosch-on-robert-louis-stevenson-dr-jekyll-and-mr-hyde/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In this week’s episode of The Learning Curve, co-hosts U-Arkansas Prof. Albert Cheng and Great Hearts Academies’ Dr. Helen Baxendale interview Leo Damrosch, Ernest Bernbaum Professor of Literature Emeritus at Harvard University, and acclaimed biographer of some of the world's greatest literary figures. Prof. Damrosch discusses his newest book Storyteller: The Life of Robert Louis Stevenson. He reflects on Stevenson's childhood in Scotland and the close relationship he maintained with his nanny, Alison Cunningham. He shares how Stevenson lived an adventurous life, with his travel inspiring classics like Treasure Island, Kidnapped, and A Child’s Garden of Verses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/harvards-leo-damrosch-on-robert-louis-stevenson-dr-jekyll-and-mr-hyde/"&gt;Harvard’s Leo Damrosch on Robert Louis Stevenson &amp;#038; Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 15:27:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Don’t Follow Nevada’s Mental Health Mistake</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/dont-follow-nevadas-mental-health-mistake/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Each day, thousands of Floridians seek therapy, some for routine mental health check-ins, others confronting serious psychiatric challenges....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/dont-follow-nevadas-mental-health-mistake/"&gt;Don’t Follow Nevada’s Mental Health Mistake&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 17:52:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Benjamin Franklin and the Birth of American Liberty—11/21 Virtual Event</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/benjamin-franklin-and-the-birth-of-american-liberty-11-21-virtual-event/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Benjamin Franklin—statesman, inventor, and journalist—stands among the great heroes of American history. And who better to tell his story than..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/benjamin-franklin-and-the-birth-of-american-liberty-11-21-virtual-event/"&gt;Benjamin Franklin and the Birth of American Liberty—11/21 Virtual Event&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 20:35:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] New Study Shows Success of School Choice in Action</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/new-study-shows-success-of-school-choice-in-action/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=new-study-shows-success-of-school-choice-in-action</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As California wallows in continued low student performance, a new study shows that school choice is making a positive difference in student outcomes in Arkansas. Recently released scores on California’s state tests in English and math show huge proportions of students failing to achieve proficiency in the basic subjects. More than half of California students...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/new-study-shows-success-of-school-choice-in-action/"&gt;New Study Shows Success of School Choice in Action&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 21:49:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Dear PPS Bond Committee: Please Tell the Taxpayers</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/testimony/testimony-before-the-pps-bond-accountability-committee/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By John A. Charles, Jr. Cascade’s president, John Charles, testified online at the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/testimony/testimony-before-the-pps-bond-accountability-committee/"&gt;Dear PPS Bond Committee: Please Tell the Taxpayers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 23:13:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/10/the-outstater-298/</link><description>The Municipally&amp;#160;Privileged &amp;#8220;All government employees should realize that the process of collective bargaining, as usually understood, cannot be transplanted into the public service.” — Franklin D. Roosevelt HAS YOUR CITY&amp;#160;worked out its new budget with the cuts and adjustments made necessary by property-tax reform? Mine has done so, and in a long, torturous process inscrutable&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/10/the-outstater-298/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 12:35:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Nichols v. DOT</title><link>https://will-law.org/nichols-v-dot/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL is challenging a state law that unlawfully restricts Wisconsin drivers’ First Amendment rights. The state uses subjective and arbitrary decisions to decide what drivers can print on their personalized license plates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/nichols-v-dot/"&gt;Nichols v. DOT&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 13:52:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Iowa’s Flat Tax Success Should Inspire the Next Chapter of Reform</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/iowas-flat-tax-success-should-inspire-the-next-chapter-of-reform/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Iowa’s Flat Tax Success Should Inspire the Next Chapter of Reform" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/tf-2026.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over six years, Iowa has climbed from 44th to 17th in the Tax Foundation’s competitiveness rankings—proof that years of conservative budgeting and tax reform have turned one of America’s least-friendly tax codes into a national model.&lt;br /&gt;
Governor Kim Reynolds’ 3.8% flat income tax, paired with falling corporate rates and a strong Taxpayer Relief Fund, has made Iowa a regional leader for growth and investment—outpacing neighboring states and inspiring others like Georgia to follow suit.&lt;br /&gt;
To sustain its momentum, Iowa must address high property taxes, apply the same spending discipline at the local level, responsibly lower the flat rate using revenue triggers, and safeguard taxpayer protections to keep its pro-growth policies permanent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/iowas-flat-tax-success-should-inspire-the-next-chapter-of-reform/"&gt;Iowa’s Flat Tax Success Should Inspire the Next Chapter of Reform&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 15:19:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Debunking 2 more property tax myths: setting mill rates and blaming legislators for unfunded mandates</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/2-property-tax-myths-mill-rates-unfunded-mandates/</link><description>Last month, we debunked several property tax myths that some local officials are using to shift the blame for their unaffordable tax increases, and now there are two more excuses to address. For years, many local officials tried to blame County Clerks for setting mill rates, saying something along the lines of ‘we just set [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 15:31:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] The New Jersey Playbook Connecticut Shouldn’t Copy</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/10/30/the-new-jersey-playbook-connecticut-shouldnt-copy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="1707" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/shutterstock_2496182785-scaled.jpg" width="2560" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connecticut lawmakers insist a major housing plan is coming — they just won’t say what’s in it. At the “Building for All” conference on Oct. 23, housing officials and legislative [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/10/30/the-new-jersey-playbook-connecticut-shouldnt-copy/"&gt;The New Jersey Playbook Connecticut Shouldn’t Copy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 16:07:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Killing the I&amp;D Tax leaps N.H. to No. 3 on national tax competitiveness index</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/10/killing-the-id-tax-leaps-n-h-to-no-3-on-national-tax-competitiveness-index/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Killing New Hampshire’s Interest &amp;#38; Dividends Tax has breathed new life into the New Hampshire Advantage. That’s the conclusion from reading the Tax Foundation’s 2026 State Tax Competitiveness Index, released on Oct. 30.  Last year, New Hampshire slipped past Texas to claim the No. 6 spot on the index. Passing the famously conservative and economically [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/10/killing-the-id-tax-leaps-n-h-to-no-3-on-national-tax-competitiveness-index/"&gt;Killing the I&amp;#038;D Tax leaps N.H. to No. 3 on national tax competitiveness index&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 17:51:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Large Scale Desalination Could Transform California</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/large-scale-desalination-could-transform-california/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=large-scale-desalination-could-transform-california</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Why is it axiomatic among California’s water agencies and policymakers that large scale desalination is inconceivable in California? That certainly isn’t the case in other arid locales. In 2024, an estimated 30 million acre feet of fresh water was produced by desalination plants worldwide. On the coast of the Red Sea, about 60 miles south of the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/large-scale-desalination-could-transform-california/"&gt;Large Scale Desalination Could Transform California&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 17:53:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Bayou Built: Louisiana Businesses are Paving the Way</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/bayou-built-louisiana-businesses-are-paving-the-way/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New Orleans has a reputation that precedes it. Fondly referred to as the “Big Easy” and known for its jazz music, food scene, and storied past marked with tragedy, the city has quietly made a name for itself as a hub for innovation and startups. And it’s not alone; businesses around the state are becoming...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/bayou-built-louisiana-businesses-are-paving-the-way/"&gt;Bayou Built: Louisiana Businesses are Paving the Way&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 18:25:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Mackinac Center Mourns Passing of Nathan Martin</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/pressroom/2025/mackinac-center-mourns-passing-of-nathan-martin</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Missouri Earns a “B” in New Fiscal Report—but Don’t Pop the Champagne Yet</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/state-and-local-government/missouri-earns-a-b-in-new-fiscal-reportbut-dont-pop-the-champagne-yet/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For the first time in recent memory, Missouri earned a “B” on Truth in Accounting’s (TIA) annual fiscal report. That [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/state-and-local-government/missouri-earns-a-b-in-new-fiscal-reportbut-dont-pop-the-champagne-yet/"&gt;Missouri Earns a “B” in New Fiscal Report—but Don’t Pop the Champagne Yet&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 18:53:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Port Washington to be land of opportunity for job-seekers</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/port-washington-to-be-land-of-opportunity-for-job-seekers/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Technical college graduates and small business owners will be big winners in the massive Vantage Data Centers development soon expected to become the largest employer in Port Washington.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/port-washington-to-be-land-of-opportunity-for-job-seekers/"&gt;Port Washington to be land of opportunity for job-seekers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 19:23:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Honoring Courage: Elijah Stacy, Goldwater’s 2025 Freedom Award Winner</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/honoring-courage-elijah-stacy-goldwaters-2025-freedom-award-winner/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Goldwater Institute is proud to honor Elijah Stacy as the recipient of our 2025 Freedom Award. Elijah’s unwavering courage,..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/honoring-courage-elijah-stacy-goldwaters-2025-freedom-award-winner/"&gt;Honoring Courage: Elijah Stacy, Goldwater&amp;#8217;s 2025 Freedom Award Winner&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 19:49:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Data Centers, Subsidies, and Electricity in Platte County and across Missouri</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/energy/data-centers-subsidies-and-electricity-in-platte-county-and-across-missouri/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Artificial intelligence and data centers have been the subject of extensive discussion in recent months. Do we need a massive [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/energy/data-centers-subsidies-and-electricity-in-platte-county-and-across-missouri/"&gt;Data Centers, Subsidies, and Electricity in Platte County and across Missouri&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 20:15:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Parsing the Impact of Mamdani’s Tax Hike Plans</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/parsing-the-impact-of-mamdanis-tax-hike-plans/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The front-running candidate for New York City mayor, Zohran Mamdani, has said he can finance his costly campaign promises –....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/parsing-the-impact-of-mamdanis-tax-hike-plans/"&gt;Parsing the Impact of Mamdani&amp;#8217;s Tax Hike Plans&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 20:28:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Iowa’s Absenteeism Challenge: Reconnecting Students to Learning</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/iowas-absenteeism-challenge-reconnecting-students-to-learning/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Iowa’s Absenteeism Challenge: Reconnecting Students to Learning" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="330" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/school-attendance-1200x618.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regular attendance is one of the most important predictors of student success. During the COVID-19 pandemic, we saw firsthand how inconsistent attendance undermined learning, lowered test scores, and set back student achievement across the country. Chronic absenteeism is defined as missing 10% or more of scheduled school days or instructional hours during a grading period. In an 180-day school year, that’s 18 or more missed days. Across the United States, chronic absenteeism surged from 15% in 2018 to 28% in 2022. Although some states have recovered from pandemic-era highs, many remain above pre-pandemic levels — and Iowa is no exception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/iowas-absenteeism-challenge-reconnecting-students-to-learning/"&gt;Iowa’s Absenteeism Challenge: Reconnecting Students to Learning&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 20:30:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] 2025 Tools for Keeping Kids Safe Online: Innovations Empower Parents, but Parents Must Use Them</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/2025-tools-for-keeping-kids-safe-online-innovations-empower-parents-but-parents-must-use-them/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Pew Research Center reported last year that teenagers are more online than ever before. The majority own smartphones, 90% use YouTube, around 60% use TikTok and Instagram, and over half report that they are online “almost constantly.” Lawmakers, caretakers, and even teens themselves have expressed concern about these trends. A variety of tools have emerged...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/2025-tools-for-keeping-kids-safe-online-innovations-empower-parents-but-parents-must-use-them/"&gt;2025 Tools for Keeping Kids Safe Online: Innovations Empower Parents, but Parents Must Use Them&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 20:54:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Texas sets the standard in the fight against human trafficking</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/texas-sets-the-standard-in-the-fight-against-human-trafficking/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Originally published in the Dallas Morning News. New legislation stiffens penalties and provides for victims. A recent police effort underscored a disturbing but resolvable truth: Human trafficking doesn’t just happen in faraway places — it happens in our own backyard, and, too often, it targets our children. Through a coordinated effort by the U.S. Marshals...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/texas-sets-the-standard-in-the-fight-against-human-trafficking/"&gt;Texas sets the standard in the fight against human trafficking&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 20:58:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Milwaukee will pay someone to say nice things about The Hop</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/milwaukee-will-pay-someone-to-say-nice-things-about-the-hop/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The City of Milwaukee is willing to pay a new marketing and communications officer for The Hop, its little-used $128 million streetcar, up to $108,000 per year plus benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/milwaukee-will-pay-someone-to-say-nice-things-about-the-hop/"&gt;Milwaukee will pay someone to say nice things about The Hop&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 21:09:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] As hunger looms, Democrats in ‘non-winnable’ situation</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/as-hunger-looms-democrats-in-non-winnable-situation/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;“Democrats put themselves in the situation we’re in, and it’s non-winnable,” says Rachidi, a researcher who has written extensively about FoodShare and SNAP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/as-hunger-looms-democrats-in-non-winnable-situation/"&gt;As hunger looms, Democrats in ‘non-winnable’ situation&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 21:22:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Beacon Wins Final Approval in $1.4 Million Stormwater Settlement, Bringing Justice to Nashville Homeowners</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/beacon-wins-final-approval-in-1-4-million-stormwater-settlement-bringing-justice-to-nashville-homeowners/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=beacon-wins-final-approval-in-1-4-million-stormwater-settlement-bringing-justice-to-nashville-homeowners</link><description>This ruling is a landmark win for property owners and sends a clear message that government overreach will not go unchecked.</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 21:26:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Easing farmworker housing rules crucial to Hawaii’s agriculture future</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/10/easing-farmworker-housing-rules-crucial-to-hawaiis-agriculture-future/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following commentary is based on remarks presented by Ted Kefalas of the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii during an Oct. 15, 2025, housing conference sponsored by Grassroot and the Hawaiʻi Appleseed Center for Law &amp;#38; Economic Justice.__________ It’s really difficult to be a farmer here in Hawaii, and one of the key issues holding that [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/10/easing-farmworker-housing-rules-crucial-to-hawaiis-agriculture-future/"&gt;Easing farmworker housing rules crucial to Hawaii&amp;#8217;s agriculture future&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 23:59:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] WI Speaks Survey Results</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/wi-speaks-survey-results/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WI 1023 Toplines (1) WI 1023 Summary of Key Findings (2) WI 1023 Summary of Key Findings (2)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/wi-speaks-survey-results/"&gt;WI Speaks Survey Results&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 00:18:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Zero Property Tax Would Be a Good Look</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/zero-property-tax-would-be-a-good-look/</link><description>Nose hair is offensive. A tax on property is like the nose hair of public policy. There may not be a more offensive tax – well, maybe a tax on breathable air, but let’s not give big government any ideas. Here are the three most nose hair-ish things about the property tax: Good news! We [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 01:37:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Virginiainstitute] Examining HJ6007 and Its Implications for Virginia’s Redistricting Process</title><link>https://virginiainstitute.org/examining-hj6007/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=examining-hj6007</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As lawmakers consider HJ6007, Virginians are asking how the proposal aligns with the 2020 constitutional amendment supporting fair maps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org/examining-hj6007/"&gt;Examining HJ6007 and Its Implications for Virginia’s Redistricting Process&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org"&gt;Virginia Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 01:53:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] ‘A lot of libertarianism feels like political science fiction’</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/podcasts/the-overton-window/brian-doherty-talks-about-shifting-the-overton-window-in-politics-statecraft-and-comic-books</link><description>Brian Doherty talks about shifting the Overton Window in politics, statecraft, and comic books</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] Snow:  Legislative Failure</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/10/snow-legislative-failure/</link><description>by Nathanael Snow, Ph.D. People respond to incentives. Governor Mike Braun has called a special session of Indiana’s legislature for the purpose of redrawing Congressional District lines. Indiana voters ask Braun why he cares so much. What’s in it for him? And then let the legislators ask the same question. A legislature is supposed to be&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/10/snow-legislative-failure/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 12:21:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] NYC Employees Receive $300k+ in Overtime</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/nyc-employees-receive-300k-in-overtime/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Two New York City employees received more than $300,000 in overtime payouts, according to fiscal year 2025 payroll data posted....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/nyc-employees-receive-300k-in-overtime/"&gt;NYC Employees Receive $300k+ in Overtime&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 13:20:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Florida Politics: No, Georgia, It’s Not a Trick; Florida Just Wants To Share a Kid-Friendly Treat</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/florida-politics-no-georgia-its-not-a-trick-florida-just-wants-to-share-a-kid-friendly-treat/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As Saturday’s&amp;#160;Georgia-Florida game&amp;#160;approaches, much attention is being paid to the fact that the Gators just fired their head...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/florida-politics-no-georgia-its-not-a-trick-florida-just-wants-to-share-a-kid-friendly-treat/"&gt;Florida Politics: No, Georgia, It’s Not a Trick; Florida Just Wants To Share a Kid-Friendly Treat&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 14:08:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Income tax proposals won’t die in Washington State</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/income-tax-proposals-won-t-die-in-washington-state</link><description>What comes back from the dead more frequently than Michael Myers, Jason Voorhees, and Freddy Krueger? Efforts to impose an income tax in Washington State. Like those perennial terrors, this income tax fixation in the Evergreen State should finally die, too. Unfortunately for taxpayers already suffering under the weight of the largest tax increase in state history  imposed earlier this year, a new income tax proposal is in the works for 2026. According to the Washington State Standard : “The...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 15:01:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] LA GATOR: Fund the Promise</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/education/la-gator-fund-the-promise/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Louisiana’s education landscape took a transformative turn in 2024 with the creation of the Louisiana Giving All True Opportunity to Rise (LA GATOR) program, a universal education savings account (ESA) initiative designed to empower families with unprecedented flexibility in choosing their child’s educational path. Modeled after successful ESA programs in states like Arizona and Florida,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/education/la-gator-fund-the-promise/"&gt;LA GATOR: Fund the Promise&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 15:21:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Week in Review: $117K to see what a school is teaching?</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-117k-to-see-what-a-school-is-teaching/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When a Rhode Island teacher made headlines for publishing videos celebrating the assassination of conservative activist Charlie Kirk, one local..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-117k-to-see-what-a-school-is-teaching/"&gt;Week in Review: $117K to see what a school is teaching?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 15:54:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Rebuilding Civic Knowledge for the Next Generation</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/rebuilding-civic-knowledge-for-the-next-generation/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Rebuilding Civic Knowledge for the Next Generation" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/classroom.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reflecting on his early education, President Calvin Coolidge wrote that in his studies he “was attracted to civil government.” He recalled:&lt;br /&gt;
“This was my first introduction to the Constitution of the United States. Although I was but thirteen years old, the subject interested me exceedingly. The study of it which I then began never ceased, and the more I study it, the more I have come to admire it, realizing that no other document devised by the hand of man ever brought so much progress and happiness to humanity. The good it has wrought can never be measured.”&lt;br /&gt;
The education Coolidge received was very different from what most students—especially those in public schools—receive today. The importance of studying American history, government, and Western civilization can no longer be sidelined. Too often, discussions about education focus solely on spending, finance, or the promotion of STEM programs—science, technology, engineering, and math.&lt;br /&gt;
Of course, students need a curriculum that prepares them for higher education and the workforce. But education must also do more—it should prepare students to be informed, responsible citizens. Education is not just about acquiring skills; it is about citizenship.&lt;br /&gt;
For decades, the nation has faced a civic education crisis. Students are leaving K–12 schools and colleges with an alarming lack of understanding of American history, government, and Western civilization. Too often, civics instruction has become politicized, with curricula emphasizing narrow or revisionist viewpoints rather than a balanced appreciation of our shared history.&lt;br /&gt;
As a result, many young people are developing shallow or distorted views of America’s founding principles and institutions. Classrooms increasingly frame citizenship in global rather than national terms, and higher education is often dominated by a limited range of political and cultural perspectives.&lt;br /&gt;
In response, the Iowa Legislature has acted to strengthen civic education and refocus instruction on the values of liberty, republican self-government, and civic virtue that define the American tradition. In 2024, lawmakers directed a revision of the state’s social studies standards to ensure those principles are emphasized throughout the curriculum. The standards remain under review, but the goal is clear: reinforce rigorous instruction in American history, government, and Western civilization so that every Iowa student gains a deeper understanding of what it means to be an informed citizen.&lt;br /&gt;
The Legislature also required all high school students to pass the U.S. citizenship exam before graduation. This modest measure at least ensures that students demonstrate a basic understanding of our nation’s founding and institutions. Iowa already requires high school students to complete a course in civics prior to graduation, but strengthening the standards in the curriculum is essential to reversing the decline.&lt;br /&gt;
When it comes to higher education the situation is different. Iowa’s Regent Universities do not require a course in civic education to graduate. Further, the James G. Martin Center for Academic Renewal notes that Iowa’s flagship institution, the University of Iowa, is absent from the list of the “most civically aligned teacher preparation programs.”&lt;br /&gt;
America’s civic ignorance contributes to its deep divisions. Patrick J. Buchanan warned in The Death of the West:&lt;br /&gt;
“How does one sever a people’s roots? Destroy its memory. Deny a people the knowledge of who they are and where they came from... Destroy the record of a people’s past, leave it in ignorance of who its ancestors were and what they did, and one can fill the empty vessels of their souls with a new history.”&lt;br /&gt;
Political philosopher Russell Kirk echoed this sentiment, writing that “ignorance is a dangerous luxury” and that Americans who lack understanding of their nation’s principles “will be susceptible to ideologies and endanger the moral security of the nation.”&lt;br /&gt;
This civic decay explains why anti-American sentiment is rising among young people—and why so many now embrace socialism and even communism. How can constitutional principles like federalism or the Electoral College survive if they are no longer taught or understood?&lt;br /&gt;
This doesn’t mean avoiding difficult chapters in our history, such as slavery.  In fact, Americans have a duty to develop an informed knowledge of history and institutions.  As author James S. Robbins wrote in Erasing America, “History is the source of all life’s lessons, the good and the bad. We turn to history to see what to embrace and what to avoid.”&lt;br /&gt;
Civic education must be about more than memorizing facts. It should cultivate responsible citizens, not activists. It should inspire patriotism, respect for America’s heritage, and a lifelong desire to learn—just as it did for Coolidge. We owe it to both our ancestors and future generations to preserve our Republic and its ideals.&lt;br /&gt;
It’s time to restore that lesson to our schools and to heed the advice President Ronald Reagan provided us, “Let’s start with some basics: more attention to American history and a greater emphasis on civic ritual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/rebuilding-civic-knowledge-for-the-next-generation/"&gt;Rebuilding Civic Knowledge for the Next Generation&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 17:48:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] CT State Police Lieutenant Made $259K Last Year — Half from Overtime He Approved Himself</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/10/31/ct-state-police-lieutenant-made-259k-last-year-half-from-overtime-he-approved-himself/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a law-enforcement agency allows its own managers to approve their own pay, accountability isn’t just missing — it’s broken.  For years, the Connecticut State Police have paid out tens [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/10/31/ct-state-police-lieutenant-made-259k-last-year-half-from-overtime-he-approved-himself/"&gt;CT State Police Lieutenant Made $259K Last Year — Half from Overtime He Approved Himself &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 19:06:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] PRESS RELEASE: MISSISSIPPI CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY HONORS LEGISLATIVE HEROES AT ANNUAL GALA CELEBRATING STATE SUCCESS</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/press-release-mississippi-center-for-public-policy-honors-legislative-heroes-at-annual-gala-celebrating-state-success/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASEOctober 30, 2025 MISSISSIPPI CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY HONORS LEGISLATIVE HEROES AT ANNUAL GALA CELEBRATING STATE SUCCESS JACKSON, MS – October 30, 2025 –Six of Mississippi’s leading lawmakers were presented with award to honor them for championing principled conservative policy. Rich Lowry, editor of the National Review, presented each of the winners. HealthcareRep. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/press-release-mississippi-center-for-public-policy-honors-legislative-heroes-at-annual-gala-celebrating-state-success/" rel="nofollow"&gt;PRESS RELEASE: MISSISSIPPI CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY HONORS LEGISLATIVE HEROES AT ANNUAL GALA CELEBRATING STATE SUCCESS&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 19:21:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Illinois Explores Free-Market Energy Policy</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/energy/illinois-explores-free-market-energy-policy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I recently wrote about how one of our neighbors, Kansas, is making moves to bring nuclear energy to the state. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/energy/illinois-explores-free-market-energy-policy/"&gt;Illinois Explores Free-Market Energy Policy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 19:41:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Medicare Wasn’t Broken Until Democrats Made It That Way</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/medicare-wasnt-broken-until-democrats-made-it-that-way/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Seniors shopping for a prescription drug plan during this year&amp;#8217;s Medicare open enrollment season are in for an unpleasant surprise. They&amp;#8217;ll have far fewer choices than in previous years — and will have a harder time getting assistance purchasing a plan. The program&amp;#8217;s cost to taxpayers, meanwhile, have soared. What happened? The Democrats&amp;#8217; 2022 Inflation [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/medicare-wasnt-broken-until-democrats-made-it-that-way/"&gt;Medicare Wasn&amp;#8217;t Broken Until Democrats Made It That Way&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 21:45:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Long delay of bowling alley on Lanai suggests need for parking reform</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/10/long-delay-of-bowling-alley-on-lanai-suggests-need-for-parking-reform/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following commentary was first published on Oct. 30, 2025, by The Maui News under the headline “Lanai bowling alley saga shines light on county&amp;#8217;s cumbersome parking mandates.&amp;#8221;_____________ Maui County lawmakers have approved a bill that clears the way for a new four-lane bowling facility in the heart of the island’s “downtown” area. But the project’s almost-two-year [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/10/long-delay-of-bowling-alley-on-lanai-suggests-need-for-parking-reform/"&gt;Long delay of bowling alley on Lanai suggests need for parking reform&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 22:35:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Winners &amp; Losers: TPPF Sues Dallas, “The Rock” Soars + Halloween</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/winners-losers-tppf-sues-dallas-the-rock-soars-halloween/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Every Friday morning, I join the Cardle &amp;#38; Woolley Show on Talk 1370 Radio in Austin to announce the week’s Winners &amp;#38; Losers. Today marks Day 31 of the government shutdown and it’s been 12 days since the big heist at the Louvre. In this special Halloween edition, here’s who made the list:   WINNER:...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/winners-losers-tppf-sues-dallas-the-rock-soars-halloween/"&gt;Winners &amp; Losers: TPPF Sues Dallas, “The Rock” Soars + Halloween&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 22:49:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Income: You Earned It, You Should Keep It</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/income-you-earned-it-you-should-keep-it/</link><description>Income Taxes: We have options Are you getting the idea that the Idaho Freedom Foundation (IFF) thinks government takes too much in taxes? Good, let’s keep going. By applying our 2026 Freedom and Family Agenda’s strong position on tax cuts, we have proposed eliminating the sales tax on groceries and have offered a plan to [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 23:08:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] How many people in your county can’t access SNAP after Nov.1?</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/how-many-people-in-your-county-cant-access-snap-after-nov-1/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;If the federal government shutdown continues, millions of Illinoisans could lose access to critical food aid after Nov. 1. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/how-many-people-in-your-county-cant-access-snap-after-nov-1/"&gt;How many people in your county can’t access SNAP after Nov.1?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 23:52:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] $53 billion pension spike advances during last-minute veto session</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/53-billion-pension-spike-advances-during-last-minute-veto-session/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A bill that would increase Tier 2 pension benefits was passed out of Illinois House Executive Committee on Oct 30. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/53-billion-pension-spike-advances-during-last-minute-veto-session/"&gt;$53 billion pension spike advances during last-minute veto session&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 23:53:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Illinois lifts nuclear ban, but tightens grip on energy supply</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/illinois-lifts-nuclear-ban-but-tightens-grip-on-energy-supply/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Lawmakers pass a bill to end the ban on large nuclear plants but include plans on expanding state control over energy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/illinois-lifts-nuclear-ban-but-tightens-grip-on-energy-supply/"&gt;Illinois lifts nuclear ban, but tightens grip on energy supply&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 23:55:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Virginiainstitute] Press Release – HJ 6007: “one of the worst ideas” passed by the General Assembly</title><link>https://virginiainstitute.org/press-release-hj6007/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=press-release-hj6007</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Virginia Institute for Public Policy has expressed concern over HJ6007, a proposed amendment to Virginia’s Constitution that would alter the state’s current redistricting process. The Institute emphasized that Virginia voters approved a bipartisan approach in 2020 to ensure fair and transparent elections for all citizens. Citing constitutional and procedural issues surrounding HJ6007, the Institute encourages lawmakers to uphold established safeguards that protect the integrity and balance of Virginia’s electoral system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org/press-release-hj6007/"&gt;Press Release – HJ 6007: “one of the worst ideas” passed by the General Assembly&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org"&gt;Virginia Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 00:15:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Week in Review: Everything Should Be Smaller in Taxes</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/week-in-review-everything-should-be-smaller-in-taxes/</link><description>That’s right, the title says “Taxes,” not “Texas.” Even in Idaho, taxes are out of control. Please enjoy — if that’s the right word — this mini-series on Idaho taxes. But, before you read, one word of reminder: high taxes are merely the symptom of the true disease: out-of-control government spending. This symptom inflicts real [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 20:04:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Oh, the absurdity: Government-run grocery stores are laughable</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/oh-the-absurdity-government-run-grocery-stores-are-laughable</link><description>When politicians start promising cheaper milk and lettuce, it’s time to check your wallet—and your common sense.</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 21:09:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] A shooting in Dinkytown, student injured</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/a-shooting-in-dinkytown-student-injured/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Another crime story soon to be disappeared. From the Minneapolis Star Tribune, Halloween overnight shooting kills one, injures two in Dinkytown. For those who don’t know, Dinkytown is the small commercial/retail neighborhood adjacent to the University of Minnesota’s main campus in central Minneapolis. Details on the incident that occurred around 2:40 a.m. Saturday morning. Police...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/a-shooting-in-dinkytown-student-injured/"&gt;A shooting in Dinkytown, student injured&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 15:32:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Trump’s tactics face challenge against top authoritarians</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/trumps-tactics-face-challenge-against-top-authoritarians/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Hal Brands explains why top Russian and Chinese leaders do not fear American President Donald Trump. President Donald Trump relishes power — its relentless accumulation at home; its bold, assertive use abroad. For 10 months, he has aggressively wielded US power to renegotiate key relationships and cut through entrenched disputes. Yet so far, this approach...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/trumps-tactics-face-challenge-against-top-authoritarians/"&gt;Trump&amp;#8217;s tactics face challenge against top authoritarians&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 10:36:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Schools of civic thought make a difference</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/schools-of-civic-thought-make-a-difference/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Benjamin Storey and Jenna Silber Storey assess a significant development in American higher education. In crafting its new college-ranking system,&amp;#160;City Journal&amp;#160;has made the unusual—but, we believe, wise—choice to reward institutions that host a School of Civic Thought on campus. But what are Schools of Civic Thought, and why should parents and students consider their presence...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/schools-of-civic-thought-make-a-difference/"&gt;Schools of civic thought make a difference&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 10:39:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Activist anti-Trump judge may have violated federal law</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/activist-anti-trump-judge-may-have-violated-federal-law/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Breccan Thies writes for the Federalist about dubious actions from a judge with a questionable history. Judge James Boasberg, the lawfare fanatic serving as the chief judge of the U.S. District Court for D.C., issued an order intended to conceal the Biden administration’s attempted seizure of Sen. Ted Cruz’s phone records. In doing so, it...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/activist-anti-trump-judge-may-have-violated-federal-law/"&gt;Activist anti-Trump judge may have violated federal law&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 10:42:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Spending Watch: The Unpleasant Arithmetic of a California Wealth Tax</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/spending-watch-the-unpleasant-arithmetic-of-a-california-wealth-tax/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Spending Watch: The Unpleasant Arithmetic of a California Wealth Tax Wayne Winegarden October 2025 A just proposed initiative to impose a one-time wealth tax on billionaires summarizes why California has fallen from the fourth to the fifth largest economy in the world. State policymakers continually view the private sector as a piggybank to be raided [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/spending-watch-the-unpleasant-arithmetic-of-a-california-wealth-tax/"&gt;Spending Watch: The Unpleasant Arithmetic of a California Wealth Tax&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 10:55:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Fifty-five bills that would free Michigan workers</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/fifty-five-bills-that-would-free-michigan-workers</link><description>House bills aim to reform state’s heavy licensing laws</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] Franke: Civic Bargain Book Review</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/11/franke-civic-bargain-book-review/</link><description>by Mark Franke One hears the word democracy so often these days — and in so many contexts &amp;#160;—&amp;#160;that it has lost its meaning. There is the tiresome charge that anything Donald Trump does is a threat to democracy on one hand and on the other hand a rather pedantic academic argument that we are&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/11/franke-civic-bargain-book-review/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 12:31:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Why Omar Fateh’s $20 minimum wage would be disastrous for Minneapolis</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/why-omar-fatehs-20-minimum-wage-would-be-disastrous-for-minneapolis/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In addition to rent control, Mayoral candidate Senator Omar Fateh wants Minneapolis to adopt a $20 minimum wage by 2028. This would be disastrous for the city, as results from California, but even from the Twin Cities, have shown. California adopted a $20 minimum wage for fast food jobs in April 2024. In a recently...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/why-omar-fatehs-20-minimum-wage-would-be-disastrous-for-minneapolis/"&gt;Why Omar Fateh&amp;#8217;s $20 minimum wage would be disastrous for Minneapolis&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Golden Turkey Nominee: A $1 million bathroom in Bloomington</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/golden-turkey-nominee-a-1-million-bathroom-in-bloomington/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When the pandemic hit, Congress responded by sending billions of dollars to states, counties, cities, businesses, and citizens. Many cities had a hard time figuring out how to use the money to fight COVID. Cities, after all, mostly maintain streets, deliver water and sewer service, and answer 911 calls. But the leaders in Minnesota’s third-largest...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/golden-turkey-nominee-a-1-million-bathroom-in-bloomington/"&gt;Golden Turkey Nominee: A $1 million bathroom in Bloomington&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 14:16:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] New Pioneer Institute Analysis Finds Proposed Massachusetts Income-Tax Cut Unlikely to Cause Major State Revenue Decline</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/news/2026-tax-cut/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Lessons from the 2000 Massachusetts Income-Tax Rollback: A Reality-Check for the 2025 Ballot Debate is an empirical analysis of Massachusetts revenue data from FY1998–FY2021. The study concludes that a one-point rate reduction is unlikely to produce large, persistent revenue shortfalls, and that long-term fiscal stability depends far more on economic performance than on marginal rate differences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/news/2026-tax-cut/"&gt;New Pioneer Institute Analysis Finds Proposed Massachusetts Income-Tax Cut Unlikely to Cause Major State Revenue Decline&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 15:06:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Why CT’s Special Session Must Be Narrow and Focused</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/11/03/why-cts-special-session-must-be-narrow-and-focused/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="1707" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/shutterstock_2628868481-scaled.jpg" width="2560" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a special session expected in mid-November, progressives are using an emerging funding crisis to revisit Connecticut’s fiscal guardrails and advance other priorities such as health care and affordable housing.   [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/11/03/why-cts-special-session-must-be-narrow-and-focused/"&gt;Why CT&amp;#8217;s Special Session Must Be Narrow and Focused&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 15:15:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Come and Build It: Housing Policy Reform in Texas</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/come-and-build-it-housing-policy-reform-in-texas/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Texas is short more than 300,000 housing units, while 90% of Texans are worried about affordability. To ease these twin crises, policymakers passed an ambitious set of free-market-minded measures to boost supply and lower costs. Key points: The 89th Texas Legislature passed five key housing market reforms to increase supply, reduce government interference, and improve...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/come-and-build-it-housing-policy-reform-in-texas/"&gt;Come and Build It: Housing Policy Reform in Texas&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 15:17:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Florida’s Established Approach to Kids’ Online Safety Doesn’t Need Tweaking | Opinion</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/floridas-established-approach-to-kids-online-safety-doesnt-need-tweaking-opinion/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;October 31, 2025 In the ongoing debate about how to best protect children online, a new proposal gaining...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/floridas-established-approach-to-kids-online-safety-doesnt-need-tweaking-opinion/"&gt;Florida’s Established Approach to Kids’ Online Safety Doesn’t Need Tweaking | Opinion&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 15:55:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Legislators should end judicial deference to state agencies</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/legislators-should-end-judicial-deference-to-state-agencies</link><description>The U.S. Supreme Court’s 2024 decision in Loper Bright Enterprises  v. Raimondo  is reshaping federal land use in Wyoming and policy throughout the United States. The ruling reversed decades of precedent requiring courts to defer to a U.S. agency’s interpretation of laws. This meant that federal judges were required to favor the government over individual taxpayers or businesses, regardless of how far off base an agency's interpretation strayed from common sense or a plain reading of the law....</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 16:23:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] No, the expiring subsidies aren’t to blame for next year’s premium hikes</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/no-the-expiring-subsidies-arent-to-blame-for-next-years-premium-hikes/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Open enrollment on Obamacare‘s exchanges is upon us. People shopping for coverage will be greeted by higher premiums. According to one recent analysis from the Peterson-KFF Health System Tracker, premiums for 2026 coverage will rise by 18 %. Out-of-pocket costs could go up hundreds or thousands of dollars, according to KFF. Read the op-ed here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/no-the-expiring-subsidies-arent-to-blame-for-next-years-premium-hikes/"&gt;No, the expiring subsidies aren’t to blame for next year’s premium hikes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 16:40:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] New Report Calls for More Freedom and Consumer Choice in Energy Policy to Lower Costs</title><link>https://will-law.org/new-report-calls-for-more-freedom-and-consumer-choice-in-energy-policy-to-lower-costs/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A new report from WILL, titled “Energy Choice for Wisconsin: A Free-Market Case for Community Solar,” outlines how privately financed community solar projects can expand consumer choice, strengthen the electric grid, preserve farmland, and inject market competition into Wisconsin’s monopoly utility system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/new-report-calls-for-more-freedom-and-consumer-choice-in-energy-policy-to-lower-costs/"&gt;New Report Calls for More Freedom and Consumer Choice in Energy Policy to Lower Costs&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 17:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>