<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>State-Policy Think-Tank Digest</title><link>https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml</link><description>Latest posts from free-market policy institutes across the U.S.</description><atom:link href="https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 05:04:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>[Mspolicy] School Choice is Coming to Mississippi!</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/school-choice-is-coming-to-mississippi/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;What would it take for Mississippi to embrace School Choice?&amp;#160;How can we join our neighboring states in empowering families to control their child's share of the education budget? For School Choice to happen, we would need to see several steps.&amp;#160; &amp;#160;&amp;#160;Number one, we would need a committed Governor, ready to invest his political capital in [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/school-choice-is-coming-to-mississippi/" rel="nofollow"&gt;School Choice is Coming to Mississippi!&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 17:23:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Rifreedom] Center Cosigns Letter Supporting Seafreeze Petition to Suspend VINEYARD WIND Construction</title><link>https://rifreedom.org/2025/08/center-cosigns-letter-supporting-seafreeze-petition-to-suspend-vineyard-wind-construction/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Today, CEO for the Rhode Island Center for Freedom &amp;#038; Prosperity, Mike Stenhouse, co-signed a letter, along with national energy expert, G. Allen Brooks, requesting Doug Brugum, Secretary of the US Department Of the Interior (DOI), and other federal officials to accept the formal petition previously filed Seafreeze Inc (and others) that calls upon the government to immediately suspend "further construction and energy generation activity" of the near-completed Vineyard Wind off-shore wind project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org/2025/08/center-cosigns-letter-supporting-seafreeze-petition-to-suspend-vineyard-wind-construction/"&gt;Center Cosigns Letter Supporting Seafreeze Petition to Suspend VINEYARD WIND Construction&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org"&gt;RI Center for Freedom and Prosperity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 17:38:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Florida: The Gold Standard in Elections Administration From Bush v. Gore to Present 2000-2025</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/florida-the-gold-standard-in-elections-administration-from-bush-v-gore-to-present-2000-2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Ben Gibson — Senior Fellow, The James Madison Institute Doug Wheeler — Director, George Gibbs Center for Economic...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/florida-the-gold-standard-in-elections-administration-from-bush-v-gore-to-present-2000-2025/"&gt;Florida: The Gold Standard in Elections Administration From Bush v. Gore to Present 2000-2025&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 04:01:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cardinalinstitute] West Virginia’s Certificate of Need Laws Are Failing You</title><link>https://cardinalinstitute.com/west-virginias-certificate-of-need-laws-are-failing-you/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;West Virginia’s Certificate of Need Laws Are Failing You The West Virginia Hospital Association’s recent op-ed defending West Virginia’s Certificate of Need (CON) laws is a masterclass in elite protectionism, dressed in concern, framed as a noble stand for community health. Make no mistake—the heart of the piece is about hospital bottom lines rather than how [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com/west-virginias-certificate-of-need-laws-are-failing-you/"&gt;West Virginia’s Certificate of Need Laws Are Failing You&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com"&gt;Cardinal Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 16:22:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Colorado’s AI Catastrophe: A Cautionary Tale</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/colorados-ai-catastrophe-a-cautionary-tale/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On May 27, 2024, Colorado became the unfortunate pioneer in a troubling new frontier of government overreach. The...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/colorados-ai-catastrophe-a-cautionary-tale/"&gt;Colorado&amp;#8217;s AI Catastrophe: A Cautionary Tale&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 15:20:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] In child care, as in housing, maybe the government’s doing a bit too much?</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/08/in-child-care-as-in-housing-maybe-the-governments-doing-a-bit-too-much/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Surging child care prices have grabbed the media’s attention here in New Hampshire, and rightly so. The price of full-time care in a licensed center “jumped 48 percent between 2013 and 2023,” landing at nearly $32,000 a year, according to an analysis last year by the Carsey School of Public Policy at UNH.   Child [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/08/in-child-care-as-in-housing-maybe-the-governments-doing-a-bit-too-much/"&gt;In child care, as in housing, maybe the government’s doing a bit too much?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 17:00:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF in National Review: The Return of Car Choice, Hopefully</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-in-national-review-the-return-of-car-choice-hopefully/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following appeared in National Review&amp;#8217;s Capital Matters on August 20, 2025. Whatever happens to the future of EVs, they should compete on an even playing field with other vehicles. While the courts have yet to have their say, one of the Trump administration’s most important accomplishments, perhaps second only to his successful crackdown on illegal [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-in-national-review-the-return-of-car-choice-hopefully/"&gt;RGF in National Review: The Return of Car Choice, Hopefully&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 17:56:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] SEPTA’s Manufactured Crisis Has Delayed State Budget Long Enough</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/08/22/septas-manufactured-crisis-has-delayed-state-budget-long-enough/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Harrisburg, Pa., August 22, 2025 — This Sunday, after eight consecutive weeks of public fearmongering, the Southeastern Pennsylvania Transportation Authority (SEPTA) will enact self-imposed service cuts. Though completely avoidable, these cuts aim to extract yet another taxpayer-funded bailout. This is not a true emergency; it is a manufactured crisis, fueled and exploited by Gov. Josh [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/08/22/septas-manufactured-crisis-has-delayed-state-budget-long-enough/"&gt;SEPTA’s Manufactured Crisis Has Delayed State Budget Long Enough&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 16:12:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Rifreedom] After Federal Action, Rhode Island Desperately Needs a Realistic Energy Strategy</title><link>https://rifreedom.org/2025/08/after-federal-action-rhode-island-desperately-needs-a-realistic-energy-strategy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Cranston, RI – The Rhode Island Center for Freedom &amp;#38; Prosperity advises state policymakers to immediately begin work to construct a new and realistic energy strategy that will put the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org/2025/08/after-federal-action-rhode-island-desperately-needs-a-realistic-energy-strategy/"&gt;After Federal Action, Rhode Island Desperately Needs a Realistic Energy Strategy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org"&gt;RI Center for Freedom and Prosperity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 15:41:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Public Recommendations to Idaho's DOGE Task Force to Increase Government Efficiency</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/public-recommendations-to-idahos-doge-task-force-to-increase-government-efficiency/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/public-recommendations-to-idahos-doge-task-force-to-increase-government-efficiency/" rel="nofollow" title="Public Recommendations to Idaho&amp;#039;s DOGE Task Force to Increase Government Efficiency"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Article-Headers-2025-09-01T114655.975.png" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Dear Members of the Idaho DOGE Task Force,&amp;#160; At the request of members of this Task Force, we have attached our analysis and recommendations for the committee's consideration. Each proposed reduction, consolidation, or elimination falls within the committee's stated purpose and offers realistic options for waste reduction.&amp;#160; The Idaho DOGE Task Force is positioned to [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 18:06:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] Beyond the Beach: Honoring the Dignity of Work</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/09/01/labor-day-honoring-the-dignity-of-work/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A free and prosperous society is built on a foundation of responsible, creative, and purposeful work. When government is limited and economic freedom is upheld, individuals are empowered to pursue their callings, provide for their families, and contribute to the common good. Labor Day, therefore, becomes a day to honor not just the physical act of labor, but the sacred dignity of work—the opportunity we have to use our gifts to create, serve, and build, all while reflecting the image of our Creator. It is a day to be grateful for the freedom to work and to be a part of a society where that freedom is protected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/09/01/labor-day-honoring-the-dignity-of-work/"&gt;Beyond the Beach: Honoring the Dignity of Work&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 19:46:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Mississippi's Progress and the Push for School Choice</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/mississippis-progress-and-the-push-for-school-choice/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This week, I’ll be traveling to Washington, D.C. talking about Mississippi’s remarkable progress, including our elimination of the income tax and how we might best advance school choice in our state. Mississippi is gaining national attention for our transformative public policies. Once seen as a perennial underdog, our state is now recognized as a leader in free-market [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/mississippis-progress-and-the-push-for-school-choice/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi&amp;#039;s Progress and the Push for School Choice&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 17:09:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Non-working adults concentrated in Georgia’s distressed communities</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/adults-not-working-in-georgia/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Many Georgia counties face high rates of non-working adults, fueling distress and limiting opportunities in struggling communities. See the percentages for your county. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/adults-not-working-in-georgia/"&gt;Non-working adults concentrated in Georgia’s distressed communities&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 18:51:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Separate but Equitable at Portland Public Schools</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/education/separate-but-equitable-at-portland-public-schools/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By John A. Charles, Jr. In 1954 the U.S. Supreme Court ruled that...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/education/separate-but-equitable-at-portland-public-schools/"&gt;Separate but Equitable at Portland Public Schools&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 14:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] New Poll: Inflation, Economy, Taxes, and Crime Top Voter Concerns, Pennsylvanians Hold Shapiro Responsible for Budget Impasse</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/09/03/new-poll-inflation-economy-taxes-and-crime-top-voter-concerns-pennsylvanians-hold-shapiro-responsible-for-budget-impasse/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Harrisburg, Pa., September 3, 2025 — Fewer than 4-in-10 Pennsylvania voters believe the state is on the right track, according to new polling released today by the Commonwealth Foundation. Inflation, the economy, taxes, and crime top their list of concerns facing the state, with nearly two-thirds of Pennsylvanians saying economic conditions are worsening for them [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/09/03/new-poll-inflation-economy-taxes-and-crime-top-voter-concerns-pennsylvanians-hold-shapiro-responsible-for-budget-impasse/"&gt;New Poll: Inflation, Economy, Taxes, and Crime Top Voter Concerns, Pennsylvanians Hold Shapiro Responsible for Budget Impasse &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 15:24:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] A conversation on New Mexico’s health care provider shortage w/ RGF’s Paul Gessing &amp; Think New Mexico’s Fred Nathan</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/a-conversation-on-new-mexicos-health-care-provider-shortage-w-rgfs-paul-gessing-think-new-mexicos-fred-nathan/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Most New Mexicans are abundantly aware of the dire medical provider shortage facing our state. The Rio Grande Foundation has been researching and discussing solutions to this problem for several years. The same is true for Think New Mexico which is led by Fred Nathan. While we don&amp;#8217;t always agree with the approach of Think [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/a-conversation-on-new-mexicos-health-care-provider-shortage-w-rgfs-paul-gessing-think-new-mexicos-fred-nathan/"&gt;A conversation on New Mexico&amp;#8217;s health care provider shortage w/ RGF&amp;#8217;s Paul Gessing &amp;#038; Think New Mexico&amp;#8217;s Fred Nathan&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 15:42:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] Distinctions Between Social Justice and Biblical Justice</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/09/04/distinctions-between-social-justice-and-biblical-justice/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The use of governmental imposition to force social justice on its people is a path that leads to more government, less freedom, and deeper division. The true path forward can be found in a return to the principles of biblical justice—impartiality, righteousness, and individual responsibility. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/09/04/distinctions-between-social-justice-and-biblical-justice/"&gt;Distinctions Between Social Justice and Biblical Justice&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 06:49:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Fact Checking Claims on Enrollment Declines</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/fact-checking-claims-on-enrollment-declines/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=fact-checking-claims-on-enrollment-declines</link><description>Despite declining enrollment occurring all across the nation, recent news reports have claimed that the problem is specific to Tennessee because of the state's new Education Freedom Scholarships (EFS) program. Not only do these accusations wrongly place blame, many critics simply get the basics of the EFS program wrong. Let’s set the record straight.</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 16:04:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] The hills are alive with the, well, approval of leftist politicians</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/wisconsin-rights-of-nature-law/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;State Rep. Joy Goeben and state Sen. Steve Nass have introduced a bill that would prohibit local governments from enacting a “rights of nature” ordinance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/wisconsin-rights-of-nature-law/"&gt;The hills are alive with the, well, approval of leftist politicians&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 20:45:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] New Hampshire rated the least corrupt state</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/09/new-hampshire-rated-the-least-corrupt-state/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;America’s freest state has just been rated its least corrupt too. Using U.S. Department of Justice data on corruption convictions in all 94 federal judicial districts from 2003-2024, the Cato Institute calculated the rate of corruption convictions per 10,000 government employees, then recently ranked states by their conviction rates. New Hampshire ranked dead last, with [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/09/new-hampshire-rated-the-least-corrupt-state/"&gt;New Hampshire rated the least corrupt state&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 00:17:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] School Choice Improves Public School Performance</title><link>https://empowerms.org/school-choice-improves-public-school-performance/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#8217;s an argument going around that deserves a response: The Parents’ Campaign has repeatedly claimed that Mississippi is gaining academically while the &amp;#8220;top choice states&amp;#8221; plummeted. This is naive, lacking any academic rigor, and a dishonest interpretation of the data.   First, the phrase &amp;#8220;top choice states&amp;#8221; is misleading. Half the states in their top 10&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/school-choice-improves-public-school-performance/"&gt;School Choice Improves Public School Performance&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 15:41:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] First Principles Series: The Plight of Property Taxes</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/first-principles-series-the-plight-of-property-taxes/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=first-principles-series-the-plight-of-property-taxes</link><description>Tennessee joins Hawaii, Vermont, and New Hampshire as the outliers where property taxes can go up without limit.</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 16:02:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Cost of Democrat-Supported Carbon Tax Reaches $500 Million Per Year</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/cost-of-democrat-supported-carbon-tax-reaches-500-million-per-year/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="630" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Democrats-Carbon-Tax-Virginia.jpg" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the&amp;#160;most recent&amp;#160;carbon tax imposed on the member states of the Regional Greenhouse Gas Initiative (RGGI), Virginians will pay about $500 million more per year for electricity if Virginia again becomes one of those member states.&amp;#160;Your vote in November may determine that.&amp;#160; Democratic nominee for governor Abigail Spanberger&amp;#160;has pledged&amp;#160;to rejoin the RGGI compact and [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/cost-of-democrat-supported-carbon-tax-reaches-500-million-per-year/"&gt;Cost of Democrat-Supported Carbon Tax Reaches $500 Million Per Year&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 23:20:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] Commonwealth Foundation Urges Legal Protection of State’s Rainy Day Fund</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/09/08/commonwealth-foundation-urges-legal-protection-of-states-rainy-day-fund/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Letter calls on Treasurer Garrity to withhold any transfer from the budget stabilization reserve fund, pending legal adjudication. Harrisburg, Pa., September 8, 2025 — Today, the Commonwealth Foundation sent a letter to leaders of the General Assembly and Pennsylvania State Treasurer Stacy Garrity, urging the legal protection of the commonwealth’s Rainy Day Fund. Gov. Josh [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/09/08/commonwealth-foundation-urges-legal-protection-of-states-rainy-day-fund/"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation Urges Legal Protection of State&amp;#8217;s Rainy Day Fund&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 15:28:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Bill 123 crucial to economic recovery of bed and breakfasts in Lahaina</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/09/bill-123-crucial-to-economic-recovery-of-bed-and-breakfasts-in-lahaina/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Maui County Council on September 8, 2025._____________ Sept. 8, 2025, 9 a.m.Kalana O Maui Building To: Maui County Council&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Alice Lee, Chair&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Yuki Lei Sugimura, Vice Chair From: Grassrot Institute of Hawaii&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Jonathan Helton, Policy Analyst RE: Bill 123 (2025) [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/09/bill-123-crucial-to-economic-recovery-of-bed-and-breakfasts-in-lahaina/"&gt;Bill 123 crucial to economic recovery of bed and breakfasts in Lahaina&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 20:37:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] How Much Does Private School Really Cost in Mississippi?</title><link>https://empowerms.org/how-much-does-private-school-really-cost-in-mississippi/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For many Mississippi families, private school feels financially out of reach. However new research shows that private education may be more affordable than most people think—and that smart policy could make it accessible to thousands more students.  Research conducted by Empower Mississippi reveals that the average tuition for private schools varies from approximately $6,710 for&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/how-much-does-private-school-really-cost-in-mississippi/"&gt;How Much Does Private School Really Cost in Mississippi?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 21:15:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] WILL Applauds Wisconsin State Assembly for Tackling Education Priorities</title><link>https://will-law.org/will-applauds-wisconsin-state-assembly-for-tackling-education-priorities/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL supports new efforts by WI legislators to tackle these pressing issues in education. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/will-applauds-wisconsin-state-assembly-for-tackling-education-priorities/"&gt;WILL Applauds Wisconsin State Assembly for Tackling Education Priorities&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 17:11:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] The ITD Money Pit of Idaho: Stop Digging!</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/the-itd-money-pit-of-idaho-stop-digging/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/the-itd-money-pit-of-idaho-stop-digging/" rel="nofollow" title="The ITD Money Pit of Idaho: Stop Digging!"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Article-Headers-2025-09-09T110039.106.png" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Want to save the state nearly $100 million and help fix the budget hole created by years of overspending? Stop digging the money pit of the Idaho Transportation Department (ITD) headquarters on State Street.&amp;#160;&amp;#160; A couple of weeks ago, the governor’s office of the Division of Financial Management revised its tax collections forecast and reported [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 18:15:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Avon Rep. Eleni Kavros Degraw Calls Non-Degree Workers a ‘Burden’ at Debt Relief Meeting</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/09/09/avon-rep-eleni-kavros-degraw-calls-non-degree-workers-a-burden-at-debt-relief-meeting/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="tf_svg_lazy attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="578" src="data:image/svg+xml,%3Csvg%20xmlns=%27http://www.w3.org/2000/svg%27%20width='1016'%20height='578'%20viewBox=%270%200%201016%20578%27%3E%3C/svg%3E" width="1016" /&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="578" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Screenshot-2025-09-09-at-2.13.19-PM.png" width="1016" /&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A legislative working group created to explore student debt relief in Connecticut took an unexpected turn last week when one of its co-chairs, Rep. Eleni Kavros DeGraw (D-Avon), suggested that [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/09/09/avon-rep-eleni-kavros-degraw-calls-non-degree-workers-a-burden-at-debt-relief-meeting/"&gt;Avon Rep. Eleni Kavros Degraw Calls Non-Degree Workers a ‘Burden’ at Debt Relief Meeting&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 18:20:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] National Poverty Rate Fails to Capture the Problem of Poverty Concentration in Georgia and Beyond</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/press-release-poverty-rate-2024/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/press-release-poverty-rate-2024/"&gt;National Poverty Rate Fails to Capture the Problem of Poverty Concentration in Georgia and Beyond&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 18:26:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] As PEEHIP Faces Funding Shortfall, it is Time for Healthcare and Pension Reforms</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/09/10/as-peehip-faces-funding-shortfall-it-is-time-for-healthcare-and-pension-reforms/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This week, the Retirement Systems of Alabama’s (RSA) Public Education Employees’ Health Insurance Plan (PEEHIP) Control Board met to discuss rising healthcare costs for state employees. The discussion highlights a stark reality: Alabama’s taxpayer funded benefit system for public employees is on an unsustainable path. PEEHIP and RSA, which includes the Teachers’ Retirement System (TRS) and Employees’ Retirement System (ERS), are consuming billions annually while carrying massive unfunded liabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/09/10/as-peehip-faces-funding-shortfall-it-is-time-for-healthcare-and-pension-reforms/"&gt;As PEEHIP Faces Funding Shortfall, it is Time for Healthcare and Pension Reforms&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 02:32:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] WILL &amp; IRG File Suit to Allow IRG to Disclose Request for Investigation Brought Against Judge</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/will-irg-file-suit-to-allow-irg-to-disclose-request-for-investigation-brought-against-judge/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL &amp;#38; IRG File Suit to Allow IRG to Disclose Request for Investigation Brought Against Judge Wisconsin Law Bars Release of Denied Requests, Violates First Amendment The News: The Institute for Reforming Government, represented by the Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;#38; Liberty, filed a lawsuit against the Wisconsin Judicial Commission challenging a statute that prohibits [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/will-irg-file-suit-to-allow-irg-to-disclose-request-for-investigation-brought-against-judge/"&gt;WILL &amp;#038; IRG File Suit to Allow IRG to Disclose Request for Investigation Brought Against Judge&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 13:05:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] UK’s Dr. Kathryn Hughes on George Eliot, Middlemarch, &amp; Victorian Novels</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/uks-dr-kathryn-hughes-on-george-eliot-middlemarch-victorian-novels/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In this week’s episode of The Learning Curve, co-hosts U-Arkansas Prof. Albert Cheng and Great Hearts Academies’ Dr. Helen Baxendale interview Dr. Kathryn Hughes, academic historian and award-winning author of George Eliot: The Last Victorian. Dr. Hughes discusses the significance of 19th-century novelist Mary Ann Evans, better known by her pen name George Eliot, in shaping British literature and capturing the societal tensions of the Victorian era.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/uks-dr-kathryn-hughes-on-george-eliot-middlemarch-victorian-novels/"&gt;UK&amp;#8217;s Dr. Kathryn Hughes on George Eliot, Middlemarch, &amp;#038; Victorian Novels&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 13:41:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Tightening Nebraska’s Property Tax Caps for Real Relief</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/tightening-nebraskas-property-tax-caps-for-real-relief/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Nebraska lawmakers can deliver stronger transparency and greater tax relief by consolidating and tightening Nebraska’s property tax caps. Nebraska has both a Truth-In-Taxation (TNT) transparency law and property tax caps for K-12 school districts and then separate caps for all other local governments.  By comparison, several less-fiscally-responsible states impose more strict property tax caps. Nebraska...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/tightening-nebraskas-property-tax-caps-for-real-relief/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Tightening Nebraska’s Property Tax Caps for Real Relief&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 13:43:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] As an LIRR Strike Looms, the Empire Center Publishes the Disputed Contracts</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/as-an-lirr-strike-looms-the-empire-center-publishes-the-disputed-contracts/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;With Long Island Rail Road workers threatening a strike that could strand hundreds of thousands of commuters, the Empire Center....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/as-an-lirr-strike-looms-the-empire-center-publishes-the-disputed-contracts/"&gt;As an LIRR Strike Looms, the Empire Center Publishes the Disputed Contracts&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 13:59:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] WILL &amp; IRG File Suit to Allow IRG to Disclose Request for Investigation Brought Against Judges</title><link>https://will-law.org/will-irg-file-suit-to-allow-irg-to-disclose-request-for-investigation-brought-against-judge/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL filed a complaint against the Wisconsin Judicial Commission on behalf of the Institute for Reforming Government (IRG) challenging confidentiality requirements for certain requests for investigation filed with the Commission. The lawsuit alleges that the confidentiality requirements violate the First Amendment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/will-irg-file-suit-to-allow-irg-to-disclose-request-for-investigation-brought-against-judge/"&gt;WILL &amp;#038; IRG File Suit to Allow IRG to Disclose Request for Investigation Brought Against Judges&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 14:02:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Kansas Needs a Reality Check—It’s Time to Relearn Econ 101</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/kansas-needs-econ-101/</link><description>When I recently published Econ 101: A Compass for a Lost Country at The Daily Economy, I aimed to remind Americans—especially policymakers—that prosperity is rooted in simple, timeless truths. Economics isn’t about government programs or political slogans. It’s about human behavior, the way people respond to incentives, and the trade-offs we all face in a [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 14:44:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Cost for Seattle’s Sound Transit rail program balloons to $185 billion -  $55,000 per person within the tax district</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/cost-for-seattle-s-sound-transit-rail-program-balloons-to-185-billion-55-000-per-person-within</link><description>Sound Transit, the agency in charge of Seattle’s rail program , recently announced a shocking, $35 billion  cost overrun on the ST3...</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 15:31:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] IRG v. Wisconsin Judicial Commission</title><link>https://will-law.org/irg-v-wisconsin-judicial-commission/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL filed a lawsuit against the Wisconsin Judicial Commission challenging a statute that prohibits publicly revealing denied requests for investigation of Wisconsin judges on First Amendment grounds. IRG filed a request for investigation, asking the Commission to open an investigation into alleged judicial misconduct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/irg-v-wisconsin-judicial-commission/"&gt;IRG v. Wisconsin Judicial Commission&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 17:06:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Student Excellence for Every Portland Public School</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/education/student-excellence-for-every-portland-public-school/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By John Charles On September 9th, the Portland Public School (PPS) board was...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/education/student-excellence-for-every-portland-public-school/"&gt;Student Excellence for Every Portland Public School&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 17:49:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] KASB tries to whitewash new lower proficiency standards with deception and false claims</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/kasb-tries-to-whitewash-new-lower-proficiency-standards-with-deception-and-false-claims/</link><description>When something sounds too good to be true, it often is…like the State School Board and the Kansas Department of Education claiming that skyrocketing proficiency levels are not related to the state dumbing down proficiency standards. Now, the Kansas Association of School Boards (KASB) is joining the chorus with a new video denying that proficiency [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 19:45:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Virginiainstitute] In memory of Charlie Kirk (1993-2025)</title><link>https://virginiainstitute.org/in-memory-of-charlie-kirk-1993-2025/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=in-memory-of-charlie-kirk-1993-2025</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Virginia Institute for Public Policy tonight remembers Charlie Kirk, his beautiful wife Erika, and his young daughter and son who will grow up without a father&amp;#8217;s loving care and&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org/in-memory-of-charlie-kirk-1993-2025/"&gt;In memory of Charlie Kirk (1993-2025)&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org"&gt;Virginia Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 02:59:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] McGowan: The Advantage of Biological Parents</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/09/14136/</link><description>by Richard McGowan, Ph.D. When I taught ethics at Butler, there were with ethical issues that did not exist when I previously taught at the now-defunct St. Joseph’s College in Rensselaer. &amp;#160; In the late 1980s and early 1990s, technological innovation was not nearly so developed as it was a mere ten years later. For&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/09/14136/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 12:48:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Aaron Withe Honors Charlie Kirk, Condemns Political Violence</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/press-release/aaron-withe-honors-charlie-kirk-condemns-political-violence/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Charlie Kirk was somebody that was brave and unapologetically stood up for the same values that we all fight for each day. I had the privilege of knowing him, and he was someone I respected. We are around the same age, had our first kids around the same time, believe the same things, and are both leaders of right-leaning organizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/press-release/aaron-withe-honors-charlie-kirk-condemns-political-violence/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Aaron Withe Honors Charlie Kirk, Condemns Political Violence&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Job Opening: Policy Analyst</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/job-opening-policy-analyst/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Policy Analyst About the Position Maine Policy Institute is seeking an energetic, organized, and detail-oriented full-time policy analyst to conduct the organization’s research, legislative testimony, blog posts and public policy outreach. This position will report directly to the chief executive officer and work closely with the director of legislative affairs and director of civic engagement [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/job-opening-policy-analyst/"&gt;Job Opening: Policy Analyst&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] John Charles’ Sept. 9 Testimony for PPS Board Meeting Re: Purchase Agreement for Center for Black Student Excellence</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/education/john-charles-sept-9-testimony-for-pps-board-meeting-re-purchase-agreement-for-center-for-black-student-excellence/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Executive Summary: On September 9th, the Portland Public School (PPS) board met to...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/education/john-charles-sept-9-testimony-for-pps-board-meeting-re-purchase-agreement-for-center-for-black-student-excellence/"&gt;John Charles’ Sept. 9 Testimony for PPS Board Meeting Re: Purchase Agreement for Center for Black Student Excellence&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 14:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Pelican Institute Files Amicus Briefs at U.S. Supreme Court to  Confront Trial-Lawyer Driven Lawfare Against American Energy Production</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/press-release/pelican-institute-files-amicus-briefs-at-u-s-supreme-court-to-confront-trial-lawyer-driven-lawfare-against-american-energy-production/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Today, the Pelican Institute for Public Policy filed amicus briefs in two landmark cases now before the United States Supreme Court, each raising urgent questions about major distortions of the U.S. legal system to wage war on American energy production. “These cases are about more than the energy industry—they are about the integrity of our...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/press-release/pelican-institute-files-amicus-briefs-at-u-s-supreme-court-to-confront-trial-lawyer-driven-lawfare-against-american-energy-production/"&gt;Pelican Institute Files Amicus Briefs at U.S. Supreme Court to  Confront Trial-Lawyer Driven Lawfare Against American Energy Production&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 17:42:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Goldwater: AZ Supreme Court Should Strike Down Donor-Doxxing Law</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/goldwater-az-supreme-court-should-strike-down-donor-doxxing-law/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Today, attorneys for the Goldwater Institute and Andrew Gould at Holtzman Vogel made a crucial stand for the freedom of..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/goldwater-az-supreme-court-should-strike-down-donor-doxxing-law/"&gt;Goldwater: AZ Supreme Court Should Strike Down Donor-Doxxing Law&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 18:44:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] In Memory of Charlie Kirk: Why Political Violence Demands A Better Response</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/in-memory-of-charlie-kirk-why-political-violence-demands-a-better-response/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The staff at Maine Policy Institute joins millions across the country in mourning the tragic and senseless killing of Charlie Kirk, founder of Turning Point USA. We offer our heartfelt condolences to his wife, children, and colleagues, and we stand in solidarity with those across the political spectrum who are grieving this immense loss. No [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/in-memory-of-charlie-kirk-why-political-violence-demands-a-better-response/"&gt;In Memory of Charlie Kirk: Why Political Violence Demands A Better Response&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 19:05:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] How Immigrants Became a Cash Cow for New York’s Essential Plan</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/how-immigrants-became-a-cash-cow-for-new-yorks-essential-plan/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Hochul administration&amp;#8217;s move to shrink the Essential Plan in response to federal budget cuts has exposed a surprising reality:....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/how-immigrants-became-a-cash-cow-for-new-yorks-essential-plan/"&gt;How Immigrants Became a Cash Cow for New York&amp;#8217;s Essential Plan&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 19:38:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Job Licensing Reviews: Judiciary, Natural Resources and Urban Affairs Committees</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/job-licensing-reviews-judiciary-natural-resources-and-urban-affairs-committees/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Occupational Board Reform Act (OBRA) was passed in 2018 and became effective in 2019. It requires legislative committees of jurisdiction to review all occupational licenses in the state, roughly 20% per year, on a five-year rotation. These reviews examine whether the licensing requirements are adequate or excessive by current standards. The committees then submit...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/job-licensing-reviews-judiciary-natural-resources-and-urban-affairs-committees/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Job Licensing Reviews: Judiciary, Natural Resources and Urban Affairs Committees&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 21:18:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Remembering Charlie Kirk</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/remembering-charlie-kirk/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;No American should be attacked for voicing their opinion, for speaking their mind, or for standing up for what they..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/remembering-charlie-kirk/"&gt;Remembering Charlie Kirk&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 21:59:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Tony Evers’ puzzlingly swift rejection of more education money</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/tony-evers-puzzlingly-swift-rejection-of-more-education-money/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When asked about whether Evers would wave his hand to let Wisconsin taxpayers use a new federal tax credit for education-related donations, the governor slammed the door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/tony-evers-puzzlingly-swift-rejection-of-more-education-money/"&gt;Tony Evers’ puzzlingly swift rejection of more education money&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 22:26:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Evers administration pigs out on livestock fees</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/wi-evers-administration-pigs-out-on-livestock-fees/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;State agencies have begun their rush through a regulatory back door that will almost certainly cost owners of businesses large and small in Wisconsin tens of millions of dollars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/wi-evers-administration-pigs-out-on-livestock-fees/"&gt;Evers administration pigs out on livestock fees&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 22:26:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Listen: Charlie Kirk’s Death and Political Violence on WGAN</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/listen-charlie-kirks-death-and-political-violence-on-wgan/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Policy analyst, Harris Van Pate, joined the WGAN Morning News to discuss the political response to the assassination of Charlie Kirk, including what lawmakers on both sides of the aisle have shared in response and what the political temperature in Augusta feels like. Listen to the full segment below. Newsradio WGAN · Maine Policy Institute&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/listen-charlie-kirks-death-and-political-violence-on-wgan/"&gt;Listen: Charlie Kirk&amp;#8217;s Death and Political Violence on WGAN&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 12:27:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] How AI can help take regulatory reforms to the next level</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/how-ai-can-help-take-regulatory-reforms-to-the-next-level</link><description>Across our region, policymakers have been taking action that significantly moves the economic needle: cutting waste and trimming red...</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 15:00:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] When It Comes to Attendance, Hartford Schools Hold Students Accountable — But Not Staff</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/09/12/when-it-comes-to-attendance-hartford-schools-hold-students-accountable-but-not-staff/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Connecticut, students who miss more than 10 percent of school days in a year are labeled “chronically absent.” That designation triggers a series of interventions: districts must notify families, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/09/12/when-it-comes-to-attendance-hartford-schools-hold-students-accountable-but-not-staff/"&gt;When It Comes to Attendance, Hartford Schools Hold Students Accountable — But Not Staff&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 15:35:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] The Court and the Computer: When a Judge Underestimated Technological Innovation</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/the-court-and-the-computer-when-a-judge-underestimated-technological-innovation/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The antitrust case against Google was filed in 2020 and did not conclude until the beginning of this month. The last five years have been a case study in the differing paces of the judiciary and technological progress. Judge Mehta, who presided over the case, ruled on the remedies last week and his decision acknowledges...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/the-court-and-the-computer-when-a-judge-underestimated-technological-innovation/"&gt;The Court and the Computer: When a Judge Underestimated Technological Innovation&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 16:15:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Virginiainstitute] Press Release – Coalition Applauds Executive Order 53</title><link>https://virginiainstitute.org/press-release-coalition-applauds-executive-order-53/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=press-release-coalition-applauds-executive-order-53</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Summary Virginia Fair Elections (VFE), a coalition committed to ensuring transparent and secure elections in Virginia, has publicly praised Governor Glenn Youngkin’s Executive Order 53, issued on September 12, 2025.&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org/press-release-coalition-applauds-executive-order-53/"&gt;Press Release – Coalition Applauds Executive Order 53&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org"&gt;Virginia Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 16:17:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] CT’s Bond Rating Upgrades Prove Fiscal Guardrails Are Working — So Why Undermine Them?</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/09/12/cts-bond-rating-upgrades-prove-fiscal-guardrails-are-working-so-why-undermine-them/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="1438" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/shutterstock_2376193717-scaled.jpg" width="2560" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connecticut’s recent bond rating upgrades are a clear sign that the state’s fiscal guardrails are delivering results. Yet, even as these reforms strengthen our long-term financial outlook, lawmakers continue to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/09/12/cts-bond-rating-upgrades-prove-fiscal-guardrails-are-working-so-why-undermine-them/"&gt;CT&amp;#8217;s Bond Rating Upgrades Prove Fiscal Guardrails Are Working — So Why Undermine Them?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 17:58:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Students Who Can’t Read Benefit from Third-Grade Retention</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/performance/students-who-cant-read-benefit-from-third-grade-retention/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This is the headline from a recent study I conducted in Indiana with my coauthor NaYoung Hwang. We study a [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/performance/students-who-cant-read-benefit-from-third-grade-retention/"&gt;Students Who Can’t Read Benefit from Third-Grade Retention&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 19:14:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Kent calls for more transparency regarding Aloha Stadium project</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/09/kent-calls-for-more-transparency-regarding-aloha-stadium-project/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A developer has been chosen for the Aloha Stadium project, but the state has yet to reveal contract details or even how much it might cost. Joe Kent, executive vice president of the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii, talked this past Sunday with H. Hawaii Media radio host Johnny Miro about the lack of transparency surrounding [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/09/kent-calls-for-more-transparency-regarding-aloha-stadium-project/"&gt;Kent calls for more transparency regarding Aloha Stadium project&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 19:34:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Join us in reviving the free exchange of ideas in New Hampshire</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/09/join-us-in-reviving-the-free-exchange-of-ideas-in-new-hampshire/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On September 9, the Foundation for Individual Rights and Expression (FIRE) released its 2026 campus free speech rankings, concluding that “America’s colleges get an ‘F’ for poor free speech climate.”  “More students than ever think violence and chaos are acceptable alternatives to peaceful protest,” FIRE Chief Research Advisor Sean Stevens said on the report’s release. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/09/join-us-in-reviving-the-free-exchange-of-ideas-in-new-hampshire/"&gt;Join us in reviving the free exchange of ideas in New Hampshire&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 20:08:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] A Reflection on the Life of Charlie Kirk and a Call to Prayer at Noon on Friday</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/a-reflection-on-the-life-of-charlie-kirk-and-a-call-to-prayer-at-noon-on-friday/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="630" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/IMG_3776.jpeg" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Friend of TJI, While we are all still processing yesterday’s tragic news of the assassination of Charlie&amp;#160;Kirk, I find great comfort in knowing that Charlie is in a better place.&amp;#160;Charlie wasn’t just an evangelist for freedom, he was a cultural missionary, of sorts, calling people to know and love God, and to know and [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/a-reflection-on-the-life-of-charlie-kirk-and-a-call-to-prayer-at-noon-on-friday/"&gt;A Reflection on the Life of Charlie Kirk and a Call to Prayer at Noon on Friday&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 23:16:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Mahomes Can’t Evade New York’s Licensing Blitz</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/mahomes-cant-evade-new-yorks-licensing-blitz/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The National Football League kicked off its new season this month and fans tuning in to television broadcasts this fall....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/mahomes-cant-evade-new-yorks-licensing-blitz/"&gt;Mahomes Can&amp;#8217;t Evade New York&amp;#8217;s Licensing Blitz&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 11:56:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Election 2025: Virginia’s Energy Future Is on the Ballot: Will Voters Choose Reliability or Risk?</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/election-2025-virginias-energy-future-is-on-the-ballot-will-voters-choose-reliability-or-risk/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="630" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Reliable-vs-Unreliable-Power-for-Virginia.jpg" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For several years now, Virginians have been told that the&amp;#160;Virginia Clean Economy Act (VCEA) is necessary to save Virginia&amp;#160;and is a necessary step to save the planet. We’ve been told that rising seas, worsening storms, and other supposedly catastrophic impacts of man-made climate change justify a radical restructuring of Virginia’s entire energy system. But what [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/election-2025-virginias-energy-future-is-on-the-ballot-will-voters-choose-reliability-or-risk/"&gt;Election 2025: Virginia&amp;#8217;s Energy Future Is on the Ballot: Will Voters Choose Reliability or Risk?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 15:14:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Study Calls for Expanding Access to Career Vocational Technical Education</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/study-calls-for-expanding-access-to-career-vocational-technical-education-acute-shortage-in-gateway-cities/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Massachusetts’ budget for fiscal 2026 that includes $100 million in grants to create an additional 3,000 career/vocational education (CVTE) seats in the Commonwealth is a good start, but more should be done to eliminate the 8,100-seat shortage of CVTE seats, according to a new study published by Pioneer Institute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/study-calls-for-expanding-access-to-career-vocational-technical-education-acute-shortage-in-gateway-cities/"&gt;Study Calls for Expanding Access to Career Vocational Technical Education&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 09:00:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Mackinac Center sends second demand letter to jobs agency</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/mackinac-center-sends-second-demand-letter-to-jobs-agency</link><description>Still waiting on March 5 information request to Michigan Economic Development Corp.</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Chicago could add 8,000 granny flats by following Los Angeles’ lead</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/chicago-could-add-8000-granny-flats-by-following-los-angeles-lead/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Legalizing additional dwelling units citywide would bring more housing choices, lower costs and help Chicagoans stay in the neighborhoods they love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/chicago-could-add-8000-granny-flats-by-following-los-angeles-lead/"&gt;Chicago could add 8,000 granny flats by following Los Angeles’ lead&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 10:00:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] Franke: and Government Power</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/09/franke-and-government-power/</link><description>by Mark Franke Sept.&amp;#160;19 is Constitution Day by act of Congress in 2004. It supplanted Citizenship Day which had been set for Sept.&amp;#160;19 but I can’t recall ever hearing about that growing up. Upon reflection it is a natural progression from citizenship to the Constitution, which reduces the duties and rights of citizens to writing.&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/09/franke-and-government-power/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 12:06:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/09/the-outstater-288/</link><description>Let&amp;#8217;s Fire Them for Cause GOOD JUDGMENT&amp;#160;like common sense is a trait considered too banal for this generation of human resource managers. Rather, decisions such as firing someone for justifying the assassination of a man for his opinion must involve an exercise in pearl-clutching and legalese. Thus, Ball State University&amp;#8217;s carefully worded response to a&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/09/the-outstater-288/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 13:48:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Montana is on the correct track for Medicaid reform</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/montana-is-on-the-correct-track-for-medicaid-reform</link><description>The Treasure State is taking important steps to help control the exploding costs of Medicaid while providing critical care to the...</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 14:21:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] A Statement From JMI’s President and CEO on the Assassination of Charlie Kirk</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/a-statement-from-jmis-president-and-ceo-on-the-assassination-of-charlie-kirk/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A statement from Dr. Robert McClure: A beloved husband, father, and son has been taken from his family,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/a-statement-from-jmis-president-and-ceo-on-the-assassination-of-charlie-kirk/"&gt;A Statement From JMI&amp;#8217;s President and CEO on the Assassination of Charlie Kirk&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 14:52:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] The Real DOGE is Happening in the States</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/the-real-doge-is-happening-in-the-states/</link><description>&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="2560" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/2025-Reynolds-01-scaled.jpg" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;" width="2560" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Real DOGE is Happening in the States" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/2025-Reynolds-01-400x400.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last month, I attended the State Policy Network’s annual meeting, where a panel of state leaders discussed their efforts to disentangle their states from federal government control. Among them, my state’s House Speaker Cameron Sexton discussed how the Tennessee legislature recently created a task force to study the strings attached to federal education funding. After the panel, Iowa Gov. Kim Reynolds spoke to a group about her own Department of Government Efficiency task force launched earlier this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/the-real-doge-is-happening-in-the-states/"&gt;The Real DOGE is Happening in the States&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 15:43:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF opinion piece: Progressive policies are killing Albuquerque</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-opinion-piece-progressive-policies-are-killing-albuquerque/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following appeared on September 14, 2025 in the Albuquerque Journal: This fall’s city elections are critical for the future of Albuquerque. A further shift to the left could do great harm to our city. Polling indicates that a majority of voters in Albuquerque want change, but it is critical that voters turn out not [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-opinion-piece-progressive-policies-are-killing-albuquerque/"&gt;RGF opinion piece: Progressive policies are killing Albuquerque&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 17:06:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Pioneer Institute Joins Pew Charitable Trusts in Call to Expand Housing Affordability</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/pioneer-institute-joins-pew-charitable-trusts-in-call-to-expand-housing-affordability/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Pioneer Institute is pleased to join a statement of shared principles organized by the Pew Charitable Trusts in Washington, D.C., aimed at enhancing housing availability and affordability nationwide. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/pioneer-institute-joins-pew-charitable-trusts-in-call-to-expand-housing-affordability/"&gt;Pioneer Institute Joins Pew Charitable Trusts in Call to Expand Housing Affordability&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 17:56:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Tips to Understand California’s Energy Economy</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/tips-to-understand-californias-energy-economy/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=tips-to-understand-californias-energy-economy</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Last month, for the uninitiated, we devoted a newsletter to the topic “Tips to Understand Our Convoluted Yet Obligatory Units of Water.” It attempted to summarize some essential facts and relevant units for anyone who wants to monitor state water policy. Now it’s time for those of us who fancy ourselves members of the energy...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/tips-to-understand-californias-energy-economy/"&gt;Tips to Understand California’s Energy Economy&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 20:12:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Reflecting on a Grim Week</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/reflecting-on-a-grim-week/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The past few days have been deeply unsettling. &amp;#160;The assassination of Charlie Kirk, gunned down while addressing young Americans on a Utah college campus, was horrifying. It seems clear that Charlie was targeted for his beliefs, which he expressed with remarkable clarity and conviction. Over the past decade, Charlie Kirk emerged as one of a [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/reflecting-on-a-grim-week/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Reflecting on a Grim Week&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 21:18:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Debunking ‘holding the line’ and other property tax myths</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/property-tax-myths/</link><description>Contrary to claims by some local elected officials, appraisers aren’t to blame for property tax increases. Elected officials set mill rates that determine property tax revenue for cities, counties, school districts, and other taxing authorities, and they alone are responsible for property tax hikes. Elected officials overseeing 62% of all local taxing authorities dropped mill [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 21:38:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Hawaii Legislature sued over ‘blank’ bills</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/09/hawaii-legislature-sued-over-blank-bills/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I’m pleased that the League of Women Voters of Hawaii has filed a lawsuit intended to stop so-called blankety-blank bills from being introduced at the Hawaii State Legislature. Blankety-blank bills, which I’ve&amp;#160;criticized&amp;#160;before, have broad and vague titles such as “Relating to government” or “Relating to taxation,” and they contain no actual content at all, other [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/09/hawaii-legislature-sued-over-blank-bills/"&gt;Hawaii Legislature sued over &amp;#8216;blank&amp;#8217; bills&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 02:52:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Some on the left sound alarm about reaction to Kirk’s death</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/some-on-the-left-sound-alarm-about-reaction-to-kirks-death/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Nick Arama writes for RedState.com about an interesting analysis of the response to Charlie Kirk’s assassination. This past week brought us a lot of troubling news. Not just the assassination of Turning Point USA co-founder Charlie Kirk, but the disturbing reaction to it by some on the left, cheering his death. How could anyone be...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/some-on-the-left-sound-alarm-about-reaction-to-kirks-death/"&gt;Some on the left sound alarm about reaction to Kirk’s death&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 09:42:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] $3.3B in road funds sit idle, yet Illinois drivers face record-high gas taxes</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/3-3b-in-road-funds-sit-idle-yet-illinois-drivers-face-record-high-gas-taxes/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;If Illinois state lawmakers are not going to spend the $3.3 billion sitting in the state’s road fund, drivers should get a break from the taxes going into it. Illinois gasoline taxes are No. 2 in the U.S.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/3-3b-in-road-funds-sit-idle-yet-illinois-drivers-face-record-high-gas-taxes/"&gt;$3.3B in road funds sit idle, yet Illinois drivers face record-high gas taxes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 10:00:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] What the Old Right Teaches us on Constitution Day</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/what-the-old-right-teaches-us-on-constitution-day/</link><description>&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1700" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/AdobeStock_2098174-scaled.jpeg" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;" width="2560" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="What the Old Right Teaches us on Constitution Day  " src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/AdobeStock_2098174-500x332.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conservatives of the 1920s viewed the Constitution as the enduring foundation of American liberty, emphasizing limited government, federalism, and the need to preserve timeless principles rather than treat the document as obsolete. They rejected the progressive notion of a “living Constitution,” instead describing it as an anchor—flexible through amendment, but grounded in unchanging truths and rooted in prudence. These conservatives believed Americans have a duty to safeguard the Constitution. Through education, civic responsibility, and vigilance against drift, liberty can be protected for future generations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/what-the-old-right-teaches-us-on-constitution-day/"&gt;What the Old Right Teaches us on Constitution Day  &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 12:58:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] An open letter to the Union Township Planning Commission</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/an-open-letter-to-the-union-township-planning-commission</link><description>Census Bureau did not exclude students from population count</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] What is the Instructional Support Levy (ISL)?</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/what-is-the-instructional-support-levy-isl/</link><description>&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="630" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/wilton-csd.jpg" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="What is the Instructional Support Levy (ISL)?" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/wilton-csd-600x315.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Instructional Support Levy (ISL) is one of the main tools available to Iowa school districts to supplement state funding for educational programs. While the state sets limits on how much can be spent per student, the ISL provides districts with a way to go beyond that cap—funding additional staff, classroom resources, and other instructional needs. Because the levy can significantly affect local property taxes and school budgets, it is important for school board members, parents, and community members to understand how it works and how it is implemented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/what-is-the-instructional-support-levy-isl/"&gt;What is the Instructional Support Levy (ISL)?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 14:15:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Medicaid Asset Protection Trusts: When asset protection becomes taxpayer exploitation</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/medicaid-asset-protection-trusts-when-asset-protection-becomes-taxpayer-exploitation/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Medicaid Asset Protection Trusts (MAPTs) are increasingly being used by affluent families to shield wealth and shift the cost of long-term care onto taxpayers. Instead of drawing down their resources, households with substantial assets can qualify for Medicaid-funded nursing home care, preserving estates that run into the millions. Long-term care is undeniably expensive, but Medicaid...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/medicaid-asset-protection-trusts-when-asset-protection-becomes-taxpayer-exploitation/"&gt;Medicaid Asset Protection Trusts: When asset protection becomes taxpayer exploitation&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 14:25:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] AI bills in Michigan House follow heavy-handed and punitive regulatory approach</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/ai-bills-in-michigan-house-follow-heavy-handed-and-punitive-regulatory-approach</link><description>‘Regulations born of fear threaten to derail beneficial innovation’</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 15:16:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] The Rise of Equitable Grading with Adam Tyner</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/education/the-rise-of-equitable-grading-with-adam-tyner/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Susan Pendergrass speaks with Adam Tyner, national research director at the Thomas B. Fordham Institute, about his new report, “Equitable” [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/education/the-rise-of-equitable-grading-with-adam-tyner/"&gt;The Rise of Equitable Grading with Adam Tyner&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 15:22:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] The PRI All Stars 2025 End of Session Wrap Up</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/the-pri-all-stars-2025-end-of-session-wrap-up/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This week, we present our annual end of session look back at the just-concluded legislative session. Steven Greenhut, Matt Fleming and Tim Anaya share their thoughts on the hot issues debated in the final weeks of the legislative session, including the cap-and-trade deal, high-speed rail funding, charter school legislation, housing policy and more. Plus, they [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/the-pri-all-stars-2025-end-of-session-wrap-up/"&gt;The PRI All Stars 2025 End of Session Wrap Up&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 16:06:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] The Erosion of Parental Trust and Responsibility in America</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/education/the-erosion-of-parental-trust-and-responsibility-in-america/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In an era where parenting is more scrutinized than ever, the United States appears to be undergoing a subtle yet profound shift: diminishing confidence in parents’ ability to raise their children effectively. This erosion manifests across key domains—education, online safety in the digital age, and juvenile crime—where state legislatures are increasingly intervening with laws that...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/education/the-erosion-of-parental-trust-and-responsibility-in-america/"&gt;The Erosion of Parental Trust and Responsibility in America&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 17:03:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Parents deserve straight answers. That is why I built Lone Star Ledger</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/parents-deserve-straight-answers-that-is-why-i-built-lone-star-ledger/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Is my kid doing OK in school? This simple question should not require a degree in data science. When a mom or dad asks whether their child is on track in reading and math, the answer should be one click away. In Texas, it is not. Key facts are scattered across state portals and long...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/parents-deserve-straight-answers-that-is-why-i-built-lone-star-ledger/"&gt;Parents deserve straight answers. That is why I built Lone Star Ledger&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 18:11:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Tennessee Lands Another Nuclear Project</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/energy/tennessee-lands-another-nuclear-project/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I really love my hometown of Clinton in East Tennessee. It’s a beautiful place where I grew up, went to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/energy/tennessee-lands-another-nuclear-project/"&gt;Tennessee Lands Another Nuclear Project&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 18:23:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Vaporizing Censorship at the Oregon Supreme Court</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/vaporizing-censorship-at-the-oregon-supreme-court/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Paul Bates faced a real pickle: the products at his Oregon vape shop were perfectly legal to sell, but for..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/vaporizing-censorship-at-the-oregon-supreme-court/"&gt;Vaporizing Censorship at the Oregon Supreme Court&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 18:35:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] The illicit trade in weight-loss drugs deserves a crackdown</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/the-illicit-trade-in-weight-loss-drugs-deserves-a-crackdown/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The market for illicit weight-loss drugs is booming in plain sight. Law enforcement officials will have no choice but to act soon. In July, telehealth firm Hims &amp;#38; Hers was hit with a securities lawsuit alleging that the company sold unapproved knock-off compounded versions of Wegovy in violation of its agreement with the drug’s developer, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/the-illicit-trade-in-weight-loss-drugs-deserves-a-crackdown/"&gt;The illicit trade in weight-loss drugs deserves a crackdown&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 18:39:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] SCOTUS Appeal Challenges Union Efforts to Stifle Opt-outs</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/press-release/scotus-appeal-challenges-union-efforts-to-stifle-opt-outs/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Freedom Foundation has filed its most recent petition for certiorari review at the United States Supreme Court, asking the justices to answer a critical First Amendment question: Do public employees have the right to leave their union?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/press-release/scotus-appeal-challenges-union-efforts-to-stifle-opt-outs/" rel="nofollow"&gt;SCOTUS Appeal Challenges Union Efforts to Stifle Opt-outs&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 18:41:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] America Can’t Tariff Its Way to a Manufacturing Boom</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/america-cant-tariff-its-way-to-a-manufacturing-boom/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;President Trump very recently signed an executive order exempting a range of products from his proposed tariffs, including some pharmaceuticals. One day prior, he issued an order exempting generic pharmaceuticals from Japan from tariffs. It&amp;#8217;s encouraging news, to be sure &amp;#8212; particularly for American patients. But policies which shield vital products such as medicines from [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/america-cant-tariff-its-way-to-a-manufacturing-boom/"&gt;America Can&amp;#8217;t Tariff Its Way to a Manufacturing Boom&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 18:51:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Why NC’s Third Provincial Congress matters to the Revolution</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/why-ncs-third-provincial-congress-matters-to-the-revolution/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I went to Hillsborough on a recent Saturday for a day of Patriotic frivolity (including tricorn hats, tents, Revolutionary-era clothes, children’s activities, and a colonial market) and to view a dramatization of the meeting of North Carolina’s Third Provincial Congress, which met from Aug. 20 to Sept. 10, 1775. The well-done dramatization in Hillsborough’s old...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/why-ncs-third-provincial-congress-matters-to-the-revolution/"&gt;Why NC’s Third Provincial Congress matters to the Revolution&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 19:23:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] THIRD-TERM TIM?! Breaking Poll Raises Questions</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/third-term-tim-breaking-polling-raises-questions/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Grace and Kathryn are once again joined by Bill Walsh to STOP THE TAPE on Walz&amp;#8217;s third term announcement. From exaggerations, to inflated stats, to flat out lies, Grace, Kathryn, and Bill correct the record for the Governor. Then the three of them break some news with our latest Thinking Minnesota Poll showing Minnesotans are...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/third-term-tim-breaking-polling-raises-questions/"&gt;THIRD-TERM TIM?! Breaking Poll Raises Questions&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 19:51:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] How Nebraska Can Improve Truth-in-Taxation: Lessons from Utah’s Property Tax Reform</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/how-nebraska-can-improve-truth-in-taxation-lessons-from-utahs-property-tax-reform/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Utah passed the nation’s first Truth-in-Taxation (TNT) law in 1985, giving the Beehive State 40 years to refine and finesse their property tax program.   Nebraska has adopted a similar law which can be improved by adjusting the schedule for when Truth-in-Taxation hearings occur so that the TNT process precedes budget adoption.  Utah’s tax transparency procedure...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/how-nebraska-can-improve-truth-in-taxation-lessons-from-utahs-property-tax-reform/" rel="nofollow"&gt;How Nebraska Can Improve Truth-in-Taxation: Lessons from Utah’s Property Tax Reform&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 19:55:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] The Taxman Cometh: City of Kyle</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/the-taxman-cometh-city-of-kyle/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Most city, county, and school district officials are right now in the process of adopting budgets and determining tax rates for the next fiscal year. In some cases, these local decisions will increase the cost of government and put upward pressure on property tax bills. In a few cases, local government action will cause tax...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/the-taxman-cometh-city-of-kyle/"&gt;The Taxman Cometh: City of Kyle&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 20:01:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Poll: Fraud top of mind as voters consider third term for Gov. Tim Walz</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/poll-fraud-top-of-mind-as-voters-consider-third-term-for-gov-tim-walz/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As Gov. Tim Walz announces his intentions to seek a rare third term, he would be wise to prepare an explanation for the fraud that occurred in state agencies under his watch. That’s because 56 percent of respondents to the latest&amp;#160;Thinking Minnesota&amp;#160;Poll don’t think he’s done enough to prevent fraud in Minnesota.&amp;#160; Worse yet for...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/poll-fraud-top-of-mind-as-voters-consider-third-term-for-gov-tim-walz/"&gt;Poll: Fraud top of mind as voters consider third term for Gov. Tim Walz&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 20:27:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] First Principles Series: Worker Freedom</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/first-principles-series-worker-freedom/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=first-principles-series-worker-freedom</link><description>More and more people are relocating to Tennessee to live and work and fleeing states that refuse to protect their freedoms, like California, Illinois, and New York.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 20:31:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] OHIO: 610 opt-outs in July and August</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/ohio-610-opt-outs-in-july-and-august/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In July and August alone, 610 Ohio public employees made the bold choice to walk away from union control — reclaiming their paychecks, their rights and their freedom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/ohio-610-opt-outs-in-july-and-august/" rel="nofollow"&gt;OHIO: 610 opt-outs in July and August&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 20:56:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] How Minnesota lawmakers disappointed the office of the Dalai Lama</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/how-minnesota-lawmakers-disappointed-the-office-of-the-dalai-lama/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In March of 2025, Namgyal Choedup, the Dalai Lama’s North American envoy, wrote a letter to Minnesota’s state legislature, pleading for their support.&amp;#160; Choedup’s plea to lawmakers came amidst a powerful Minnesotan-Tibetan relationship. The Tibetan community in Minnesota is one of the largest Tibetan communities in the United States. Indeed, Minnesota is home to a...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/how-minnesota-lawmakers-disappointed-the-office-of-the-dalai-lama/"&gt;How Minnesota lawmakers disappointed the office of the Dalai Lama&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 21:30:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] The Shining Light on a Hill: America’s Constitution</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/the-shining-light-on-a-hill-americas-constitution/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;“If I cannot live in the land of my birth, I wish to live in America, under the Constitution.” I owe my existence to this sentiment, uttered by my great-grandfather, a Czech who escaped Soviet rule. I never met him, but I know his story: When he realized that he could not raise his children...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/the-shining-light-on-a-hill-americas-constitution/"&gt;The Shining Light on a Hill: America’s Constitution&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 21:58:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Peoria Heights mayor vetoes grocery tax as Chicago considers it</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/peoria-heights-mayor-vetoes-grocery-tax-as-chicago-considers-it/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Peoria Heights’ mayor vetoed a grocery tax, saying the village would not balance its budget on the backs of families at the grocery checkout. Now Chicago is considering taking $73.5 million through the tax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/peoria-heights-mayor-vetoes-grocery-tax-as-chicago-considers-it/"&gt;Peoria Heights mayor vetoes grocery tax as Chicago considers it&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 22:15:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Fact-Checking Newsom’s ‘Clean Energy’ Claims</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/newsoms-clean-energy/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=newsoms-clean-energy</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In a recent guest op-ed published by the Wall Street Journal, California Governor Newsom claimed that “Clean Energy Powers California’s Economic Growth,” a claim that is transparently false. Aggressive “clean energy” mandates, paired with perpetually escalating restrictions on conventional energy sources, are the reasons Californians pay the highest prices in America for gasoline and electricity, and nearly the highest...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/newsoms-clean-energy/"&gt;Fact-Checking Newsom’s ‘Clean Energy’ Claims&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 22:32:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Rebekah Staples: Work Work Work</title><link>https://empowerms.org/rebekah-staples-work-work-work/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Rebekah Staples: Work Work Work More than just a paycheck, work is the foundation of prosperity and the pathway to earned success. This week, host Grant Callen sits down with Rebekah Staples President &amp;#38; Founder of Free State Strategies and a Contributing Fellow at Empower Mississippi. Hailing from The Free State of Jones (County), Rebekah&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/rebekah-staples-work-work-work/"&gt;Rebekah Staples: Work Work Work&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 23:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] The Reading Crisis: Why Illiteracy Threatens California’s Future and What We Can Do Now</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/the-reading-crisis-why-illiteracy-threatens-californias-future-and-what-we-can-do-now/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=the-reading-crisis-why-illiteracy-threatens-californias-future-and-what-we-can-do-now</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The 2024 National Assessment of Educational Progress (NAEP) results for Grade 12 reading are out — and the numbers are grim. Only a staggering 35 percent of high school seniors nationwide were proficient in reading. Nearly one in three graduates struggles to draw basic conclusions from a text, a skill essential for everything from voting to...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/the-reading-crisis-why-illiteracy-threatens-californias-future-and-what-we-can-do-now/"&gt;The Reading Crisis: Why Illiteracy Threatens California’s Future and What We Can Do Now&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 23:09:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] The Political Bait and Switch: When Promises Become Propaganda</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/the-political-bait-and-switch-when-promises-become-propaganda/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/the-political-bait-and-switch-when-promises-become-propaganda/" rel="nofollow" title="The Political Bait and Switch: When Promises Become Propaganda   "&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Article-Headers-2025-09-16T164920.750.png" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Imagine there’s a business you are looking to invest in. The businessman pitches you a compelling plan, explains how your money will be used, and promises long-term returns. You cut them a check and leave them to their work, excited for the future. A month later, you check in — only to find the original [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 23:12:02 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>