<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>State-Policy Think-Tank Digest</title><link>https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml</link><description>Latest posts from free-market policy institutes across the U.S.</description><atom:link href="https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 14:03:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>[Mspolicy] Mississippi's Progress and the Push for School Choice</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/mississippis-progress-and-the-push-for-school-choice/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This week, I’ll be traveling to Washington, D.C. talking about Mississippi’s remarkable progress, including our elimination of the income tax and how we might best advance school choice in our state. Mississippi is gaining national attention for our transformative public policies. Once seen as a perennial underdog, our state is now recognized as a leader in free-market [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/mississippis-progress-and-the-push-for-school-choice/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi&amp;#039;s Progress and the Push for School Choice&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 17:09:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] Commonwealth Foundation Urges Legal Protection of State’s Rainy Day Fund</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/09/08/commonwealth-foundation-urges-legal-protection-of-states-rainy-day-fund/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Letter calls on Treasurer Garrity to withhold any transfer from the budget stabilization reserve fund, pending legal adjudication. Harrisburg, Pa., September 8, 2025 — Today, the Commonwealth Foundation sent a letter to leaders of the General Assembly and Pennsylvania State Treasurer Stacy Garrity, urging the legal protection of the commonwealth’s Rainy Day Fund. Gov. Josh [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/09/08/commonwealth-foundation-urges-legal-protection-of-states-rainy-day-fund/"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation Urges Legal Protection of State&amp;#8217;s Rainy Day Fund&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 15:28:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] National Poverty Rate Fails to Capture the Problem of Poverty Concentration in Georgia and Beyond</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/press-release-poverty-rate-2024/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/press-release-poverty-rate-2024/"&gt;National Poverty Rate Fails to Capture the Problem of Poverty Concentration in Georgia and Beyond&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 18:26:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Virginiainstitute] In memory of Charlie Kirk (1993-2025)</title><link>https://virginiainstitute.org/in-memory-of-charlie-kirk-1993-2025/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=in-memory-of-charlie-kirk-1993-2025</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Virginia Institute for Public Policy tonight remembers Charlie Kirk, his beautiful wife Erika, and his young daughter and son who will grow up without a father&amp;#8217;s loving care and&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org/in-memory-of-charlie-kirk-1993-2025/"&gt;In memory of Charlie Kirk (1993-2025)&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org"&gt;Virginia Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 02:59:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Virginiainstitute] Press Release – Coalition Applauds Executive Order 53</title><link>https://virginiainstitute.org/press-release-coalition-applauds-executive-order-53/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=press-release-coalition-applauds-executive-order-53</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Summary Virginia Fair Elections (VFE), a coalition committed to ensuring transparent and secure elections in Virginia, has publicly praised Governor Glenn Youngkin’s Executive Order 53, issued on September 12, 2025.&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org/press-release-coalition-applauds-executive-order-53/"&gt;Press Release – Coalition Applauds Executive Order 53&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org"&gt;Virginia Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 16:17:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Join us in reviving the free exchange of ideas in New Hampshire</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/09/join-us-in-reviving-the-free-exchange-of-ideas-in-new-hampshire/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On September 9, the Foundation for Individual Rights and Expression (FIRE) released its 2026 campus free speech rankings, concluding that “America’s colleges get an ‘F’ for poor free speech climate.”  “More students than ever think violence and chaos are acceptable alternatives to peaceful protest,” FIRE Chief Research Advisor Sean Stevens said on the report’s release. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/09/join-us-in-reviving-the-free-exchange-of-ideas-in-new-hampshire/"&gt;Join us in reviving the free exchange of ideas in New Hampshire&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 20:08:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Mahomes Can’t Evade New York’s Licensing Blitz</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/mahomes-cant-evade-new-yorks-licensing-blitz/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The National Football League kicked off its new season this month and fans tuning in to television broadcasts this fall....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/mahomes-cant-evade-new-yorks-licensing-blitz/"&gt;Mahomes Can&amp;#8217;t Evade New York&amp;#8217;s Licensing Blitz&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 11:56:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Reflecting on a Grim Week</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/reflecting-on-a-grim-week/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The past few days have been deeply unsettling. &amp;#160;The assassination of Charlie Kirk, gunned down while addressing young Americans on a Utah college campus, was horrifying. It seems clear that Charlie was targeted for his beliefs, which he expressed with remarkable clarity and conviction. Over the past decade, Charlie Kirk emerged as one of a [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/reflecting-on-a-grim-week/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Reflecting on a Grim Week&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 21:18:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Debunking ‘holding the line’ and other property tax myths</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/property-tax-myths/</link><description>Contrary to claims by some local elected officials, appraisers aren’t to blame for property tax increases. Elected officials set mill rates that determine property tax revenue for cities, counties, school districts, and other taxing authorities, and they alone are responsible for property tax hikes. Elected officials overseeing 62% of all local taxing authorities dropped mill [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 21:38:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] First Principles Series: Worker Freedom</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/first-principles-series-worker-freedom/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=first-principles-series-worker-freedom</link><description>More and more people are relocating to Tennessee to live and work and fleeing states that refuse to protect their freedoms, like California, Illinois, and New York.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 20:31:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Rebekah Staples: Work Work Work</title><link>https://empowerms.org/rebekah-staples-work-work-work/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Rebekah Staples: Work Work Work More than just a paycheck, work is the foundation of prosperity and the pathway to earned success. This week, host Grant Callen sits down with Rebekah Staples President &amp;#38; Founder of Free State Strategies and a Contributing Fellow at Empower Mississippi. Hailing from The Free State of Jones (County), Rebekah&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/rebekah-staples-work-work-work/"&gt;Rebekah Staples: Work Work Work&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 23:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG Court Watch Celebrates Constitution Day</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-court-watch-celebrates-constitution-day/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government (IRG) released the following statement honoring Constitution Day and the document that has guided our nation with the principles of limited government, individual liberty, and personal responsibility for more than two centuries. &amp;#160; THE QUOTE:  “Our Constitution was designed to protect the people by restraining government and [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-court-watch-celebrates-constitution-day/"&gt;IRG Court Watch Celebrates Constitution Day&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 17:38:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] GCO welcomes new team members to grow our BETTER WORK initiative</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/gco-welcomes-new-team-members/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/gco-welcomes-new-team-members/"&gt;GCO welcomes new team members to grow our BETTER WORK initiative&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 17:55:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] Charlie Kirk wasn’t killed for his politics – he was martyred for the Gospel</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/09/17/charlie-kirk-wasnt-killed-for-his-politics-he-was-martyred-for-the-gospel/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The alarming responses to the cold-blooded assassination of Charlie Kirk from both sides of the political aisle are derived from the same source: false worldview.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/09/17/charlie-kirk-wasnt-killed-for-his-politics-he-was-martyred-for-the-gospel/"&gt;Charlie Kirk wasn’t killed for his politics – he was martyred for the Gospel&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 18:51:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] In defense of murder</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/09/17/in-defense-of-murder/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The alarming responses to the cold-blooded assassination of Charlie Kirk from both sides of the political aisle are derived from the same source: false worldview.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/09/17/in-defense-of-murder/"&gt;In defense of murder&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 18:52:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG: The Real State of Education</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-the-real-state-of-education/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;IRG: The Real State of Education Wisconsin Students are Left Behind Despite Record Investment in Schools Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government (IRG) released the following statement outlining the real State of Education in Wisconsin ahead of Superintendent of Public Instruction Jill Underly’s annual State of Education Address. &amp;#160; THE REAL STATE OF [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-the-real-state-of-education/"&gt;IRG: The Real State of Education&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 13:25:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] The James Madison Institute Joins the America 250 Civics Education Coalition in Partnership With U.S. Department of Education and Over 40 National and State Organizations</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/the-james-madison-institute-joins-the-america-250-civics-education-coalition-in-partnership-with-u-s-department-of-education-and-over-40-national-and-state-organizations/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;JMI&amp;#8217;s William Mattox joined U.S. Secretary of Education Linda McMahon and the U.S. Department of Education in partnership...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/the-james-madison-institute-joins-the-america-250-civics-education-coalition-in-partnership-with-u-s-department-of-education-and-over-40-national-and-state-organizations/"&gt;The James Madison Institute Joins the America 250 Civics Education Coalition in Partnership With U.S. Department of Education and Over 40 National and State Organizations&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 17:41:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Hugh Hewitt to headline Libertas Award Dinner; Frank Edelblut to receive 2025 Libertas Award</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/09/hugh-hewitt-to-headline-libertas-award-dinner-frank-edelblut-to-receive-2025-libertas-award/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Josiah Bartlett Center for Public Policy is proud to announce our 2025 Libertas Award Dinner on Monday, Nov. 10, featuring special guest Hugh Hewitt and recognizing Frank Edelblut with our 2025 Libertas Award.  “At a time when fair, honest, and open discourse is so important for New Hampshire and the nation, we’re thrilled to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/09/hugh-hewitt-to-headline-libertas-award-dinner-frank-edelblut-to-receive-2025-libertas-award/"&gt;Hugh Hewitt to headline Libertas Award Dinner; Frank Edelblut to receive 2025 Libertas Award&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 18:31:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Kids who kill and maim</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/milwaukee-kids-who-kill-and-maim/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;And what adults who’ve lost control need to do about it Sometimes they get lucky, the many kids in Milwaukee who shoot people, and they sidestep homicide charges because their victims happen not to die. Removing luck and counting up the number of child-shooters who either killed or just wounded a victim, the numbers are [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/milwaukee-kids-who-kill-and-maim/"&gt;Kids who kill and maim&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 21:33:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] Sec. McMahon, TPUSA, AFPI, API, and Partners Launch National Civics Coalition</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/09/18/sec-mcmahon-tpusa-afpi-api-and-partners-launch-national-civics-coalition/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Department of Education (the Department), in partnership the America First Policy Institute (AFPI), Turning Point USA, Hillsdale College and more than 40 leading national and state-based organizations, today announced the launch of the America 250 Civics Education Coalition. This landmark initiative is dedicated to renewing patriotism, strengthening civic knowledge, and advancing a shared understanding of America’s founding principles in schools across the nation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/09/18/sec-mcmahon-tpusa-afpi-api-and-partners-launch-national-civics-coalition/"&gt;Sec. McMahon, TPUSA, AFPI, API, and Partners Launch National Civics Coalition&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 23:19:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Kansas Needs More Capitalism, Not Cronyism or Socialism</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/kansas-needs-more-capitalism/</link><description>Gallup recently found that just 54% of Americans now view capitalism positively, the lowest share since they began asking the question in 2010. That’s down from 60% in 2021, which is about where it has been since at least 2010. Meanwhile, 39% still view socialism positively, a number that hasn’t changed much overall but masks [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 14:00:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF president discusses elimination of federal Rail Trail Funding w/ KOAT Channel 7</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-president-discusses-elimination-of-federal-rail-trail-funding-w-koat-channel-7/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Rio Grande Foundation president Paul Gessing had a chance to sit down with KOAT to discuss the fact that the Trump Administration has eliminated $11.5 million in federal funds for the wildly overpriced Albuquerque rail trail being built in Albuquerque at the behest of the Tim Keller Administration. The canceled $11.5 million was allocated under [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-president-discusses-elimination-of-federal-rail-trail-funding-w-koat-channel-7/"&gt;RGF president discusses elimination of federal Rail Trail Funding w/ KOAT Channel 7&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 19:55:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Listen: Free Speech Issues on WGAN</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/listen-free-speech-on-wgan/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Policy analyst, Harris Van Pate, joined the WGAN Morning News to discuss Attorney General Pam Bondi&amp;#8217;s controversial comments this week regarding &amp;#8220;hate speech,&amp;#8221; as well as the free speech backlash following the temporary suspension of Jimmy Fallon&amp;#8217;s late night show. Listen below. Newsradio WGAN · Maine Policy Institute&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/listen-free-speech-on-wgan/"&gt;Listen: Free Speech Issues on WGAN&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 23:30:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Weight Loss Drugs Pack on the Fat to State Spending</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/weight-loss-drugs-pack-on-the-fat-to-state-spending/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/weight-loss-drugs-pack-on-the-fat-to-state-spending/" rel="nofollow" title="Weight Loss Drugs Pack on the Fat to State Spending"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Article-Headers-2025-09-19T163637.101.png" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Well, isn’t that generous? The Group Insurance Advisory Committee (GIAC), under the Office of Group Insurance (OGI) within the Department of Administration — ever the example of fiscal responsibility — unilaterally decided to extend the GLP-1 weight-loss drugs to the employee health benefits plan for the previous few years. But don’t worry, when it was [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 23:51:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] Franke: The ‘Rechurching’ of America</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/09/franke-the-rechurching-of-america/</link><description>by Mark Franke In unsettled times people of faith turn to prayer. This phenomenon can be seen in history, such as the number of revival meetings in American Civil War army campsites. There are no atheists in foxholes, so the saying goes. Given the constant bad news about violence and killings, it is not surprising&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/09/franke-the-rechurching-of-america/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 12:57:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] There is no ‘hate speech’ exception to the First Amendment</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/there-is-no-hate-speech-exception-to-the-first-amendment/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Last week, United States Attorney General Pam Bondi suggested that the Department of Justice under President Trump would “target” and “go after” individuals engaging in “hate speech” in response to public reactions following the tragic killing of conservative political activist Charlie Kirk.&amp;#160; Understandably, many were outraged by the celebration or mockery of Kirk’s death that [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/there-is-no-hate-speech-exception-to-the-first-amendment/"&gt;There is no &amp;#8216;hate speech&amp;#8217; exception to the First Amendment&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Orlando Sentinel: Commentary: Campus Culture Wars and the Kirk Assassination</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/orlando-sentinel-commentary-campus-culture-wars-and-the-kirk-assassination/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The tragic assassination of Charlie Kirk has already sparked a storm of finger-pointing. Some insist he was targeted...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/orlando-sentinel-commentary-campus-culture-wars-and-the-kirk-assassination/"&gt;Orlando Sentinel: Commentary: Campus Culture Wars and the Kirk Assassination&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 14:17:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] WILL Proposes Audit to Enforce Wisconsin’s Citizenship Voting Amendment</title><link>https://will-law.org/will-proposes-audit-to-enforce-wisconsins-citizenship-voting-amendment/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL unveiled a new report, “The WILL of The People: A Roadmap to Enforce Wisconsin’s Citizenship Voting Amendment,” which outlines a clear process to audit Wisconsin’s voter rolls using existing state and federal data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/will-proposes-audit-to-enforce-wisconsins-citizenship-voting-amendment/"&gt;WILL Proposes Audit to Enforce Wisconsin&amp;#8217;s Citizenship Voting Amendment&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 17:03:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] Governor Shapiro Again Blames PJM for High Energy Prices, Ignores True Culprit: His Policies</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/09/22/governor-shapiro-again-blames-pjm-for-high-energy-prices-ignores-true-culprit-his-policies/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Harrisburg, Pa., September 22, 2025 — This week, Gov. Josh Shapiro is speaking as Pennsylvania hosts PJM governors for the Multi-State Technical Conference in Philadelphia. The conference comes on the heels of rising criticism of PJM from certain governors, expressing concerns over rising electricity costs, reliability of the electric grid, and project delays. Gov. Shapiro [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/09/22/governor-shapiro-again-blames-pjm-for-high-energy-prices-ignores-true-culprit-his-policies/"&gt;Governor Shapiro Again Blames PJM for High Energy Prices, Ignores True Culprit: His Policies&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 20:11:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Oregon Energy Strategy is Doomed to Fail</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/transportation/oregon-energy-strategy-is-doomed-to-fail/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Randal O’Toole The Oregon Department of Energy “Oregon Energy Strategy” for saving...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/transportation/oregon-energy-strategy-is-doomed-to-fail/"&gt;Oregon Energy Strategy is Doomed to Fail&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 14:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] What They Make 2025</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/what-they-make-2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A total of 475 local government employees in New York (outside New York City), most of them police officers, were....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/what-they-make-2025/"&gt;What They Make 2025&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 14:25:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Freedom Wins: The Future of Education is Here</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/freedom-wins-the-future-of-education-is-here/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=freedom-wins-the-future-of-education-is-here</link><description>While the EFS success is a great reason to celebrate, there is more work to be done to unlock education freedom for all Tennesseans.</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 16:17:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Mississippi Leadership Academy Kicks Off 2025 Program with State Leaders</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/mississippi-leadership-academy-kicks-off-2025-program-with-state-leaders/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For Immediate Release Jackson, MS – September 23, 2025&amp;#160;— Students from across Mississippi gathered in Jackson on Saturday for the&amp;#160;opening session of the 2025 Mississippi Leadership Academy, a program that equips high school and college students with leadership training, civic knowledge, and direct access to state leaders. This year’s kickoff featured&amp;#160;State Auditor Shad White, Representative [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/mississippi-leadership-academy-kicks-off-2025-program-with-state-leaders/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Leadership Academy Kicks Off 2025 Program with State Leaders&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 20:50:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] We Are Charlie Kirk: The Call of a Generation</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/we-are-charlie-kirk-the-call-of-a-generation/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/we-are-charlie-kirk-the-call-of-a-generation/" rel="nofollow" title="We Are Charlie Kirk: The Call of a Generation"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Article-Headers-2.jpg" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;It’s been 13 days since one of the most influential political and religious figures of the 21st century was assassinated on a university campus in Orem, Utah. September 10, 2025, will forever be branded as one of the most significant dates in contemporary American history. It will live in infamy alongside dates such as November [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 23:28:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Testimony and Analysis: Wisconsin’s Report Cards are Far from “Fine”</title><link>https://will-law.org/testimony-and-analysis-wisconsins-report-cards-are-far-from-fine/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Will Flanders testified on DPI's continued efforts to water down standards. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/testimony-and-analysis-wisconsins-report-cards-are-far-from-fine/"&gt;Testimony and Analysis: Wisconsin&amp;#8217;s Report Cards are Far from &amp;#8220;Fine&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 13:00:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Nebraskanomics: Governor Jim Pillen on Moving Nebraska Forward</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/nebraskanomics-governor-jim-pillen-on-moving-nebraska-forward/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Tune in to the latest episode of Nebraskanomics as we welcome the 41st Governor of the State of Nebraska, Governor Jim Pillen. During the episode Governor Pillen and Platte Institute Chief Executive Officer Jim Vokal discuss how we provide property tax reform for Nebraskans, the importance of making the most of federal funds, and what’s...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/nebraskanomics-governor-jim-pillen-on-moving-nebraska-forward/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Nebraskanomics: Governor Jim Pillen on Moving Nebraska Forward&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 14:43:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Improve Education Outcomes by Removing Barriers</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/education/improve-education-outcomes-by-removing-barriers/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Kathryn Hickok The National Association of Education Progress (NAEP) annually releases a...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/education/improve-education-outcomes-by-removing-barriers/"&gt;Improve Education Outcomes by Removing Barriers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 17:12:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Ryan Walters Named CEO of the Teacher Freedom Alliance, Launching National Campaign to Challenge Teachers Unions</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/education/ryan-walters-named-ceo-of-the-teacher-freedom-alliance-launching-national-campaign-to-challenge-teachers-unions/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Oklahoma State Superintendent Ryan Walters has been named incoming Chief Executive Officer of the Teacher Freedom Alliance. He officially assumes the CEO role on October 1, 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/education/ryan-walters-named-ceo-of-the-teacher-freedom-alliance-launching-national-campaign-to-challenge-teachers-unions/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Ryan Walters Named CEO of the Teacher Freedom Alliance, Launching National Campaign to Challenge Teachers Unions &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 13:05:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Nebraska Property Taxes Keep Rising Despite Tax Caps</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-property-taxes-keep-rising-despite-tax-caps/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Nebraska’s Truth-in-Taxation season brings surprises each year, shining a light on local government tax increases. That’s because Nebraska’s Truth-in-Taxation law requires local governments to notify property owners of proposed tax increases as a prelude to public hearings about the tax proposals.  Residents of Omaha were hit with another set of unsustainable tax increases in 2025, as...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-property-taxes-keep-rising-despite-tax-caps/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Nebraska Property Taxes Keep Rising Despite Tax Caps&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 15:30:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF in National Review: Take It from Albuquerque: Free Transit Is a Bad Idea</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-in-national-review-take-it-from-albuquerque-free-transit-is-a-bad-idea/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following appeared at National Review on September 25, 2025. Zohran Mamdani should get the hint and scrap his proposal for New York City. The cities of Albuquerque and New York don’t have a great deal in common. One is a densely packed East Coast metropolis, while the other is a relatively spread out (and much [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-in-national-review-take-it-from-albuquerque-free-transit-is-a-bad-idea/"&gt;RGF in National Review: Take It from Albuquerque: Free Transit Is a Bad Idea&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 16:44:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Study Rates Every State’s Telehealth Laws for Patient Access and Ease of Providing Services</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/healthcare/study-rates-every-states-telehealth-laws-for-patient-access-and-ease-of-providing-services-2/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Los Angeles (Jan. 5, 2022) — A new report from Reason Foundation, Cicero Institute and Pioneer Institute rates every state’s telehealth policy for patient access and ease of providing virtual care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/healthcare/study-rates-every-states-telehealth-laws-for-patient-access-and-ease-of-providing-services-2/"&gt;Study Rates Every State’s Telehealth Laws for Patient Access and Ease of Providing Services&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 17:01:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Statement of Pioneer Institute on Board Member Mike Kennealy’s Bid for Governor</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/transparency/statement-of-pioneer-institute-on-board-member-mike-kennealys-bid-for-governor/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This statement was released on April 15, 2025. BOSTON – Congratulations to Mike Kennealy on his decision to run for Governor of Massachusetts. Mike has served as a thoughtful and deeply engaged member of Pioneer Institute’s board since 2023. We are grateful for his contributions and his commitment to the Commonwealth. Pioneer is an independent, non-partisan think tank with offices in Boston and Washington, D.C. Our work is grounded in four policy areas essential to human potential: K–12 education, healthcare, economic opportunity, and American civic values. These issues are especially vital in Massachusetts—a state whose success depends on attracting talent and capital. Innovation has always come from the states, and democracy depends on citizens who bring ideas, commitment, and a spirit [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/transparency/statement-of-pioneer-institute-on-board-member-mike-kennealys-bid-for-governor/"&gt;Statement of Pioneer Institute on Board Member Mike Kennealy’s Bid for Governor&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 17:14:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] Test Scores Changes Backfire on Education Establishment</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/test-scores-changes-backfire-on-education-establishment/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Test Scores Changes Backfire on Education Establishment Test score changes display widening gaps Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government (IRG) released the following statement following the release of Forward Exam and ACT test scores on Thursday showing mixed performance of K-12 schools in Wisconsin.  WHAT HAPPENED: Under Superintendent of Public Instruction Jill Underly’s [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/test-scores-changes-backfire-on-education-establishment/"&gt;Test Scores Changes Backfire on Education Establishment&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 17:52:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Leveraging Lagniappe: How Can Louisiana Make the Most of Leftover BEAD Funding?</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/leveraging-lagniappe-how-can-louisiana-make-the-most-of-leftover-bead-funding/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When the Trump administration announced modified regulations for the federal Broadband Equity Access and Deployment program (BEAD) program and a requirement that states conduct a new “Benefit of the Bargain” round of projects, broadband offices around the country were put on high alert. After a multi-year approval process to receive funding from the massive program,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/leveraging-lagniappe-how-can-louisiana-make-the-most-of-leftover-bead-funding/"&gt;Leveraging Lagniappe: How Can Louisiana Make the Most of Leftover BEAD Funding?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 18:12:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Overwhelming demand for choice schools in Milwaukee drives massive philanthropy and big builds</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/overwhelming-demand-for-choice-schools-in-milwaukee-drives-massive-philanthropy-and-big-builds/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A family’s huge bet on bettering the lives of thousands of Milwaukee children is moving a step closer to launch as St. Augustine Preparatory School starts taking names for its $104 million north campus in Glendale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/overwhelming-demand-for-choice-schools-in-milwaukee-drives-massive-philanthropy-and-big-builds/"&gt;Overwhelming demand for choice schools in Milwaukee drives massive philanthropy and big builds&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 21:40:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Village’s hostility chases out restaurateur who bought derelict Door County resort</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/villages-hostility-chases-out-restaurateur-who-bought-derelict-door-county-resort/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;After a storm of controversy surrounding the old Egg Harbor property, the owner of the Alpine Resort no longer thinks it’s “worth it” to make his home among such neighbors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/villages-hostility-chases-out-restaurateur-who-bought-derelict-door-county-resort/"&gt;Village’s hostility chases out restaurateur who bought derelict Door County resort&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 21:40:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Cost containment needed on rail, Aloha Stadium, Kent tells Hamada</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/09/cost-containment-needed-on-rail-aloha-stadium-kent-tells-hamada/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii Executive Vice President Joe Kent discussed the Honolulu rail project, the construction of a new Aloha Stadium and the rebuilding of Lahaina this week on “The Rick Hamada Program” on KHVH radio. Kent and host Rick Hamada agreed that costs must be contained on the two Oahu projects and things need [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/09/cost-containment-needed-on-rail-aloha-stadium-kent-tells-hamada/"&gt;Cost containment needed on rail, Aloha Stadium, Kent tells Hamada&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 01:55:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] The ‘I do not care about your economics’ approach to housing</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/09/the-i-do-not-care-about-your-economics-approach-to-housing/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;With a single heated remark to a developer, a Portsmouth Planning Board member last week showed exactly how the municipal development process is broken. Developer Mark McNabb has proposed converting a property he owns on Congress Street to a 125-unit co-living apartment building. Co-living units, once common, were zoned nearly out of existence in U.S. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/09/the-i-do-not-care-about-your-economics-approach-to-housing/"&gt;The &amp;#8216;I do not care about your economics&amp;#8217; approach to housing&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 13:47:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] The Business Case for Second Chance Hiring</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/opportunity-policy/the-business-case-for-second-chance-hiring/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Louisiana faces no shortage of economic challenges—from persistent poverty to low labor force participation. At the same time, our state has had one of the highest incarceration rates in the country. As men and women return home from prison, they encounter one of the greatest barriers to rebuilding their lives: finding a job. This is...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/opportunity-policy/the-business-case-for-second-chance-hiring/"&gt;The Business Case for Second Chance Hiring&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 16:23:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/09/the-outstater-290/</link><description>I.U. and the &amp;#8216;Stupid Stuff&amp;#8217; “We can require public universities to return to strong and mandatory core curricula, which challenges students to think, brings them together around shared knowledge and ideas and prepares them for lives as productive and engaged citizens.&amp;#8221; — Andrea Neal in &amp;#8220;Indiana Mandate: A Return to Founding Principles.&amp;#8221; GIVE SOME CREDIT&amp;#160;to&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/09/the-outstater-290/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 17:02:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Week in Review: Fired by DEI</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-fired-by-dei/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When Dr. Tabia Lee was hired by De Anza College to lead its Office of Equity, Social Justice, and Multicultural..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-fired-by-dei/"&gt;Week in Review: Fired by DEI&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 17:19:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Connecticut Families Deserve a Tax Credit for Education — Not Just Athletics</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/09/26/connecticut-families-deserve-a-tax-credit-for-education-not-just-athletics/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="630" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/universal_social_thumbnail.png" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connecticut made national news this month with a policy first: creating a $5 million state tax credit program to incentivize donations to a university athletics department. Supporters are quick to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/09/26/connecticut-families-deserve-a-tax-credit-for-education-not-just-athletics/"&gt;Connecticut Families Deserve a Tax Credit for Education — Not Just Athletics&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 17:20:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Idaho’s Parental Choice Tax Credit Is Constitutional</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/idahos-parental-choice-tax-credit-is-constitutional/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/idahos-parental-choice-tax-credit-is-constitutional/" rel="nofollow" title="Idaho’s Parental Choice Tax Credit Is Constitutional"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Article-Headers-2025-09-26T132715.417.png" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;A coalition of Leftist activists, including the Idaho Education Association, the Moscow School District, and Rep. Stephanie Mickelsen (R), has filed a challenge to block the implementation of Idaho’s parental choice tax credit. However, petitioners’ frivolous claims lack any basis in either our state constitution or Idaho Supreme Court precedent. Idaho’s school choice program is [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 19:54:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Iowa’s Quiet Conservative: Senate Majority Leader Jack Whitver</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/iowas-quiet-conservative-senate-majority-leader-jack-whitver-2/</link><description>&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="750" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/Whitver2.jpg" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;" width="1125" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Iowa’s Quiet Conservative: Senate Majority Leader Jack Whitver" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/Whitver2-600x400.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Describing his policy objectives, Senator Whitver has said, “In one sentence, here’s the plan: cut taxes, control spending, reform government, and let Iowans be great.” In 2024, Governing magazine honored Iowa Governor Kim Reynolds as “Public Official of the Year” for her numerous policy achievements — including historic tax reform, parental choice in education, state government reform, and defending traditional values. For two years, the CATO Institute honored Governor Reynolds as the most fiscally conservative governor in the nation. Perhaps her most-significant award has come from voters, who expanded Republican majorities in state government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/iowas-quiet-conservative-senate-majority-leader-jack-whitver-2/"&gt;Iowa’s Quiet Conservative: Senate Majority Leader Jack Whitver&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 15:37:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] The James Madison Institute Releases Latest JMI Poll of Florida Voters</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/the-james-madison-institute-releases-latest-jmi-poll-of-florida-voters/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE&amp;#160; September 29, 2025 Contact&amp;#160; Logan Elizabeth Padgett 850-386-3131 lpadgett@jamesmadison.org&amp;#160; The James Madison Institute Releases Latest...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/the-james-madison-institute-releases-latest-jmi-poll-of-florida-voters/"&gt;The James Madison Institute Releases Latest JMI Poll of Florida Voters&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] McGowan: Fatherhood — Tussling With the WSJ</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/09/mcgowan-fatherhood-tussling-with-the-wsj/</link><description>by Richard McGowan, Ph.D. My experience with the Wall Street Journal, chronicled in this column&amp;#160;a year and a half ago, showed how little awareness the paper had regarding domestic violence.&amp;#160;My recent experience with the newspaper&amp;#160;shows how much improvement the WSJ and United States could make in order to promote equality among the individuals in our&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/09/mcgowan-fatherhood-tussling-with-the-wsj/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 12:49:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Washington’s digital ad tax is unwise, discriminatory and illegal</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/washington-s-digital-ad-tax-is-unwise-discriminatory-and-illegal</link><description>Idaho’s top real estate agents are not cashing commissions in Boise—they’re writing tax laws in Olympia. Washington legislators keep...</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 14:27:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Gavin Newsom: California’s Censor</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/gavin-newsom-californias-censor/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=gavin-newsom-californias-censor</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Any Governor Gavin Newsom appearance ought to come labeled with one of California’s infamous Prop 65 warning labels. Like many politicians, you can count on Newsom to say precisely the opposite of what’s true. In that sense, he’s like a compass that always points to true south. He is invariable in his wrongness. That’s why...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/gavin-newsom-californias-censor/"&gt;Gavin Newsom: California’s Censor&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 15:49:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] The Silent Decline of Hillcrest Christian School: When Private Doesn’t Mean Privileged</title><link>https://empowerms.org/the-silent-decline-of-hillcrest-christian-school-when-private-doesnt-mean-privileged/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In the heart of Mississippi sits Hillcrest Christian School, a beacon of faith-based education serving predominantly African-American students in south Jackson. Once bustling with 1,200 students, today the halls echo with just over 200 enrolled children. This steep decline is more than just numbers—it’s a story of a community at risk of losing a vital&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/the-silent-decline-of-hillcrest-christian-school-when-private-doesnt-mean-privileged/"&gt;The Silent Decline of Hillcrest Christian School: When Private Doesn’t Mean Privileged&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 18:00:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] ITR Foundation Poll Finds Broad, Bipartisan Support for Taxpayer Protections</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/itr-foundation-poll-finds-broad-bipartisan-support-for-taxpayer-protections/</link><description>&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="628" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/two-percent-limit-1200x630-1.jpg" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="ITR Foundation Poll Finds Broad, Bipartisan Support for Taxpayer Protections" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/two-percent-limit-1200x630-1-600x314.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new Iowans for Tax Relief Foundation (ITRF) poll of likely general election voters in Iowa reveals overwhelming and consistent support for taxpayer safeguards, including constitutional amendments to protect against income tax hikes, and limits on property tax increases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The survey, conducted from September 22 to September 23, 2025, found that 71% of Iowans support requiring a two-thirds supermajority of the state legislature to approve any tax increases. This strong backing extends across political lines; 77% of independent voters, and 56% of democrat voters, favor this protection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/itr-foundation-poll-finds-broad-bipartisan-support-for-taxpayer-protections/"&gt;ITR Foundation Poll Finds Broad, Bipartisan Support for Taxpayer Protections&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 18:59:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] A Patchwork of Regulations Stifles Innovation and Commerce</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/a-patchwork-of-regulations-stifles-innovation-and-commerce/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Department of Justice’s recent call for public comments on state laws that significantly burden the national economy is..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/a-patchwork-of-regulations-stifles-innovation-and-commerce/"&gt;A Patchwork of Regulations Stifles Innovation and Commerce&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 19:07:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Cast your vote now for the 2025 Sawtooth Leadership Academy scholarships!</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/cast-your-vote-now-for-the-2025-sawtooth-leadership-academy-scholarships</link><description>Mountain States Policy Center is proud to announce the four finalists for the 2025 Sawtooth Leadership Academy scholarships.</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 20:41:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Connecticut’s ‘Sinkhole State’ Problem — and Why Guardrails Matter</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/09/29/connecticuts-sinkhole-state-problem-and-why-guardrails-matter/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="602" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Screenshot-2025-09-29-at-4.29.52-PM.png" width="387" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Thursday, Sept. 25, Truth in Accounting (TIA) released its annual Financial State of the States report, and once again Connecticut finds itself near the very bottom. The state earned [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/09/29/connecticuts-sinkhole-state-problem-and-why-guardrails-matter/"&gt;Connecticut’s ‘Sinkhole State’ Problem — and Why Guardrails Matter &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 20:41:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Do we really want a ‘rubber stamp’ Legislature?</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/09/do-we-really-want-a-rubber-stamp-legislature/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I’m a big fan of cooperation. My colleagues and I at the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii are always looking for opportunities to work with people from across the political spectrum toward a common goal. But this does not mean that we ignore our differences. In fact, too much agreement can sometimes cover up serious problems. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/09/do-we-really-want-a-rubber-stamp-legislature/"&gt;Do we really want a &amp;#8216;rubber stamp&amp;#8217; Legislature?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 21:06:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Grassroot testimonies during September 2025</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/09/grassroot-testimonies-during-september-2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following are testimonies submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii over the past few weeks during September 2025 for consideration by the Honolulu and Maui county councils, plus the Lanai, Maui and Molokai planning commissions: HONOLULU COUNTY COUNCIL &amp;#62;&amp;#62;&amp;#160;Bill 34 (2025)&amp;#160;—&amp;#160;“Any new tax class tiers should reflect changes in property values” &amp;#62;&amp;#62;&amp;#160;Bill 40 (2025)&amp;#160;—&amp;#160;“Longer [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/09/grassroot-testimonies-during-september-2025/"&gt;Grassroot testimonies during September 2025&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 21:40:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Long Beach Teachers Union Demands Higher Pay Amid $46M Deficit, $100M Projected Shortfall</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/long-beach-teachers-union-demands-higher-pay-amid-46m-deficit-100m-projected-shortfall/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=long-beach-teachers-union-demands-higher-pay-amid-46m-deficit-100m-projected-shortfall</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Contract negotiations in Long Beach Unified School District have been stalled for weeks, and the end is not in sight yet. The contract between the school district and the Teachers Association of Long Beach (TALB) expired in June. Union representatives and the district reached a tentative agreement that month, but in a development described as...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/long-beach-teachers-union-demands-higher-pay-amid-46m-deficit-100m-projected-shortfall/"&gt;Long Beach Teachers Union Demands Higher Pay Amid $46M Deficit, $100M Projected Shortfall&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 22:28:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Traverse City fiber network rolls out slowly and expensively</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/traverse-city-fiber-network-rolls-out-slowly-and-expensively</link><description>Taxpayers spend millions on government-run internet that is more expensive than private service</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] KSDE and the Kansas State Board of Education ignore state literacy law; will the Legislature let them get away with it?</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/ksdes-state-board-of-education-literacy-law/</link><description>Time after time, the Kansas Department of Education and the State Board of Education allow school districts to violate state laws designed to improve student outcomes, and now they’ve shamelessly done it again. The Legislature passed the Every Child Can Read Act in 2022, requiring literacy to be attained through the Science of Reading, evidence-based [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 12:15:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Why Affordable Housing is Unaffordable</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/land-use/why-affordable-housing-is-unaffordable/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Randal O’Toole Last week KGW news reported that Portland area rents are...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/land-use/why-affordable-housing-is-unaffordable/"&gt;Why Affordable Housing is Unaffordable&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 12:48:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] A lawsuit fighting ed choice could unleash tax chaos in Idaho</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/a-lawsuit-fighting-ed-choice-could-unleash-tax-chaos-in-idaho</link><description>If the courts adopt the unions’ radical theory, Idaho’s tax code could be turned upside down, creating chaos for families, uncertainty for schools, and higher costs for everyone. That’s not justice—it’s activism at its worst.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 15:00:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] De-Chartered Territory: Texas Capitol District</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/de-chartered-territory-texas-capitol-district/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The City of Austin, in its current form, is catastrophically mismanaged and does not represent the ideals of the people of Texas. Key points: Austin has failed to uphold its obligations to its citizens under the social contract. Crime, homelessness, and taxation have become untenable. In Jackson, Mississippi, where this policy has been implemented, overall...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/de-chartered-territory-texas-capitol-district/"&gt;De-Chartered Territory: Texas Capitol District&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 15:23:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Overtime Spiking in the State Police</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/09/30/overtime-spiking-in-the-state-police/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="876" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Screenshot-2025-09-25-092253-1.jpg" width="1224" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new report commissioned by Yankee Institute and the Nutmeg Research Initiative uncovers widespread overtime (OT) spiking within the Connecticut State Police that inflates pensions and imposes significant costs on [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/09/30/overtime-spiking-in-the-state-police/"&gt;Overtime Spiking in the State Police&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 15:25:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] CSEA strike has nothing to do with teachers and everything to do with politics</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/colorado/csea-strike-has-nothing-to-with-teachers-and-everything-to-do-with-politics/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The community’s real teachers will be in the classroom on Oct. 8 while the union activists, under the guise of strike, will be knocking on your doors to get you to vote followed by a picnic in the park.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/colorado/csea-strike-has-nothing-to-with-teachers-and-everything-to-do-with-politics/" rel="nofollow"&gt;CSEA strike has nothing to do with teachers and everything to do with politics&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 15:43:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Louisiana’s Top-Ten Ranking: Turning Perception into Prosperity</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/tax-budget/louisianas-top-ten-ranking-turning-perception-into-prosperity/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For the first time, Louisiana has cracked the Top 10 States for Doing Business, coming in at #9 in Area Development’s 2025 rankings. Long dismissed as an economic underperformer, Louisiana now stands shoulder to shoulder with heavyweights like Georgia, Texas, and North Carolina.  This leap signals progress, as site consultants and corporate decision-makers increasingly see...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/tax-budget/louisianas-top-ten-ranking-turning-perception-into-prosperity/"&gt;Louisiana’s Top-Ten Ranking: Turning Perception into Prosperity&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 18:22:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] The Fiscal Facts Behind School Choice with Marty Lueken</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/education/the-fiscal-facts-behind-school-choice-with-marty-lueken/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Susan Pendergrass speaks with Marty Lueken, director of EdChoice’s Fiscal Research and Education Center, about the 2025 Fiscal Fact Book. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/education/the-fiscal-facts-behind-school-choice-with-marty-lueken/"&gt;The Fiscal Facts Behind School Choice with Marty Lueken&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 18:26:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Freedom Foundation Supports Congressional Probe into NEA Retirement Scheme</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/press-release/freedom-foundation-supports-congressional-probe-into-nea-retirement-scheme/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Freedom Foundation CEO Aaron Withe today commended U.S. Rep. Tim Walberg (R-Mich.) for launching an investigation into whether the National Education Association (NEA) has been profiting at teachers' expense through questionable retirement investment arrangements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/press-release/freedom-foundation-supports-congressional-probe-into-nea-retirement-scheme/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation Supports Congressional Probe into NEA Retirement Scheme&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 19:01:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Green Means Stop</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/transportation/green-means-stop/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier this week, the City of St. Louis and the Bi-State Development Agency, better known as Metro, officially cancelled the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/transportation/green-means-stop/"&gt;Green Means Stop&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 21:47:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Jere Nash: Reconstruction in Mississippi</title><link>https://empowerms.org/jere-nash-reconstruction-in-mississippi/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Jere Nash: Reconstruction in Mississippi On this episode, host Grant Callen sits down with historian Jere Nash, a Greenville native, retired political consultant, and co-author of award-winning books. Jere’s latest work, Reconstruction in Mississippi, 1862-1877, offers a definitive look at a pivotal era. We discuss why Jere chose to explore Reconstruction, debunk common myths, and examine&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/jere-nash-reconstruction-in-mississippi/"&gt;Jere Nash: Reconstruction in Mississippi&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 22:00:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Recasting Lawrenceville as a resilient, connected community</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/recast-lawrenceville-josiah-story/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/recast-lawrenceville-josiah-story/"&gt;Recasting Lawrenceville as a resilient, connected community&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:04:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] Hours Away from Federal Government Shutdown, Pennsylvania Remains Vulnerable</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/09/30/governor-shapiros-failed-leadership-resulting-in-a-monthslong-state-budget-impasse-has-left-pennsylvanians-more-vulnerable-in-the-event-of-a-federal-shutdown/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Harrisburg, Pa., September 30, 2025 —&amp;#160;A federal government shutdown is set to begin at midnight, barring a last-minute deal.&amp;#160;For Pennsylvania residents, the commonwealth remains in a dangerously precarious position, with a looming federal shutdown overlapping with its four-month-long state budget impasse. Despite reporting that a budget deal was “very, very close” in June, Gov. Josh [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/09/30/governor-shapiros-failed-leadership-resulting-in-a-monthslong-state-budget-impasse-has-left-pennsylvanians-more-vulnerable-in-the-event-of-a-federal-shutdown/"&gt;Hours Away from Federal Government Shutdown, Pennsylvania Remains Vulnerable &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 01:50:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Why they want your money</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/why-they-want-your-money</link><description>Elected officials want an easy job, and that’s not good for the public</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Illinois superintendent pay doesn’t match performance: district consolidation could help</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/illinois-superintendent-pay-doesnt-match-performance-district-consolidation-could-help/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Superintendent salaries often do not reflect the district’s size, wealth or student performance. School district consolidation could help fix that. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/illinois-superintendent-pay-doesnt-match-performance-district-consolidation-could-help/"&gt;Illinois superintendent pay doesn’t match performance: district consolidation could help&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 10:00:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] See what your Illinois school district superintendent made in 2024</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/see-what-your-illinois-school-district-superintendent-made-in-2024/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Illinois school district superintendent pay topped out at $537,197 in 2024. See your local superintendent's salary here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/see-what-your-illinois-school-district-superintendent-made-in-2024/"&gt;See what your Illinois school district superintendent made in 2024&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 10:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Ag labor myths persist, posing challenges to reform</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/ag-labor-myths-persist-posing-challenges-to-reform/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The national average for the Adverse Effect Wage Rate (AEWR) is $17.33/hr., with individual states being held to a fluctuating rate. California’s current federally mandated AEWR is $19.75/hr., making it one of the top five highest in the nation. However, wage rates are not the only cost associated with the H-2A visa program. They are [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/ag-labor-myths-persist-posing-challenges-to-reform/"&gt;Ag labor myths persist, posing challenges to reform&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 10:00:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Let’s teach our kids why America is worth fighting for</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/lets-teach-our-kids-why-america-is-worth-fighting-for/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Education chief meets with 40+ groups as polling shows 93% of Americans think citizens lack basic civic knowledge. On Sept. 17, in Washington, D.C., a coalition of more than 40 groups gathered with U.S. Secretary of Education Linda McMahon to plan to upgrade civic and history education on the eve of America’s semiquincentennial — the 250th birthday...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/lets-teach-our-kids-why-america-is-worth-fighting-for/"&gt;Let’s teach our kids why America is worth fighting for&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 12:08:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] New Study Shows Hidden Costs of Portland’s Rent Control</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/new-study-shows-hidden-costs-of-portlands-rent-control/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Portland’s leaders sold rent control as a lifeline for struggling tenants. But a new independent economic study reveals it’s becoming a noose around the neck of the city’s homeowners, who are already shouldering rising costs across the board. The Greater Portland Board of Realtors recently released an independent study conducted by Wallace Economic Advisers that [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/new-study-shows-hidden-costs-of-portlands-rent-control/"&gt;New Study Shows Hidden Costs of Portland&amp;#8217;s Rent Control&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 12:54:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Nebraska Property Taxes Now 4th Highest Nationwide</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-property-taxes-now-4th-highest-nationwide/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Nebraska’s property taxes have risen to fourth highest in the United States, according to a 2025 study from the Tax Foundation using 2023 tax data. Illinois (1.83%) has the highest taxes as a share of home value, followed closely by New Jersey (1.77%). Following New Jersey is Connecticut (1.48%) which is only slightly higher than...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-property-taxes-now-4th-highest-nationwide/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Nebraska Property Taxes Now 4th Highest Nationwide&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 13:48:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] POLITICO: NJEA hit with lawsuit for $40M gov race spending</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/10/politico-njea-hit-with-lawsuit-for-40m-gov-race-spending/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;NJEA hit with lawsuit for $40M gov race spending The Fairness Center, a Pennsylvania-based nonprofit, is representing two teachers in [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/10/politico-njea-hit-with-lawsuit-for-40m-gov-race-spending/"&gt;POLITICO: NJEA hit with lawsuit for $40M gov race spending&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 14:24:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Iowa’s Reliance on Washington: Why a Shutdown Should Worry Us All</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/iowas-reliance-on-washington-why-a-shutdown-should-worry-us-all/</link><description>&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="723" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/AdobeStock_359303153-1.jpeg" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Iowa’s Reliance on Washington: Why a Shutdown Should Worry Us All" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/AdobeStock_359303153-1-600x362.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The federal government has officially shut down, and while the headlines focus on Washington, the real consequences are being felt here in Iowa. In Fiscal Year 2024, the State of Iowa received $13.2 billion in federal funds. Compare that to the legislature’s $9.4 billion state budget, and the picture is clear: Iowa relies heavily on Washington for many government programs. Cities collected another $545 million from the federal government just last year, adding to the dependency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/iowas-reliance-on-washington-why-a-shutdown-should-worry-us-all/"&gt;Iowa’s Reliance on Washington: Why a Shutdown Should Worry Us All&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 14:27:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] NJ 101.5: NJ teachers union leader abused $40M for failed political aspirations, lawsuit says</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/10/nj-101-5-nj-teachers-union-leader-abused-40m-for-failed-political-aspirations-lawsuit-says/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;NJ teachers union leader abused $40M for failed political aspirations, lawsuit says By Rick Rickman September 30, 2025 New Jersey [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/10/nj-101-5-nj-teachers-union-leader-abused-40m-for-failed-political-aspirations-lawsuit-says/"&gt;NJ 101.5: NJ teachers union leader abused $40M for failed political aspirations, lawsuit says&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 14:30:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] U-Ark’s Randall Woods on John Quincy Adams: Statesman of the Early Republic</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/news/u-arks-randall-woods-on-john-quincy-adams-statesman-of-the-early-republic/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In this week’s episode of The Learning Curve, co-hosts U-Arkansas Prof. Albert Cheng and Center for Public Schools’ Alisha Searcy interview Randall Woods, John A. Cooper Distinguished Professor of History at the University of Arkansas, and author of John Quincy Adams: A Man for the Whole People. Prof. Woods shares the life and career of American statesman John Quincy Adams, the “first son of the Republic,” whose upbringing in the household of John and Abigail Adams shaped his lifelong devotion to public service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/news/u-arks-randall-woods-on-john-quincy-adams-statesman-of-the-early-republic/"&gt;U-Ark&amp;#8217;s Randall Woods on John Quincy Adams: Statesman of the Early Republic&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 15:33:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Podcast: Why Free Speech Is Losing to DEI on Campus</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/podcast-why-free-speech-is-losing-to-dei-on-campus/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Nico Perrino has spent his career defending the First Amendment. As executive vice president of the Foundation for Individual Rights..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/podcast-why-free-speech-is-losing-to-dei-on-campus/"&gt;Podcast: Why Free Speech Is Losing to DEI on Campus&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 15:33:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] NJ ED REPORT: Two NJ Teachers Sue NJEA For Misusing Their Union Dues In Bid for Governor</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/10/nj-ed-report-two-nj-teachers-sue-njea-for-misusing-their-union-dues-in-bid-for-governor/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;#160; Two NJ Teachers Sue NJEA For Misusing Their Union Dues In Bid for Governor By Laura Waters  October 1, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/10/nj-ed-report-two-nj-teachers-sue-njea-for-misusing-their-union-dues-in-bid-for-governor/"&gt;NJ ED REPORT: Two NJ Teachers Sue NJEA For Misusing Their Union Dues In Bid for Governor&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 15:49:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] The Double-Edged Sword Of AI In The Classroom</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/the-double-edged-sword-of-ai-in-the-classroom/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;With the new school year started, one of the growing challenges facing students, parents, and teachers is how to address the classroom uses of AI, which has become a double-edged sword in the education process. Read the op-ed here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/the-double-edged-sword-of-ai-in-the-classroom/"&gt;The Double-Edged Sword Of AI In The Classroom&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 16:09:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Why New York’s Health Premiums Keep Going Up</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/why-new-yorks-health-premiums-keep-going-up/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New Yorkers continue to face some of the costliest health premiums in the U.S., and the insurance industry&amp;#8217;s recently finalized....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/why-new-yorks-health-premiums-keep-going-up/"&gt;Why New York&amp;#8217;s Health Premiums Keep Going Up&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 16:29:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Charlie Kirk and the rise of radical ideology in K–12 schools</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/charlie-kirk-and-the-rise-of-radical-ideology-in-k-12-schools/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The murder of Charlie Kirk has raised awareness of the danger that politicized anger and resentment pose to American society. Attention has largely focused on the internet’s role in radicalizing young people and impelling them to violent action. But this toxic impulse is not just coming from the digital world’s dark recesses or from strident...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/charlie-kirk-and-the-rise-of-radical-ideology-in-k-12-schools/"&gt;Charlie Kirk and the rise of radical ideology in K–12 schools&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 17:01:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] First Principles Series: The Importance of Protecting our First Amendment Rights</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/first-amendment-fp/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=first-amendment-fp</link><description>Beacon tirelessly advocates for the principles of liberty whether government officials like them or not. Thanks to the First Amendment, all Americans are free to do the same.</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 18:16:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Eden Prairie industrial technology teacher wins $50,000 prize</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/eden-prairie-industrial-technology-teacher-wins-50000-prize/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Eden Prairie High School hailed a beloved teacher as the winner of a national contest this Tuesday.&amp;#160; Sheila Stalberger, who teaches Intro to Woodcrafting, Intermediate Wood Custom Design, and Advanced Wood Crafting in the Industrial Technology Program at Eden Prairie High School, won the 2025 Harbor Freight Tools for Schools contest that recognizes exceptional teachers...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/eden-prairie-industrial-technology-teacher-wins-50000-prize/"&gt;Eden Prairie industrial technology teacher wins $50,000 prize&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 18:42:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Cool, Clear Water: For the Future of Texas</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/cool-clear-water-for-the-future-of-texas/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Water is critical to ensure a prosperous future for Texas. That’s a statement that virtually no one disagrees with. Water satisfies thirsty communities, fuels industry, powers next generation technologies, sustains reliable generation of electricity, and maintains the natural beauty of the state. But Texans will soon go to the polls to vote on legislation that...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/cool-clear-water-for-the-future-of-texas/"&gt;Cool, Clear Water: For the Future of Texas&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 18:51:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] Opinion piece: In New Mexico, there’s money for everything but roads</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/opinion-piece-in-new-mexico-theres-money-for-everything-but-roads/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following appeared in the Santa Fe New Mexican on September 27, 2025 (and other New Mexico papers). New Mexico is facing an increasingly dire situation on its roads. A recent Albuquerque Journal story stated that “New Mexico faces a $471.6 million gap in funding for priority projects around the state.” A total of $5.6 billion is [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/opinion-piece-in-new-mexico-theres-money-for-everything-but-roads/"&gt;Opinion piece: In New Mexico, there&amp;#8217;s money for everything but roads&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 19:30:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Accounting for Growth: Physical capital per worker, 2024</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/accounting-for-growth-physical-capital-per-worker-2024/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In our report &amp;#8220;The State of Minnesota’s Economy: 2020: A focus on economic growth,&amp;#8221; we wrote that: Per capita economic growth comes from three sources: an increase in the amount of labor provided by a given population (a higher employment rate/ratio or hours worked) [and the quality of that labor]; growth of capital per worker...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/accounting-for-growth-physical-capital-per-worker-2024/"&gt;Accounting for Growth: Physical capital per worker, 2024&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 19:34:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Trump DOT Rule Restores Equality, Ends Racial Quotas Nationwide</title><link>https://will-law.org/trump-dot-rule-restores-equality-ends-racial-quotas-nationwide/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A national litigation firm, based in Wisconsin, is preparing for multi-state legal action against state governments, including Wisconsin, as well as cities, counties, and private companies that continue to discriminate against roadbuilders, following a new rule issued by the United States Department of Transportation (DOT) suspending race and sex-based quotas within the Disadvantaged Business Enterprise (DBE) program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/trump-dot-rule-restores-equality-ends-racial-quotas-nationwide/"&gt;Trump DOT Rule Restores Equality, Ends Racial Quotas Nationwide&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 19:45:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Medicaid in Trouble?</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/medicaid/medicaid-in-trouble/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Missouri’s Medicaid enrollment numbers are telling a story, but it may not be one that the federal government wants to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/medicaid/medicaid-in-trouble/"&gt;Medicaid in Trouble?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 21:50:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] The Cost and the Upside of the “Big Gulp”</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/the-cost-and-the-upside-of-the-big-gulp/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=the-cost-and-the-upside-of-the-big-gulp</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;#160; Of all the possible ways to increase California’s water supply, nothing compares to the potential of the so-called “big gulp,” that is, the ability of new and improved water infrastructure to safely divert millions of acre feet from the Sacramento-San Joaquin Delta during high winter flows. How much water? A study published by the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/the-cost-and-the-upside-of-the-big-gulp/"&gt;The Cost and the Upside of the “Big Gulp”&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 21:59:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Military hits recruiting targets now that Biden is gone</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/military-hits-recruiting-targets-now-that-biden-is-gone/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Shawn Fleetwood of the Federalist responds to recent military recruiting numbers. America’s propaganda press have wound up with egg on their faces a few many times over the past several years. And that could not be truer than when it comes to the military recruitment crisis that helped define Joe Biden’s failed presidency. On Monday,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/military-hits-recruiting-targets-now-that-biden-is-gone/"&gt;Military hits recruiting targets now that Biden is gone&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 09:36:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Americans fear job losses, danger from AI</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/americans-fear-job-losses-danger-from-ai/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Terry Jones writes for Issues and Insights about interesting new poll data. Computer industry executives, economists, government officials and businesspeople all seem to be very high on the prospects for artificial intelligence (AI). But what about average Americans? They mostly believe AI should be feared, not embraced, the latest I&amp;#38;I/TIPP Poll shows. To kick off...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/americans-fear-job-losses-danger-from-ai/"&gt;Americans fear job losses, danger from AI&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 09:39:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Trump touts new Harvard trade schools</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/trump-touts-new-harvard-trade-schools/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Steven Nelson writes for the New York Post about the president’s response to a potential deal with the nation’s oldest university. President Trump said Tuesday that Harvard University has reached a tentative deal with his administration to restore $2.4 billion in frozen federal grants. America’s oldest college will spend about $500 million to launch and...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/trump-touts-new-harvard-trade-schools/"&gt;Trump touts new Harvard trade schools&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 09:42:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Traverse City gets in the Zone</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/traverse-city-gets-in-the-zone</link><description>World Cherry Capital’s regulatory reform is a significant step toward developing more housing</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Insurers return to California, but we’re not yet out of the woods</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/insurers-return-to-california-but-were-not-yet-out-of-the-woods/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;California’s property insurance market had been on the precipice before the massive wildfires wreaked havoc in Pacific Palisades and Altadena this year, with insurers fleeing the state following a series of costly wildfires from 2017 to 2021. January’s fires were among the worst in the state’s history, with estimated industry losses that could reach $40 [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/insurers-return-to-california-but-were-not-yet-out-of-the-woods/"&gt;Insurers return to California, but we’re not yet out of the woods&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 10:00:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Chicago misses grocery tax deadline, saving shoppers $40M</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/chicago-misses-grocery-tax-deadline-saving-shoppers-40m/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Chicago missed the Oct. 1 deadline to extend the grocery tax. Grocery shoppers will save $40 million for at least six months starting Jan. 1, 2026.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/chicago-misses-grocery-tax-deadline-saving-shoppers-40m/"&gt;Chicago misses grocery tax deadline, saving shoppers $40M&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 10:00:39 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>