<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>State-Policy Think-Tank Digest</title><link>https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml</link><description>Latest posts from free-market policy institutes across the U.S.</description><atom:link href="https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 20:14:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>[Mspolicy] HB2 – Mississippi’s School Choice Bill is Here!</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/hb2-mississippis-school-choice-bill-is-here/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Last week, House Speaker Jason White unveiled&amp;#160;HB2, the&amp;#160;Mississippi Education Freedom Act - the most exciting and ambitious advancement for school choice in our state in years, perhaps ever!&amp;#160;This comprehensive bill delivers everything supporters of parental power have long hoped for, and it aligns perfectly with President Trump’s strong commitment to education freedom.&amp;#160;This isn’t some minor [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/hb2-mississippis-school-choice-bill-is-here/" rel="nofollow"&gt;HB2 – Mississippi’s School Choice Bill is Here!&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 17:31:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] ABQ Journal opinion piece: More investigative journalism is a must</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/abq-journal-opinion-piece-more-investigative-journalism-is-a-must/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following appeared in Albuquerque Journal on January 11, 2026. The Albuquerque Journal recently made appeals on its pages for donations to increase investigative journalism efforts. Even though the Rio Grande Foundation is in direct competition for limited donor dollars, we applaud the paper for focusing attention on investigative journalism currently. The issue of investigative journalism is [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/abq-journal-opinion-piece-more-investigative-journalism-is-a-must/"&gt;ABQ Journal opinion piece: More investigative journalism is a must&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 19:54:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] ABQ Ethics Board Dismisses frivolous “sweatshirt-gate” ethics complaint made by Keller campaign against RGF’s Paul Gessing</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/abq-ethics-board-dismisses-frivolous-sweatshirt-gate-ethics-complaint-made-by-keller-campaign-against-rgfs-paul-gessing/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This afternoon in a hearing, the Albuquerque Board of Ethics (BOE) unanimously dismissed a complaint filed by Daymon Ely for the Tim Keller campaign that was made against Rio Grande Foundation president Paul Gessing. The complaint arose out of the Foundation’s reporting over the purchase and delivery of yellow hoodie sweatshirts to members of Albuquerque’s [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/abq-ethics-board-dismisses-frivolous-sweatshirt-gate-ethics-complaint-made-by-keller-campaign-against-rgfs-paul-gessing/"&gt;ABQ Ethics Board Dismisses frivolous “sweatshirt-gate” ethics complaint made by Keller campaign against RGF’s Paul Gessing&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 22:08:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cardinalinstitute] 2026 State of the State Response</title><link>https://cardinalinstitute.com/2026-state-of-the-state-response/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;2026 State of the State Response On Wednesday evening, Governor Patrick Morrisey delivered his annual State of the State address, outlining his priorities for the year ahead and offering a window into his governing philosophy. As is customary, the speech functioned as both pep rally and agenda-setting exercise. State of the state addresses tend to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com/2026-state-of-the-state-response/"&gt;2026 State of the State Response&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com"&gt;Cardinal Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 15:07:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF opinion piece: Data centers are coming: How to handle them</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-opinion-piece-data-centers-are-coming-how-to-handle-them/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following appeared in the Santa Fe New Mexican on January 10, 2026. It has appeared in several other publications as well. &amp;#160; After years of failure to land a “big fish” business for New Mexico’s economy (or effectively use the oil and gas revenues to grow the economy) Gov. Michelle Lujan Grisham, with the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-opinion-piece-data-centers-are-coming-how-to-handle-them/"&gt;RGF opinion piece: Data centers are coming: How to handle them&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 15:48:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Rifreedom] “Doc” Skoly Stepping Down as Center’s Chair to Pursue Congressional Seat</title><link>https://rifreedom.org/2026/01/doc-skoly-stepping-down-as-centers-chair-to-pursue-congressional-seat/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The  Rhode Island Center for Freedom &amp;#038; Prosperity announced today that Dr. Stephen "Doc" Skoly has stepped down as Chairman of its Board of Directors to pursue a run for the US House of Representatives in Rhode Island's second Congressional district.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org/2026/01/doc-skoly-stepping-down-as-centers-chair-to-pursue-congressional-seat/"&gt;&amp;#8220;Doc&amp;#8221; Skoly Stepping Down as Center&amp;#8217;s Chair to Pursue Congressional Seat&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org"&gt;RI Center for Freedom and Prosperity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 15:10:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Policy Pathway for Principled Tax Reform</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/policy-pathway-for-principled-tax-reform/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Policy Pathway for Principled Tax Reform outlines a framework for evaluating tax policy through the lens of sound tax principles including transparency, simplicity, stability, neutrality, and economic efficiency. The report examines Nebraska’s major tax types including property, income, and sales and offers practical, principle-based recommendations to improve affordability, competitiveness, and long-term fiscal sustainability. While designed...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/policy-pathway-for-principled-tax-reform/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Policy Pathway for Principled Tax Reform&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 19:40:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cardinalinstitute] Healthcare in West Virginia</title><link>https://cardinalinstitute.com/healthcare-in-west-virginia/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Healthcare in West Virginia Healthcare policy is complicated. These resources make it understandable. If you are trying to make sense of West Virginia’s latest healthcare debates, you are not alone. PBM regulation, PEIA’s recurring funding crises, and Certificate of Need laws all affect what care costs, where it is available, and who has choices. We [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com/healthcare-in-west-virginia/"&gt;Healthcare in West Virginia&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com"&gt;Cardinal Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 15:44:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Wisconsin Senate Passes WILL-Backed ﻿Amendment to End Tax-Veto Loopholes</title><link>https://will-law.org/wisconsin-senate-passes-will-backed-amendment-to-end-tax-veto-loopholes/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL issued a statement applauding the Wisconsin State Senate for passing Senate Joint Resolution 116 (SJR 116). This proposed amendment to the Wisconsin Constitution curbs executive overreach by prohibiting the governor from using the partial veto to create or increase taxes or fees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/wisconsin-senate-passes-will-backed-amendment-to-end-tax-veto-loopholes/"&gt;Wisconsin Senate Passes WILL-Backed ﻿Amendment to End Tax-Veto Loopholes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 17:40:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] WILL-Backed Equality Amendment ﻿On November 2026 Ballot</title><link>https://will-law.org/will-backed-equality-amendment-on-november-2026-ballot/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The “Equality Amendment,” otherwise known as Assembly Joint Resolution 102 (AJR 102) will be on the November 2026 ballot after the Wisconsin State Senate voted in favor today. The Wisconsin State Assembly passed the amendment last week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/will-backed-equality-amendment-on-november-2026-ballot/"&gt;WILL-Backed Equality Amendment ﻿On November 2026 Ballot&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 20:58:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Cascade Policy Institute is Hiring – Development Assistant</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/news/cascade-policy-institute-is-hiring-development-assistant/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;We are seeking a detail-oriented, organized, part-time Development Assistant to support Cascade Policy...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/news/cascade-policy-institute-is-hiring-development-assistant/"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute is Hiring &amp;#8211; Development Assistant&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 23:07:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Understanding welfare work requirements: new eligibility rules for SNAP and Medicaid</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/understanding-snap-and-medicaid-work-requirements/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Big changes are in process for some recipients of Medicaid and Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP or food stamps) benefits and for the state governments that administer the programs. See a breakdown of the changes and who they will actually affect. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/understanding-snap-and-medicaid-work-requirements/"&gt;Understanding welfare work requirements: new eligibility rules for SNAP and Medicaid&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 18:53:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] If You Want Parent Power, Only HB2 Will Do</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/if-you-want-parent-power-only-hb2-will-do/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past few years, Mississippi lawmakers have passed some critical conservative reforms.&amp;#160;Last year, Mississippi became the first state in America to legislate to eliminate the income tax in 40 years.&amp;#160; In 2022, we implemented flat tax reform.&amp;#160; A few years before that, we passed important labor market reforms.&amp;#160; In 2024, we reformed school funding [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/if-you-want-parent-power-only-hb2-will-do/" rel="nofollow"&gt;If You Want Parent Power, Only HB2 Will Do&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 16:09:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] A Trillion Dollar Energy Law – HB2021: Watch John Charles on PDX Real</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/environment/a-trillion-dollar-energy-law-hb2021-watch-john-charles-on-pdx-real/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;“All we want as consumers is reliable, affordable energy.” ~John A. Charles, Jr.,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/environment/a-trillion-dollar-energy-law-hb2021-watch-john-charles-on-pdx-real/"&gt;A Trillion Dollar Energy Law &amp;#8211; HB2021: Watch John Charles on PDX Real&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 00:12:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Rifreedom] MEDIA RELEASE: Center Launches Petition Calling for Affordable Energy Policies</title><link>https://rifreedom.org/2026/01/media-release-center-launches-petition-calling-for-affordable-energy-policies/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Rhode Island Center for Freedom &amp;#038; Prosperity today announced that it has launched an online petition drive calling for policymakers to support a fundamental pivot away from our state's current energy strategy, which will lead to staggeringly high electricity prices and potentially dangerous blackouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org/2026/01/media-release-center-launches-petition-calling-for-affordable-energy-policies/"&gt;MEDIA RELEASE: Center Launches Petition Calling for Affordable Energy Policies&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org"&gt;RI Center for Freedom and Prosperity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 14:19:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] California’s Drought is Over, But We Still Must Invest in Water Supply Projects</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/californias-drought-is-over-but-we-still-must-invest-in-water-supply-projects/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=californias-drought-is-over-but-we-still-must-invest-in-water-supply-projects</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For the last 25 years, the US Drought Monitor (USDM), a collaborative effort by the University of Nebraska, NOAA, the USDA, and other experts throughout the country, has released a weekly map that shows the location and intensity of drought across the United States. On January 8, for the first time ever, USDM’s weekly map showed the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/californias-drought-is-over-but-we-still-must-invest-in-water-supply-projects/"&gt;California’s Drought is Over, But We Still Must Invest in Water Supply Projects&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 19:25:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Open enrollment: Know the basics</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2026/01/open-enrollment-know-the-basics/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In 2025, New Hampshire legislators passed a law allowing students to enroll in any public school within their assigned district, as long as the school had room. This year, lawmakers might allow students to enroll in any New Hampshire public school that has room. This policy brief answers six core questions commonly raised about open [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2026/01/open-enrollment-know-the-basics/"&gt;Open enrollment: Know the basics&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 19:28:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] Day One, Energy First: Governor Mikie Sherrill’s Opening Strategy on Affordability</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/01/day-one-energy-first-governor-mikie-sherrills-opening-strategy-on-affordability/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Sean Barry, NJPI Jr. Fellow When Governor Mikie Sherrill was sworn in as New Jersey’s 57th governor, she did [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/01/day-one-energy-first-governor-mikie-sherrills-opening-strategy-on-affordability/"&gt;Day One, Energy First: Governor Mikie Sherrill’s Opening Strategy on Affordability&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 19:08:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] A New Governor Takes Office. Will She Deliver on Education?</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/01/a-new-governor-takes-office-will-she-deliver-on-education/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;by Aiden DeMarsey, NJPI Jr. Fellow &amp;#160; Governor Mikie Sherrill, sworn into office last week, enters her term with a [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/01/a-new-governor-takes-office-will-she-deliver-on-education/"&gt;A New Governor Takes Office. Will She Deliver on Education?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 19:10:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] A foolish law wages war against homemade shindigs</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/a-foolish-law-wages-war-against-homemade-shindigs/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The law, passed in 2023, decrees that venues rented for private events at which the people holding the party bring their own alcohol can host only six such events a year, and only one a month — unless they prohibit bring-your-own drinks and instead get a liquor license like a tavern. Those are subject to strict quotas. Town board can simply refuse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/a-foolish-law-wages-war-against-homemade-shindigs/"&gt;A foolish law wages war against homemade shindigs&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 19:33:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] New housing permits are highest since 2006, but single-family homes lag</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2026/01/new-housing-permits-are-highest-since-2006-but-single-family-homes-lag/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New Hampshire towns and cities are permitting more residential housing units than they have in years, which is great news. But the new units are skewed heavily toward rentals, suggesting that local restrictions on small, single-family homes remain a significant barrier. Local governments issued permits for 5,822 new housing units in 2024, the highest number [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2026/01/new-housing-permits-are-highest-since-2006-but-single-family-homes-lag/"&gt;New housing permits are highest since 2006, but single-family homes lag&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:16:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] The Denial of Distinctions</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/the-denial-of-distinctions/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Denial of Distinctions By Abe Greenwald Yesterday, I wrote about the return of American disorder in the form of mobs that obstruct ICE raids. Part of what makes anti-ICE/open-border activism so strange is that it attacks the most fundamental aspect of what it means to be a country: its physical boundaries. When leftists repeat, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/the-denial-of-distinctions/"&gt;The Denial of Distinctions&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:37:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Crime is down, and it should end ‘root cause’ excuse-making for good</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/crime-is-down-and-it-should-end-root-cause-excuse-making-for-good/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/crime-is-down-and-it-should-end-root-cause-excuse-making-for-good/"&gt;Crime is down, and it should end ‘root cause’ excuse-making for good&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 22:13:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Federal Investigation Finds California Department of Education Violated FERPA by Keeping Secrets from Parents</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/federal-investigation-finds-california-department-of-education-violated-ferpa-by-keeping-secrets-from-parents/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=federal-investigation-finds-california-department-of-education-violated-ferpa-by-keeping-secrets-from-parents</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Department of Education announced this week that its investigation into the California Department of Education found that state policies that pressure schools to keep secrets from parents violate federal law. Specifically, the DOE said the “California Department of Education (CDE) is in continued violation of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA)—a federal law...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/federal-investigation-finds-california-department-of-education-violated-ferpa-by-keeping-secrets-from-parents/"&gt;Federal Investigation Finds California Department of Education Violated FERPA by Keeping Secrets from Parents&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 23:34:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Sedgwick County Commissioners use scare tactics and false claim to oppose property tax assessment limit</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/sedgwick-assessment-limit-scare-tactics/</link><description>Neutral testimony from the Kansas Association of Counties on the proposed 3% valuation assessment limit says, “The major benefit for taxpayers is predictability,” and notes that predictability could also help counties by having fewer disputes over valuations. Sedgwick County Commissioners, on the other hand, are taking a ‘sky is falling’ approach replete with scare tactics [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 16:56:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Introducing TennSight, Tennessee’s only hub for voter insights</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/introducing-tennsight-tennessees-only-hub-for-voter-insights/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=introducing-tennsight-tennessees-only-hub-for-voter-insights</link><description>We hope that TennSight will become the go-to source for you to learn what matters most to your fellow Tennesseans, why it matters, and what can be done about it.</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 13:08:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] A Steady-State Budget in a Moment of Crisis</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/a-steady-state-budget-in-a-moment-of-crisis/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Governor Maura Healey’s fiscal year 2027 budget totals $62.8 billion, a 3.8 percent year-over-year increase. The budget avoids sweeping new initiatives and largely preserves existing structures. That might be defensible in a period of stability. It is indefensible now. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/a-steady-state-budget-in-a-moment-of-crisis/"&gt;A Steady-State Budget in a Moment of Crisis &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 16:44:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Idaho schools paying $1.2 million per year for IEA/NEA dues</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/labor/idaho-schools-paying-1-2-million-per-year-for-iea-nea-dues/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;According to a new Freedom Foundation analysis, the Boise and Twin Falls School Districts are spending more than $1.2 million per year on programs to cover the cost of teachers union dues to the Idaho Education Association. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/labor/idaho-schools-paying-1-2-million-per-year-for-iea-nea-dues/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Idaho schools paying $1.2 million per year for IEA/NEA dues&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 17:33:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Beacon Poll: January 2026 Results</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/beacon-poll-january-2026-results/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=beacon-poll-january-2026-results</link><description>Today, we released the latest installment of the Beacon Poll, a statewide survey of 1,200 Tennessee voters featuring questions about voters’ views on property taxes, the federal school choice tax credit included in the One Big Beautiful Bill Act, and political approval ratings at the state and federal level, and more. Tennesseans continue to prioritize key...</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 19:35:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Johnson County superintendents fail 4th-grade math</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/johnson-county-supers-fail-4th-grade-math/</link><description>Today’s math riddle is brought to you by Johnson County school superintendents: How can taxpayers give school districts hundreds of millions of dollars more for special education without increasing total spending or cutting other state funding? The obvious answer is that it’s not possible, but that is what they tell taxpayers, and in their pitch [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 00:15:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Age Verification Isn’t Parenting</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/age-verification-isnt-parenting/</link><description>Kansas lawmakers are weighing a proposal that would require new age-verification measures for online platforms, part of a growing national effort to address concerns about children’s safety in digital spaces. The goal is understandable. Parents across Kansas want their kids protected online. The harder question is how far government should go—and whether mandates aimed at [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 16:00:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Dr. John Dixon: Charter Schools, Choice, and Accountability</title><link>https://empowerms.org/dr-john-dixon-charter-schools-choice-and-accountability/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Dr. John Dixon: Charter Schools, Choice, and Accountability As the 2026 legislative session moves forward, the conversation around school choice continues to intensify. While much of the focus has been on ESAs and public school transfers, one form of public school choice has quietly served thousands of Mississippi families for years: public charter schools. In&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/dr-john-dixon-charter-schools-choice-and-accountability/"&gt;Dr. John Dixon: Charter Schools, Choice, and Accountability&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 18:41:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] The TIF that Keeps Taking</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/article/corporate-welfare/the-tif-that-keeps-taking/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Thomas Friestad at the Kansas City Business Journal wrote recently that an engineering firm (Gannett Fleming TranSystems, formerly GFT) is moving its offices to the H&amp;#38;R Block building in downtown [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/article/corporate-welfare/the-tif-that-keeps-taking/"&gt;The TIF that Keeps Taking&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 19:16:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] A State of the State Built on “You’re Welcome”</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/a-state-of-the-state-built-on-youre-welcome/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Last week Governor Janet Mills delivered her final State of the State address. The hour-long speech was heavy on reflection and self-congratulation. Again and again, the Governor reminded Mainers, sometimes explicitly, that we should be thanking her for her governance. But self gratitude is not a governing philosophy. And after seven years in office, Mainers [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/a-state-of-the-state-built-on-youre-welcome/"&gt;A State of the State Built on “You’re Welcome”&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 20:59:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2026/02/14432/</link><description>&amp;#8216;Home&amp;#8217; Needs Some Definition COMMUNITY TRUST is breaking down as crime becomes more wanton, the roads are disintegrating in sub-zero temperatures and the city budget is not prioritized. So what is our mayor doing? Bringing casino gambling to town and establishing government grocery stores, to repeat complaints of mine, plus some new diversions. Among the last is&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2026/02/14432/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 15:00:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cardinalinstitute] Op-Ed: Hospitals Collect Tax Breaks. West Virginians Collect Medical Debt.</title><link>https://cardinalinstitute.com/op-ed-hospitals-collect-tax-breaks-west-virginians-collect-medical-debt/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;To many West Virginians, healthcare continues to be a burden more than a lifeline as roughly 180,000 residents, or 13.3% of adults, now facing some sort of  medical debt. This is well above the national average of 8.6% and, even worse, nearly one in four of these residents in rural Appalachia have medical debt in [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com/op-ed-hospitals-collect-tax-breaks-west-virginians-collect-medical-debt/"&gt;Op-Ed: Hospitals Collect Tax Breaks. West Virginians Collect Medical Debt.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com"&gt;Cardinal Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 15:16:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Why Portland’s Suggested Statewide Eviction Moratorium Would Hurt Maine’s Housing Market</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/why-portlands-suggested-statewide-eviction-moratorium-would-hurt-maines-housing-market/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Portland city officials are urging Gov. Janet Mills to impose a 60-day statewide eviction moratorium in response to “fear and instability” that they are linking to federal immigration enforcement. While the resolution is framed as an emergency measure that they are claiming is only meant to protect “vulnerable residents,” such a moratorium risks repeating a [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/why-portlands-suggested-statewide-eviction-moratorium-would-hurt-maines-housing-market/"&gt;Why Portland&amp;#8217;s Suggested Statewide Eviction Moratorium Would Hurt Maine’s Housing Market&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 16:38:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Can California’s Oil Industry Survive?</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/can-californias-oil-industry-survive/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=can-californias-oil-industry-survive</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Even confirmed skeptics should be impressed at the rapid improvement in the price and performance of EVs. A new 2026 Nissan Leaf sells for just under $30,000, and can charge in 30 minutes. That’s still not competitive with affordable gasoline powered vehicles, but the gap is closing fast. But while we may be sanguine about the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/can-californias-oil-industry-survive/"&gt;Can California’s Oil Industry Survive?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 17:57:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] Tim Pawlenty: The Crisis Will Subside in Minnesota, but Trust Will Need to be Rebuilt</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/tim-pawlenty-the-crisis-will-subside-in-minnesota-but-trust-will-need-to-be-rebuilt/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;We’ll all be part of that task. Here’s where efforts could be focused. By Tim Pawlenty For the Star Tribune It’s been said that trust is the glue that holds relationships together. That may well explain why recent events in Minnesota have stretched our relationship with government to the breaking point. Fraudsters stole a ton [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/tim-pawlenty-the-crisis-will-subside-in-minnesota-but-trust-will-need-to-be-rebuilt/"&gt;Tim Pawlenty: The Crisis Will Subside in Minnesota, but Trust Will Need to be Rebuilt&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 19:57:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] The Numbers Don’t Lie: The CHOOSE Act is Empowering Alabama’s Families</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2026/02/04/the-numbers-dont-lie-the-choose-act-is-empowering-alabamas-families/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For decades, the Alabama Policy Institute has championed a simple, powerful idea: every child in Alabama deserves a high-quality education, regardless of their zip code or their size of their parents’ bank account. With the passage and implementation of the CHOOSE Act, that vision is finally becoming a reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2026/02/04/the-numbers-dont-lie-the-choose-act-is-empowering-alabamas-families/"&gt;The Numbers Don’t Lie: The CHOOSE Act is Empowering Alabama’s Families&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 22:48:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] 312 Out of More than 3 Million Votes</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/312-out-of-more-than-3-million-votes/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Federal prosecutors are closing in on prosecuting more than 100 Minnesotans for rampant fraud in several social service programs designed to serve children and low-income residents. By the time the US Attorney’s office is done investigating, charging, convicting, and sentencing these felons, this unchecked fraud will significantly increase Minnesota’s prison population. But there’s one other [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/312-out-of-more-than-3-million-votes/"&gt;312 Out of More than 3 Million Votes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 13:58:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Empire Center Report Makes the Case Against Further Tax Hikes</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/empire-center-report-makes-the-case-against-further-tax-hikes/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Adding to New York&amp;#8217;s already high tax burden would be both unnecessary and dangerous for the state&amp;#8217;s economy, according to....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/empire-center-report-makes-the-case-against-further-tax-hikes/"&gt;Empire Center Report Makes the Case Against Further Tax Hikes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 16:12:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Study Urges New K–12 Accountability Framework Following End of MCAS Graduation Requirement</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/study-urges-new-k-12-accountability-framework-following-end-of-mcas-graduation-requirement/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Calls for choices of high school pathways, early and end-of-course exams, and independent district accountability  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/study-urges-new-k-12-accountability-framework-following-end-of-mcas-graduation-requirement/"&gt;Study Urges New K–12 Accountability Framework Following End of MCAS Graduation Requirement&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 16:14:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Education Is Economic Development: Why Business Leaders Should Support House Bill</title><link>https://empowerms.org/education-is-economic-development-why-business-leaders-should-support-house-bill/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This article was originally published in the February 2026 edition of the Mississippi Business Journal. Mississippi’s business community understands a basic but often overlooked reality: economic development does not begin with tax incentives or site selectors. It begins with people. If we want our state to grow, we must be able to attract, retain, and&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/education-is-economic-development-why-business-leaders-should-support-house-bill/"&gt;Education Is Economic Development: Why Business Leaders Should Support House Bill&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 18:43:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Record-breaking start to 2026: 6,000 employees opt out</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/record-breaking-start-to-2026-6000-employees-opt-out/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Freedom Foundation set an all-time record in January with 6,000 public employees opting out—topping our previous record by nearly 3,000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/record-breaking-start-to-2026-6000-employees-opt-out/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Record-breaking start to 2026: 6,000 employees opt out&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 18:57:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Time for UW-Madison to do away with ethnic studies requirement</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/time-for-uw-madison-to-do-away-with-ethnic-studies-requirement/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Time can be better spent on other things like AI Here’s a question I hope somebody asks anyone who applies to be the next chancellor of the University of Wisconsin-Madison: Why in the world in 2026 should we continue to have an ethnic studies requirement for all undergrads? Here’s another one: Do you even know [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/time-for-uw-madison-to-do-away-with-ethnic-studies-requirement/"&gt;Time for UW-Madison to do away with ethnic studies requirement&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 20:05:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] A Badger Institute policy report: Character education and teacher retention</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/a-badger-institute-policy-report-character-education-and-teacher-retention/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Wisconsinites should be concerned the state's growing crisis of disappearing educators — a phenomenon the Badger Institute has been taking a closer look at. Multiple studies confirm that retaining good teachers is essential to school effectiveness and student achievement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/a-badger-institute-policy-report-character-education-and-teacher-retention/"&gt;A Badger Institute policy report: Character education and teacher retention&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 20:25:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Testimony: SB 1526 Creates State-Sponsored Nonprofit for Net Zero Projects</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/testimony/testimony-sb-1526-creates-state-sponsored-nonprofit-for-net-zero-projects/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By John A. Charles Jr. PORTLAND, OR – John Charles, President and CEO...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/testimony/testimony-sb-1526-creates-state-sponsored-nonprofit-for-net-zero-projects/"&gt;Testimony: SB 1526 Creates State-Sponsored Nonprofit for Net Zero Projects&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 20:40:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Rifreedom] TESTIMONY: Senate Commission to Study the Successful Implementation of the Act on Climate</title><link>https://rifreedom.org/2026/02/senate-commission-act-on-climate/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In this powerful testimony, Mike Stenhouse, CEO of the RI Center for Freedom &amp;#038; Prosperity, explains why energy policy—not taxes, not housing, not government services—is the single most important determinant of Rhode Island’s future prosperity or poverty. Whether one believes in climate change or not, the economic consequences of the Act on Climate are unavoidable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org/2026/02/senate-commission-act-on-climate/"&gt;TESTIMONY: Senate Commission to Study the Successful Implementation of the Act on Climate&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org"&gt;RI Center for Freedom and Prosperity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 21:12:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] The Rise of Labor-Based Grading and the Continuing De-emphasis on Skill Development at U.S. Universities</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/article/education/the-rise-of-labor-based-grading-and-the-continuing-de-emphasis-on-skill-development-at-u-s-universities/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Evidence of grade inflation continues to mount in K-12 education and at universities (e.g., see here and here). The rising grades reflect a degradation of academic standards. There is clear [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/article/education/the-rise-of-labor-based-grading-and-the-continuing-de-emphasis-on-skill-development-at-u-s-universities/"&gt;The Rise of Labor-Based Grading and the Continuing De-emphasis on Skill Development at U.S. Universities&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 22:15:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] What’s the Wisconsin Department of Public Instruction Hiding?</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/whats-the-wisconsin-department-of-public-instruction-hiding/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;What&amp;#8217;s the Wisconsin Department of Public Instruction Hiding? Things are rotten in the Wisconsin Department of Public Instruction (DPI). Late last year, a damning report showed hundreds of educational professionals, including aides and teachers, were investigated for sexual misconduct. Many of them were simply allowed to resign and kept their licenses. On top of that, educational standards [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/whats-the-wisconsin-department-of-public-instruction-hiding/"&gt;What&amp;#8217;s the Wisconsin Department of Public Instruction Hiding?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 22:49:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG’s Jake Curtis Joins the Vicki McKenna Show to talk about DPI Spending</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irgs-jake-curtis-joins-the-vicki-mckenna-show-to-talk-about-dpi-spending/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irgs-jake-curtis-joins-the-vicki-mckenna-show-to-talk-about-dpi-spending/"&gt;IRG&amp;#8217;s Jake Curtis Joins the Vicki McKenna Show to talk about DPI Spending&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 22:51:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] Republicans delay Wisconsin DPI funding over water park spending concerns</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/republicans-delay-wisconsin-dpi-funding-over-water-park-spending-concerns/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Republicans delay Wisconsin DPI funding over water park spending concerns The state Legislature&amp;#8217;s Joint Finance Committee delayed voting on the Department of Public Instruction&amp;#8217;s request to release operating funds Feb. 3, following a report from a conservative news outlet that criticized the agency for hosting a four-day event at a water park in Wisconsin Dells. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/republicans-delay-wisconsin-dpi-funding-over-water-park-spending-concerns/"&gt;Republicans delay Wisconsin DPI funding over water park spending concerns&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 23:01:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] ‘A country where opportunity is still possible’</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/podcasts/the-overton-window/justin-callais-discusses-what-helps-states-improve-life-outcomes</link><description>Justin Callais discusses what helps states improve life outcomes</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] BERGEN RECORD: NJ climate superfund is a blank check with no accountability | Opinion</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/02/bergen-record-nj-climate-superfund-is-a-blank-check-with-no-accountability-opinion/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;#160; New Jersey’s Climate Superfund Is a Blank Check With No Accountability by Rosemary Becchi New Jersey lawmakers are considering [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/02/bergen-record-nj-climate-superfund-is-a-blank-check-with-no-accountability-opinion/"&gt;BERGEN RECORD: NJ climate superfund is a blank check with no accountability | Opinion&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 13:58:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] The Virginian-Pilot: Federal Scholarship Tax Credits Should be a No-Brainer for Virginia</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/the-virginian-pilot-federal-scholarship-tax-credits-should-be-a-no-brainer-for-virginia/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/tax-credit-featured-image.jpg" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In today’s The Virginian-Pilot, Thomas Jefferson Institute Senior Advisor and Former President Chris Braunlich discusses Virginia’s participation in the new Federal Scholarship Tax Credit (FSTC) for K-12 students which, starting in 2027, will give taxpayers a dollar for dollar federal tax credit of up to $1,700 for donations to scholarship programs offering students in public [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/the-virginian-pilot-federal-scholarship-tax-credits-should-be-a-no-brainer-for-virginia/"&gt;The Virginian-Pilot: Federal Scholarship Tax Credits Should be a No-Brainer for Virginia&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 16:11:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Week in Review: Down with DEI Mandates</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-down-with-dei-mandates/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Despite the national backlash to diversity, equity, and inclusion (DEI), many universities across the country still require their employees to..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-down-with-dei-mandates/"&gt;Week in Review: Down with DEI Mandates&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 16:18:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Governor Mills’ Supplemental Budget Abandons Fiscal Discipline, Sets Maine Up for Higher Costs</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/governor-millss-supplemental-budget-abandons-fiscal-discipline-sets-maine-up-for-higher-costs/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Governor Janet Mills’ FY 2026 supplemental budget marks a clear break from the fiscal restraint her administration often claimed to practice. Rather than using Maine’s strong revenue growth to stabilize taxpayers after years of tax increases and inflation, the proposal dramatically expands spending, broadens emergency powers, and doubles down on distortionary tax policy choices that [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/governor-millss-supplemental-budget-abandons-fiscal-discipline-sets-maine-up-for-higher-costs/"&gt;Governor Mills’ Supplemental Budget Abandons Fiscal Discipline, Sets Maine Up for Higher Costs&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 17:22:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Stacked Local Taxes Are Making Virginia Less Affordable, Not More</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/stacked-local-taxes-are-making-virginia-less-affordable-not-more/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="630" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/virginia-local-taxes-v2.jpg" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Virginia’s restaurant and lodging sector is still in a fragile post-COVID recovery, yet local governments across the Commonwealth are piling on new and higher taxes that make affordability worse for families and survival harder for small businesses. A new statewide analysis of meals, lodging, and related sales taxes across all 133 Virginia localities by the&amp;#160;Virginia [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/stacked-local-taxes-are-making-virginia-less-affordable-not-more/"&gt;Stacked Local Taxes Are Making Virginia Less Affordable, Not More&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 17:43:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] A New Era of Opportunity: How Governor Landry’s LA GATOR ESA Outshines Outdated Vouchers</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/education/lagator-outshines-vouchers/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In the heart of Louisiana, where innovation and opportunity should define our future, the new LA GATOR Scholarship Program stands as a bold testament to free-market principles in education. Enacted by Governor Jeff Landry and the Louisiana Legislature 2024 and launched in 2025, this education savings account (ESA) initiative represents a seismic shift from the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/education/lagator-outshines-vouchers/"&gt;A New Era of Opportunity: How Governor Landry’s LA GATOR ESA Outshines Outdated Vouchers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 18:02:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Courts vs. Communities: Should Judges Override Local Land-Use Decisions?</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/legal-regulatory/courts-vs-communities/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Can the courts substitute their judgment for the reasonable judgment of local governments when it comes to land use? That’s the question counsel for St. James Parish put to the Louisiana Supreme Court when it heard oral argument in Beverly Alexander, et al., v. St. James Parish on January 22, 2026. At issue is the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/legal-regulatory/courts-vs-communities/"&gt;Courts vs. Communities: Should Judges Override Local Land-Use Decisions?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 18:48:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Affordability tops the list of state priorities for 2026</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/affordability-tops-the-list-of-state-priorities-for-2026/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/affordability-tops-the-list-of-state-priorities-for-2026/"&gt;Affordability tops the list of state priorities for 2026&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 21:36:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] 2026 Capitol Chat: Week 5</title><link>https://empowerms.org/2026-capitol-chat-week-5/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Capitol Chat: Week 5 Week 5 at the Capitol featured some of the most consequential policy and political moves yet. In this episode, we walk through some of the biggest developments, including shifts in the education debate, major House action, an update on the ballot initiative, and another big deadline on the horizon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/2026-capitol-chat-week-5/"&gt;2026 Capitol Chat: Week 5&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 22:11:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Structural Limits Are the Missing Link in Tax Reform</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/structural-limits-are-the-missing-link-in-tax-reform/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Structural Limits Are the Missing Link in Tax Reform" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/iowa-constitution-pages.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tax reform without structural limits is temporary, as spending pressures and special interests will eventually overwhelm even well-designed tax cuts unless constitutional guardrails are put in place. Two key constitutional protections—a supermajority requirement for tax increases and protection of the flat tax—work together to restrain spending, reduce special-interest influence, and preserve economic freedom while still allowing responsible governance. Enshrining these protections would lock in Iowa’s pro-growth tax structure, ensuring long-term certainty, transparency, and discipline so that future prosperity benefits taxpayers rather than unchecked government expansion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/structural-limits-are-the-missing-link-in-tax-reform/"&gt;Structural Limits Are the Missing Link in Tax Reform&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 13:01:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2026/02/the-outstater-325/</link><description>Our &amp;#8216;Somali Mindset&amp;#8217; WHY, REALLY,&amp;#160;do the impoverished want to come to America? Is it the promises embedded in our Declaration of Independence? Perhaps a&amp;#160;legal system based on 800 years of Common Law and respect for private property? Liberty with responsibility? That would make us proud. But why is it,&amp;#160;to pick an example from the news,&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2026/02/the-outstater-325/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 14:59:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Union Activists Launch Full Scale Attack on Students, Families in AZ</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/union-activists-launch-full-scale-attack-on-students-families-in-az/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As students across the state continue to find new opportunity through Arizona’s Empowerment Scholarship Account (ESA) program, the total number..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/union-activists-launch-full-scale-attack-on-students-families-in-az/"&gt;Union Activists Launch Full Scale Attack on Students, Families in AZ&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 20:42:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] National Review: Thirty Candles for the Internet’s Foundation</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/national-review-thirty-candles-for-the-internets-foundation/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Today marks an unusual anniversary, not of a person, but of 26 words that built the modern internet. Section 230...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/national-review-thirty-candles-for-the-internets-foundation/"&gt;National Review: Thirty Candles for the Internet’s Foundation&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 16:12:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] House bill a shot in the arm for Schools of Choice law</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2026/house-bill-a-shot-in-the-arm-for-schools-of-choice-law</link><description>Michigan can help students by making the program universal</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2026/02/the-outstater-326/</link><description>Pimping for Data Centers &amp;#8220;The idea is to get back to a society where people can live together as neighbors and not just as wage slaves or bureaucratic cogs.” — G.K. Chesterton LOOK, I LIKE PROGRESS&amp;#160;as much as the next guy but sacrificing local autonomy is stupid. There are nine distinct regions of Indiana, each&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2026/02/the-outstater-326/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 13:21:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Mind the Body</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/mind-the-body/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;There are wars in the Middle East. Future battles with China. Covert missions in Latin America. And Elon Musk wants to build a Mars colony. All of these require one, simple biological necessity: human beings. Unfortunately, Americans are fat. And the obesity problem with our children has only ballooned. To protect our sovereignty, secure our...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/mind-the-body/"&gt;Mind the Body&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 14:16:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] The sun is stronger than our electric grid — and we are defenseless against it</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/the-sun-is-stronger-than-our-electric-grid-and-we-are-defenseless-against-it/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Carrington Event literally shocked telegraph operators. A repeat could shock an entire civilization into the pre-industrial age. Imagine being a telegraph operator in September 1859. You’re sitting at your station, using cutting-edge technology to tap out messages hundreds and thousands of miles away. Suddenly, brilliant auroras light up the night sky from the tropics...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/the-sun-is-stronger-than-our-electric-grid-and-we-are-defenseless-against-it/"&gt;The sun is stronger than our electric grid — and we are defenseless against it&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 14:25:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Ayotte: Maximize economic freedom, and New Hampshire will thrive</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2026/02/ayotte-maximize-economic-freedom-and-new-hampshire-will-thrive/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Gov. Kelly Ayotte’s 2026 State of the State address can be summed up in seven words: New Hampshire wins by competing on freedom. Leading with a list of eight No. 1 national rankings for the state—including economic freedom, economic opportunity and taxpayer return on investment—Ayotte noted that, overall, “U.S. News ranks us the #2 state [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2026/02/ayotte-maximize-economic-freedom-and-new-hampshire-will-thrive/"&gt;Ayotte: Maximize economic freedom, and New Hampshire will thrive&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 14:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Cowboy State needs to protect itself from shifting federal priorities</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/post/cowboy-state-needs-to-protect-itself-from-shifting-federal-priorities</link><description>Wyoming legislators are right to address the necessity of upholding the principles of federalism in the 2026 Legislative Session in the form of SJ 2.</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 14:57:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] ITR Foundation Brings the Property Tax Conversation Directly to Iowans</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/itr-foundation-brings-the-property-tax-conversation-directly-to-iowans/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="ITR Foundation Brings the Property Tax Conversation Directly to Iowans" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/hendrickson-maga-nation.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ITR Foundation is taking the property tax conversation directly to Iowans, engaging grassroots audiences alongside elected officials and candidates to address the real-world impact of rising property taxes. The data show a clear problem: Iowa property taxes have grown by more than 100 percent over the past two decades, far outpacing population growth and inflation, driven primarily by sustained growth in local government spending rather than assessments alone. Meaningful property tax relief requires spending discipline, including reasonable caps on revenue growth, to complement Iowa’s recent income tax reforms and ensure taxpayers, homeowners, farmers, and small businesses are not squeezed by unchecked local spending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/itr-foundation-brings-the-property-tax-conversation-directly-to-iowans/"&gt;ITR Foundation Brings the Property Tax Conversation Directly to Iowans&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 15:07:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Wisconsin Is Ripping and Replacing What Already Works</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/wisconsin-is-ripping-and-replacing-what-already-works/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Chinese government-backed hacking group Salt Typhoon spent two years inside America&amp;#8217;s largest telecom networks, accessing call records for...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/wisconsin-is-ripping-and-replacing-what-already-works/"&gt;Wisconsin Is Ripping and Replacing What Already Works&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 15:26:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Idaho considers an amendments convention</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/post/idaho-considers-an-amendments-convention</link><description>Our Founders gave us a precious constitutional right to correct the federal government when it has gone off the rails. It is our privilege, and obligation, to use it, and Idaho has the opportunity to join the majority of other states that have voted to do so.</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 15:32:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Nine More Massachusetts Towns Subject of State Litigation over MBTA Communities Act Noncompliance</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/nine-more-massachusetts-towns-subject-of-state-litigation-over-mbta-communities-act-noncompliance/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;February's edition of The House Call discusses new legal action over Massachusetts' multifamily zoning mandate for transit-accessible communities. It also highlights a new federal data release that shows where many Massachusetts homeowners tend to overestimate - or underestimate - their property values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/nine-more-massachusetts-towns-subject-of-state-litigation-over-mbta-communities-act-noncompliance/"&gt;Nine More Massachusetts Towns Subject of State Litigation over MBTA Communities Act Noncompliance&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 16:58:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] House Bill 583 — Short-term rentals, regulations (+1)</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/house-bill-583-short-term-rentals-regulations/</link><description>Bill Description:&amp;#160;House Bill 583 would limit local regulations on short-term rentals. It would also require property owners who offer short-term rentals privately to pay a variety of business taxes.&amp;#160; Rating: +1 Does it increase barriers to entry into the market? Examples include occupational licensure, the minimum wage, and restrictions on home businesses. Conversely, does it [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 17:20:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] House Bill 581 — Idaho Supreme Court Rules, Legislative Review (+1)</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/house-bill-581-idaho-supreme-court-rules-legislative-review/</link><description>Bill Description: House Bill 581 would amend the language in Section 1-213, Idaho Code, to allow the Legislature to review court rules, and establish a process to advise the Idaho Supreme Court — via a House or Senate resolution — of conflicts between court rules and Idaho code.  Rating: +1 Does it in any way restrict [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 17:22:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] When Political Rhetoric Goes Too Far</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/when-political-rhetoric-goes-too-far/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Empty phrases routinely populate our politics. But ever so often, there are irrefutable moments where rhetoric is wielded as a weapon to be used in animating hostility. “The day the Latino, African American, Asian and other communities realize that they share the same oppressor is the day we start winning because we are the majority...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/when-political-rhetoric-goes-too-far/"&gt;When Political Rhetoric Goes Too Far&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 17:23:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Facing Medicaid Fraud Allegations, California Changes The Subject</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/facing-medicaid-fraud-allegations-california-changes-the-subject/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Dr. Mehmet Oz has been raising a stir over what he claims is rampant Medicaid fraud. The administrator of the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services alleges that California has spent an estimated $1.3 billion in federal funds providing coverage to undocumented immigrants through the program. That would violate federal law. Rather than address the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/facing-medicaid-fraud-allegations-california-changes-the-subject/"&gt;Facing Medicaid Fraud Allegations, California Changes The Subject&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 17:54:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Senate Bill 1264 — Rural health transformation (-3)</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/senate-bill-1264-rural-health-transformation-3/</link><description>Bill Description:&amp;#160;Senate Bill 1264 would create the Idaho Rural Health Transformation Fund in the state treasury and establish the Rural Health Transformation Committee which would provide direction and legislative oversight to any appropriated funds. Rating: -3 Note: This Bill is nearly identical to S1253, with only the makeup of the committee being altered. Does it [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 18:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Chicago business activity growing for first time since November 2023</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/chicago-business-activity-growing-for-first-time-since-november-2023/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Chicago employment situation improves after hitting lowest level since 2009 in December 2025. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/chicago-business-activity-growing-for-first-time-since-november-2023/"&gt;Chicago business activity growing for first time since November 2023&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 19:58:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Keep an Eye on the DATA Act in Washington, D.C.</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/article/energy/keep-an-eye-on-the-data-act-in-washington-d-c/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As a writer, there are moments when someone else articulates an idea so well that rewriting it in my own words would be unnecessary. A recent op-ed in The Hill [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/article/energy/keep-an-eye-on-the-data-act-in-washington-d-c/"&gt;Keep an Eye on the DATA Act in Washington, D.C.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 21:27:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] Alabama Senate unanimously passes App Store Accountability Act</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2026/02/09/alabama-senate-unanimously-passes-app-store-accountability-act/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The App Store Accountability Act passed the Alabama Senate with a unanimous vote on Feb. 5. The bill is focused on online safety for children and teens by requiring parental approval for kids to download apps from the App Store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2026/02/09/alabama-senate-unanimously-passes-app-store-accountability-act/"&gt;Alabama Senate unanimously passes App Store Accountability Act&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 23:47:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] Alabama Senate passes App Store age verification requirement</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2026/02/10/alabama-senate-passes-app-store-age-verification-requirement/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Lawmakers spoke before the Senate in favor of shielding minors from inappropriate content, requiring parental permission for account creation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2026/02/10/alabama-senate-passes-app-store-age-verification-requirement/"&gt;Alabama Senate passes App Store age verification requirement&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 02:12:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Legislators Not Curious About Cost, Safety or Efficiency As Massive Battery Mandate Rushes Toward Approval</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/legislators-not-curious-about-cost-safety-or-efficiency-as-massive-battery-mandate-rushes-toward-approval/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="720" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Virginia-green-battery-mandate.jpg" width="1280" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, a Senate committee is scheduled to take up the bill directing Virginia’s two investor-owned utilities to propose huge battery installations that will cover square miles of ground, cost ratepayers billions of dollars, and produce zero energy to power our homes and businesses. The bill has Governor Abigail Spanberger’s endorsement. So far, legislators have been in a “see, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/legislators-not-curious-about-cost-safety-or-efficiency-as-massive-battery-mandate-rushes-toward-approval/"&gt;Legislators Not Curious About Cost, Safety or Efficiency As Massive Battery Mandate Rushes Toward Approval&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 03:40:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] The Gordon Chang Report–Arctic: The Next Cold War</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/the-gordon-chang-report-arctic-the-next-cold-war/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;READ THE PDF Arctic: The Next Cold War “You have Russian destroyers and submarines and China destroyers and submarines all over the place,” President Donald Trump said in January, referring to the Arctic. Hostile powers are just about everywhere at the top of the world. In late summer 2015, five Chinese warships, after participating in [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/the-gordon-chang-report-arctic-the-next-cold-war/"&gt;The Gordon Chang Report–Arctic: The Next Cold War&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 10:00:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] ISSUE BRIEF: Government Policy Is Consolidating the Practice of Medicine</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/issue-brief-government-policy-is-consolidating-the-practice-of-medicine/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A new issue brief released today by the Pacific Research Institute—the California-based, nonpartisan, free market think tank—finds that certain states&amp;#8217; efforts to tighten corporate practice of medicine laws hurt independent physicians, empower hospitals to consolidate local provider markets, and raise healthcare costs. &amp;#8220;Competition is a prerequisite for affordable, high-quality care,&amp;#8221; said Dr. Wayne Winegarden, the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/issue-brief-government-policy-is-consolidating-the-practice-of-medicine/"&gt;ISSUE BRIEF: Government Policy Is Consolidating the Practice of Medicine&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 10:07:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Mamdani hires multiple anti-Israel activists</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/mamdani-hires-multiple-anti-israel-activists/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Jon Levine writes for the Washington Free Beacon about the New York City mayor’s dubious staffing decisions. New York City mayor Zohran Mamdani (D.) has stocked a variety of operational roles in his administration with a cadre of anti-Israel extremists, including a man who called people who ripped down flyers of Israeli hostages &amp;#8220;heroes&amp;#8221; and...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/mamdani-hires-multiple-anti-israel-activists/"&gt;Mamdani hires multiple anti-Israel activists&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 10:36:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Removing illegals from census could limit Democrats’ power</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/removing-illegals-from-census-could-limit-democrats-power/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Ben Weingarten writes for the Federalist about the potential political implications of removing illegal immigrants from the American census. There are many drivers behind the new nullification crisis that the left is stoking over immigration, but perhaps the most significant political one is that the Trump administration’s mass deportation policy poses a greater threat to...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/removing-illegals-from-census-could-limit-democrats-power/"&gt;Removing illegals from census could limit Democrats&amp;#8217; power&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 10:39:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Clear majority of Americans fear nuclear war</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/clear-majority-of-americans-fear-nuclear-war/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Terry Jones writes for Issues and Insights about a disturbing new poll result. Americans have lived with the threat of nuclear war for more than seven decades, yet the deadly weapons get little serious attention outside of wonky policy circles. But, as a major U.S.-Russia nuclear weapons agreement expires and nuclear talks with Iran continue,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/clear-majority-of-americans-fear-nuclear-war/"&gt;Clear majority of Americans fear nuclear war&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 10:42:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Interest rates should be left to the private market</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2026/interest-rates-should-be-left-to-the-private-market</link><description>Why I signed onto a letter opposing price controls</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Chicago Peace Initiative: Reducing violence with jobs</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/chicago-peace-initiative-reducing-violence-with-jobs/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Gangs and prison often keep Chicago’s youth out of the workforce, but the Chicago Peace Initiative works to change that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/chicago-peace-initiative-reducing-violence-with-jobs/"&gt;Chicago Peace Initiative: Reducing violence with jobs&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 11:00:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Testimony of Bill Hammond on the Health and Medicaid Budget for FY 2027</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/testimony-of-bill-hammond-on-the-health-and-medicaid-budget-for-fy-2027/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Testimony of Bill Hammond Senior Fellow, Empire Center for Public Policy Before the Joint Legislative Fiscal Committees February 10, 2026....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/testimony-of-bill-hammond-on-the-health-and-medicaid-budget-for-fy-2027/"&gt;Testimony of Bill Hammond on the Health and Medicaid Budget for FY 2027&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 13:36:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Hammond Calls for Restraint on Medicaid Spending</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/hammond-calls-for-restraint-on-medicaid-spending/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Albany, N.Y. — The state and its taxpayers cannot afford to allow Medicaid spending to keep growing at five times the....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/hammond-calls-for-restraint-on-medicaid-spending/"&gt;Hammond Calls for Restraint on Medicaid Spending&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 13:36:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Did Jefferson Raid Its Water Fund? Lawsuit Puts City Finances Under Scrutiny</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/did-jefferson-raid-its-water-fund-lawsuit-puts-city-finances-under-scrutiny/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Did Jefferson Raid Its Water Fund? Lawsuit Puts City Finances Under Scrutiny" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/jefferson-iowajpg.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lawsuit challenges Jefferson’s use of taxpayer dollars after the city transferred $800,000 from its Water Plant Construction Fund into economic development and TIF-related accounts. Plaintiffs argue the transfer violated Iowa law and public process, claiming the city neither demonstrated a lawful surplus nor created a binding repayment obligation, and failed to follow required budget amendment procedures. The case raises broader concerns about transparency and taxpayer trust, highlighting the risks of diverting funds and the potential for residents to pay twice through higher future rates or taxes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/did-jefferson-raid-its-water-fund-lawsuit-puts-city-finances-under-scrutiny/"&gt;Did Jefferson Raid Its Water Fund? Lawsuit Puts City Finances Under Scrutiny&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 14:09:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Water law: Stopping the leaks in the Montana Constitution</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/post/water-law-stopping-the-leaks-in-the-montana-constitution</link><description>Because water is so precious, the law governing it should be fair and certain. People are entitled to know what they can and can’t do. They need assurance that the rules will not change suddenly. Unfortunately, the Montana state constitution’s water provisions are confused and contradictory.</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 14:43:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Clarify definitions to improve emergency management law</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/02/clarify-definitions-to-improve-emergency-management-law/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the House Committee on Pubic Safety on Feb. 6, 2026._____________ Feb 6, 2026, 10:15 a.m.Hawaii State CapitolConference Room 411 and Videoconference To: House Committee on Public Safety&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Rep. Della Au Belatti, Chair&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Rep. Kim Coco Iwamoto, Vice Chair From: Grassroot Institute [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/02/clarify-definitions-to-improve-emergency-management-law/"&gt;Clarify definitions to improve emergency management law&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 16:00:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Require criminal convictions before law enforcement can seize assets</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/02/require-criminal-convictions-before-law-enforcement-can-seize-assets/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Senate Committee on Judiciary on Feb. 6, 2026._____________ Feb. 6, 2026, 9 a.m.  Hawaii State CapitolConference Room 016 and Videoconference To: Senate Committee on Judiciary&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; &amp;#160;Sen. Karl Rhoads, Chair&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; &amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;Sen. Mike Gabbard, Vice Chair From: Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Ted [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/02/require-criminal-convictions-before-law-enforcement-can-seize-assets/"&gt;Require criminal convictions before law enforcement can seize assets&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 16:16:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Join compact for psychology to improve mental health treatment</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/02/join-compact-for-psychology-to-improve-mental-health-treatment/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii on Feb. 6, 2026, for consideration by the Senate Committees on Health and Human Services and Commerce and Consumer Protection._____________ Feb. 6, 2026, 9 a.m.Hawaii State CapitolConference Room 229 and Videoconference To: Senate Committee on Health and Human Services&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Sen. Joy A. San Buenaventura, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/02/join-compact-for-psychology-to-improve-mental-health-treatment/"&gt;Join compact for psychology to improve mental health treatment&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 16:19:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] On Lincoln’s Birthday, Remember the Right to Rise</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/principles-of-liberty/right-to-rise/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As Americans, we remember the great leaders of our country and reflect on their contributions to our present-day lives. February 12, 1809, marks the birthday of Abraham Lincoln—undoubtedly among the most famous and revered figures in our nation’s history, and with good reason. He was not only the Great Emancipator, but an exemplar of the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/principles-of-liberty/right-to-rise/"&gt;On Lincoln’s Birthday, Remember the Right to Rise&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 16:46:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Freedom Foundation Attorneys Secure Compensation from SEIU 099 for a Public-School Employee</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/litigation/freedom-foundation-attorneys-secure-compensation-from-seiu-099-for-a-public-school-employee/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Freedom Foundation attorneys have successfully freed California public school employee Keshawna Adams from SEIU 099’ unconstitutional dues deductions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/litigation/freedom-foundation-attorneys-secure-compensation-from-seiu-099-for-a-public-school-employee/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation Attorneys Secure Compensation from SEIU 099 for a Public-School Employee&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 17:52:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Habeas 800</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/habeas-800/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Habeas corpus cases have soared past the 800 mark in Minnesota for 2026, so far, even as higher courts look to limit the practice. As of this afteroon, some 819 habeas cases have been filed in federal court, each seeking the release of one or more illegal aliens held in ICE detention. Down in Texas,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/habeas-800/"&gt;Habeas 800&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:05:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] It’s Time for Arizona’s Supreme Court to Protect ‘The Most Precious Liberty Man Possesses’</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/its-time-for-arizonas-supreme-court-to-protect-the-most-precious-liberty-man-possesses/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Goldwater Institute today filed a brief in the Arizona Supreme Court urging the justices to extend full constitutional protection..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/its-time-for-arizonas-supreme-court-to-protect-the-most-precious-liberty-man-possesses/"&gt;It’s Time for Arizona’s Supreme Court to Protect ‘The Most Precious Liberty Man Possesses’&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:33:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] WILL Releases New Model Policy Protecting Girls Privacy at School</title><link>https://will-law.org/will-releases-new-model-policy-protecting-girls-privacy-at-school/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL has released a new model school board policy outlining how and why sex-separated bathrooms are legal and critical to protecting girls at school. This policy release follows a national debate over sex-separated bathrooms and a controversy in the New Richmond, WI, school district over a policy allowing biological boys to use the girls’ bathrooms over the protest and concerns of parents and students alike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/will-releases-new-model-policy-protecting-girls-privacy-at-school/"&gt;WILL Releases New Model Policy Protecting Girls Privacy at School&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:54:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] College degrees no longer guarantee an edge in the job market</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/college-degrees-no-longer-guarantee-an-edge-in-the-job-market/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Recent Bureau of Labor Statistics data, highlighted by The Washington Post, show that for the first time in decades, workers with associate degrees or skilled trades training now experience lower unemployment rates than those with traditional four-year degrees. According to the Post, the long-standing advantage once held by bachelor&amp;#8217;s degree holders has narrowed significantly. This...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/college-degrees-no-longer-guarantee-an-edge-in-the-job-market/"&gt;College degrees no longer guarantee an edge in the job market&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:55:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Why the 2026 legislature must avoid a massive bonding bill</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/why-the-2026-legislature-must-avoid-a-massive-bonding-bill/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Beginning February 17, Minnesota legislators will convene for the 2026 legislative session. Lawmakers will likely have to decide, among other things, whether and how much to spend on an infrastructure package, commonly known as a bonding bill due to the nature of its funding. To get that process started, Governor Walz has proposed a $907...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/why-the-2026-legislature-must-avoid-a-massive-bonding-bill/"&gt;Why the 2026 legislature must avoid a massive bonding bill&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 19:08:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Florida Politics: Florida’s CHINA Prevention Unit Is a Needed Step To Safeguard Health Data</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/floridas-china-prevention-unit-is-a-needed-step-to-safeguard-health-data/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Once again, Florida is showing the rest of the country how to lead in protecting its citizens from...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/floridas-china-prevention-unit-is-a-needed-step-to-safeguard-health-data/"&gt;Florida Politics: Florida’s CHINA Prevention Unit Is a Needed Step To Safeguard Health Data&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 19:20:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] 5 Ways state law empowers Chicago Teachers Union and how it can change</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/5-ways-state-law-empowers-chicago-teachers-union-and-how-it-can-change/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Chicago Teachers Union is widely regarded as one of the most powerful teachers’ unions in the country because of massive political spending, militant activism and its adopted model of progressive political organizing. The union’s success is rooted in its deep political involvement, influencing elections, state and local policy to a level that sets it...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/5-ways-state-law-empowers-chicago-teachers-union-and-how-it-can-change/"&gt;5 Ways state law empowers Chicago Teachers Union and how it can change&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 19:50:28 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>