<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>State-Policy Think-Tank Digest</title><link>https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml</link><description>Latest posts from free-market policy institutes across the U.S.</description><atom:link href="https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 23:03:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>[Empowerms] If Lawmakers Are Trying to Defund Public Education, They Aren’t Very Good at It</title><link>https://empowerms.org/if-lawmakers-are-trying-to-defund-public-education-they-arent-very-good-at-it/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;You’ve probably heard the claim that Mississippi’s Republican leaders are “defunding” public education, and that school choice is just another way to siphon dollars away from public schools. But if that’s true, they’re doing a remarkably bad job of it.  Over the past decade, Mississippi has dramatically increased its investment in public education. According to&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/if-lawmakers-are-trying-to-defund-public-education-they-arent-very-good-at-it/"&gt;If Lawmakers Are Trying to Defund Public Education, They Aren’t Very Good at It&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 02:00:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Nebraska’s Tax Treatment of Non-Profits</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/nebraskas-tax-treatment-of-non-profits/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The origins of favorable tax treatment for nonprofit and not-for-profit organizations in the United States were based on the admirable ideals promoting community service and public good.    However, today the United States’ federally tax-exempt economy makes up 15% of gross domestic output (GDP) and spans 1.8 million organizations. A total of $3.3 trillion dollars of...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/nebraskas-tax-treatment-of-non-profits/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Nebraska&amp;#8217;s Tax Treatment of Non-Profits&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 19:37:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] Court ratifies City of Albuquerque donation to Planned Parenthood</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/court-ratifies-city-of-albuquerque-donation-to-planned-parenthood/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In what can only be described as a ruling based on twisted logic a New Mexico District Judge (Denise Barela Shepherd) has decided that it is somehow NOT a violation of New Mexico&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8220;anti-donation clause&amp;#8221; for the City of Albuquerque to explicitly donation $250,000 of our tax dollars to Planned Parenthood.  Our friends at the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/court-ratifies-city-of-albuquerque-donation-to-planned-parenthood/"&gt;Court ratifies City of Albuquerque donation to Planned Parenthood&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 22:24:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Frightfully pricey treats: Why Halloween fun is costing Georgia families more</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/georgia-halloween-candy-prices/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As Halloween approaches, Georgia families look forward to making great memories involving adorable costumes and fun candy hauls. But candy prices have become nothing short of scary for families trying to make ends meet. Here's why prices are on the rise for Georgia's favorite Halloween treats. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/georgia-halloween-candy-prices/"&gt;Frightfully pricey treats: Why Halloween fun is costing Georgia families more&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 16:01:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Mayor John Horhn: Jackson Rising</title><link>https://empowerms.org/mayor-john-horhn-jackson-rising/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Mayor John Horhn: Jackson Rising What does it take to turn around a city? In this special episode recorded at Jackson City Hall, host Grant Callen talks with Mayor John Horhn about his love for Jackson, the lessons from his childhood and career in public service, and his mission to restore trust, safety, and opportunity&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/mayor-john-horhn-jackson-rising/"&gt;Mayor John Horhn: Jackson Rising&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 01:00:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG Court Watch: Options for Structural Reforms for our Courts</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-court-watch-options-for-structural-reforms-for-our-courts/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;IRG Court Watch: Options for Structural Reforms for our Courts Voters Open to Reform after Multi-Million Dollar, Partisan Judicial Elections Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government’s (IRG)‘s Court Watch initiative released a report, Structural Reform of Judicial Selection in Wisconsin, detailing potential structural reforms to strengthen judicial integrity and public trust in Wisconsin [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-court-watch-options-for-structural-reforms-for-our-courts/"&gt;IRG Court Watch: Options for Structural Reforms for our Courts&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 13:38:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Maine’s 2025 Ballot Questions: What Voters Should Know</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/maines-2025-ballot-questions-what-voters-should-know/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As Maine heads into the 2025 election, voters will face two ballot questions that cut to the heart of the state’s debates over election integrity and gun rights. Both questions resurrect legislative fights that failed in Augusta and are now placed directly before the people. Ballot Question 1: Election Integrity Ballot Summary:“Do you want to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/maines-2025-ballot-questions-what-voters-should-know/"&gt;Maine’s 2025 Ballot Questions: What Voters Should Know&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 21:09:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] WI Speaks Polling Results</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/wi-speaks-survey-results/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WI 1023 Toplines (1) WI 1023 Summary of Key Findings (2) WI 1023 Summary of Key Findings (2)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/wi-speaks-survey-results/"&gt;WI Speaks Polling Results&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 00:18:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Virginiainstitute] Examining HJ6007 and Its Implications for Virginia’s Redistricting Process</title><link>https://virginiainstitute.org/examining-hj6007/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=examining-hj6007</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As lawmakers consider HJ6007, Virginians are asking how the proposal aligns with the 2020 constitutional amendment supporting fair maps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org/examining-hj6007/"&gt;Examining HJ6007 and Its Implications for Virginia’s Redistricting Process&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org"&gt;Virginia Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 01:53:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] NYC Employees Receive $300k+ in Overtime</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/nyc-employees-receive-300k-in-overtime/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Two New York City employees received more than $300,000 in overtime payouts, according to fiscal year 2025 payroll data posted....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/nyc-employees-receive-300k-in-overtime/"&gt;NYC Employees Receive $300k+ in Overtime&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 13:20:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Virginiainstitute] Press Release – HJ 6007: “one of the worst ideas” passed by the General Assembly</title><link>https://virginiainstitute.org/press-release-hj6007/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=press-release-hj6007</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Virginia Institute for Public Policy has expressed concern over HJ6007, a proposed amendment to Virginia’s Constitution that would alter the state’s current redistricting process. The Institute emphasized that Virginia voters approved a bipartisan approach in 2020 to ensure fair and transparent elections for all citizens. Citing constitutional and procedural issues surrounding HJ6007, the Institute encourages lawmakers to uphold established safeguards that protect the integrity and balance of Virginia’s electoral system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org/press-release-hj6007/"&gt;Press Release – HJ 6007: “one of the worst ideas” passed by the General Assembly&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org"&gt;Virginia Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 00:15:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] Average Twin Cities Commuter = 73 Hours Stuck in Traffic</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/average-twin-cities-commuter-73-hours-stuck-in-traffic/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Every year, the Texas A&amp;#38;M Transportation Institute issues a report documenting the price of road congestion on American roads. This 2025 report is notable for Minnesota commuters because it documented that the “average Twin Cities car commuter now spends a record 73 hours a year stuck in traffic.” This is an increase after a COVID-pandemic [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/average-twin-cities-commuter-73-hours-stuck-in-traffic/"&gt;Average Twin Cities Commuter = 73 Hours Stuck in Traffic&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 18:14:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF in National Review: New Mexico’s ‘Free’ Child Care an Attempt to Cover for Past Failures</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-in-national-review-new-mexicos-free-child-care-an-attempt-to-cover-for-past-failures/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following appeared at National Review on November 11, 2025. Child care isn’t cheap, especially once the government gets involved. Recently, New Mexico’s Democratic Governor Michelle Lujan Grisham announced a new plan for taxpayers to fund “free” child care for all New Mexicans, regardless of their income levels. The announcement generated favorable news coverage in [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-in-national-review-new-mexicos-free-child-care-an-attempt-to-cover-for-past-failures/"&gt;RGF in National Review: New Mexico’s ‘Free’ Child Care an Attempt to Cover for Past Failures&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 21:15:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] AEA Has Shown Alabamians Who They Are: Believe Them</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/11/04/aea-has-shown-alabamians-who-they-are-believe-them/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;AEA has worked for decades to stop school choice legislation. AEA actively worked against the passage of the AAA Scholarship program, the PRICE Act, and the CHOOSE Act. AEA used political influence and political contributions to people and parties to weaken parental rights in the CHOOSE Act and then tried to kill the CHOOSE Act unless they could “control the spending” with a cap. Further, AEA worked last legislative session to minimize funding for special needs kids, military kids, and kids whose families are living in poverty; they are currently working against future CHOOSE Act schoolchildren. AEA is trying to render void the promises legislators made to Alabama parents when they passed the law in 2024. They are attempting to undercut the work and the word of Governor Kay Ivey, Lt. Governor Will Ainsworth, Speaker Nathaniel Ledbetter, Chairman Danny Garrett, Chairman Arthur Orr, and each of the ninety-two legislators who voted on behalf of the people they represent for universal school choice for Alabama’s children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/11/04/aea-has-shown-alabamians-who-they-are-believe-them/"&gt;AEA Has Shown Alabamians Who They Are: Believe Them&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 05:04:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] SNAP in Nebraska: Current Rules, Economic Impact, and What’s Next</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/snap-in-nebraska-current-rules-economic-impact-and-whats-next/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Program Overview  The Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP), formerly known as the Food Stamp Program, is the most extensive federal nutrition assistance program in the United States. It serves as a &amp;#8220;safety net&amp;#8221; program that helpslow-income individuals and families access and purchase healthy food. The program is funded by the Department of Agriculture (USDA) and...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/snap-in-nebraska-current-rules-economic-impact-and-whats-next/" rel="nofollow"&gt;SNAP in Nebraska: Current Rules, Economic Impact, and What’s Next&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 16:16:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Nebraska lost $300 million from tax migration in 2022</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-lost-300-million-from-tax-migration-in-2022/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Elections occur every other November. But taxpayers vote with their feet every day, and these votes should be counted and tallied just like the votes for a November election.  A “Great Pandemic Wealth Migration” began when the coronavirus pandemic caused Americans to move to work-from-home employment. This meant workers were no longer tied to aphysical...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-lost-300-million-from-tax-migration-in-2022/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Nebraska lost $300 million from tax migration in 2022&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 19:03:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] November 2025 Beacon Poll Results</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/november-2025-beacon-poll/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=november-2025-beacon-poll</link><description>Today, we released the latest installment of the Beacon Poll, a statewide survey of 1,200 Tennessee voters featuring questions about voters&amp;#8217; views on socialism versus capitalism, the National Guard in Memphis, political violence, and more. In a surprising result that could have a national impact, a majority of Democrats in Tennessee hold a favorable view...</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 13:00:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] California Just Blew Past Last Year’s Record — And We’re Still Climbing</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/california-just-blew-past-last-years-record-and-were-still-climbing/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;California public employees are opting out of their unions in record numbers thanks to the work of the Freedom Foundation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/california-just-blew-past-last-years-record-and-were-still-climbing/" rel="nofollow"&gt;California Just Blew Past Last Year’s Record — And We’re Still Climbing&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 23:30:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] NH’s youngest lawmakers to discuss civility in politics at Civil Discourses kickoff event</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/11/nhs-youngest-lawmakers-to-discuss-civility-in-politics-at-civil-discourses-kickoff-event/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Josiah Bartlett Center for Public Policy will bring a bipartisan group of New Hampshire’s youngest state representatives together on Dec. 1 for a frank and open conversation on the importance of civility in public life.  Josiah Bartlett Center President Andrew Cline will moderate a conversation among:: Rep. Jessica Grill, Democrat of Manchester; Rep. Sam [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/11/nhs-youngest-lawmakers-to-discuss-civility-in-politics-at-civil-discourses-kickoff-event/"&gt;NH&amp;#8217;s youngest lawmakers to discuss civility in politics at Civil Discourses kickoff event&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 13:31:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] ROI-NJ: A blueprint for abundant, affordable energy for New Jersey families | Op-Ed</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/11/roi-nj-a-blueprint-for-abundant-affordable-energy-for-new-jersey-families-op-ed/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A blueprint for abundant, affordable energy for New Jersey families &amp;#124; Op-Ed By Erica Jedynak, New Jersey Policy Institute November [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/11/roi-nj-a-blueprint-for-abundant-affordable-energy-for-new-jersey-families-op-ed/"&gt;ROI-NJ: A blueprint for abundant, affordable energy for New Jersey families | Op-Ed&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 16:11:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] WFSE loses 1,000 members for second consecutive year</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/washington/wfse-loses-1000-members-for-second-consecutive-year/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For the second year in a row, the largest union representing Washington state employees has lost more than 1,000 members, thanks in large part to the ongoing outreach efforts of the Freedom Foundation to help of workers understand their right to opt out of paying union dues.&amp;#160; With annual union dues averaging around $1,000 per [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/washington/wfse-loses-1000-members-for-second-consecutive-year/" rel="nofollow"&gt;WFSE loses 1,000 members for second consecutive year&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 17:55:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] State Tax Competitiveness Index: Minnesota Falls to 44th out of 50!</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/state-tax-competitiveness-index-minnesota-falls-to-44th-out-of-50/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For 20 years, the Tax Foundation has released an annual report evaluating state tax codes – everything from income to property to sales taxes. Each state has its own summary including an interactive map that includes suggestions on how the state could become more competitive. Minnesota state leadership, however appears to be determined for our [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/state-tax-competitiveness-index-minnesota-falls-to-44th-out-of-50/"&gt;State Tax Competitiveness Index: Minnesota Falls to 44th out of 50!&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 19:06:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Budget Update Paints Less Alarming Picture of Federal Health Cuts</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/budget-update-paints-less-alarming-picture/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A new fiscal report from the state Budget Division suggests federal funding cuts will hit New York&amp;#8217;s health-care budget less....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/budget-update-paints-less-alarming-picture/"&gt;Budget Update Paints Less Alarming Picture of Federal Health Cuts&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 14:23:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Will Concord or Laconia reap the rewards of creating NH’s first social district?</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/11/will-concord-or-laconia-reap-the-rewards-of-creating-nhs-first-social-district/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The term “economic growth” seldom pops up in local news stories. But there it was in the third paragraph of the Concord Monitor’s story on Tuesday’s election results.  After quoting a former teacher who complained about the slow pace of change in Concord due to “a lot of governmental, bureaucratic red tape,” the Monitor described [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/11/will-concord-or-laconia-reap-the-rewards-of-creating-nhs-first-social-district/"&gt;Will Concord or Laconia reap the rewards of creating NH&amp;#8217;s first social district?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 17:30:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] Minnesotans Cannot Afford Four More Years of Walz Energy Policy</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/minnesotans-cannot-afford-four-more-years-of-walz-energy-policy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;What happens when working families see electric bills climb to meet the governor’s idealistic demands? By Annette Meeks Gov. Tim Walz officially announced that he wants to serve four more years leading Minnesota. He did not make this announcement in a public meeting, rally or policy speech, but with a carefully crafted video. It was a politically manufactured [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/minnesotans-cannot-afford-four-more-years-of-walz-energy-policy/"&gt;Minnesotans Cannot Afford Four More Years of Walz Energy Policy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 19:02:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Kansas’s Tax Competitiveness Moment</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/kansas-tax-competitiveness/</link><description>Kansas stands in a better position today than it did just a few years ago. According to the Tax Foundation’s 2026 State Tax Competitiveness Index, the state now ranks 23rd overall in the nation. That’s respectable progress, but in a country where states are competing aggressively for people, jobs, and investment, “respectable” isn’t enough. The [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 16:00:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] The fantasy that cutting prison populations saves a lot of money</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/the-fantasy-that-cutting-prison-populations-saves-a-lot-of-money/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/the-fantasy-that-cutting-prison-populations-saves-a-lot-of-money/"&gt;The fantasy that cutting prison populations saves a lot of money&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 16:02:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Those Dark Clouds are the Debt</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/those-dark-clouds-are-the-debt/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The future for our state looks bright.  In just the past five years, Mississippi has seen more economic growth than in the entire fifteen years before that combined. We’re on track to phase out the state income tax entirely, allowing families to keep more of what they earn.  Mississippi has attracted a surge of new investment, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/those-dark-clouds-are-the-debt/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Those Dark Clouds are the Debt&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 18:39:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] New Report: Shapiro’s ‘Get Sh*t Done’ Slogan Doesn’t Match His Record</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/11/10/shapiro-get-sht-done-slogan-doesnt-match-record/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Gov. Josh Shapiro remains Pennsylvania’s least legislatively productive governor in the past 50 years. Harrisburg, Pa., November 10, 2025 — As presidential ambitions of Pennsylvania’s 48th governor become increasingly prominent, many question: Is Governor Shapiro as productive as he claims? A new report from the Commonwealth Foundation found Gov. Josh Shapiro to be the least [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/11/10/shapiro-get-sht-done-slogan-doesnt-match-record/"&gt;New Report: Shapiro’s ‘Get Sh*t Done’ Slogan Doesn’t Match His Record&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 19:58:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Shutdown Endgame: What the Deal Means for Maine and the Nation</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/shutdown-endgame-what-the-deal-means-for-maine-and-the-nation/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;After more than 40 days, the longest government shutdown in American history appears to be nearing an end. The Senate voted 60–40 on a short-term funding bill that would reopen shuttered federal agencies and extend operations through late January. In a rare show of bipartisanship, eight Democrats, including Senator Angus King, joined Republicans to advance [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/shutdown-endgame-what-the-deal-means-for-maine-and-the-nation/"&gt;Shutdown Endgame: What the Deal Means for Maine and the Nation&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 01:28:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] What You Need To Know For Special Session</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/11/11/what-you-need-to-know-for-special-session/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="1216" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/Screenshot-2025-08-19-134951.jpg" width="1736" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connecticut lawmakers are moving quickly in a special session — tackling housing, emergency spending, and healthcare policy from Nov. 12-13. Some proposals represent steps in the right direction. Others risk [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/11/11/what-you-need-to-know-for-special-session/"&gt;What You Need To Know For Special Session&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 15:50:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] DPI Rates 0 Districts 1 Star, Half of All Schools 4 or 5 Stars on New School Report Cards</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/dpi-rates-0-districts-1-star-half-of-all-schools-4-or-5-stars-on-new-school-report-cards/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;DPI Rates 0 Districts 1 Star, Half of All Schools 4 or 5 Stars on New School Report Cards DPI’s rankings make report cards mostly meaningless  Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government (IRG) released the following statement following the release of 2025 district and school report cards using a lenient formula, resulting in [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/dpi-rates-0-districts-1-star-half-of-all-schools-4-or-5-stars-on-new-school-report-cards/"&gt;DPI Rates 0 Districts 1 Star, Half of All Schools 4 or 5 Stars on New School Report Cards&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 17:31:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] NJBIZ: OPINION: Why New Jersey should repeal its bag ban</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/11/njbiz-opinion-why-new-jersey-should-repeal-its-bag-ban-wells-winegar/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;OPINION: Why New Jersey should repeal its bag ban by Wells Winegar November 10, 2025 &amp;#160; Walk into any New [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/11/njbiz-opinion-why-new-jersey-should-repeal-its-bag-ban-wells-winegar/"&gt;NJBIZ: OPINION: Why New Jersey should repeal its bag ban&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 18:56:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] TriMet Retreat Should Focus on Crisis, Not Expansion</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/transportation/trimet-retreat-should-focus-on-crisis-not-expansion/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By John A. Charles, Jr. On November 12, the TriMet Board will hold...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/transportation/trimet-retreat-should-focus-on-crisis-not-expansion/"&gt;TriMet Retreat Should Focus on Crisis, Not Expansion &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 22:56:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Dr. Brad Wilcox: Get Married</title><link>https://empowerms.org/dr-brad-wilcox-get-married/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Dr. Brad Wilcox: Get Married On this episode of The Empower Podcast, host Grant Callen talks with Dr. Brad Wilcox, Director of the National Marriage Project at the University of Virginia and author of Get Married: Why Americans Must Defy the Elites, Forge Strong Families, and Save Civilization. Dr. Wilcox shares striking research on how&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/dr-brad-wilcox-get-married/"&gt;Dr. Brad Wilcox: Get Married&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 00:00:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] UK Uni. of St Andrews’ Sir Hew Strachan on the First World War</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/uk-uni-of-st-andrews-sir-hew-strachan-on-the-first-world-war/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In this week’s episode of The Learning Curve, co-hosts U-Arkansas Prof. Albert Cheng and Center for Strong Public Schools’ Alisha Searcy speak with Sir Hew Strachan, Professor of International Relations at the University of St Andrews, Scotland, and recipient of the 2016 Pritzker Literature Award for Lifetime Achievement in Military Writing. Prof. Sir Hew, author of numerous award-winning books, including The First World War, the basis of the definitive 10-part Channel 4/BBC documentary, discusses how World War I shaped the 20th century and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/uk-uni-of-st-andrews-sir-hew-strachan-on-the-first-world-war/"&gt;UK Uni. of St Andrews&amp;#8217; Sir Hew Strachan on the First World War&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 16:56:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] Rio Grande Foundation Soiree a Huge Success!</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rio-grande-foundation-soiree-a-huge-success/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;What do you call 175 freedom loving New Mexicans gathered in one place? A good start! In all seriousness the Rio Grande Foundation hosted its 25th anniversary Laissez Faire Soiree this past Saturday night and we are pleased to report  the event was a smashing success with 175 attendees and lots of fun. Thanks to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rio-grande-foundation-soiree-a-huge-success/"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation Soiree a Huge Success!&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 19:40:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] Despite Shapiro’s Failed Leadership, 2025-26 Budget Secures Key Permitting Wins, Ends Threat of RGGI</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/11/12/pennsylvania-2025-26-budget-secures-key-permitting-wins-ends-rggi/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Harrisburg, Pa., November 12,&amp;#160;2025 —&amp;#160;Despite Gov. Josh Shapiro’s failed leadership and a 135-day stalemate, Pennsylvania lawmakers passed a compromise budget for the 2025–2026 fiscal year. The Commonwealth Foundation has released a comprehensive analysis of the newly passed budget, available here. The budget, totaling $50.09 billion, includes a 5.1 percent spending increase. While the agreement includes [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/11/12/pennsylvania-2025-26-budget-secures-key-permitting-wins-ends-rggi/"&gt;Despite Shapiro&amp;#8217;s Failed Leadership, 2025-26 Budget Secures Key Permitting Wins, Ends Threat of RGGI&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 19:42:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Volunteering for Higher Taxes? Assessing Tennessee’s Uncapped Property Taxes</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/volunteering-for-higher-taxes-assessing-tennessees-uncapped-property-taxes/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=volunteering-for-higher-taxes-assessing-tennessees-uncapped-property-taxes</link><description>If Tennessee wants to protect its residents in all aspects and truly take claim to being a low-tax state, lawmakers should look around the nation and see that we are in the small minority that fails to protect citizens from unjust property tax hikes.</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 19:52:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alaskapolicyforum] Is Anchorage’s New Proposed “Short-Term Rental-Only” Tax Really the Answer?</title><link>https://alaskapolicyforum.org/2025/11/is-anchorages-new-proposed-short-term-rental-only-tax-really-the-answer/#utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=is-anchorages-new-proposed-short-term-rental-only-tax-really-the-answer</link><description>&lt;div style="margin: 5px 5% 10px 5%;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" height="675" src="https://alaskapolicyforum.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/jon-tyson-XS_o-Iuf9Go-unsplash-scaled-e1762980183585.jpg" title="" width="506" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This blog looks at an urgent issue for Anchorage, which is considering a new short-term rental tax next week. That may seem like an easy fix for housing, but in reality, it raises seriousRead More&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alaskapolicyforum.org/2025/11/is-anchorages-new-proposed-short-term-rental-only-tax-really-the-answer/"&gt;Is Anchorage’s New Proposed “Short-Term Rental-Only” Tax Really the Answer?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://alaskapolicyforum.org"&gt;Alaska Policy Forum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 21:06:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] WILL Defends Rights of Christian Parent in Charter School Curriculum Controversy</title><link>https://will-law.org/will-defends-rights-of-christian-parent-in-charter-school-curriculum-controversy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On behalf of a Wisconsin parent, WILL has notified Lighthouse Learning Academy that it is prepared to take legal action over the school's refusal to provide certain curriculum materials, even though most of the items requested were non-religious, simply because some were created by a Christian publisher or contained a few religious references.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/will-defends-rights-of-christian-parent-in-charter-school-curriculum-controversy/"&gt;WILL Defends Rights of Christian Parent in Charter School Curriculum Controversy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 21:07:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Most UW System schools’ enrollments are stagnant as tech colleges flourish</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/most-uw-system-schools-enrollments-are-stagnant-as-tech-colleges-flourish/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;While undergraduate enrollment in most University of Wisconsin System schools trends downward, there has been a dramatic increase in students choosing the state’s technical colleges since the pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/most-uw-system-schools-enrollments-are-stagnant-as-tech-colleges-flourish/"&gt;Most UW System schools’ enrollments are stagnant as tech colleges flourish&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 22:08:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Multnomah Audit Finds Fraud in Construction Recycling</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/economic-opportunity/multnomah-audit-finds-fraud-in-construction-recycling/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Naomi Inman What happens to all that construction debris on public works...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/economic-opportunity/multnomah-audit-finds-fraud-in-construction-recycling/"&gt;Multnomah Audit Finds Fraud in Construction Recycling&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 17:13:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] The RGGI trap</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/11/the-rggi-trap/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;According to national media reports, Pennsylvania’s 2025 budget deal caused the state to “exit” RGGI. Media coverage also used the words “leave,” “quit” and “pull out” to describe Pennsylvania’s abandonment of RGGI. Pennsylvania, though, wasn’t actually a member of RGGI.  In 2019, then-Gov. Tom Wolf issued an executive order for his administration to adopt regulations [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/11/the-rggi-trap/"&gt;The RGGI trap&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 20:15:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Before the Ink Dried, the Union Was Already Calling the Shots at Waterbury Hospital</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/11/14/before-the-ink-dried-the-union-was-already-calling-the-shots-at-waterbury-hospital/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bill authorizing UConn Health to purchase Waterbury Hospital wasn’t even written when one of Connecticut’s most politically influential healthcare unions began issuing demands.   On Oct. 17 — weeks before [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/11/14/before-the-ink-dried-the-union-was-already-calling-the-shots-at-waterbury-hospital/"&gt;Before the Ink Dried, the Union Was Already Calling the Shots at Waterbury Hospital&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 20:33:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] A legacy of healing — Documentary tells ReCAST Lawrenceville’s journey through residents’ stories</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/recast-lawrenceville-documentary/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/recast-lawrenceville-documentary/"&gt;A legacy of healing — Documentary tells ReCAST Lawrenceville’s journey through residents’ stories&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:43:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] 3 Things to Know About the Lawsuit Challenging Louisiana’s Act 409</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/legal-regulatory/3-things-to-know-about-the-lawsuit-challenging-louisianas-act-409/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;1. What Is Louisiana’s Act 409 (“Charlie’s Law”)? Everyone can agree that child safety matters—especially for three- and four-year-olds in pre-K programs. Act 409, a.k.a Charlie’s Law was intended to strengthen safety by adding new licensing and operational requirements to certain prekindergarten programs. What changed: Schools covered by Act 409 must now meet many of...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/legal-regulatory/3-things-to-know-about-the-lawsuit-challenging-louisianas-act-409/"&gt;3 Things to Know About the Lawsuit Challenging Louisiana’s Act 409&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 14:31:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] New Jersey Policy Institute Announces Inaugural Class of 2026 Junior Fellows</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/11/new-jersey-policy-institute-announces-inaugural-class-of-2026-junior-fellows/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Parsippany, NJ – The New Jersey Policy Institute (NJPI) is proud to announce the inaugural class of its 2026 Junior Fellowship [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/11/new-jersey-policy-institute-announces-inaugural-class-of-2026-junior-fellows/"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute Announces Inaugural Class of 2026 Junior Fellows&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 18:43:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] New WILL Lawsuit Targets the Beating Heart of Federal DEI Programs</title><link>https://will-law.org/new-will-lawsuit-targets-the-beating-heart-of-federal-dei-programs/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL and the Center for Individual Rights (CIR) filed a major lawsuit against the Trump Administration today, targeting the foundation for many of the remaining federal DEI programs: the preference for so-called “socially disadvantaged individuals.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/new-will-lawsuit-targets-the-beating-heart-of-federal-dei-programs/"&gt;New WILL Lawsuit Targets the Beating Heart of Federal DEI Programs&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 20:38:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Kansas Doesn’t Need to Play Ball With Corporate Welfare</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/kansas-doesnt-need-to-play-ball/</link><description>Taxpayers want markets, not handouts, to drive growth A new SurveyUSA poll of Overland Park and Leawood residents confirms what many Kansans already feel in their gut: people love their teams, but their desire to spend tax dollars on it declines as the taxes hit closer to home.  When asked if the state should use [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 22:00:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Mississippi Voters Demand Universal School Choice – New Poll Shows Overwhelming Support</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/mississippi-voters-demand-universal-school-choice-new-poll-shows-overwhelming-support/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Big news on School Choice this week!&amp;#160; A fresh poll shows massive support in Mississippi to have&amp;#160;families, not government, control their child’s education.&amp;#160; Mississippi voters say they’ll reward lawmakers who make it happen. The brand-new statewide survey (October 27-30, 2025) conducted by The Tarrance Group shows&amp;#160;rock-solid support&amp;#160;for expanding education freedom.&amp;#160; There is massive bipartisan support [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/mississippi-voters-demand-universal-school-choice-new-poll-shows-overwhelming-support/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Voters Demand Universal School Choice – New Poll Shows Overwhelming Support&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 22:06:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Washington employers are sounding the alarm. Will lawmakers listen?</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/washington-employers-are-sounding-the-alarm-will-lawmakers-listen</link><description>If you have ever wondered how many warning flares Washington policymakers need before they stop piling new taxes on employers, the answer is always, “At least one more.” An Association of Washington Business (AWB) survey  of more than 400 employers is just the latest indicator that Washington’s tax climate is stifling confidence, investment, and growth. Sixty-five percent of employers now list taxes as their top concern, up from 58 percent just months ago. Roughly three out of four businesses...</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 15:27:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Fighting For Government Transparency at the Arizona Supreme Court</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/fighting-for-government-transparency-at-the-arizona-supreme-court/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Transparency is the rule for public records in Arizona, and for good reason: sunshine, as the saying goes, is the..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/fighting-for-government-transparency-at-the-arizona-supreme-court/"&gt;Fighting For Government Transparency at the Arizona Supreme Court&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 19:38:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] A blueprint for property tax reform in Iowa</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/a-blueprint-for-property-tax-reform-in-iowa/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="A blueprint for property tax reform in Iowa" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/the-gazette-1200x630-1.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just a few years ago, the Tax Foundation ranked Iowa among the worst states for business tax climates. In 2020, Iowa placed 43rd in the State Tax Competitiveness Index. Thanks to the pro-growth policies of Gov. Kim Reynolds and the Legislature, Iowa has since climbed to 17th — a remarkable improvement. Yet despite this progress, Iowa still ranks 33rd nationally in property tax burden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/a-blueprint-for-property-tax-reform-in-iowa/"&gt;A blueprint for property tax reform in Iowa&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 20:53:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] McGowan:  Other Pitchers Who Could Hit</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/11/mcgowan-other-pitchers-who-could-hit/</link><description>by Richard McGowan, Ph.D. Now that the final 2025 MLB baseball game has been played, fans can start dissecting the past season.&amp;#160; Of course, that also means examining the media coverage of the season, especially during the&amp;#160; playoffs. Some observations easily avail themselves.&amp;#160; If Ohtani’s greatness is owed in part to his being a two-way&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/11/mcgowan-other-pitchers-who-could-hit/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 22:37:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Repealing Medicaid Expansion Is the Right Move for Idaho</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/repealing-medicaid-expansion-is-the-right-move-for-idaho/</link><description>The term cognitive dissonance is applied to people who hold two conflicting beliefs in their heads at the same time. In no other public policy is this more apparent than how Idaho has handled the topic of Medicaid expansion to able-bodied adults in Idaho. Let’s provide some details: Right out of the gate, in its [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 22:57:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Michigan can easily handle adding data centers</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/michigan-can-easily-handle-adding-data-centers</link><description>Do you realize how much more water we use in other activities?</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Study: Accessory Dwelling Units Now Legal Statewide, but Construction Still Lags</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/economic_opportunity/study-accessory-dwelling-units-now-legal-statewide-but-construction-still-lags/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;BOSTON – Even after statewide legalization in 2024, production of accessory dwelling units (ADUs) in Massachusetts remains far from that of other states due to local zoning and permitting practices that continue to discourage development, according to a new Pioneer Institute study. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/economic_opportunity/study-accessory-dwelling-units-now-legal-statewide-but-construction-still-lags/"&gt;Study: Accessory Dwelling Units Now Legal Statewide, but Construction Still Lags&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 12:51:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Biden’s green energy fiasco, not Trump’s reforms, is jacking up your electric bill</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/bidens-green-energy-fiasco-not-trumps-reforms-is-jacking-up-your-electric-bill/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;California&amp;#8217;s 127% price surge since 2010 exposes costly reality behind wind and solar power. There’s a battle to define a narrative about what’s to blame for rising electricity prices. Some claim higher electricity prices are due to President Donald Trump’s &amp;#8220;one big beautiful bill,&amp;#8221; which curtailed subsidies for &amp;#8220;cheap&amp;#8221; wind and solar installations. Others blame AI’s...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/bidens-green-energy-fiasco-not-trumps-reforms-is-jacking-up-your-electric-bill/"&gt;Biden’s green energy fiasco, not Trump’s reforms, is jacking up your electric bill&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 14:53:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Statement From The James Madison Institute on the District Court Ruling in FTC v. Meta</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/statement-from-the-james-madison-institute-on-the-district-court-ruling-in-ftc-v-meta/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE November 19, 2025 CONTACT Nicole Kiser (850) 386-3131 TALLAHASSEE — Yesterday, the U.S. District Court...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/statement-from-the-james-madison-institute-on-the-district-court-ruling-in-ftc-v-meta/"&gt;Statement From The James Madison Institute on the District Court Ruling in FTC v. Meta&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 15:14:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] New federal court case confirms that Montana should join the call for an Amendments Convention</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/new-federal-court-case-confirms-that-montana-should-join-the-call-for-an-amendments-convention</link><description>On November 5, a federal district court decided Thompson v. Masterson . The decision may put to rest objections in the Montana legislature to calling for a “convention of states” to address the federal government’s dysfunction.   To understand why, let’s start with some history:   The delegates to the 1787 Constitutional Convention recognized that America needed more powerful federal institutions. But they also recognized that power can be abused and misused. So they inserted checks and...</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 15:17:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Houston Supt. Mike Miles on Urban School District Reform</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/learning-curve/houston-supt-mike-miles-on-urban-school-district-reform/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In this week’s episode of The Learning Curve, co-hosts Great Heart Academies’ Dr. Helen Baxendale and American Federation for Children’s Shaka Mitchell speak with Mike Miles, superintendent of the Houston Independent School District. Miles has devoted his life to public service, starting as a soldier, then as a diplomat in Poland and Russia during the Cold War before moving into K-12 education reform. He discussed how his family background and early educational experiences shaped his commitment to service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/learning-curve/houston-supt-mike-miles-on-urban-school-district-reform/"&gt;Houston Supt. Mike Miles on Urban School District Reform&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 15:29:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Aaron Withe Statement on Trump Administration’s Bold Action to Dismantle Education Bureaucracy</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/education/aaron-withe-statement-on-trump-administrations-bold-action-to-dismantle-education-bureaucracy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Freedom Foundation CEO and Teacher Freedom Alliance President Aaron Withe issued the following statement regarding President Trump’s plans to dismantle the Department of Education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/education/aaron-withe-statement-on-trump-administrations-bold-action-to-dismantle-education-bureaucracy/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Aaron Withe Statement on Trump Administration&amp;#8217;s Bold Action to Dismantle Education Bureaucracy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 16:15:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Congress Must Act: Preempt State AI Patchwork to Fuel America’s—and Louisiana’s—Innovation Fire</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/congress-must-act-preempt-state-ai-patchwork-to-fuel-americas-and-louisianas-innovation-fire/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As the National Defense Authorization Act (NDAA) barrels toward a December showdown, House Republicans, led by Louisiana’s own Speaker Mike Johnson and Majority Leader Steve Scalise, are considering a much-needed moratorium on state AI regulations. This echoes President Donald J. Trump’s urgent X post: “Investment in AI is helping to make the U.S. Economy the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/congress-must-act-preempt-state-ai-patchwork-to-fuel-americas-and-louisianas-innovation-fire/"&gt;Congress Must Act: Preempt State AI Patchwork to Fuel America’s—and Louisiana’s—Innovation Fire&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 18:54:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Mississippi is globally recognized!</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/mississippi-is-globally-recognized/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/mississippi-is-globally-recognized/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi is globally recognized!&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 18:55:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Capital Young Professionals Gathering</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/capital-young-professionals-gathering/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;JMI, Red Hills Strategies, and Floridian Partners are back with another Capital Young Professionals Gathering on December 3....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/capital-young-professionals-gathering/"&gt;Capital Young Professionals Gathering&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 19:14:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Permit family dwellings by right in mixed-use, commercial zones</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/11/permit-family-dwellings-by-right-in-mixed-use-commercial-zones/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Hawaii County Council on Nov. 19, 2025._____________ Nov. 19, 2025, 11 a.m.Hawai‘i County Council Chambers in Hilo To: Hawai‘i County Council       Holeka Goro Inaba, Chair       Dennis “Fresh” Onishi, Vice Chair From: Grassroot Institute of Hawaii            Jonathan Helton, Policy Analyst RE: [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/11/permit-family-dwellings-by-right-in-mixed-use-commercial-zones/"&gt;Permit family dwellings by right in mixed-use, commercial zones&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 19:44:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Allow Hawaii Island backyard henneries, revisit income potential</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/11/allow-hawaii-island-backyard-henneries-revisit-income-potential/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Hawaii County Council on Nov. 19, 2025._____________ Nov. 19, 2025, 11 a.m.Hawai‘i County Council Chambers in Hilo To: Hawai‘i County Council       Holeka Goro Inaba, Chair       Dennis “Fresh” Onishi, Vice Chair From: Grassroot Institute of Hawaii            Jonathan Helton, Policy Analyst RE: [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/11/allow-hawaii-island-backyard-henneries-revisit-income-potential/"&gt;Allow Hawaii Island backyard henneries, revisit income potential&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 19:45:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Allow taxicabs to keep up with inflation, industry competition</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/11/allow-taxicabs-to-keep-up-with-inflation-industry-competition/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Honolulu City Council Committee on Infrastructure, Transportation and Technology on Nov. 19, 2025._____________ Nov. 19, 2025, 9 a.m.Honolulu Hale To: Honolulu City Council Committee on Infrastructure, Transportation and Technology&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Radiant Cordero, Chair&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Val Okimoto, Vice Chair From: Grassroot Institute of [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/11/allow-taxicabs-to-keep-up-with-inflation-industry-competition/"&gt;Allow taxicabs to keep up with inflation, industry competition&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 19:45:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] How a Parody of Citizen Government Turned California Into a Hyper-Gerrymandered State</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/how-a-parody-of-citizen-government-turned-california-into-a-hyper-gerrymandered-state/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=how-a-parody-of-citizen-government-turned-california-into-a-hyper-gerrymandered-state</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Ballot initiatives are supposed to empower the people to stand up to moneyed special interests. Fifteen states permit the people to pass laws and amend their state constitutions by popular vote. A fixture in California politics since 1914, the citizen ballot initiative enabled notable victories for the Californians, perhaps most notably Proposition 13 in 1978,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/how-a-parody-of-citizen-government-turned-california-into-a-hyper-gerrymandered-state/"&gt;How a Parody of Citizen Government Turned California Into a Hyper-Gerrymandered State&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 19:55:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] WILL Applauds Wisconsin Assembly for Passing Important Education Reforms</title><link>https://will-law.org/will-applauds-wisconsin-assembly-for-passing-important-education-reforms/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL applauded the Wisconsin State Assembly for its action in passing two important education reforms: the Wisconsin Teacher Bill of Rights (AB 614) and the Federal Scholarship Tax Credit Opt-in Bill (AB 602).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/will-applauds-wisconsin-assembly-for-passing-important-education-reforms/"&gt;WILL Applauds Wisconsin Assembly for Passing Important Education Reforms&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 21:42:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Departments Aren’t Banks – Nor Legislatures</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/departments-arent-banks-nor-legislatures/</link><description>Did you know that many Idaho government agencies are sitting on hundreds of millions of your tax dollars with no obligations or direction on how to spend them? Single departments are sitting on cash balances large enough to cover the State of Idaho’s so-called deficit, itself a symptom of government excess. Money just sitting there, [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 22:30:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Shifting Costs Does Not Solve California’s Electricity Shortages</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/shifting-costs-does-not-solve-californias-electricity-shortages/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=shifting-costs-does-not-solve-californias-electricity-shortages</link><description>&lt;p&gt;California’s Little Hoover Commission was created in 1962 “as an independent and bipartisan state agency charged with making recommendations to the governor and Legislature on ways to make state programs more efficient.” Funded by taxpayers, officially nonpartisan, they’ve just released a set of recommendations to lower “The High Cost of Electricity in California.” They’re right about the high...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/shifting-costs-does-not-solve-californias-electricity-shortages/"&gt;Shifting Costs Does Not Solve California’s Electricity Shortages&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 04:03:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Smarter rules and better schools could get Michigan back on its feet</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/smarter-rules-and-better-schools-could-get-michigan-back-on-its-feet</link><description>Business Leaders for Michigan report has some good suggestions</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Republican candidates join nationwide scrutiny of tenure</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/republican-candidates-join-nationwide-scrutiny-of-tenure/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Republican candidates for Wisconsin governor are joining politicians across the country who are increasingly skeptical of tenure guarantees for professors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/republican-candidates-join-nationwide-scrutiny-of-tenure/"&gt;Republican candidates join nationwide scrutiny of tenure&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 11:07:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Wisconsin DPI mired in one scandal after another</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/wisconsin-dpi-mired-in-one-scandal-after-another/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Wisconsin Department of Public Instruction is facing a crisis of confidence after accusations of gutting academic standards, manipulating report cards, slacking on fiscal oversight and bungling oversight of sexual misconduct among teachers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/wisconsin-dpi-mired-in-one-scandal-after-another/"&gt;Wisconsin DPI mired in one scandal after another&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 12:16:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Newly Retired NYPD Retirees Average $100,000+ in Pension</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/newly-retired-nypd-retirees-average-100000-in-pension/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Newly retired1 “full career”2 members of the New York Police Department (NYPD) collected an average of $103,859, according to new....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/newly-retired-nypd-retirees-average-100000-in-pension/"&gt;Newly Retired NYPD Retirees Average $100,000+ in Pension&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 14:07:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] “Inspire Oregon” Tackles Rural Housing Crisis</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/land-use/inspire-oregon-tackles-rural-housing-crisis/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Madilynne Clark The University of Oregon’s Institute for Policy Research and Engagement...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/land-use/inspire-oregon-tackles-rural-housing-crisis/"&gt;“Inspire Oregon” Tackles Rural Housing Crisis&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Maine Human Rights Commission’s New Lawsuit a State-Level Battle in a National Storm</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/maine-human-rights-commissions-new-lawsuit-a-state-level-battle-in-a-national-storm/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On November 17, the Maine Human Rights Commission (MHRC) filed suit against five school systems, MSAD 70, RSU 24, RSU 73, Baileyville and Richmond, arguing that their recently enacted “biological sex” policies violate the Maine Human Rights Act (MHRA). The Commission is suing on its own authority, not through the Attorney General, and its core [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/maine-human-rights-commissions-new-lawsuit-a-state-level-battle-in-a-national-storm/"&gt;Maine Human Rights Commission’s New Lawsuit a State-Level Battle in a National Storm&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 17:27:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] BEAD the Call: What the First Four Years of BEAD can Teach Us</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/bead-the-call-what-the-first-four-years-of-bead-can-teach-us/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Broadband Equity Access and Deployment program (BEAD) has followed a long and winding road since its inception in 2021. Nationally, the final approval process for receiving BEAD funding is still ongoing, but one takeaway has become evident: competition and innovation, not red tape regulations, are the key to unlocking fast and accessible internet. Louisiana...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/bead-the-call-what-the-first-four-years-of-bead-can-teach-us/"&gt;BEAD the Call: What the First Four Years of BEAD can Teach Us&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 17:36:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Union Cronies Wanted: Goldwater Fights University of Rhode Island’s Illegal Hiring Preferences</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/union-cronies-wanted-goldwater-fights-university-of-rhode-islands-illegal-hiring-preferences/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When she saw a job posting for an administrative assistant at the University of Rhode Island near her home, Nicole Solas had..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/union-cronies-wanted-goldwater-fights-university-of-rhode-islands-illegal-hiring-preferences/"&gt;Union Cronies Wanted: Goldwater Fights University of Rhode Island’s Illegal Hiring Preferences&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:25:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Chicago Teachers Union radicalism is officially statewide</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/chicago-teachers-union-radicalism-is-officially-statewide-2/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Chicago Teachers Union President Stacy Davis Gates is bringing her militant agenda to 200 more school districts as president of the Illinois Federation of Teachers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/chicago-teachers-union-radicalism-is-officially-statewide-2/"&gt;Chicago Teachers Union radicalism is officially statewide&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:37:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Congress Should Embrace Competition To Promote Affordability</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/congress-should-embrace-competition-to-promote-affordability/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Joining the Senate, the U.S. House of Representatives is now taking up the problem of skyrocketing healthcare costs. Democrats have proposed extending the expanded subsidies for the Affordable Care Act (aka, Obamacare or ACA), but this will not address the problem of rising costs. Promoting greater healthcare affordability requires reforms that promote competition and empowers [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/congress-should-embrace-competition-to-promote-affordability/"&gt;Congress Should Embrace Competition To Promote Affordability&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 19:11:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/11/the-outstater-306/</link><description>Redistricting Disassembled O, beware, my lord, of jealousy;It is the green-eyed monster, which doth mockThe meat it feeds on.&amp;#8221; (Othello 3.3.165-167)  THERE IS A WAY to make sense of the Republican rift over redistricting. You start by eliminating all the stated explanations: Which leaves us with what is at the heart of every political story —&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/11/the-outstater-306/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 19:21:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Tennessee Tax System &amp; Reform Efforts Webinar</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/tennessee-tax-system-reform-efforts-webinar/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=tennessee-tax-system-reform-efforts-webinar</link><description>Join the Beacon Center for a timely discussion on Tennessee’s tax system, ongoing reform efforts, and how tax policy impacts families, workers, and businesses across the state. We’ll be joined by a panel of experts: Carey Bringle, Nashville business owner Patrick Gleason, Americans for Tax Reform, Beacon Senior Fellow for Tax Policy Justin Owen, CEO,...</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 20:38:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] How to get Idaho’s State Spending Back on Track</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/how-to-get-idahos-state-spending-back-on-track/</link><description>Sometimes, events suggest action. At other times, they require action. As has been widely reported and we have written about, Idaho’s state government faces a growing deficit for the upcoming fiscal year based on current revenue projections. We did not have to get to this point. Had spending restraints been built into the budget process, [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 21:26:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Shocker! Kansas City’s Affordable Housing Set-Asides Nets Zero Housing Units</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/municipal-policy/shocker-kansas-citys-affordable-housing-set-asides-nets-zero-housing-units/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In 2021, Kansas City passed an ordinance requiring large market-rate apartment developments to either set aside 20% of units at [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/municipal-policy/shocker-kansas-citys-affordable-housing-set-asides-nets-zero-housing-units/"&gt;Shocker! Kansas City’s Affordable Housing Set-Asides Nets Zero Housing Units&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 21:36:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Civics Education Update</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/civics-education-update/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=civics-education-update</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The latest news on history, civics, and patriotism in our public schools is a mixed bag. In the early days of our republic, George Washington understood that civic education was essential for preserving freedom. More recently, the late Supreme Court Justice Sandra Day O’Connor reminded us that civic knowledge isn’t inherited genetically but must be...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/civics-education-update/"&gt;Civics Education Update&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 22:24:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] What the Government Shutdown Was Really About with Elias Tsapelas</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/health-care/what-the-government-shutdown-was-really-about-with-elias-tsapelas/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Susan Pendergrass is joined by Elias Tsapelas, director of state budget and fiscal policy at the Show-Me Institute, to explain [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/health-care/what-the-government-shutdown-was-really-about-with-elias-tsapelas/"&gt;What the Government Shutdown Was Really About with Elias Tsapelas&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 22:31:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Trump Has a Subsidy Alternative, We Should Take it Seriously</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/trump-has-a-subsidy-alternative-we-should-take-it-seriously/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In a social media post earlier this month, President Trump laid out his own alternative to the enhanced Obamacare subsidies that fueled the record-breaking 43-day government shutdown. &amp;#8220;I am recommending to Senate Republicans that the Hundreds of Billions of Dollars currently being sent to money sucking Insurance Companies in order to save the bad Healthcare [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/trump-has-a-subsidy-alternative-we-should-take-it-seriously/"&gt;Trump Has a Subsidy Alternative, We Should Take it Seriously&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 22:38:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] MSPC Welcomes Scholar Rob Natelson as Senior Fellow in Constitutional Jurisprudence</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/mspc-welcomes-scholar-robert-g-natelson-as-senior-fellow-in-constitutional-jurisprudence</link><description>One of America’s most respected constitutional scholars, his addition represents a major advance for MSPC and significantly expands the organization’s legal and constitutional research capacity.</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 04:26:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Privatizing the loo: A solution for cities’ restroom debacle?</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/privatizing-the-loo-a-solution-for-cities-restroom-debacle/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Privatizing the loo: A solution for cities’ restroom debacle? By D. Dowd Muska &amp;#124; November 21, 2025 Spend enough time researching the subject, and one can be forgiven for abandoning all hope. Simply put, America’s public restrooms are a disaster. First, there aren’t enough of them. Writer Quinn O’Callaghan considers the lack of options when [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/privatizing-the-loo-a-solution-for-cities-restroom-debacle/"&gt;Privatizing the loo: A solution for cities’ restroom debacle?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 10:12:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Democrats’ violent rhetoric will impact midterms</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/democrats-violent-rhetoric-will-impact-midterms/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;M.D. Kittle writes for the Federalist about the impact of Democrats’ over-the-top rhetoric and actions. On Sept. 12, Rep. Eugene Vindman joined fellow Virginia congressional Democrats in condemning political violence. Said condemnation came two days after an assassin murdered conservative icon Charlie Kirk while he was speaking at a free speech event in Utah.&amp;#160; “The...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/democrats-violent-rhetoric-will-impact-midterms/"&gt;Democrats&amp;#8217; violent rhetoric will impact midterms&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 10:39:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] DEI dogma contributes to Michelle Obama’s odd complaints</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/dei-dogma-contributes-to-michelle-obamas-odd-complaints/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Victor Davis Hanson explores a key source of a former first lady’s woes. Diversity, Equity, and Inclusion (DEI) is a euphemism for a rigid racialist theology. It deductively postulates that a large percentage of the population is oppressed by racism and sexism, mostly by white males. DEI makes no allowance for the class or wealth...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/dei-dogma-contributes-to-michelle-obamas-odd-complaints/"&gt;DEI dogma contributes to Michelle Obama&amp;#8217;s odd complaints&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 10:42:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Union Township metrics point to stagnation, decline</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/union-township-metrics-point-to-stagnation-decline</link><description>Population declines as taxable value falls behind</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Illinois can’t afford to miss out on 10,000 extra homes</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/illinois-cant-afford-to-miss-out-on-10000-extra-homes/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Families rely on single-family homes. Illinois must relax zoning laws and lower minimum lot sizes to make them more affordable statewide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/illinois-cant-afford-to-miss-out-on-10000-extra-homes/"&gt;Illinois can’t afford to miss out on 10,000 extra homes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 11:00:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Illinois lawmakers again push disguised ‘retirement tax’</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/illinois-lawmakers-again-push-disguised-retirement-tax/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Illinois voters soundly rejected a progressive state income tax because it was a path to tax retirees. That isn’t stopping state lawmakers from trying again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/illinois-lawmakers-again-push-disguised-retirement-tax/"&gt;Illinois lawmakers again push disguised ‘retirement tax’&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 11:00:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Hayek Saw It Coming: Why Centralized Education Was Destined to Fail</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/hayek-saw-it-coming-why-centralized-education-was-destined-to-fail/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;“The Department of Education is being torn apart in real time,” the New York Times declared this week. The Trump administration has kicked off the boldest federal education shake-up in 45 years, carving up its core functions across Labor, State, Interior, and HHS. To understand why this was inevitable, we must go back to the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/hayek-saw-it-coming-why-centralized-education-was-destined-to-fail/"&gt;Hayek Saw It Coming: Why Centralized Education Was Destined to Fail&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 13:50:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/11/the-outstater-307/</link><description>Our Cultural Disconnect WITH THE 250th ANNIVERSARY&amp;#160;of the Declaration of Independence ahead of us, we asked our&amp;#160;assistant, Grok, to review recent polling on what American youth know about this founding document. I leave the results with you to decide whether we have reached a state of total cultural disconnection: The Annenberg Public Policy Center’s Civics&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/11/the-outstater-307/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 13:59:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] AI Cuts School Paperwork and Puts Time Back Into Teaching</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/ai-cuts-school-paperwork-and-puts-time-back-into-teaching/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Sebastian Girstl Efficiency is a core principle that drives progress, yet this idea has often not received the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/ai-cuts-school-paperwork-and-puts-time-back-into-teaching/"&gt;AI Cuts School Paperwork and Puts Time Back Into Teaching&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 14:31:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Property tax reform won’t reduce student achievement</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/property-tax-reform-student-achievement/</link><description>Kansas Representative Shannon Francis (R-Liberal) told KSNT-TV that he thinks higher property taxes may be bringing people to Kansas. He said higher property taxes have led to investment in schools, and that, as a result, “Kansas schools are a lot better than Oklahoma.” It may be intuitive to think that more spending translates to better [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 16:03:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Chamber report echoes what American Experiment has been saying for years</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/chamber-report-echoes-what-american-experiment-has-been-saying-for-years/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A new report from the Minnesota Chamber of Commerce has generated some interest among the state&amp;#8217;s media this week. Headlines include: KSTP: MN Chamber of Commerce report says the state’s economy is ‘losing ground’ KEYC: Report: Minnesota’s economy is losing ground Fox 9: Minnesota’s economy falling behind, report finds Star Tribune: In face of slowing...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/chamber-report-echoes-what-american-experiment-has-been-saying-for-years/"&gt;Chamber report echoes what American Experiment has been saying for years&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 16:27:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] ITR Engages Legislators and Local Leaders on Property Tax Reform</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/itr-engages-legislators-and-local-leaders-on-property-tax-reform/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="ITR Engages Legislators and Local Leaders on Property Tax Reform" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="337" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/hendrickson.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The legislative session is almost two months away, but the Iowans for Tax Relief (ITR) team had a busy week engaging legislators, local leaders, and Iowa voters on the topics of property tax reform and spending restraint. ITR leaders reinforced the organization’s commitment to advancing sound fiscal policy and providing clear, accessible information that helps Iowans understand how government spending impacts their tax burden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/itr-engages-legislators-and-local-leaders-on-property-tax-reform/"&gt;ITR Engages Legislators and Local Leaders on Property Tax Reform&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 17:40:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Week in Review: Union Members Only? Nope.</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-union-members-only-nope/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When people apply for government jobs, they should be judged on their merits and their ability to do the work...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-union-members-only-nope/"&gt;Week in Review: Union Members Only? Nope.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 18:23:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Connecticut Cannot Solve Its Housing Crisis While Ignoring Union-Driven Costs</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/11/21/connecticut-cannot-solve-its-housing-crisis-while-ignoring-union-driven-costs/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Connecticut’s 2025 State of Housing Conference on Nov. 17 and 18, one panel stood out for all the wrong reasons. The session titled “Union-Built Affordable Housing” was billed as [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/11/21/connecticut-cannot-solve-its-housing-crisis-while-ignoring-union-driven-costs/"&gt;Connecticut Cannot Solve Its Housing Crisis While Ignoring Union-Driven Costs&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 19:01:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] New National Debt Analysis Offers Fresh Lens for Missouri’s Fiscal Picture</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/budget-and-spending/new-national-debt-analysis-offers-fresh-lens-for-missouris-fiscal-picture/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, I wrote about the annual rating by Truth in Accounting (TIA), which found that Missouri earned a [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/budget-and-spending/new-national-debt-analysis-offers-fresh-lens-for-missouris-fiscal-picture/"&gt;New National Debt Analysis Offers Fresh Lens for Missouri’s Fiscal Picture&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 21:14:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Catch the last episode of Ken Burns’ “The American Revolution” tonight</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/catch-the-last-episode-of-ken-burns-the-american-revolution-tonight/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Tonight at 8 p.m., PBS North Carolina will air the last episode of Ken Burns’ “The American Revolution” documentary series. I have learned a great deal about the complex nature and widespread impact of the Revolution so far and have been struck by how so many Patriots stayed loyal to the cause of liberty when...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/catch-the-last-episode-of-ken-burns-the-american-revolution-tonight/"&gt;Catch the last episode of Ken Burns&amp;#8217; &amp;#8220;The American Revolution&amp;#8221; tonight&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 21:16:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Rebates or Restraint With Tariff Revenue?</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/rebates-or-restraint-with-tariff-revenue/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Rebates or Restraint With Tariff Revenue?" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/rebate-check.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;President Trump is considering $2,000 tariff-funded rebate checks to help Americans with affordability challenges, but the plan risks worsening inflation and adds long-term uncertainty amid already severe federal debt and deficits. For long-term economic growth, policymakers should focus on pro-growth measures such as spending cuts, deregulation, energy expansion, and responsible tax policy rather than short-term cash payments that echo past inflation-driving stimulus efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/rebates-or-restraint-with-tariff-revenue/"&gt;Rebates or Restraint With Tariff Revenue?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 22:08:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] The federal tax-credit scholarship that runs without federal cash</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/the-federal-tax-credit-scholarship-that-runs-without-federal-cash/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Educational Choice for Children Act (ECCA) represents a major shift in how federal policy can expand educational opportunity without increasing federal spending. Passed just this summer, the ECCA has emerged as one of the most significant federal education-policy provisions in decades. Unlike traditional programs that rely on direct federal spending, this tax-credit scholarship program...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/the-federal-tax-credit-scholarship-that-runs-without-federal-cash/"&gt;The federal tax-credit scholarship that runs without federal cash&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 22:11:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Winners &amp; Losers: Foreign Terrorists, College Degrees, Texas FEMA &amp; Jelly Roll</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/winners-losers-foreign-terrorists-college-degrees-texas-fema-jelly-roll/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Every Friday morning, I join the Cardle &amp;#38; Woolley Show on Talk 1370 Radio in Austin to announce the week’s Winners &amp;#38; Losers. While the congressional map wars continue and would-be candidates wait for the smoke to clear, here’s who made the list: WINNER: Gov. Greg Abbott Goes After Muslim Extremists in Texas After recent...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/winners-losers-foreign-terrorists-college-degrees-texas-fema-jelly-roll/"&gt;Winners &amp; Losers: Foreign Terrorists, College Degrees, Texas FEMA &amp; Jelly Roll&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 22:25:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Teachers financially penalized for working in some high-poverty, high-minority schools</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/teachers-financially-penalized-for-working-in-some-high-poverty-high-minority-schools/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Are teachers paid more when they work in more difficult schools? Generally, there&amp;#8217;s an assumption that harder jobs will grant higher pay &amp;#8212; that&amp;#8217;s why, for example, an underwater welder is paid handsomely. That&amp;#8217;s called the theory of “compensating wage differentials.&amp;#8221; But does the theory reflect the actual practice of the education system? Do less-desired...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/teachers-financially-penalized-for-working-in-some-high-poverty-high-minority-schools/"&gt;Teachers financially penalized for working in some high-poverty, high-minority schools&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 23:01:52 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>