<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>State-Policy Think-Tank Digest</title><link>https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml</link><description>Latest posts from free-market policy institutes across the U.S.</description><atom:link href="https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 14:15:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] ABQ Ethics Board Dismisses frivolous “sweatshirt-gate” ethics complaint made by Keller campaign against RGF’s Paul Gessing</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/abq-ethics-board-dismisses-frivolous-sweatshirt-gate-ethics-complaint-made-by-keller-campaign-against-rgfs-paul-gessing/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This afternoon in a hearing, the Albuquerque Board of Ethics (BOE) unanimously dismissed a complaint filed by Daymon Ely for the Tim Keller campaign that was made against Rio Grande Foundation president Paul Gessing. The complaint arose out of the Foundation’s reporting over the purchase and delivery of yellow hoodie sweatshirts to members of Albuquerque’s [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/abq-ethics-board-dismisses-frivolous-sweatshirt-gate-ethics-complaint-made-by-keller-campaign-against-rgfs-paul-gessing/"&gt;ABQ Ethics Board Dismisses frivolous “sweatshirt-gate” ethics complaint made by Keller campaign against RGF’s Paul Gessing&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 22:08:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cardinalinstitute] 2026 State of the State Response</title><link>https://cardinalinstitute.com/2026-state-of-the-state-response/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;2026 State of the State Response On Wednesday evening, Governor Patrick Morrisey delivered his annual State of the State address, outlining his priorities for the year ahead and offering a window into his governing philosophy. As is customary, the speech functioned as both pep rally and agenda-setting exercise. State of the state addresses tend to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com/2026-state-of-the-state-response/"&gt;2026 State of the State Response&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com"&gt;Cardinal Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 15:07:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF opinion piece: Data centers are coming: How to handle them</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-opinion-piece-data-centers-are-coming-how-to-handle-them/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following appeared in the Santa Fe New Mexican on January 10, 2026. It has appeared in several other publications as well. &amp;#160; After years of failure to land a “big fish” business for New Mexico’s economy (or effectively use the oil and gas revenues to grow the economy) Gov. Michelle Lujan Grisham, with the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-opinion-piece-data-centers-are-coming-how-to-handle-them/"&gt;RGF opinion piece: Data centers are coming: How to handle them&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 15:48:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Rifreedom] “Doc” Skoly Stepping Down as Center’s Chair to Pursue Congressional Seat</title><link>https://rifreedom.org/2026/01/doc-skoly-stepping-down-as-centers-chair-to-pursue-congressional-seat/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The  Rhode Island Center for Freedom &amp;#038; Prosperity announced today that Dr. Stephen "Doc" Skoly has stepped down as Chairman of its Board of Directors to pursue a run for the US House of Representatives in Rhode Island's second Congressional district.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org/2026/01/doc-skoly-stepping-down-as-centers-chair-to-pursue-congressional-seat/"&gt;&amp;#8220;Doc&amp;#8221; Skoly Stepping Down as Center&amp;#8217;s Chair to Pursue Congressional Seat&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org"&gt;RI Center for Freedom and Prosperity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 15:10:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Policy Pathway for Principled Tax Reform</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/policy-pathway-for-principled-tax-reform/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Policy Pathway for Principled Tax Reform outlines a framework for evaluating tax policy through the lens of sound tax principles including transparency, simplicity, stability, neutrality, and economic efficiency. The report examines Nebraska’s major tax types including property, income, and sales and offers practical, principle-based recommendations to improve affordability, competitiveness, and long-term fiscal sustainability. While designed...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/policy-pathway-for-principled-tax-reform/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Policy Pathway for Principled Tax Reform&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 19:40:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cardinalinstitute] Healthcare in West Virginia</title><link>https://cardinalinstitute.com/healthcare-in-west-virginia/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Healthcare in West Virginia Healthcare policy is complicated. These resources make it understandable. If you are trying to make sense of West Virginia’s latest healthcare debates, you are not alone. PBM regulation, PEIA’s recurring funding crises, and Certificate of Need laws all affect what care costs, where it is available, and who has choices. We [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com/healthcare-in-west-virginia/"&gt;Healthcare in West Virginia&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com"&gt;Cardinal Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 15:44:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] If You Want Parent Power, Only HB2 Will Do</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/if-you-want-parent-power-only-hb2-will-do/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past few years, Mississippi lawmakers have passed some critical conservative reforms.&amp;#160;Last year, Mississippi became the first state in America to legislate to eliminate the income tax in 40 years.&amp;#160; In 2022, we implemented flat tax reform.&amp;#160; A few years before that, we passed important labor market reforms.&amp;#160; In 2024, we reformed school funding [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/if-you-want-parent-power-only-hb2-will-do/" rel="nofollow"&gt;If You Want Parent Power, Only HB2 Will Do&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 16:09:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Rifreedom] MEDIA RELEASE: Center Launches Petition Calling for Affordable Energy Policies</title><link>https://rifreedom.org/2026/01/media-release-center-launches-petition-calling-for-affordable-energy-policies/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Rhode Island Center for Freedom &amp;#038; Prosperity today announced that it has launched an online petition drive calling for policymakers to support a fundamental pivot away from our state's current energy strategy, which will lead to staggeringly high electricity prices and potentially dangerous blackouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org/2026/01/media-release-center-launches-petition-calling-for-affordable-energy-policies/"&gt;MEDIA RELEASE: Center Launches Petition Calling for Affordable Energy Policies&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org"&gt;RI Center for Freedom and Prosperity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 14:19:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Open enrollment: Know the basics</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2026/01/open-enrollment-know-the-basics/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In 2025, New Hampshire legislators passed a law allowing students to enroll in any public school within their assigned district, as long as the school had room. This year, lawmakers might allow students to enroll in any New Hampshire public school that has room. This policy brief answers six core questions commonly raised about open [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2026/01/open-enrollment-know-the-basics/"&gt;Open enrollment: Know the basics&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 19:28:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] Day One, Energy First: Governor Mikie Sherrill’s Opening Strategy on Affordability</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/01/day-one-energy-first-governor-mikie-sherrills-opening-strategy-on-affordability/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Sean Barry, NJPI Jr. Fellow When Governor Mikie Sherrill was sworn in as New Jersey’s 57th governor, she did [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/01/day-one-energy-first-governor-mikie-sherrills-opening-strategy-on-affordability/"&gt;Day One, Energy First: Governor Mikie Sherrill’s Opening Strategy on Affordability&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 19:08:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] A New Governor Takes Office. Will She Deliver on Education?</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/01/a-new-governor-takes-office-will-she-deliver-on-education/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;by Aiden DeMarsey, NJPI Jr. Fellow &amp;#160; Governor Mikie Sherrill, sworn into office last week, enters her term with a [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/01/a-new-governor-takes-office-will-she-deliver-on-education/"&gt;A New Governor Takes Office. Will She Deliver on Education?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 19:10:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] New housing permits are highest since 2006, but single-family homes lag</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2026/01/new-housing-permits-are-highest-since-2006-but-single-family-homes-lag/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New Hampshire towns and cities are permitting more residential housing units than they have in years, which is great news. But the new units are skewed heavily toward rentals, suggesting that local restrictions on small, single-family homes remain a significant barrier. Local governments issued permits for 5,822 new housing units in 2024, the highest number [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2026/01/new-housing-permits-are-highest-since-2006-but-single-family-homes-lag/"&gt;New housing permits are highest since 2006, but single-family homes lag&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:16:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] The Denial of Distinctions</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/the-denial-of-distinctions/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Denial of Distinctions By Abe Greenwald Yesterday, I wrote about the return of American disorder in the form of mobs that obstruct ICE raids. Part of what makes anti-ICE/open-border activism so strange is that it attacks the most fundamental aspect of what it means to be a country: its physical boundaries. When leftists repeat, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/the-denial-of-distinctions/"&gt;The Denial of Distinctions&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:37:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Crime is down, and it should end ‘root cause’ excuse-making for good</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/crime-is-down-and-it-should-end-root-cause-excuse-making-for-good/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/crime-is-down-and-it-should-end-root-cause-excuse-making-for-good/"&gt;Crime is down, and it should end ‘root cause’ excuse-making for good&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 22:13:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Introducing TennSight, Tennessee’s only hub for voter insights</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/introducing-tennsight-tennessees-only-hub-for-voter-insights/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=introducing-tennsight-tennessees-only-hub-for-voter-insights</link><description>We hope that TennSight will become the go-to source for you to learn what matters most to your fellow Tennesseans, why it matters, and what can be done about it.</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 13:08:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Idaho schools paying $1.2 million per year for IEA/NEA dues</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/labor/idaho-schools-paying-1-2-million-per-year-for-iea-nea-dues/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;According to a new Freedom Foundation analysis, the Boise and Twin Falls School Districts are spending more than $1.2 million per year on programs to cover the cost of teachers union dues to the Idaho Education Association. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/labor/idaho-schools-paying-1-2-million-per-year-for-iea-nea-dues/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Idaho schools paying $1.2 million per year for IEA/NEA dues&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 17:33:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Beacon Poll: January 2026 Results</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/beacon-poll-january-2026-results/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=beacon-poll-january-2026-results</link><description>Today, we released the latest installment of the Beacon Poll, a statewide survey of 1,200 Tennessee voters featuring questions about voters’ views on property taxes, the federal school choice tax credit included in the One Big Beautiful Bill Act, and political approval ratings at the state and federal level, and more. Tennesseans continue to prioritize key...</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 19:35:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Johnson County superintendents fail 4th-grade math</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/johnson-county-supers-fail-4th-grade-math/</link><description>Today’s math riddle is brought to you by Johnson County school superintendents: How can taxpayers give school districts hundreds of millions of dollars more for special education without increasing total spending or cutting other state funding? The obvious answer is that it’s not possible, but that is what they tell taxpayers, and in their pitch [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 00:15:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Age Verification Isn’t Parenting</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/age-verification-isnt-parenting/</link><description>Kansas lawmakers are weighing a proposal that would require new age-verification measures for online platforms, part of a growing national effort to address concerns about children’s safety in digital spaces. The goal is understandable. Parents across Kansas want their kids protected online. The harder question is how far government should go—and whether mandates aimed at [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 16:00:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Dr. John Dixon: Charter Schools, Choice, and Accountability</title><link>https://empowerms.org/dr-john-dixon-charter-schools-choice-and-accountability/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Dr. John Dixon: Charter Schools, Choice, and Accountability As the 2026 legislative session moves forward, the conversation around school choice continues to intensify. While much of the focus has been on ESAs and public school transfers, one form of public school choice has quietly served thousands of Mississippi families for years: public charter schools. In&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/dr-john-dixon-charter-schools-choice-and-accountability/"&gt;Dr. John Dixon: Charter Schools, Choice, and Accountability&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 18:41:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cardinalinstitute] Op-Ed: Hospitals Collect Tax Breaks. West Virginians Collect Medical Debt.</title><link>https://cardinalinstitute.com/op-ed-hospitals-collect-tax-breaks-west-virginians-collect-medical-debt/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;To many West Virginians, healthcare continues to be a burden more than a lifeline as roughly 180,000 residents, or 13.3% of adults, now facing some sort of  medical debt. This is well above the national average of 8.6% and, even worse, nearly one in four of these residents in rural Appalachia have medical debt in [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com/op-ed-hospitals-collect-tax-breaks-west-virginians-collect-medical-debt/"&gt;Op-Ed: Hospitals Collect Tax Breaks. West Virginians Collect Medical Debt.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com"&gt;Cardinal Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 15:16:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Why Portland’s Suggested Statewide Eviction Moratorium Would Hurt Maine’s Housing Market</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/why-portlands-suggested-statewide-eviction-moratorium-would-hurt-maines-housing-market/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Portland city officials are urging Gov. Janet Mills to impose a 60-day statewide eviction moratorium in response to “fear and instability” that they are linking to federal immigration enforcement. While the resolution is framed as an emergency measure that they are claiming is only meant to protect “vulnerable residents,” such a moratorium risks repeating a [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/why-portlands-suggested-statewide-eviction-moratorium-would-hurt-maines-housing-market/"&gt;Why Portland&amp;#8217;s Suggested Statewide Eviction Moratorium Would Hurt Maine’s Housing Market&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 16:38:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] Tim Pawlenty: The Crisis Will Subside in Minnesota, but Trust Will Need to be Rebuilt</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/tim-pawlenty-the-crisis-will-subside-in-minnesota-but-trust-will-need-to-be-rebuilt/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;We’ll all be part of that task. Here’s where efforts could be focused. By Tim Pawlenty For the Star Tribune It’s been said that trust is the glue that holds relationships together. That may well explain why recent events in Minnesota have stretched our relationship with government to the breaking point. Fraudsters stole a ton [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/tim-pawlenty-the-crisis-will-subside-in-minnesota-but-trust-will-need-to-be-rebuilt/"&gt;Tim Pawlenty: The Crisis Will Subside in Minnesota, but Trust Will Need to be Rebuilt&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 19:57:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] The Numbers Don’t Lie: The CHOOSE Act is Empowering Alabama’s Families</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2026/02/04/the-numbers-dont-lie-the-choose-act-is-empowering-alabamas-families/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For decades, the Alabama Policy Institute has championed a simple, powerful idea: every child in Alabama deserves a high-quality education, regardless of their zip code or their size of their parents’ bank account. With the passage and implementation of the CHOOSE Act, that vision is finally becoming a reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2026/02/04/the-numbers-dont-lie-the-choose-act-is-empowering-alabamas-families/"&gt;The Numbers Don’t Lie: The CHOOSE Act is Empowering Alabama’s Families&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 22:48:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] 312 Out of More than 3 Million Votes</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/312-out-of-more-than-3-million-votes/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Federal prosecutors are closing in on prosecuting more than 100 Minnesotans for rampant fraud in several social service programs designed to serve children and low-income residents. By the time the US Attorney’s office is done investigating, charging, convicting, and sentencing these felons, this unchecked fraud will significantly increase Minnesota’s prison population. But there’s one other [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/312-out-of-more-than-3-million-votes/"&gt;312 Out of More than 3 Million Votes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 13:58:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Empire Center Report Makes the Case Against Further Tax Hikes</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/empire-center-report-makes-the-case-against-further-tax-hikes/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Adding to New York&amp;#8217;s already high tax burden would be both unnecessary and dangerous for the state&amp;#8217;s economy, according to....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/empire-center-report-makes-the-case-against-further-tax-hikes/"&gt;Empire Center Report Makes the Case Against Further Tax Hikes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 16:12:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Study Urges New K–12 Accountability Framework Following End of MCAS Graduation Requirement</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/study-urges-new-k-12-accountability-framework-following-end-of-mcas-graduation-requirement/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Calls for choices of high school pathways, early and end-of-course exams, and independent district accountability  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/study-urges-new-k-12-accountability-framework-following-end-of-mcas-graduation-requirement/"&gt;Study Urges New K–12 Accountability Framework Following End of MCAS Graduation Requirement&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 16:14:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Education Is Economic Development: Why Business Leaders Should Support House Bill</title><link>https://empowerms.org/education-is-economic-development-why-business-leaders-should-support-house-bill/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This article was originally published in the February 2026 edition of the Mississippi Business Journal. Mississippi’s business community understands a basic but often overlooked reality: economic development does not begin with tax incentives or site selectors. It begins with people. If we want our state to grow, we must be able to attract, retain, and&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/education-is-economic-development-why-business-leaders-should-support-house-bill/"&gt;Education Is Economic Development: Why Business Leaders Should Support House Bill&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 18:43:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Record-breaking start to 2026: 6,000 employees opt out</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/record-breaking-start-to-2026-6000-employees-opt-out/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Freedom Foundation set an all-time record in January with 6,000 public employees opting out—topping our previous record by nearly 3,000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/record-breaking-start-to-2026-6000-employees-opt-out/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Record-breaking start to 2026: 6,000 employees opt out&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 18:57:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] A Badger Institute policy report: Character education and teacher retention</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/a-badger-institute-policy-report-character-education-and-teacher-retention/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Wisconsinites should be concerned the state's growing crisis of disappearing educators — a phenomenon the Badger Institute has been taking a closer look at. Multiple studies confirm that retaining good teachers is essential to school effectiveness and student achievement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/a-badger-institute-policy-report-character-education-and-teacher-retention/"&gt;A Badger Institute policy report: Character education and teacher retention&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 20:25:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Testimony: SB 1526 Creates State-Sponsored Nonprofit for Net Zero Projects</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/testimony/testimony-sb-1526-creates-state-sponsored-nonprofit-for-net-zero-projects/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By John A. Charles Jr. PORTLAND, OR – John Charles, President and CEO...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/testimony/testimony-sb-1526-creates-state-sponsored-nonprofit-for-net-zero-projects/"&gt;Testimony: SB 1526 Creates State-Sponsored Nonprofit for Net Zero Projects&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 20:40:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Rifreedom] TESTIMONY: Senate Commission to Study the Successful Implementation of the Act on Climate</title><link>https://rifreedom.org/2026/02/senate-commission-act-on-climate/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In this powerful testimony, Mike Stenhouse, CEO of the RI Center for Freedom &amp;#038; Prosperity, explains why energy policy—not taxes, not housing, not government services—is the single most important determinant of Rhode Island’s future prosperity or poverty. Whether one believes in climate change or not, the economic consequences of the Act on Climate are unavoidable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org/2026/02/senate-commission-act-on-climate/"&gt;TESTIMONY: Senate Commission to Study the Successful Implementation of the Act on Climate&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org"&gt;RI Center for Freedom and Prosperity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 21:12:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] BERGEN RECORD: NJ climate superfund is a blank check with no accountability | Opinion</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/02/bergen-record-nj-climate-superfund-is-a-blank-check-with-no-accountability-opinion/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;#160; New Jersey’s Climate Superfund Is a Blank Check With No Accountability by Rosemary Becchi New Jersey lawmakers are considering [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/02/bergen-record-nj-climate-superfund-is-a-blank-check-with-no-accountability-opinion/"&gt;BERGEN RECORD: NJ climate superfund is a blank check with no accountability | Opinion&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 13:58:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] The Virginian-Pilot: Federal Scholarship Tax Credits Should be a No-Brainer for Virginia</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/the-virginian-pilot-federal-scholarship-tax-credits-should-be-a-no-brainer-for-virginia/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/tax-credit-featured-image.jpg" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In today’s The Virginian-Pilot, Thomas Jefferson Institute Senior Advisor and Former President Chris Braunlich discusses Virginia’s participation in the new Federal Scholarship Tax Credit (FSTC) for K-12 students which, starting in 2027, will give taxpayers a dollar for dollar federal tax credit of up to $1,700 for donations to scholarship programs offering students in public [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/the-virginian-pilot-federal-scholarship-tax-credits-should-be-a-no-brainer-for-virginia/"&gt;The Virginian-Pilot: Federal Scholarship Tax Credits Should be a No-Brainer for Virginia&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 16:11:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Governor Mills’ Supplemental Budget Abandons Fiscal Discipline, Sets Maine Up for Higher Costs</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/governor-millss-supplemental-budget-abandons-fiscal-discipline-sets-maine-up-for-higher-costs/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Governor Janet Mills’ FY 2026 supplemental budget marks a clear break from the fiscal restraint her administration often claimed to practice. Rather than using Maine’s strong revenue growth to stabilize taxpayers after years of tax increases and inflation, the proposal dramatically expands spending, broadens emergency powers, and doubles down on distortionary tax policy choices that [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/governor-millss-supplemental-budget-abandons-fiscal-discipline-sets-maine-up-for-higher-costs/"&gt;Governor Mills’ Supplemental Budget Abandons Fiscal Discipline, Sets Maine Up for Higher Costs&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 17:22:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Stacked Local Taxes Are Making Virginia Less Affordable, Not More</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/stacked-local-taxes-are-making-virginia-less-affordable-not-more/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="630" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/virginia-local-taxes-v2.jpg" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Virginia’s restaurant and lodging sector is still in a fragile post-COVID recovery, yet local governments across the Commonwealth are piling on new and higher taxes that make affordability worse for families and survival harder for small businesses. A new statewide analysis of meals, lodging, and related sales taxes across all 133 Virginia localities by the&amp;#160;Virginia [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/stacked-local-taxes-are-making-virginia-less-affordable-not-more/"&gt;Stacked Local Taxes Are Making Virginia Less Affordable, Not More&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 17:43:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Affordability tops the list of state priorities for 2026</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/affordability-tops-the-list-of-state-priorities-for-2026/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/affordability-tops-the-list-of-state-priorities-for-2026/"&gt;Affordability tops the list of state priorities for 2026&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 21:36:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] 2026 Capitol Chat: Week 5</title><link>https://empowerms.org/2026-capitol-chat-week-5/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Capitol Chat: Week 5 Week 5 at the Capitol featured some of the most consequential policy and political moves yet. In this episode, we walk through some of the biggest developments, including shifts in the education debate, major House action, an update on the ballot initiative, and another big deadline on the horizon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/2026-capitol-chat-week-5/"&gt;2026 Capitol Chat: Week 5&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 22:11:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Union Activists Launch Full Scale Attack on Students, Families in AZ</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/union-activists-launch-full-scale-attack-on-students-families-in-az/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As students across the state continue to find new opportunity through Arizona’s Empowerment Scholarship Account (ESA) program, the total number..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/union-activists-launch-full-scale-attack-on-students-families-in-az/"&gt;Union Activists Launch Full Scale Attack on Students, Families in AZ&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 20:42:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2026/02/the-outstater-326/</link><description>Pimping for Data Centers &amp;#8220;The idea is to get back to a society where people can live together as neighbors and not just as wage slaves or bureaucratic cogs.” — G.K. Chesterton LOOK, I LIKE PROGRESS&amp;#160;as much as the next guy but sacrificing local autonomy is stupid. There are nine distinct regions of Indiana, each&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2026/02/the-outstater-326/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 13:21:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Ayotte: Maximize economic freedom, and New Hampshire will thrive</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2026/02/ayotte-maximize-economic-freedom-and-new-hampshire-will-thrive/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Gov. Kelly Ayotte’s 2026 State of the State address can be summed up in seven words: New Hampshire wins by competing on freedom. Leading with a list of eight No. 1 national rankings for the state—including economic freedom, economic opportunity and taxpayer return on investment—Ayotte noted that, overall, “U.S. News ranks us the #2 state [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2026/02/ayotte-maximize-economic-freedom-and-new-hampshire-will-thrive/"&gt;Ayotte: Maximize economic freedom, and New Hampshire will thrive&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 14:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] ITR Foundation Brings the Property Tax Conversation Directly to Iowans</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/itr-foundation-brings-the-property-tax-conversation-directly-to-iowans/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="ITR Foundation Brings the Property Tax Conversation Directly to Iowans" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/hendrickson-maga-nation.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ITR Foundation is taking the property tax conversation directly to Iowans, engaging grassroots audiences alongside elected officials and candidates to address the real-world impact of rising property taxes. The data show a clear problem: Iowa property taxes have grown by more than 100 percent over the past two decades, far outpacing population growth and inflation, driven primarily by sustained growth in local government spending rather than assessments alone. Meaningful property tax relief requires spending discipline, including reasonable caps on revenue growth, to complement Iowa’s recent income tax reforms and ensure taxpayers, homeowners, farmers, and small businesses are not squeezed by unchecked local spending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/itr-foundation-brings-the-property-tax-conversation-directly-to-iowans/"&gt;ITR Foundation Brings the Property Tax Conversation Directly to Iowans&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 15:07:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Nine More Massachusetts Towns Subject of State Litigation over MBTA Communities Act Noncompliance</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/nine-more-massachusetts-towns-subject-of-state-litigation-over-mbta-communities-act-noncompliance/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;February's edition of The House Call discusses new legal action over Massachusetts' multifamily zoning mandate for transit-accessible communities. It also highlights a new federal data release that shows where many Massachusetts homeowners tend to overestimate - or underestimate - their property values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/nine-more-massachusetts-towns-subject-of-state-litigation-over-mbta-communities-act-noncompliance/"&gt;Nine More Massachusetts Towns Subject of State Litigation over MBTA Communities Act Noncompliance&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 16:58:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Keep an Eye on the DATA Act in Washington, D.C.</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/article/energy/keep-an-eye-on-the-data-act-in-washington-d-c/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Listen to this article As a writer, there are moments when someone else articulates an idea so well that rewriting it in my own words would be unnecessary. A recent [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/article/energy/keep-an-eye-on-the-data-act-in-washington-d-c/"&gt;Keep an Eye on the DATA Act in Washington, D.C.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 21:27:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] Alabama Senate unanimously passes App Store Accountability Act</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2026/02/09/alabama-senate-unanimously-passes-app-store-accountability-act/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The App Store Accountability Act passed the Alabama Senate with a unanimous vote on Feb. 5. The bill is focused on online safety for children and teens by requiring parental approval for kids to download apps from the App Store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2026/02/09/alabama-senate-unanimously-passes-app-store-accountability-act/"&gt;Alabama Senate unanimously passes App Store Accountability Act&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 23:47:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] Alabama Senate passes App Store age verification requirement</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2026/02/10/alabama-senate-passes-app-store-age-verification-requirement/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Lawmakers spoke before the Senate in favor of shielding minors from inappropriate content, requiring parental permission for account creation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2026/02/10/alabama-senate-passes-app-store-age-verification-requirement/"&gt;Alabama Senate passes App Store age verification requirement&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 02:12:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Legislators Not Curious About Cost, Safety or Efficiency As Massive Battery Mandate Rushes Toward Approval</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/legislators-not-curious-about-cost-safety-or-efficiency-as-massive-battery-mandate-rushes-toward-approval/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="720" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Virginia-green-battery-mandate.jpg" width="1280" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, a Senate committee is scheduled to take up the bill directing Virginia’s two investor-owned utilities to propose huge battery installations that will cover square miles of ground, cost ratepayers billions of dollars, and produce zero energy to power our homes and businesses. The bill has Governor Abigail Spanberger’s endorsement. So far, legislators have been in a “see, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/legislators-not-curious-about-cost-safety-or-efficiency-as-massive-battery-mandate-rushes-toward-approval/"&gt;Legislators Not Curious About Cost, Safety or Efficiency As Massive Battery Mandate Rushes Toward Approval&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 03:40:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Testimony of Bill Hammond on the Health and Medicaid Budget for FY 2027</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/testimony-of-bill-hammond-on-the-health-and-medicaid-budget-for-fy-2027/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Testimony of Bill Hammond Senior Fellow, Empire Center for Public Policy Before the Joint Legislative Fiscal Committees February 10, 2026....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/testimony-of-bill-hammond-on-the-health-and-medicaid-budget-for-fy-2027/"&gt;Testimony of Bill Hammond on the Health and Medicaid Budget for FY 2027&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 13:36:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Hammond Calls for Restraint on Medicaid Spending</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/hammond-calls-for-restraint-on-medicaid-spending/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Albany, N.Y. — The state and its taxpayers cannot afford to allow Medicaid spending to keep growing at five times the....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/hammond-calls-for-restraint-on-medicaid-spending/"&gt;Hammond Calls for Restraint on Medicaid Spending&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 13:36:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Did Jefferson Raid Its Water Fund? Lawsuit Puts City Finances Under Scrutiny</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/did-jefferson-raid-its-water-fund-lawsuit-puts-city-finances-under-scrutiny/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Did Jefferson Raid Its Water Fund? Lawsuit Puts City Finances Under Scrutiny" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/jefferson-iowajpg.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lawsuit challenges Jefferson’s use of taxpayer dollars after the city transferred $800,000 from its Water Plant Construction Fund into economic development and TIF-related accounts. Plaintiffs argue the transfer violated Iowa law and public process, claiming the city neither demonstrated a lawful surplus nor created a binding repayment obligation, and failed to follow required budget amendment procedures. The case raises broader concerns about transparency and taxpayer trust, highlighting the risks of diverting funds and the potential for residents to pay twice through higher future rates or taxes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/did-jefferson-raid-its-water-fund-lawsuit-puts-city-finances-under-scrutiny/"&gt;Did Jefferson Raid Its Water Fund? Lawsuit Puts City Finances Under Scrutiny&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 14:09:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] On Lincoln’s Birthday, Remember the Right to Rise</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/principles-of-liberty/right-to-rise/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As Americans, we remember the great leaders of our country and reflect on their contributions to our present-day lives. February 12, 1809, marks the birthday of Abraham Lincoln—undoubtedly among the most famous and revered figures in our nation’s history, and with good reason. He was not only the Great Emancipator, but an exemplar of the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/principles-of-liberty/right-to-rise/"&gt;On Lincoln’s Birthday, Remember the Right to Rise&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 16:46:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Freedom Foundation Attorneys Secure Compensation from SEIU 099 for a Public-School Employee</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/litigation/freedom-foundation-attorneys-secure-compensation-from-seiu-099-for-a-public-school-employee/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Freedom Foundation attorneys have successfully freed California public school employee Keshawna Adams from SEIU 099’ unconstitutional dues deductions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/litigation/freedom-foundation-attorneys-secure-compensation-from-seiu-099-for-a-public-school-employee/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation Attorneys Secure Compensation from SEIU 099 for a Public-School Employee&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 17:52:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] It’s Time for Arizona’s Supreme Court to Protect ‘The Most Precious Liberty Man Possesses’</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/its-time-for-arizonas-supreme-court-to-protect-the-most-precious-liberty-man-possesses/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Goldwater Institute today filed a brief in the Arizona Supreme Court urging the justices to extend full constitutional protection..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/its-time-for-arizonas-supreme-court-to-protect-the-most-precious-liberty-man-possesses/"&gt;It’s Time for Arizona’s Supreme Court to Protect ‘The Most Precious Liberty Man Possesses’&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 18:33:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Florida Politics: Florida’s CHINA Prevention Unit Is a Needed Step To Safeguard Health Data</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/floridas-china-prevention-unit-is-a-needed-step-to-safeguard-health-data/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Once again, Florida is showing the rest of the country how to lead in protecting its citizens from...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/floridas-china-prevention-unit-is-a-needed-step-to-safeguard-health-data/"&gt;Florida Politics: Florida’s CHINA Prevention Unit Is a Needed Step To Safeguard Health Data&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 19:20:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] Book: ‘Decade of Disunion’</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2026/02/book-decade-of-disunion/</link><description>by Mark Franke I have a fondness for counter-factual history, perhaps too much so. This category of fiction begins with a what if question about some critical point in history and then hypothesizes a chain of events to follow. Some end up with a radically different ending while others argue that history would have worked&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2026/02/book-decade-of-disunion/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 12:09:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Senior discount won’t solve Michigan’s property tax problem</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2026/senior-discount-wont-solve-michigans-property-tax-problem</link><description>Reformers should aim to reduce overall rates</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Strengthening families for generational change: GCO welcomes Travis Thorne to the team</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/welcoming-travis-thorne/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/welcoming-travis-thorne/"&gt;Strengthening families for generational change: GCO welcomes Travis Thorne to the team&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 14:26:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Fox News: Gradually, Then Suddenly, Blue State America Is Heading for Financial Disaster</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/fox-news-gradually-then-suddenly-blue-state-america-is-heading-for-financial-disaster/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In his famous 20th century novel &amp;#8220;The Sun Also Rises,&amp;#8221; Ernest Hemingway’s character, Mike Campbell, was asked by...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/fox-news-gradually-then-suddenly-blue-state-america-is-heading-for-financial-disaster/"&gt;Fox News: Gradually, Then Suddenly, Blue State America Is Heading for Financial Disaster&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 14:34:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] YI President Carol Platt Liebau Featured in The Hartford Courant</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/02/11/yi-president-carol-platt-liebau-featured-in-the-hartford-courant/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="630" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/1.jpg" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yankee Institute President Carol Platt Liebau argues that affordability and opportunity should guide every proposal in Connecticut&amp;#8217;s 2026 legislative session — from protecting fiscal guardrails and reducing pension debt, to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/02/11/yi-president-carol-platt-liebau-featured-in-the-hartford-courant/"&gt;YI President Carol Platt Liebau Featured in The Hartford Courant&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 15:00:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] When a Landmark Trial Misses the Mark</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/misses-the-mark/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Social media use among young people is widespread, but so too are accounts of depression, anxiety, and exploitation. Because of this, families, mental health providers, advocates, and elected officials are operating under a sense of urgency. Some have turned to government to help keep kids safe online. Unfortunately, many of these efforts have resulted in...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/misses-the-mark/"&gt;When a Landmark Trial Misses the Mark &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 16:00:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF talks to KOAT TV about roads</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-talks-to-koat-tv-about-roads/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;SB 2 has passed which means that the road issue has been &amp;#8220;put to bed&amp;#8221; for the time being. The bill which has been signed by the Gov. includes: $1.5 billion in new road spending via a bond (debt) package. This also includes: A 35% increase in the weight-distance tax on trucks A 25% increase [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-talks-to-koat-tv-about-roads/"&gt;RGF talks to KOAT TV about roads&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 16:09:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] House Bill 588 — Virtual Public Education (0)</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/house-bill-588-virtual-public-education-0/</link><description>Bill Description: House Bill 588 (H588) revises various provisions regarding how school districts can conduct virtual education programs, including reporting requirements and teacher certification and curricula standards.&amp;#160; Rating: 0 Does it increase government spending (for objectionable purposes) or debt? Conversely, does it decrease government spending or debt? H588 would ensure that school districts are not [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 18:34:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Arizona Republicans should stop trying to ban mRNA vaccines</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/arizona-republicans-should-stop-trying-to-ban-mrna-vaccines/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Despite Democratic Governor Hobbs&amp;#8217; past efforts to expand Arizonans&amp;#8217; access to cutting-edge medicines, the state Legislature continues to propose harmful anti-mRNA bills. The latest example is House Bill 2332, which, if enacted, would deny Arizonans access to promising technologies that could cure cancer and minimize the health consequences from deadly diseases. Lawmakers should reject this [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/arizona-republicans-should-stop-trying-to-ban-mrna-vaccines/"&gt;Arizona Republicans should stop trying to ban mRNA vaccines&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 19:04:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Wisconsin Senate Passes WILL-Backed ﻿“Red Tape Reset”</title><link>https://will-law.org/wisconsin-senate-passes-will-backed-red-tape-reset/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The WILL-backed “Red Tape Reset” is one step closer to becoming law after the Wisconsin State Senate voted in favor of the legislative package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/wisconsin-senate-passes-will-backed-red-tape-reset/"&gt;Wisconsin Senate Passes WILL-Backed ﻿“Red Tape Reset”&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 19:13:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Watch: The Public Safety Climate in the City of St Louis</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/article/state-and-local-government/watch-the-public-safety-climate-in-the-city-of-st-louis/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On January 21, 2026, the Show-Me Institute hosted an in-depth discussion on crime and public safety trends in the City of St. Louis at the Knight Center at Washington University. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/article/state-and-local-government/watch-the-public-safety-climate-in-the-city-of-st-louis/"&gt;Watch: The Public Safety Climate in the City of St Louis&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 19:57:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Emancipator and Economic Nationalist</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/emancipator-and-economic-nationalist/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Emancipator and Economic Nationalist" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/lincoln.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abraham Lincoln’s legacy is most often framed around the Civil War and slavery, but his economic philosophy—particularly his support for protectionism and economic nationalism—is frequently overlooked. Influenced by the Whig and Federalist traditions and leaders like Henry Clay, Lincoln championed the American System, which emphasized protective tariffs, a national bank, and internal improvements as essential to national prosperity and independence. Lincoln’s economic nationalism shaped Republican policy for generations, with tariffs and related reforms playing a central role in his administration and influencing American economic thought well into the 20th century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/emancipator-and-economic-nationalist/"&gt;Emancipator and Economic Nationalist&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 21:11:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] More Evidence on Grade Inflation in Our Schools</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/article/performance/more-evidence-on-grade-inflation-in-our-schools/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Listen to this article QNS, a local news outlet covering Queens, New York, released an interesting article about a local high school under investigation by New York City Public Schools. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/article/performance/more-evidence-on-grade-inflation-in-our-schools/"&gt;More Evidence on Grade Inflation in Our Schools&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 22:10:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Waste watch: Illinois gives $45M to select business groups</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/waste-watch-illinois-gives-45m-to-select-business-groups/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Some Illinois lawmakers handed money to their local business associations. Should everyone’s taxes subsidize certain groups because their lawmakers had clout?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/waste-watch-illinois-gives-45m-to-select-business-groups/"&gt;Waste watch: Illinois gives $45M to select business groups&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 22:48:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Governor Evers To Consider “Teacher Bill of Rights” Legislation</title><link>https://will-law.org/governor-evers-to-consider-teacher-bill-of-rights-legislation/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL applauds the Wisconsin State Assembly and State Senate for acting on AB 614 / SB 611, known as the Teacher Bill of Rights. The bill creates protections for teachers and students by strengthening teachers’ authority to manage their classrooms, requiring parental notification when serious incidents occur, and establishing clear accountability so teachers can focus on teaching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/governor-evers-to-consider-teacher-bill-of-rights-legislation/"&gt;Governor Evers To Consider “Teacher Bill of Rights” Legislation&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 23:36:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Governor Newsom: Turn Up the Delta Pumps!</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/turn-up-the-delta-pumps/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=turn-up-the-delta-pumps</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When it comes to the water supply in California for cities and farms, nothing matters more than how we manage the Sacramento-San Joaquin Delta. As of 2/09 we were 132 days into the 2025-26 rainfall season which began on 10/01/2025. That’s enough time to get an idea of how delta management is shaping up this...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/turn-up-the-delta-pumps/"&gt;Governor Newsom: Turn Up the Delta Pumps!&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 23:47:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] California Forever Stagnating</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/california-forever-stagnating/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=california-forever-stagnating</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When Permission Replaces Property Rights, the California Dream Becomes a Dream Deferred For over a century, California stood as a frontier of first resort for the ambitious, attracting those eager to escape old-world constraints in exchange for a promise of radical autonomy. This California Dream was not a byproduct of luck; it was forged by...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/california-forever-stagnating/"&gt;California Forever Stagnating&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 01:05:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Michigan only enacted 74 laws in 2025. So what?</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2026/michigan-only-enacted-74-laws-in-2025-so-what</link><description>It’s more important to kill bad bills than to pass good ones</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Lawsuit’s End Latest Sign of High Speed Rail’s Woes</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/lawsuits-end-latest-sign-of-high-speed-rails-woes/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;An HSRA official said the decision to pull the lawsuit was made because “the federal government is not a reliable, constructive, or trustworthy partner in advancing high-speed rail in California.” In reality, it’s a tacit admission from the HSRA that it doesn’t deserve the money. At this point, it’s become rather tedious to recite the high-speed rail’s catalog of troubles. The California [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/lawsuits-end-latest-sign-of-high-speed-rails-woes/"&gt;Lawsuit’s End Latest Sign of High Speed Rail’s Woes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 11:00:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG: DPI’s Refusal to Explain $368,885 Secret Waterpark Meeting  Risks Invalidation of New Exam Standards</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-dpis-refusal-to-explain-368885-secret-waterpark-meeting-risks-invalidation-of-new-exam-standards/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;IRG: DPI’s Refusal to Explain $368,885 Secret Waterpark Meeting  Risks Invalidation of New Exam Standards 3 Questions The Legislature Needs DPI to Immediately Answer Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government is raising new questions surrounding the Department of Public Instruction’s actions to hold its Wisconsin Forward Exam standard-setting workshop in private, at a [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-dpis-refusal-to-explain-368885-secret-waterpark-meeting-risks-invalidation-of-new-exam-standards/"&gt;IRG: DPI’s Refusal to Explain $368,885 Secret Waterpark Meeting  Risks Invalidation of New Exam Standards&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 13:59:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Border on the brink as cartel drones force US to act after years of paralysis</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/border-on-the-brink-as-cartel-drones-force-us-to-act-after-years-of-paralysis/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Wednesday&amp;#8217;s El Paso action is welcome and long overdue — another step in last summer’s call by President Trump for military action against the cartels. The sudden closure of airspace over El Paso, Texas, on Wednesday, Feb. 11 was a big deal — but likely not for the reason you think. For years, the Federal Aviation...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/border-on-the-brink-as-cartel-drones-force-us-to-act-after-years-of-paralysis/"&gt;Border on the brink as cartel drones force US to act after years of paralysis&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 14:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Two Presidents. Two Paid Days Off. One Taxpayer</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/02/12/two-presidents-two-paid-days-off-one-taxpayer/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="1024" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/ChatGPT-Image-Feb-12-2026-at-08_51_55-AM.png" width="1024" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy Lincoln’s Birthday.  If you work for the State of Connecticut, you may be enjoying your second February paid holiday in just four days.  Most Americans observe a single Presidents’ [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/02/12/two-presidents-two-paid-days-off-one-taxpayer/"&gt;Two Presidents. Two Paid Days Off. One Taxpayer &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 14:03:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Domestic Outmigration is Hollowing Out Massachusetts’ Workforce and Economy</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/domestic-outmigration-is-hollowing-out-massachusetts-workforce-and-economy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;From April 2020 through July 2025, Massachusetts experienced a net loss of approximately 182,000 residents to domestic outmigration — the equivalent of losing one-and-a-half Cambridges. While a recent surge in international immigration temporarily boosted labor force numbers, new research from Pioneer Institute shows that underlying demographic, workforce, and economic challenges continue to threaten the Commonwealth’s long-term competitiveness. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/domestic-outmigration-is-hollowing-out-massachusetts-workforce-and-economy/"&gt;Domestic Outmigration is Hollowing Out Massachusetts’ Workforce and Economy &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 14:37:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Florida Politics: Florida’s A+ Plan To Help ‘Plan B’ Families</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/floridas-a-plan-to-help-plan-b-families/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;February 11, 2026 Lawmakers seek to expand private school classroom access It was a curious finding that seemed...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/floridas-a-plan-to-help-plan-b-families/"&gt;Florida Politics: Florida’s A+ Plan To Help ‘Plan B’ Families&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 14:47:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Meghan Portfolio and Frank Ricci Appear in The Daily Caller</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/02/12/meghan-portfolio-and-frank-ricci-appear-in-the-daily-caller/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="630" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/3.jpg" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In The Daily Caller, Yankee Institute Manager of Research and Analysis Meghan Portfolio and Labor Fellow Frank Ricci contend that the American Federation of Teachers is exploiting perceived “crises” to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/02/12/meghan-portfolio-and-frank-ricci-appear-in-the-daily-caller/"&gt;Meghan Portfolio and Frank Ricci Appear in The Daily Caller&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 15:00:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] High Demand Shows Texas Families Want More Educational Freedom</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/high-demand-shows-texas-families-want-more-educational-freedom/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The rollout of Texas’ Education Freedom Accounts (TEFA) has already become a major success. When state officials opened applications on February 4, demand poured in at an unprecedented rate, with tens of thousands of families rushing to apply. Early figures show the scale of that demand. Within just hours of launch, more than 20,000 applications...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/high-demand-shows-texas-families-want-more-educational-freedom/"&gt;High Demand Shows Texas Families Want More Educational Freedom&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 15:07:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] The bare necessities of emergency rule making</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/post/the-bare-necessities-of-emergency-rule-making</link><description>Idaho’s regulatory stewardship is impressive, but there is always room for improvement. HB 539 offers these favorable reforms that protect the role of the legislature and limit the ability of the executive branch to go overboard with the definition of an ‘emergency.’</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 15:09:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] The Wisconsin Higher-Ed Reform Model</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/the-wisconsin-higher-ed-reform-model/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Republican lawmakers managed to pass a conservative-coded policy in a purple state with a Democratic governor. It’s all well and good to point to Florida or Texas and wish that every state could do likewise. Unfortunately, not every state capitol boasts a conservative governor ready to pick controversial fights backed up by a large Republican majority. Wisconsin demonstrates that even purple states can win meaningful, albeit limited, conservative victories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/the-wisconsin-higher-ed-reform-model/"&gt;The Wisconsin Higher-Ed Reform Model&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 15:34:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Bipartisan electoral politics stand in the way of property tax relief</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/electoral-politics-property-tax-relief/</link><description>Kansas homeowners aren’t just facing higher property taxes — they’re facing unaffordable assessed valuation increases that make it impossible to budget for life essentials or stay in their homes. Property tax is the #1 affordability issue facing many Kansans, but nothing may be done about it – again – because electoral politics is the #1 [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 15:59:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] An Open Letter to Maine’s Legislature: Stop Advancing a Bill You Know is Unconstitutional</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/an-open-letter-to-maines-legislature-stop-advancing-a-bill-you-know-is-unconstitutional/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Last June, Maine Policy Institute urged Governor Janet Mills to veto LD 1666, a bill expanding ranked-choice voting (RCV) to elections for Governor, State Senator, and State Representative. That request was grounded in clear constitutional text, the Maine Supreme Judicial Court’s 2017 advisory opinion, and Governor Mills’ own legal analysis as Attorney General. Since then, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/an-open-letter-to-maines-legislature-stop-advancing-a-bill-you-know-is-unconstitutional/"&gt;An Open Letter to Maine’s Legislature: Stop Advancing a Bill You Know is Unconstitutional&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 16:39:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Fool Me Twice: Why the Texas Grid is Still Vulnerable to Winter Storms | Part 3: How Texas Can Solve Its Winter Reliability Problem</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/fool-me-twice-why-the-texas-grid-is-still-vulnerable-to-winter-storms-part-3-how-texas-can-solve-its-winter-reliability-problem/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Part 3: How Texas Can Solve Its Winter Reliability Problem Five years after Winter Storm Uri, the ERCOT grid is still not ready for the next major winter storm. The first two installments of this series showed that demand has grown more than 20% since 2021 while firm generation capacity has barely budged, and the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/fool-me-twice-why-the-texas-grid-is-still-vulnerable-to-winter-storms-part-3-how-texas-can-solve-its-winter-reliability-problem/"&gt;Fool Me Twice: Why the Texas Grid is Still Vulnerable to Winter Storms | Part 3: How Texas Can Solve Its Winter Reliability Problem&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 16:50:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Medicaid mission-creeps its way into the housing business</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/medicaid-mission-creeps-its-way-into-providing-homes-for-wisconsinites/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Very few people know it, but Wisconsin’s Medicaid program is in the housing business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not construction or real estate, but assistance in finding a home for any Medicaid recipient with a qualifying health or mental health issue and a qualifying risk of homelessness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/medicaid-mission-creeps-its-way-into-providing-homes-for-wisconsinites/"&gt;Medicaid mission-creeps its way into the housing business&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 17:31:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2026/02/the-outstater-327/</link><description>The Media: Prescience Matters &amp;#8220;A journalist needs a disciplined reverence for the facts, because the temptations of story-telling are strong and seductive.&amp;#8221; — Lance Morrow in &amp;#8220;The Noise of Typewriters&amp;#8221; A SCHOLAR OF OUR FOUNDATION&amp;#160;is an expert at framing questions, instructions and context for Artificial Intelligence (AI). He&amp;#160;and others are training a new profession, Prompt&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2026/02/the-outstater-327/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 18:20:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Wyoming legislators get serious about hospital pricing</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/post/wyoming-legislators-get-serious-about-hospital-pricing</link><description>The Wyoming Legislature is considering a bill that would require hospitals in the state to post prices.  The language of SF 57 would essentially force hospitals to list prices for services and materials, which would allow patients to become informed consumers of health care.</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 18:24:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Increased tax on petroleum would translate to higher cost of living</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/02/increased-tax-on-petroleum-would-translate-to-higher-cost-of-living/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii on Feb. 12, 2026, for consideration by the Senate Committees on Agriculture and Environment and Energy and Intergovernmental Affairs._____________ Feb. 12, 2026, 3:10 p.m.Hawaii State CapitolConference Room 224 and Videoconference To: Senate Committee on Agriculture and Environment       Sen. Mike Gabbard, Chair       Sen. Herbert M. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/02/increased-tax-on-petroleum-would-translate-to-higher-cost-of-living/"&gt;Increased tax on petroleum would translate to higher cost of living&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 18:29:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Louisiana’s Grid Gambit: Is It Time to Let Private Power Play?</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/energy/private-power-play/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Last month, the New Orleans City Council voted unanimously to impose a one-year moratorium on data center development across the city. The debate was heated and familiar: overwhelming concerns about the strain these facilities could place on an already vulnerable grid, the risk of compromised reliability during our next storm season, and the potential for higher electricity...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/energy/private-power-play/"&gt;Louisiana’s Grid Gambit: Is It Time to Let Private Power Play?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 18:45:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Texas Parents Break Records for School Choice Applications</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/education/texas-parents-break-records-for-school-choice-applications/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Kathryn Hickok At last count, more than one and a half million...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/education/texas-parents-break-records-for-school-choice-applications/"&gt;Texas Parents Break Records for School Choice Applications&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 19:45:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Idaho online safety bill would track a child's every click</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/post/idaho-online-safety-bill-would-track-a-child-s-every-click</link><description>At its core, H542 does not merely regulate social media. It mandates the creation of a vast, permanent tracking system that would monitor how long every user spends online, trigger escalating identity checks, and store increasingly sensitive personal data. That should give every Idahoan pause.</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 19:54:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Metro’s Plan for Making Housing More Expensive</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/reports/metros-plan-for-making-housing-more-expensive/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Randal O’Toole High housing prices in the Portland area led to a&amp;#160;legislative...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/reports/metros-plan-for-making-housing-more-expensive/"&gt;Metro’s Plan for Making Housing More Expensive&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 20:18:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Bookmark this site: MNFraud Files.com</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/bookmark-this-site-mnfraud-files-com/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Center of the American Experiment today launched&amp;#160;MNFraudFiles.com, a website that will serve as a clearinghouse for information on Minnesota’s epidemic of fraud in state government. The site was in production before Gov. Tim Walz released his “Fact Check” webpage this week, attempting to rebut five random claims about fraud in Minnesota.&amp;#160;MNFraudFiles.com&amp;#160;is a robust site with...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/bookmark-this-site-mnfraud-files-com/"&gt;Bookmark this site: MNFraud Files.com&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 20:53:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] Jake Curtis Joins the Benjamin Yount Show</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/jake-curtis-joins-the-benjamin-yount-show/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Listen to the interview here. https://youtu.be/sxbsni1kot4?si=EU3oINN-O1XkTNTN&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/jake-curtis-joins-the-benjamin-yount-show/"&gt;Jake Curtis Joins the Benjamin Yount Show&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 21:03:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG urges Wisconsin lawmakers to question DPI secrecy</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-urges-wisconsin-lawmakers-to-question-dpi-secrecy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;IRG urges Wisconsin lawmakers to question DPI secrecy (The Center Square) – It’s not just the nearly $400,000 expense that has one watchdog group wanting more from Wisconsin’s public school managers. The Institute for Reforming Government on Thursday said lawmakers in Madison need to question the secrecy around the Department of Public Instruction&amp;#8217;s 2024 meeting to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-urges-wisconsin-lawmakers-to-question-dpi-secrecy/"&gt;IRG urges Wisconsin lawmakers to question DPI secrecy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 21:08:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Illinois on track to lose another congressional seat</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/illinois-on-track-to-lose-another-congressional-seat/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Illinois is on pace to lose a seat in Congress based on new census data. International immigration and interstate migration are driving those projections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/illinois-on-track-to-lose-another-congressional-seat/"&gt;Illinois on track to lose another congressional seat&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 21:39:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Kent: Legislators should cut budget, not hike taxes</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/02/kent-legislators-should-cut-budget-not-hike-taxes/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Gov. Josh Green’s proposal to “pause” the phase-in of Hawaii’s historic income tax cuts enacted in 2024 is essentially a tax hike, according to Joe Kent, executive vice president of the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii.&amp;#160; “A lot of people in Hawaii were counting on this money, and we need it to survive the cost of [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/02/kent-legislators-should-cut-budget-not-hike-taxes/"&gt;Kent: Legislators should cut budget, not hike taxes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 22:06:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Legislature Advances WILL-Backed Initiatives to Rein in Regulatory Authority of Unelected Bureaucrats</title><link>https://will-law.org/legislature-advances-will-backed-initiatives-to-rein-in-regulatory-authority-of-unelected-bureaucrats/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Wisconsin Assembly voted in favor of several legislative initiatives supported by WILL to reign in the bureaucratic state, which has taken rulemaking and regulatory authority away from Wisconsin’s Legislative Branch.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/legislature-advances-will-backed-initiatives-to-rein-in-regulatory-authority-of-unelected-bureaucrats/"&gt;Legislature Advances WILL-Backed Initiatives to Rein in Regulatory Authority of Unelected Bureaucrats&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 23:19:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Commuter changed jobs to avoid tolls, warns of rate hikes</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/commuter-changed-jobs-to-avoid-tolls-warns-of-rate-hikes/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;State lawmakers voted to hike road tolls in 2027, even though the state has billions in the road fund it’s not using. Some drivers are reconsidering their commutes; Laura Valdez explains why she cut toll roads out of her routine years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/commuter-changed-jobs-to-avoid-tolls-warns-of-rate-hikes/"&gt;Commuter changed jobs to avoid tolls, warns of rate hikes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 23:41:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] A factless fact check</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/a-factless-fact-check/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Walz Adminitration debuted their fraud &amp;#8220;fact check&amp;#8221; to much acclaim earlier this week. Tag line, The place for Minnesotans to find accurate information about our fight against fraud. From the Minneapolis Star Tribune, Minnesota creates fraud &amp;#8216;fact check&amp;#8217; amid national political scrutiny. Perhaps &amp;#8220;acclaim&amp;#8221; was too strong, given the scare quotes in the Star...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/a-factless-fact-check/"&gt;A factless fact check&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 00:38:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Court-Appointed Monitor Spends Tens of Millions While Leaving Taxpayers in the Dark</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/court-monitor/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In 2007, a traffic stop in Cave Creek, Arizona, set in motion a chain of events that would ultimately redefine..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/court-monitor/"&gt;Court-Appointed Monitor Spends Tens of Millions While Leaving Taxpayers in the Dark&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 01:35:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] California’s healthcare industrial complex is booming. Guess who’s paying?</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/californias-healthcare-industrial-complex-is-booming-guess-whos-paying/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=californias-healthcare-industrial-complex-is-booming-guess-whos-paying</link><description>&lt;p&gt;California’s hospitals recorded $11.3 billion in total net income in 2024 — 10% above pre-pandemic levels. The average hospital CEO in the state earns roughly $920,000 a year. And the largest union representing healthcare workers collected $114.5 million in dues in 2024 alone, according to its federal LM-2 filing — spending just 16 cents of...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/californias-healthcare-industrial-complex-is-booming-guess-whos-paying/"&gt;California’s healthcare industrial complex is booming. Guess who’s paying?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 03:28:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Grassroot testimonies — early February 2026</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/02/grassroot-testimonies-early-february-2026/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following are state and county testimonies submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii in February 2026._____________ STATE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES &gt;&gt; HB276 HD1 — “Exempt certain condo builders from unsold unit fees, annual reporting” &gt;&gt; HB1521 — “Apply sunshine law to contractors working for public agencies” &gt;&gt; HB1611 — “Phase out GE tax on [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/02/grassroot-testimonies-early-february-2026/"&gt;Grassroot testimonies — early February 2026&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 03:53:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] House Bill 598 — Campaign finance, accounts (-1)</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/house-bill-598-campaign-finance-accounts/</link><description>Bill Description:&amp;#160;House Bill 598 would require political candidates to open a separate bank account for campaign contributions and to transfer any personal loans to the campaign into the separate campaign bank account. Rating: -1 Does it violate the spirit or the letter of either the United States Constitution or the Idaho Constitution? Examples include restrictions [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 03:57:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] House Bill 632 — Government ethics, public record (+1)</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/house-bill-632-government-ethics-public-record/</link><description>Bill Description:&amp;#160;House Bill 632 would make it clear that public employees can share non-confidential information with the Idaho Legislature and prohibit their employers from retaliating.&amp;#160; NOTE: House Bill 632 is similar to House Bill 510 (2026). Compared to its predecessor, House Bill 632 provides some clarifications and wording changes that do not substantively change the [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 04:00:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Elite white liberals show disdain for others in voter ID debate</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/elite-white-liberals-show-disdain-for-others-in-voter-id-debate/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;M.D. Kittle writes for the Federalist about Democrats’ collective response to voter ID. Elite white liberals think black voters are helpless, incompetent, and stupid. They don’t think too highly of married women and rural Americans, either. Or poor people and Native Americans and the disabled for that matter.&amp;#160; That condescension was on full display again...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/elite-white-liberals-show-disdain-for-others-in-voter-id-debate/"&gt;Elite white liberals show disdain for others in voter ID debate&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 10:36:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Feds find links between Chinese communists and Code Pink</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/feds-find-links-between-chinese-communists-and-code-pink/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Natalia Mittelstadt writes for Just the News about a federal agency’s interesting revelation. The State Department has concluded that Code Pink and People&amp;#8217;s Forum are linked to Chinese influence operations, according to a report the agency sent to Congress. “Partisan hacks spent years peddling the phony Russia collusion hoax while turning a blind eye to...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/feds-find-links-between-chinese-communists-and-code-pink/"&gt;Feds find links between Chinese communists and Code Pink&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 10:39:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Feds expose another $120M Medicaid scam in New York</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/feds-expose-another-120m-medicaid-scam-in-new-york/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Samuel Short writes for the Western Journal about a recently exposed case of government fraud. Fraud is not just a Minnesota problem or a California problem; it’s proving itself to be a problem&amp;#160;across the country. The latest saw two Korean men in Queens, New York, allegedly defraud Medicaid for $120 million through a senior care...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/feds-expose-another-120m-medicaid-scam-in-new-york/"&gt;Feds expose another $120M Medicaid scam in New York&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 10:42:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] I (heart) freedom, and you should too</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2026/i-(heart)-freedom-and-you-should-too</link><description>The Mackinac Center has many ways to show you care</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Tariffs: The high price homebuilding pays for protectionism</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/tariffs-the-high-price-homebuilding-pays-for-protectionism/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Reality-television stars are rarely consulted on matters of public policy. But in April, Realtor.com asked Tarek El Moussa to comment on the White House’s “Liberation Day” tariffs.. The Southern California entrepreneur, who rose to fame on the popularity of HGTV’s Flip or Flop franchise, warned that higher import taxes would harm “new-home builders” and “first-time buyers” the most [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/tariffs-the-high-price-homebuilding-pays-for-protectionism/"&gt;Tariffs: The high price homebuilding pays for protectionism&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 11:00:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Common ground on immigration: Poll finds 85% of Minnesotans support cooperation between local police and federal immigration authorities</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/common-ground-on-immigration-poll-finds-85-of-minnesotans-support-cooperation-between-local-police-and-federal-immigration-authorities/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Operation Metro Surge is winding down. What should state government do going forward? In the last couple of weeks, I have tried to use polling data to discover what Minnesotans think our state government ought to do about the issue of illegal immigration. Its options are limited owing to the fact that immigration policy is...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/common-ground-on-immigration-poll-finds-85-of-minnesotans-support-cooperation-between-local-police-and-federal-immigration-authorities/"&gt;Common ground on immigration: Poll finds 85% of Minnesotans support cooperation between local police and federal immigration authorities&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 14:00:19 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>