<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>State-Policy Think-Tank Digest</title><link>https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml</link><description>Latest posts from free-market policy institutes across the U.S.</description><atom:link href="https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 20:03:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>[Foropportunity] On Thanksgiving, remember that gratitude makes good citizens, heals divisions</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/gratitude-makes-good-citizens-and-heals-divisions/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/gratitude-makes-good-citizens-and-heals-divisions/"&gt;On Thanksgiving, remember that gratitude makes good citizens, heals divisions&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 23:00:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] The War of Visions</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/11/28/the-war-of-visions/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Across the country, Americans are no longer divided simply by policy or party but by rival moral imaginations—two incompatible visions of truth, freedom, and even human nature itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/11/28/the-war-of-visions/"&gt;The War of Visions&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 00:23:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] A Very Grateful Immigrant’s Thanksgiving</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/a-very-grateful-immigrants-thanksgiving/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Having just celebrated Thanksgiving across the United States, I’ve been reminded of what makes this holiday truly special.&amp;#160;&amp;#160;If you’re an American who’s grown up with the holiday your whole life, it’s easy to take it for granted. Speaking as an immigrant, let me tell you: there’s something genuinely magical about a country setting aside a [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/a-very-grateful-immigrants-thanksgiving/" rel="nofollow"&gt;A Very Grateful Immigrant’s Thanksgiving&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 21:11:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] New Hampshire ranked freest state in North America for 24th time</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/12/new-hampshire-ranked-freest-state-in-north-america-for-24th-time/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New Hampshire ranks as the freest state in North America, as measured in this year’s Economic Freedom of North America report, released today by the Josiah Bartlett Center for Public Policy in conjunction with Canada’s Fraser Institute. For the 24th time, New Hampshire is the freest state among all U.S. states, having scored 8.34 out [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/12/new-hampshire-ranked-freest-state-in-north-america-for-24th-time/"&gt;New Hampshire ranked freest state in North America for 24th time&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 12:52:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG Polling: April 2025</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-polling-april-2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;April 16, 2025 NEW IRG Poll: Voters Decided Election on Abortion, Musk &amp;#38; Trump’s Agenda Despite all the emphasis on crime, voters were focused elsewhere  Delafield, Wis. –  The Institute for Reforming Government (IRG) is continuing its public polling project with Napolitan News Service and Scott Rasmussen in 2025, with the focus in this poll on Wisconsin’s [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-polling-april-2025/"&gt;IRG Polling: April 2025&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 20:28:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Book Highlights Advances in Digital Education, Policies to Unlock Its Benefits</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/book-highlights-advances-in-digital-education-policies-to-unlock-its-benefits/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;BOSTON – A new book co-edited by national digital education leader Julie Young draws on best practices and multiple studies published by Pioneer Institute to recount three decades of advances in digital education and highlights the policies necessary for students to fully...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/book-highlights-advances-in-digital-education-policies-to-unlock-its-benefits/"&gt;Book Highlights Advances in Digital Education, Policies to Unlock Its Benefits &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 12:06:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] Court Watch: Wisconsin Supreme Court Reverses, Consolidates Power Through New Court Management Order</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/court-watch-wisconsin-supreme-court-reverses-consolidates-power-through-new-court-management-order/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Court Watch: Wisconsin Supreme Court Reverses, Consolidates Power Through New Court Management Order Progressive majority reshapes internal court governance to cement its control of the judicial branch Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government’s Court Watch issued the following statement after the Wisconsin Supreme Court quietly issued a new court management order just days [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/court-watch-wisconsin-supreme-court-reverses-consolidates-power-through-new-court-management-order/"&gt;Court Watch: Wisconsin Supreme Court Reverses, Consolidates Power Through New Court Management Order&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 16:58:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] The Hidden Gem: Why Education Freedom is the New Economic Development</title><link>https://empowerms.org/the-hidden-gem-why-education-freedom-is-the-new-economic-development/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Forget industrial parks. The driver for economic growth in rural Mississippi is education freedom, which is the most powerful yet often overlooked tool in our economic development chest. I’ve dedicated my academic research to the topic, stemming from a comment I heard years ago at Starkville City Hall: “Education is the biggest driver of community-economic&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/the-hidden-gem-why-education-freedom-is-the-new-economic-development/"&gt;The Hidden Gem: Why Education Freedom is the New Economic Development&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 17:46:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Portland Public Schools’ Risky Real Estate Gamble</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/education/portland-public-schools-risky-real-estate-gamble/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Eric Fruits, Ph.D. On December 2, Portland Public Schools (PPS) board voted...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/education/portland-public-schools-risky-real-estate-gamble/"&gt;Portland Public Schools’ Risky Real Estate Gamble&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 01:25:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] A ‘Repeal Day’ glance at Liquor Commission revenues</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/12/a-repeal-day-glance-at-liquor-commission-revenues/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;December 5 is neither a federal nor state day of celebration, but it probably should be. On Dec. 5, 1933, Pennsylvania, Ohio and Utah became the final states to ratify the 21st Amendment to the U.S. Constitution.  The night before, toasting your Aunt Gertrude’s 92nd birthday with a glass of champagne was illegal. That evening, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/12/a-repeal-day-glance-at-liquor-commission-revenues/"&gt;A &amp;#8216;Repeal Day&amp;#8217; glance at Liquor Commission revenues&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 22:09:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Georgia candidates for governor should make welfare reform a top priority</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/georgia-candidates-for-governor-should-make-welfare-reform-a-top-priority/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/georgia-candidates-for-governor-should-make-welfare-reform-a-top-priority/"&gt;Georgia candidates for governor should make welfare reform a top priority&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 16:58:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] OPINION: New Mexico’s economic freedom is now dead last</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/opinion-new-mexicos-economic-freedom-is-now-dead-last/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following appeared in the Albuquerque Journal  on December 7, 2025. In a study published earlier this year, we highlighted the fact that New Mexico was the only state in the U.S. to have lost economic freedom since 1981. We now know that it is worse than we thought. People are more economically free when [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/opinion-new-mexicos-economic-freedom-is-now-dead-last/"&gt;OPINION: New Mexico&amp;#8217;s economic freedom is now dead last&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 17:53:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Wichita should reallocate spending rather than add a new (rushed?) 1% sales tax</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/sales-tax-proposal-rushed-wichita/</link><description>The Wichita City Council seems poised to rush a proposal to the ballot for a 1-cent sales tax to raise $850 million over seven years for several new projects. That at least implies that imposing a new tax is the only way to fund “public safety projects, property tax relief, and revitalizing Century II and [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 19:55:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] Empty Schools, Empty Wallets: How ESSER Pandemic Aid Led to More School Referenda</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/empty-schools-empty-wallets-how-esser-pandemic-aid-led-to-more-school-referenda/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Empty Schools, Empty Wallets: How ESSER Pandemic Aid Led to More School Referenda New IRG analysis reveals hiring sprees and poor financial decisions as Wisconsin schools fall behind national leaders Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government released a new report on Tuesday, “Empty Schools, Empty Wallets: What Happened to $1.49 Billion in ESSER [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/empty-schools-empty-wallets-how-esser-pandemic-aid-led-to-more-school-referenda/"&gt;Empty Schools, Empty Wallets: How ESSER Pandemic Aid Led to More School Referenda&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 15:02:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Massachusetts Subsidized Housing Inventory Update Shows Record Number of Communities Exceed Critical Threshold</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/massachusetts-subsidized-housing-inventory-update-shows-record-number-of-communities-exceed-critical-threshold/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This edition of The House Call explores the 2025 update to Massachusetts&amp;#8217; Subsidized Housing Inventory, showing a spike in the number of communities that have at least 10% of their housing stocks in the Inventory. It also explains the housing-related ballot questions that could...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/massachusetts-subsidized-housing-inventory-update-shows-record-number-of-communities-exceed-critical-threshold/"&gt;Massachusetts Subsidized Housing Inventory Update Shows Record Number of Communities Exceed Critical Threshold&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 20:35:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Commissioner Andy Gipson: Family, Food Security, and Mississippi’s Future</title><link>https://empowerms.org/commissioner-andy-gipson-family-food-security-and-mississippis-future/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Commissioner Andy Gipson: Family, Food Security, and Mississippi’s Future On this episode of The Empower Podcast, host Grant Callen sits down with Commissioner Andy Gipson—Mississippi’s Commissioner of Agriculture and Commerce, former state legislator, Baptist minister, cattleman, and announced candidate for governor. Gipson shares how his journey into public service began with a desire to secure&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/commissioner-andy-gipson-family-food-security-and-mississippis-future/"&gt;Commissioner Andy Gipson: Family, Food Security, and Mississippi’s Future&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:49:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Nebraska Zoning Permitting Process: Recommended Adjustments in Nebraska</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-zoning-permitting-process-recommended-adjustments-in-nebraska/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Nebraska’s zoning and permitting process for livestock operations is inconsistent, unpredictable, and varies widely from county to county. This report examines how Nebraska’s Conditional Use Permit (CUP) system works, the origins and goals of the Livestock Siting Assessment Matrix created under LB106, and why the Matrix remains underused nearly a decade later. Drawing on survey...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-zoning-permitting-process-recommended-adjustments-in-nebraska/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Nebraska Zoning Permitting Process: Recommended Adjustments in Nebraska&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 15:17:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] WILL Hires Associate Counsel to Grow Legal and Policy Capacity in Wisconsin and Beyond</title><link>https://will-law.org/will-hires-associate-counsel-to-grow-legal-and-policy-capacity-in-wisconsin-and-beyond/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL has announced Erin Gamble as our new Associate Counsel. Her hire reflects our organization’s commitment to fighting back against bureaucratic overreach in Wisconsin and across the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/will-hires-associate-counsel-to-grow-legal-and-policy-capacity-in-wisconsin-and-beyond/"&gt;WILL Hires Associate Counsel to Grow Legal and Policy Capacity in Wisconsin and Beyond&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 15:23:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Creating links that change lives: Georgia Center for Opportunity partners with Connect to Work GA</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/gco-partners-with-connect-to-work-ga/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This collaboration will help lift job seekers above the poverty line by providing opportunities for successful careers and upward mobility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/gco-partners-with-connect-to-work-ga/"&gt;Creating links that change lives: Georgia Center for Opportunity partners with Connect to Work GA&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 20:09:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Legislature balks as Evers demands millions for more food aid bureaucrats</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/legislature-balks-as-evers-demands-millions-for-more-food-aid-bureaucrats/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Gov. Tony Evers is pressing the Legislature for $70 million to process FoodShare applications to stave off federal penalties that could cost state taxpayers as much as $225 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/legislature-balks-as-evers-demands-millions-for-more-food-aid-bureaucrats/"&gt;Legislature balks as Evers demands millions for more food aid bureaucrats&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 21:58:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] “Fully Funded Schools” Are a Moving Goal Post</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/education/fully-funded-schools-are-a-moving-goal-post/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Kathryn Hickok How much money does it take to “fully fund” Oregon’s...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/education/fully-funded-schools-are-a-moving-goal-post/"&gt;“Fully Funded Schools” Are a Moving Goal Post&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 17:22:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Taxpayers Asked to Fund a Hospital Takeover They’re Not Allowed to See</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/12/12/taxpayers-asked-to-fund-a-hospital-takeover-theyre-not-allowed-to-see/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Connecticut lawmakers pushed the UConn Health hospital acquisition bill through the November special session — without a public hearing — it was clear transparency was not the priority.   [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/12/12/taxpayers-asked-to-fund-a-hospital-takeover-theyre-not-allowed-to-see/"&gt;Taxpayers Asked to Fund a Hospital Takeover They’re Not Allowed to See&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 18:13:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Would you invest in Massachusetts or New Hampshire?</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/12/would-you-invest-in-massachusetts-or-new-hampshire/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;If U.S. states were companies that traded on the stock market, the only New England state with a “buy” rating would probably be New Hampshire.  Massachusetts could be called “Big Blue,” the tradition-bound leader cruising on its prior reputation, but falling behind smaller upstarts that have embraced innovation and rapid growth.  New Hampshire would be [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/12/would-you-invest-in-massachusetts-or-new-hampshire/"&gt;Would you invest in Massachusetts or New Hampshire?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 21:10:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Arkansaspolicyfoundation] ARKANSAS GOV. SARAH HUCKABEE SANDERS &amp; STATE INCOME TAX CUTS</title><link>https://arkansaspolicyfoundation.org/arkansas-gov-sarah-huckabee-sanders-state-income-tax-cuts/</link><description>(4Q-2025) Arkansas Gov. Sarah Huckabee Sanders is the Natural State’s first female governor. Since taking office in January 2023, Sanders has also distinguished herself by advancing three separate reductions in Arkansas’ top income tax rate from 4.9 to 3.9 percent. The income tax was reduced from 7.0% to 6.9% in 2013 under Democratic Gov. Mike [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 14:33:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Todd Schaible: The Importance of Career and Technical Education in Tennessee Schools</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/todd-schaible-the-importance-of-career-technical-education-in-tennessee-schools/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=todd-schaible-the-importance-of-career-technical-education-in-tennessee-schools</link><description>By elevating CTE in Tennessee schools, we can increase support for employers and improve workforce readiness for students across the state.</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 15:34:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] Albuquerque Journal editorializes in defense of free speech, Rio Grande Foundation in “hoodie-gate”</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/albuquerque-journal-editorializes-in-defense-of-free-speech-rio-grande-foundation-in-hoodie-gate/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Rio Grande Foundation has received a great deal of publicity from all corners of Albuquerque&amp;#8217;s political scene due to our involvement in reporting on the I ♥ Tim Keller &amp;#8220;hoodies for the homeless&amp;#8221; effort. As we&amp;#8217;ve discussed at length here and in other locations the Mayor&amp;#8217;s campaign has reacted to our reporting and refusal [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/albuquerque-journal-editorializes-in-defense-of-free-speech-rio-grande-foundation-in-hoodie-gate/"&gt;Albuquerque Journal editorializes in defense of free speech, Rio Grande Foundation in &amp;#8220;hoodie-gate&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 16:53:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Portland Studies Inclusionary Zoning (Again) Despite Evidence</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/portland-studies-inclusionary-zoning-again-despite-evidence/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Portland is commissioning its own study on the “effects of inclusionary zoning,” as if the question was unsettled, novel, or open. It isn’t. Across the ideological spectrum, from UC Berkeley to NYU Law to George Mason and numerous think tanks, colleges, and studies across the country, the research record is remarkably consistent: inclusionary zoning reduces housing [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/portland-studies-inclusionary-zoning-again-despite-evidence/"&gt;Portland Studies Inclusionary Zoning (Again) Despite Evidence&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 17:47:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] Franke: Reapportionment</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/12/franke-reapportionment/</link><description>by Mark Franke The Indiana General Assembly’s special session appears to be over, having voted down a mid-decade congressional reapportionment proposal. The legislature is required to reapportion after each decennial census but not more often, although nothing prevents more frequent efforts other than their fiscal and political costs. Despite the heavy-handed involvement of Donald Trump&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/12/franke-reapportionment/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 17:48:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Mississippi's Free-Market Turnaround: A Model for America</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/mississippis-free-market-turnaround-a-model-for-america/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For decades, Mississippi has been the punchline in national discussions about economic performance - often ranked at the bottom in income, education, and opportunity. But something remarkable has happened in recent years: the Magnolia State is undergoing a genuine resurgence, driven not by federal handouts or gimmicks, but by principled free-market reforms. A major national [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/mississippis-free-market-turnaround-a-model-for-america/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi&amp;#039;s Free-Market Turnaround: A Model for America&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 21:13:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Enrollment and Employment: Is Tennessee Preparing K-12 Students for Today’s Economy?</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/enrollment-and-employment-is-tennessee-preparing-k-12-students-for-todays-economy/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=enrollment-and-employment-is-tennessee-preparing-k-12-students-for-todays-economy</link><description>Tennessee is doing well in providing Career and Technical Education (CTE) opportunities to students, but policymakers should recognize that improvements can be made.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 02:17:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Florida Politics: Bedrock, We Have a Problem</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/florida-politics-bedrock-we-have-a-problem/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A funny thing happened in the Legislature last week. While the House was holding an “AI Week” to...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/florida-politics-bedrock-we-have-a-problem/"&gt;Florida Politics: Bedrock, We Have a Problem&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 16:05:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Introducing EPIC: A New Investment in Solution Development</title><link>https://empowerms.org/introducing-epic-a-new-investment-in-solution-development/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For more than a decade, Empower Mississippi has worked to advance opportunity-focused policy at the State Capitol. Many of you have been partners in that work — meeting with lawmakers, investing financially, and championing reforms that help Mississippians live free, work meaningfully, and learn effectively. From the beginning, our advocacy has been grounded in research&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/introducing-epic-a-new-investment-in-solution-development/"&gt;Introducing EPIC: A New Investment in Solution Development&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 16:08:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Kansas’s Revenue Mirage and the Case for a Responsible Budget in 2026</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/kansas-revenue-mirage-responsible-budget/</link><description>The Kansas State government may be collecting more money than expected, but that should make lawmakers nervous, not comfortable.  Individual income tax collections are surging, but at the same time retail sales are slowing and corporate income tax revenues are weakening. When workers get paid more while consumers and businesses pull back, the economy is [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 16:34:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Matthew Gagnon: Gov. Mills Allowing ICE Bill to Pass is “Cowardly”</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/matt-gagnon-gov-mills-allowing-ice-bill-to-pass-is-cowardly/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In an op-ed written to the Portland Press Herald, Governor Janet Mills announced that she will allow a controversial bill, LD 1971, to become law without her signature, limiting police cooperation with federal immigration authorities. Citing concerns about the bill’s broadness and President Trump’s actions, Mills argued that the times necessitate the law, despite not [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/matt-gagnon-gov-mills-allowing-ice-bill-to-pass-is-cowardly/"&gt;Matthew Gagnon: Gov. Mills Allowing ICE Bill to Pass is &amp;#8220;Cowardly&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 20:07:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] Franke: Farm Subsidies — A Better Way</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/12/franke-farm-subsidies-a-better-way/</link><description>by Mark Franke One of the reasons I look forward to our monthly Socratic discussion group is the opportunity to learn something new. Regardless of what knowledge I have of the designated topic going in, two hours of rigorous discussion later and I leave knowing much more. Last month the topic was agricultural subsidies and&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/12/franke-farm-subsidies-a-better-way/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 13:30:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Research Note: Changes in AI Regulations</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/research-note-changes-in-ai-regulations/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On Thursday, December 11, President Trump signed an executive order aimed at limiting state-level regulations on artificial intelligence (AI). The order is the latest in a series of efforts by the administration to centralize AI governance at the federal level. While it takes a distinctive approach, the order also introduces several practical and legal challenges.  ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/research-note-changes-in-ai-regulations/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Research Note: Changes in AI Regulations&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 15:29:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Pioneer New England Legal Foundation and Sullivan &amp; Worcester Sue Boston Over Retaliatory Tax Scheme</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/pioneer-legal-foundation-sullivan-worcester-sue-boston-over-retaliatory-tax-scheme/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Class action challenges city’s unlawful penalties against commercial taxpayers who exercised their right to appeal; seeks court intervention to end this retaliatory scheme in next fiscal year BOSTON, MA — Pioneer New England Legal Foundation (the Legal Foundation) and Sullivan &amp;#38; Worcester...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/pioneer-legal-foundation-sullivan-worcester-sue-boston-over-retaliatory-tax-scheme/"&gt;Pioneer New England Legal Foundation and Sullivan &amp;amp; Worcester Sue Boston Over Retaliatory Tax Scheme&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 18:43:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Florida Politics: The Ghost (Students) of Public School Future?</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/florida-politics-the-ghost-students-of-public-school-future/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;U.S. Secretary of Education Linda McMahon announced last week that her department plans to step up efforts to...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/florida-politics-the-ghost-students-of-public-school-future/"&gt;Florida Politics: The Ghost (Students) of Public School Future?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 14:49:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] A promising AI safety tool for teen accounts</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/a-promising-ai-safety-tool-for-teen-accounts</link><description>In October, Meta announced a new “teen AI safety” approach for Instagram, Facebook, and its other platforms.  The headline change is simple but important: parents will soon have a built-in “kill switch” for one-on-one chats between their teens and AI characters. Additionally, it’ll provide better insight into what their teens are doing with AI on Meta’s apps. This is exactly the type of voluntary, market-driven parental tool we highlighted in The Parental Guide to Understanding Digital Media...</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 15:14:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] We’ve Got Talent: Encouraging the Innovators and Students of Our Nation Towards Excellence</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/encouraging-the-innovators-and-students-of-our-nation-towards-excellence/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The United States is home to some of the most genius innovators and groundbreaking technologies of the modern age. Headlines in high profile news outlets frequently recount the cutthroat competition between tech companies and entrepreneurs, eager to develop products that change lives and win over the market. Excellence is the result of this competitive environment,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/encouraging-the-innovators-and-students-of-our-nation-towards-excellence/"&gt;We’ve Got Talent: Encouraging the Innovators and Students of Our Nation Towards Excellence&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 15:59:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Marquette poll finds 80 percent of Americans trust government ‘only some of the time’ or ‘never’</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/marquette-poll-finds-80-percent-of-americans-trust-government-only-some-of-the-time-or-never/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Widespread, intergenerational skepticism of government is not merely the result of America’s increasingly cutthroat politics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/marquette-poll-finds-80-percent-of-americans-trust-government-only-some-of-the-time-or-never/"&gt;Marquette poll finds 80 percent of Americans trust government ‘only some of the time’ or ‘never’&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 16:58:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Freedom Foundation Forces AFSCME to Refund Dues and Honor Minnesota Worker’s Rights</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/litigation/freedom-foundation-forces-afscme-to-refund-dues-and-honor-minnesota-workers-rights/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A simple request was met with silence. In July of 2024, John Cashman, a senior press operator with the Minnesota Department of Transportation, followed his employer’s instructions and contacted AFSCME Local 221 directly to resign his union membership and revoke his dues authorization.&amp;#160;&amp;#160; He emailed a field representative affirmatively stating his intent to opt out [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/litigation/freedom-foundation-forces-afscme-to-refund-dues-and-honor-minnesota-workers-rights/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation Forces AFSCME to Refund Dues and Honor Minnesota Worker’s Rights&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 17:09:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Santa aids Freedom Foundation outreach for another holiday season</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/santa-aids-freedom-foundation-outreach-for-another-holiday-season/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;To cut through the holiday and end-of-year chaos, we took a familiar twist. As they do every year, our outreach team members suited up as Santa Claus and his helpers to spark conversations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/santa-aids-freedom-foundation-outreach-for-another-holiday-season/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Santa aids Freedom Foundation outreach for another holiday season&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 21:05:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Albany’s School Speed Zone Camera Summer Daze</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/albanys-school-speed-zone-camera-summer-daze/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This fall, Governor Kathy Hochul signed into law bills containing the state’s permission for three cities — Mount Vernon, Schenectady....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/albanys-school-speed-zone-camera-summer-daze/"&gt;Albany’s School Speed Zone Camera Summer Daze&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 21:59:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] U.S. House defangs federal protection of gray wolves in Wisconsin</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/us-house-defangs-federal-protection-of-gray-wolves-in-wisconsin/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The U.S. House of Representatives Thursday passed a bill that would remove the state’s rapidly expanding and aggressive gray wolf population from the endangered species list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/us-house-defangs-federal-protection-of-gray-wolves-in-wisconsin/"&gt;U.S. House defangs federal protection of gray wolves in Wisconsin&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 22:32:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Ugly Math for Taxpayers</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/ugly-math-for-taxpayers/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=ugly-math-for-taxpayers</link><description>Taxpayer-funded lobbying (TFL) is nothing new in Tennessee, but it is almost universally frowned upon.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 22:52:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Senator Bill Cassidy Champions Pro-Worker Policies</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/legal-regulatory/senator-bill-cassidy-champions-pro-worker-policies/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Last month, United States Senator Bill Cassidy (R-Louisiana) and his colleagues on the Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions (HELP) Committee introduced a package of bills intended to modernize labor law, protect workers’ paychecks and privacy rights, and ensure that workers are empowered to decide whether their union is working for them. Sen. Cassidy explained...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/legal-regulatory/senator-bill-cassidy-champions-pro-worker-policies/"&gt;Senator Bill Cassidy Champions Pro-Worker Policies&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 23:00:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] The Public Purpose Program: California’s Hidden Tax Driving Up Utility Bills</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/17209-2/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=17209-2</link><description>&lt;p&gt;After several rate hikes implemented in the last few years alone, Californians are asking why their energy bills keep climbing when they use the same amount of electricity or gas. According to a 2023 report from the Transparency Foundation, residents of California pay up to 67% more for electricity and 30% more for natural gas...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/17209-2/"&gt;The Public Purpose Program: California’s Hidden Tax Driving Up Utility Bills&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 23:58:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Oregon’s “Prosperity Roadmap” Must Follow the Path of Liberty</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/economic-opportunity/oregons-prosperity-roadmap-must-follow-the-path-of-liberty/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Naomi Inman Early this December, Governor Tina Kotek’s newsroom unveiled “Oregon’s Prosperity...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/economic-opportunity/oregons-prosperity-roadmap-must-follow-the-path-of-liberty/"&gt;Oregon’s “Prosperity Roadmap” Must Follow the Path of Liberty&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 00:20:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] Why the Proposed Shift in Investigatory Power Raises Serious Concerns</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/12/why-the-proposed-shift-in-investigatory-power-raises-serious-concerns/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;by Megan Whitman, NJPI Junior Economy Fellow &amp;#160; New Jersey lawmakers have been considering Bill S4924, which would significantly change [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/12/why-the-proposed-shift-in-investigatory-power-raises-serious-concerns/"&gt;Why the Proposed Shift in Investigatory Power Raises Serious Concerns&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 13:41:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Ninety New York Educators Receive $300k+ in Annual Pay</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/ninety-new-york-educators-receive-300k-in-annual-pay/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Ninety employees from New York’s school districts (outside New York City) received more than $300,000 during fiscal year 2025, according....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/ninety-new-york-educators-receive-300k-in-annual-pay/"&gt;Ninety New York Educators Receive $300k+ in Annual Pay&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 14:27:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] Schansberg: Tariffs on Santa Claus?</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/12/schansberg-tariffs-on-santa-claus/</link><description>by Eric Schansberg, Ph.D. Following in the footsteps of President Donald Trump, I have a modest policy proposal that is extravagant in style and would hurt the economy — a petition to eliminate competition from Santa Claus through tariffs and other trade barriers. From a Trumpian perspective, Santa’s enterprise is clearly an unfair and harmful&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/12/schansberg-tariffs-on-santa-claus/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 14:58:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] The Subsidy Scheme</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/the-subsidy-scheme/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The House just took an important step toward restoring sanity to America’s health care system by voting to support the Republican health care plan. While critics will reflexively attack the vote, the reality is that the right is finally confronting the real drivers of high health care costs. It rolls back costly federal mandates, expands...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/the-subsidy-scheme/"&gt;The Subsidy Scheme&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 17:05:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Medicaid’s Wake-Up Call</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/health-care/medicaids-wake-up-call/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For years, federal audits of state Medicaid programs weren&amp;#8217;t much more than a bureaucratic annoyance. Come 2030, Missouri has something [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/health-care/medicaids-wake-up-call/"&gt;Medicaid&amp;#8217;s Wake-Up Call&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 17:21:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] CDC Labels Minority Neighborhoods as “Vulnerable,” Encouraging the Spread of DEI Spending Nationwide</title><link>https://will-law.org/cdc-labels-minority-neighborhoods-as-vulnerable-encouraging-the-spread-of-dei-spending-nationwide/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In new findings provided to the Trump Administration’s Health and Human Services (HHS) agency, WILL has uncovered that the Center for Disease Control (CDC) uses a race-based criteria to declare whole communities and neighborhoods as “socially vulnerable” based on the number of minorities living there. Cities and states around the country rely on the CDC’s “social vulnerability index” (SVI) to allocate taxpayer funding for parks, drinking water, and disaster assistance.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/cdc-labels-minority-neighborhoods-as-vulnerable-encouraging-the-spread-of-dei-spending-nationwide/"&gt;CDC Labels Minority Neighborhoods as “Vulnerable,” Encouraging the Spread of DEI Spending Nationwide&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 18:18:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Housing Advocates Acknowledge New Law Shifts Authority Away from Towns</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/12/19/housing-advocates-acknowledge-new-law-shifts-authority-away-from-towns/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When H.B.8002 was passed during November’s special session, Democratic leaders and the bill’s supporters promoted it under the slogan “Towns Take the Lead.”   Signed into law by Gov. Ned [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/12/19/housing-advocates-acknowledge-new-law-shifts-authority-away-from-towns/"&gt;Housing Advocates Acknowledge New Law Shifts Authority Away from Towns&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 18:47:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Parental Freedom Update</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/parental-freedom-update/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=parental-freedom-update</link><description>&lt;p&gt;According to EdChoice, about 1.5 million students are now enrolled in voucher, educational savings account (ESA), and tax-credit programs, nearly doubling the number from just three years ago. Education Week reports that 30 states and the District of Columbia now have at least one private school choice program. Of those, 19 states have at least...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/parental-freedom-update/"&gt;Parental Freedom Update&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 19:05:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Week in Review: The Greatest Gift</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-the-greatest-gift/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For millions of Americans, the holiday season is a time for family as well as giving and receiving gifts. But..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-the-greatest-gift/"&gt;Week in Review: The Greatest Gift &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 19:15:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] TPPF’s 2025 Year in Litigation</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/tppfs-2025-year-in-litigation/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Texas Public Policy Foundation’s Center for the American Future had a busy and successful year defending the Constitution. Below is a list of key victories, along with some new cases that launched in the last 12 months. VICTORIES  1. ATF Reverses “Zero Tolerance” Policy for Revoking Gun Store Licenses The Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/tppfs-2025-year-in-litigation/"&gt;TPPF’s 2025 Year in Litigation&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 21:50:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Louisiana’s Toxic Relationship with Lawsuit Abuse</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/legal-regulatory/lawsuit-abuse/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For years, lawsuit abuse has dragged down Louisiana’s competitiveness, acting as a hidden tax on families, consumers, and businesses across the state. Frivolous claims, inflated damage awards, and politically motivated lawsuits undermine justice and contribute to Louisiana’s long struggle with excessive and opportunistic litigation, especially against important job-creating industries like energy, manufacturing, and insurance. This...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/legal-regulatory/lawsuit-abuse/"&gt;Louisiana’s Toxic Relationship with Lawsuit Abuse&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 22:40:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Plan to close J.H. Campbell power plant is misguided</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/plan-to-close-jh-campbell-power-plant-is-misguided</link><description>House Democrats’ warnings don’t hold up</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Modernizing Financial Oversight: Senator Tim Scott’s STREAMLINE Act and the Case for Reducing Regulatory Burden</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/modernizing-financial-oversight-senator-tim-scotts-streamline-act-and-the-case-for-reducing-regulatory-burden/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Streamlining Transaction Reporting and Ensuring Anti-Money Laundering Improvements for a New Era Act (STREAMLINE Act), introduced by...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/modernizing-financial-oversight-senator-tim-scotts-streamline-act-and-the-case-for-reducing-regulatory-burden/"&gt;Modernizing Financial Oversight: Senator Tim Scott’s STREAMLINE Act and the Case for Reducing Regulatory Burden&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] California Home Care Workers Take on Union Abuse in Court</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/litigation/california-home-care-workers-take-on-union-abuse-in-court/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, the Freedom Foundation filed a class-action lawsuit against United Domestic Workers of America, AFSCME Local 3930 (UDW) on behalf of in-home supportive services (IHSS) workers across California. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/litigation/california-home-care-workers-take-on-union-abuse-in-court/" rel="nofollow"&gt;California Home Care Workers Take on Union Abuse in Court&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 15:50:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] In Case You Missed It: WILL Raised Key Voter Roll Concerns Ahead of DOJ Lawsuit</title><link>https://will-law.org/in-case-you-missed-it-will-raised-key-voter-roll-concerns-ahead-of-doj-lawsuit/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Department of Justice has filed a lawsuit against the Wisconsin Election Commission’s (WEC) for refusing to comply with their investigation into the state’s voter rolls. The request from USDOJ was for a copy of Wisconsin’s computerized registration list including information necessary to audit the list for ineligible voters, including driver’s license number and/or the last 4 digits of the social security number. The lawsuit also comes after an investigation from our organization released earlier this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/in-case-you-missed-it-will-raised-key-voter-roll-concerns-ahead-of-doj-lawsuit/"&gt;In Case You Missed It: WILL Raised Key Voter Roll Concerns Ahead of DOJ Lawsuit&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 15:57:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Congress had a viable health care reform plan once – It should be considered again</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/congress-had-a-viable-health-care-reform-plan-once-it-should-be-considered-again</link><description>Health care has become a major policy issue in Congress. The recent government shutdown was caused by the minority party insisting on extending the deadline for the COVID-era, generous taxpayer subsidies in the Obamacare exchanges. This was in spite of the fact that when in the majority, they were the ones who set the deadline for December 31, 2025. Obamacare has been an abject failure. It has not provided universal health insurance coverage as was promised, nor has it controlled the...</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 16:01:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Bellows Trying to Block Routine Federal Oversight of Voter Lists</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/bellows-trying-to-block-routine-federal-oversight-of-voter-lists/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On December 12th, Secretary of State Shenna Bellows asked a federal court to throw out the U.S. Department of Justice lawsuit challenging Maine’s refusal to provide electronic copies of its voter registration list and basic information about how that list is maintained. This dispute isn’t about ballot secrecy or voter intimidation; it’s about whether states [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/bellows-trying-to-block-routine-federal-oversight-of-voter-lists/"&gt;Bellows Trying to Block Routine Federal Oversight of Voter Lists&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 16:16:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Right to Property: The Global Lack of Home Affordability</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/right-to-property-the-global-lack-of-home-affordability/</link><description>Let’s be clear up front about the issue of home affordability: there is no silver bullet, no quick fixes, and it has been decades in the making. If you care to examine home costs in countries as close as Canada and as far afield as New Zealand, you will find out that home affordability is [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 17:53:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] Civic Foundations: Are we Properly Preparing the Next Generation of Citizens?</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/12/civic-foundations-are-we-properly-preparing-the-next-generation-of-citizens/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;by Aiden DeMarsey – Evesham Twp. Board of Ed. Member &amp;#38; NJPI Junior Education Policy Fellow The state of New [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/12/civic-foundations-are-we-properly-preparing-the-next-generation-of-citizens/"&gt;Civic Foundations: Are we Properly Preparing the Next Generation of Citizens?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 18:30:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] The Economic and Legal Risks of New Jersey’s Proposed Climate Superfund Act</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/12/the-economic-and-legal-risks-of-new-jerseys-proposed-climate-superfund-act/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Sean Barry, NJPI Junior Energy Policy Fellow For the past several months, New Jersey lawmakers have been considering Assembly [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/12/the-economic-and-legal-risks-of-new-jerseys-proposed-climate-superfund-act/"&gt;The Economic and Legal Risks of New Jersey’s Proposed Climate Superfund Act&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 18:35:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF discusses MLG National Guard deployment as they depart</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-discusses-mlg-national-guard-deployment-as-they-depart/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In a unique example of the Rio Grande Foundation being more positive about the Gov.&amp;#8217;s policy than the Gov. herself, the Rio Grande Foundation was asked to comment on whether MLG&amp;#8217;s deployment of the National Guard to Albuquerque was &amp;#8220;a disappointment.&amp;#8221; On the one hand, while we 100% agree with the Gov. that &amp;#8220;lax engagement [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-discusses-mlg-national-guard-deployment-as-they-depart/"&gt;RGF discusses MLG National Guard deployment as they depart&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 18:49:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] From Magna Carta to Mass Arrests: Britain’s Warning to America</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/from-magna-carta-to-mass-arrests-britains-warning-to-america/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Imagine facing arrest simply for posting sharp or critical comments online. Picture police at your door for expressing opposition to mass immigration. Envision a country where you could be imprisoned for years without a jury ever deciding your guilt. This isn't dystopian fiction - it's the reality unfolding in Britain today, my former home and [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/from-magna-carta-to-mass-arrests-britains-warning-to-america/" rel="nofollow"&gt;From Magna Carta to Mass Arrests: Britain’s Warning to America&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 20:01:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Goldwater Urges Supreme Court to Protect Parental Rights</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/goldwater-urges-supreme-court-to-protect-parental-rights/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Amber Lavigne had no idea a school social worker was secretly advising her 13-year-old about “gender transitioning.” Even worse, the..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/goldwater-urges-supreme-court-to-protect-parental-rights/"&gt;Goldwater Urges Supreme Court to Protect Parental Rights&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 22:58:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Height limits another barrier to rebuilding Lahaina as it was</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/12/height-limits-another-barrier-to-rebuilding-lahaina-as-it-was/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following commentary was first published on Dec. 18, 2025, in Maui Now under the headline “Height-limit rule limits scope of Lahaina rebuilding .”_____________ Almost two and a half years after wildfires destroyed much of Lahaina, homeowners and business owners in the town core are still struggling to return — and strict county regulations are [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/12/height-limits-another-barrier-to-rebuilding-lahaina-as-it-was/"&gt;Height limits another barrier to rebuilding Lahaina as it was&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 23:37:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] ‘CON laws hurt our community more than they might help’</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/12/con-laws-hurt-our-community-more-than-they-might-help/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following commentary was first published simultaneously on Dec. 20, 2025, in the Hawaii Tribune-Herald and West Hawaii Today and under the headline “Hawaii healthcare hindered by ‘certificates of need.’”_____________ Hawaii’s health care shortages weren’t created overnight, and there is no quick fix to the problem. But removing the state’s burdensome “certificate of need” requirements [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/12/con-laws-hurt-our-community-more-than-they-might-help/"&gt;&amp;#8216;CON laws hurt our community more than they might help&amp;#8217;&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 00:00:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Unions don’t deliver for workers</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/unions-dont-deliver-for-workers</link><description>It's time to rethink the rules</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Our ‘little tree’ needs a little love: Why agriculture deserves better policy</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/our-little-tree-needs-a-little-love-why-agriculture-deserves-better-policy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Farmers and ranchers are remarkable people. Collectively, farms in the United States earned $159 billion in take-home pay in 2025. That earned income seems astronomical until the gross income is considered – $624 billion in 2025, meaning about $465 billion was spent on overall operating costs. It is not easy to be a farmer or [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/our-little-tree-needs-a-little-love-why-agriculture-deserves-better-policy/"&gt;Our ‘little tree’ needs a little love: Why agriculture deserves better policy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 11:00:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Principles Applied: Controlling Spending and Empowering Taxpayers</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/principles-applied-controlling-spending-and-empowering-taxpayers/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Principles Applied: Controlling Spending and Empowering Taxpayers" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/homeowners.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iowa can deliver meaningful, lasting property tax relief by focusing reform on two areas: capping local government spending growth at 2 percent and replacing Iowa’s ineffective notification system with a Minnesota-style Truth-in-Taxation model. A spending cap would confront local government spending, the primary driver of Iowa’s rapidly rising property taxes, and treat all taxpayers fairly while improving competitiveness and protecting property rights. A clearer, standardized transparency notice would empower taxpayers to understand proposed tax impacts, increase participation in local budget hearings, and hold governments accountable, aligning directly with all five principles of sound tax policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/principles-applied-controlling-spending-and-empowering-taxpayers/"&gt;Principles Applied: Controlling Spending and Empowering Taxpayers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 13:51:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] A Chapter 353 Tax Abatement Plan is the Last Thing Charleston Needs</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/state-and-local-government/a-chapter-353-tax-abatement-plan-is-the-last-thing-charleston-needs/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Supporters of a plan to “revitalize” Charleston, a city in southeast Missouri just a bit north of the Bootheel, are [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/state-and-local-government/a-chapter-353-tax-abatement-plan-is-the-last-thing-charleston-needs/"&gt;A Chapter 353 Tax Abatement Plan is the Last Thing Charleston Needs&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 14:21:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Idaho takes another step towards its nuclear future</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/idaho-takes-another-step-towards-its-nuclear-future</link><description>Idaho has been making major moves to attract and develop nuclear energy in the Gem State. Earlier this year, Governor Little created the  Idaho Advanced Nuclear Energy Task Force.   Little announced, “As we usher in President Donald Trump’s Nuclear Renaissance, my executive order refreshes our efforts and empowers a new group of leaders dedicated to ensuring Idaho continues to lead the way in nuclear innovation, energy security, and economic growth.”   Governor Little’s most recent effort is...</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 15:57:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Guest Editorial: The role of Credit Unions in Nebraska</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/guest-editorial-the-role-of-credit-unions-in-nebraska/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Credit unions have always stood apart from other financial services providers because of how and why they were first built starting in 1864. Credit Unions are formed by people — workers such as manufacturing employees, farmers, teachers,firefighters, church groups and more to pool their resources and provide low-cost credit to one another. That origin story...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/guest-editorial-the-role-of-credit-unions-in-nebraska/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Guest Editorial: The role of Credit Unions in Nebraska&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 16:46:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] What Is the School Choice Situation in Kansas?</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/what-is-the-school-choice-situation-in-kansas/</link><description>The debate over school choice in Kansas often gets bogged down in politics and process. But the latest data make the stakes clear. The 2026 ABCs of School Choice from EdChoice is the most comprehensive inventory of private school choice programs in the country. After 25 years of tracking these policies, EdChoice doesn’t just catalog [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:00:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Chicago gets $16.6B budget after mayor refuses to veto</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/chicago-gets-16-6b-budget-after-mayor-signs-it/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Chicago avoided a city shutdown when Mayor Brandon Johnson accepted the alternative budget aldermen passed despite his wishes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/chicago-gets-16-6b-budget-after-mayor-signs-it/"&gt;Chicago gets $16.6B budget after mayor refuses to veto&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:20:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Last Christmas, I Gave You My … Tax Dollars?</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/last-christmas-i-gave-you-my-tax-dollars/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Christmas is a time for giving. Unfortunately, some government officials believe that means they can hand out public tax dollars to special interests at year’s..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/last-christmas-i-gave-you-my-tax-dollars/"&gt;Last Christmas, I Gave You My … Tax Dollars?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:30:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Family, Community, and Connection</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/family-community-and-connection/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Set at a New England boarding school around Christmas 1970, Alexander Payne’s 2023 film, The Holdovers centers on the school’s three holiday “holdovers”, that is, those who are unable to leave campus for the winter break. Occupying the empty campus during the frigid northeastern winter is Paul Hunham (Paul Giamatti), a cranky, unmarried classics teacher...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/family-community-and-connection/"&gt;Family, Community, and Connection&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:59:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Affordability Isn’t a Mystery—It’s a Spending Problem</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/affordability-isnt-a-mystery-its-a-spending-problem/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Affordability Isn’t a Mystery—It’s a Spending Problem" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/AdobeStock_229508405.jpeg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Affordability challenges stem from rising local government spending, not an elusive formula of tax incentives and abatements, and property taxes remain high because spending continues to outpace taxpayers’ ability to pay. Targeted tax abatements and business incentives have failed to deliver broad affordability, instead shifting tax burdens onto other residents while benefiting a narrow group of property owners or employers, often for a limited amount of time. True affordability requires fiscal restraint and broad-based tax relief, not expanded incentive programs or policy tweaks that avoid confronting the underlying spending problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/affordability-isnt-a-mystery-its-a-spending-problem/"&gt;Affordability Isn’t a Mystery—It’s a Spending Problem&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 18:42:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] A $500 Million Temporary Emergency Fund Is Starting to Look Like an Open-Ended Obligation</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/12/23/a-500-million-temporary-emergency-fund-is-starting-to-look-like-an-open-ended-obligation/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connecticut’s new half-billion-dollar emergency relief fund, passed during the legislature’s November special session, was presented to the public as a short-term solution — a two-month bridge to prevent families from [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/12/23/a-500-million-temporary-emergency-fund-is-starting-to-look-like-an-open-ended-obligation/"&gt;A $500 Million Temporary Emergency Fund Is Starting to Look Like an Open-Ended Obligation&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 18:46:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Federal Judge Issues Permanent Injunction Against Parental Exclusion Policies  in California Schools</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/mirabelli-olson-federal-judge-issues-permanent-injunction/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=mirabelli-olson-federal-judge-issues-permanent-injunction</link><description>&lt;p&gt;SAN DIEGO &amp;#8211; In a landmark victory for parental rights, a federal judge in Southern California ruled Monday that parents have a constitutional right to be informed if their minor child socially transitions their gender at school and that teachers have a constitutional right to inform parents of the transition. U.S. District Judge Roger Benitez...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/mirabelli-olson-federal-judge-issues-permanent-injunction/"&gt;Federal Judge Issues Permanent Injunction Against Parental Exclusion Policies  in California Schools&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 18:55:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] The Hierarchy of Rights: Life Begets Liberty</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/the-hierarchy-of-rights-life-begets-liberty/</link><description>One of the greatest sentences penned in U.S. history comes from the Declaration of Independence:&amp;#160; “We hold these truths to be self-evident, that all men are created equal, that they are endowed by their Creator with certain unalienable Rights, that among these are Life, Liberty and the pursuit of Happiness.” Notice among the unalienable rights, [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 19:26:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Turning up the gaslight(ing) this holiday season</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/turning-up-the-gaslighting-this-holiday-season/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Photo source: KSTP video Governor Tim Walz, and other Democrat elected leaders held a joint press conference today at Shiloh Temple in North Minneapolis.&amp;#160; The purpose was to continue “whistling” their opposition to the surge in Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) activity that has occurred in the Twin Cities in December.&amp;#160; That surge has resulted...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/turning-up-the-gaslighting-this-holiday-season/"&gt;Turning up the gaslight(ing) this holiday season&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 21:19:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Idaho Freedom Foundation to Hold Press Conference for Freedom &amp; Family Legislative Agenda</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/idaho-freedom-foundation-to-hold-press-conference-for-freedom-family-legislative-agenda/</link><description>BOISE, ID – (December 23, 2025) – As Idaho families gather to celebrate the Christmas holiday and prepare for the new year, the Idaho Freedom Foundation (IFF) today announced it will host a press conference to outline our 2026 Freedom &amp;#38; Family Agenda. Following the successful launch of our agenda in September, this press conference [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 22:21:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] $207 Million in Medicaid for dead people</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/207-million-in-medicaid-for-dead-people/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As much controversy as there is in Minnesota right now regarding waste, fraud and abuse, there should be agreement to stop paying the health insurance costs for the deceased. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/207-million-in-medicaid-for-dead-people/"&gt;$207 Million in Medicaid for dead people&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:11:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Akina hails highlights of 2025, has high hopes for more victories in 2026</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/12/akina-hails-highlights-of-2025-has-high-hopes-for-more-victories-in-2026/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;There is much to be upbeat about the past year, according to Keli‘i Akina, president of the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii. And the future looks bright for 2026 as well, he said, speaking this past Sunday with host Johnny Miro on the H. Hawaii Media radio network. “I&amp;#8217;m hopeful for 2026 and the years to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/12/akina-hails-highlights-of-2025-has-high-hopes-for-more-victories-in-2026/"&gt;Akina hails highlights of 2025, has high hopes for more victories in 2026&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 02:40:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Happy Holidays from the Show-Me Institute</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/uncategorized/happy-holidays-from-the-show-me-institute/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/uncategorized/happy-holidays-from-the-show-me-institute/"&gt;Happy Holidays from the Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 08:00:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Heritage scholars move to Pence’s group</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/heritage-scholars-move-to-pences-group/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Zach Kessel writes for the Washington Free Beacon about a significant development in the American conservative movement. Leaders of Advancing American Freedom (AAF), the nonprofit led by former vice president Mike Pence, said that their move to hire more than a dozen former Heritage Foundation employees represents a significant shift within the American right. AAF...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/heritage-scholars-move-to-pences-group/"&gt;Heritage scholars move to Pence&amp;#8217;s group&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 10:36:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Naming Greg Biffle an American hero</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/naming-greg-biffle-an-american-hero/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Christopher Jacobs writes for the Federalist about a recently departed NACAR star. When it comes to sports, we often become obsessed with feats of heroism in the arena — the feats of strength, endurance, and determination that inspire fans worldwide. But sometimes, sports can also remind us that true heroism occurs away from the playing...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/naming-greg-biffle-an-american-hero/"&gt;Naming Greg Biffle an American hero&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 10:39:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Describing lawyers as ‘official adjunct’ of Democratic Party</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/describing-lawyers-as-official-adjunct-of-democratic-party/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;John Hinderaker of the Powerline blog documents an interesting development in the American legal community. Not too many years ago, the bar was one of the pillars of the Republican Party. Abraham Lincoln was the patron saint of lawyers; my father had a lovely portrait of Lincoln, painted on wood, in his law office for...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/describing-lawyers-as-official-adjunct-of-democratic-party/"&gt;Describing lawyers as &amp;#8216;official adjunct&amp;#8217; of Democratic Party&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 10:42:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Christmas movies with the Mackinac Center</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/christmas-movies-with-the-mackinac-center</link><description>Rudolph, Kevin McCallister, and what they suggest about public policy</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Do price controls affect which drugs patients have access to and how soon?</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/do-price-controls-affect-which-drugs-patients-have-access-to-and-how-soon/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Do price controls affect which drugs patients have access to and how soon? They absolutely do. Just look at the situation in Europe. For years, drug companies have been choosing to withhold certain medicines from European markets rather than accept the price constraints imposed by governments there. As a result, many of the latest drugs [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/do-price-controls-affect-which-drugs-patients-have-access-to-and-how-soon/"&gt;Do price controls affect which drugs patients have access to and how soon?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 11:00:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Kids home alone could land Illinois parents on naughty list</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/kids-home-alone-could-land-illinois-parents-on-naughty-list/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Illinois parents can now leave their kids home alone at any age, but a state worker or judge could still label their decision as neglect or abuse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/kids-home-alone-could-land-illinois-parents-on-naughty-list/"&gt;Kids home alone could land Illinois parents on naughty list&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 11:00:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Naughty list includes state lawmakers, county leaders, mayors</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/naughty-list-includes-state-lawmakers-county-leaders-mayors/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The nation’s longest-serving legislative speaker, a state senator and a former Cook County commissioner were on Illinois’ too-long list of corrupt politicians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/naughty-list-includes-state-lawmakers-county-leaders-mayors/"&gt;Naughty list includes state lawmakers, county leaders, mayors&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 11:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] New York’s Education Shows Improvement, but Questions Remain</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/new-yorks-education-shows-improvement-but-questions-remain/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In the effort to improve transparency and accountability of New York’s education system, the Empire Center has systematized and published....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/new-yorks-education-shows-improvement-but-questions-remain/"&gt;New York&amp;#8217;s Education Shows Improvement, but Questions Remain&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 14:15:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] 98 Minnesota mayors blast state government for hiking property taxes</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/98-minnesota-mayors-blast-state-government-for-hiking-property-taxes/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Property taxes are increasing across Minnesota. Not surprisingly, a poll for Alpha News: &amp;#8230;found that 60% of those surveyed are very concerned about rising property taxes; another 27% of respondents said they are somewhat concerned. &amp;#8230; Taken together, a combined 87% of respondents are either somewhat concerned or very concerned by increasing property taxes. The...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/98-minnesota-mayors-blast-state-government-for-hiking-property-taxes/"&gt;98 Minnesota mayors blast state government for hiking property taxes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 15:28:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Dreaming of a White Christmas? Vermont Taxpayers Are Facing a Different Forecast</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/dreaming-of-a-white-christmas-vermont-taxpayers-are-facing-a-different-forecast/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Dreaming of a White Christmas? Vermont Taxpayers Are Facing a Different Forecast" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/cardinal-winter.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vermont is facing a projected 12% property tax increase, driven by declining student enrollment and rapidly escalating public education spending—now over $29,000 per pupil.&lt;br /&gt;
 Lawmakers passed Act 73 to restructure the education system and reduce long-term costs, but disagreements remain over school consolidation and implementation, while other states like Wisconsin, New Hampshire, and South Dakota are considering similar reforms.&lt;br /&gt;
The Vermont experience shows that buying down taxes with surplus funds does not solve underlying funding problems, and provides a warning to states like Iowa that durable property tax relief depends on structural reform and spending restraint—not temporary patches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/dreaming-of-a-white-christmas-vermont-taxpayers-are-facing-a-different-forecast/"&gt;Dreaming of a White Christmas? Vermont Taxpayers Are Facing a Different Forecast&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 15:39:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] What America Needs from a GOP Healthcare Package</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/what-america-needs-from-a-gop-healthcare-package/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The U.S. House just passed legislation that will help make health insurance more affordable — without extending the enhanced premium subsidies for exchange coverage that Democrats enacted during the COVID-19 pandemic. The House action comes on the heels of votes on two measures in the Senate: one from Democrats that would have extended those subsidies [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/what-america-needs-from-a-gop-healthcare-package/"&gt;What America Needs from a GOP Healthcare Package&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 16:50:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>