<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>State-Policy Think-Tank Digest</title><link>https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml</link><description>Latest posts from free-market policy institutes across the U.S.</description><atom:link href="https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 01:31:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>[Mspolicy] School Choice is Coming to Mississippi!</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/school-choice-is-coming-to-mississippi/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;What would it take for Mississippi to embrace School Choice?&amp;#160;How can we join our neighboring states in empowering families to control their child's share of the education budget? For School Choice to happen, we would need to see several steps.&amp;#160; &amp;#160;&amp;#160;Number one, we would need a committed Governor, ready to invest his political capital in [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/school-choice-is-coming-to-mississippi/" rel="nofollow"&gt;School Choice is Coming to Mississippi!&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 17:23:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Rifreedom] Center Cosigns Letter Supporting Seafreeze Petition to Suspend VINEYARD WIND Construction</title><link>https://rifreedom.org/2025/08/center-cosigns-letter-supporting-seafreeze-petition-to-suspend-vineyard-wind-construction/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Today, CEO for the Rhode Island Center for Freedom &amp;#038; Prosperity, Mike Stenhouse, co-signed a letter, along with national energy expert, G. Allen Brooks, requesting Doug Brugum, Secretary of the US Department Of the Interior (DOI), and other federal officials to accept the formal petition previously filed Seafreeze Inc (and others) that calls upon the government to immediately suspend "further construction and energy generation activity" of the near-completed Vineyard Wind off-shore wind project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org/2025/08/center-cosigns-letter-supporting-seafreeze-petition-to-suspend-vineyard-wind-construction/"&gt;Center Cosigns Letter Supporting Seafreeze Petition to Suspend VINEYARD WIND Construction&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org"&gt;RI Center for Freedom and Prosperity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 17:38:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Florida’s Election Reform Sets the Standard Nationwide</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/floridas-election-reform-sets-the-standard-nationwide/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE August 19, 2025 CONTACT Logan Elizabeth Padgett 850-386-3131 Florida’s Election Reform Sets the Standard Nationwide...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/floridas-election-reform-sets-the-standard-nationwide/"&gt;Florida’s Election Reform Sets the Standard Nationwide &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 04:01:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Florida: The Gold Standard in Elections Administration From Bush v. Gore to Present 2000-2025</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/florida-the-gold-standard-in-elections-administration-from-bush-v-gore-to-present-2000-2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Ben Gibson — Senior Fellow, The James Madison Institute Doug Wheeler — Director, George Gibbs Center for Economic...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/florida-the-gold-standard-in-elections-administration-from-bush-v-gore-to-present-2000-2025/"&gt;Florida: The Gold Standard in Elections Administration From Bush v. Gore to Present 2000-2025&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 04:01:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] What’s at stake in Albuquerque’s City Elections?</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/whats-at-stake-in-albuquerques-city-elections/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Paul recently sat down with Diane Kinderwater for an episode of &amp;#8220;Issues and Answers&amp;#8221; on KCHF TV. The show airs statewide and can be streamed live right here. In a recent conversation Paul had a chance to discuss what&amp;#8217;s at stake in the City of Albuquerque elections this fall. We discuss crime, homelessness, the economy, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/whats-at-stake-in-albuquerques-city-elections/"&gt;What&amp;#8217;s at stake in Albuquerque&amp;#8217;s City Elections?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 19:34:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cardinalinstitute] West Virginia’s Certificate of Need Laws Are Failing You</title><link>https://cardinalinstitute.com/west-virginias-certificate-of-need-laws-are-failing-you/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;West Virginia’s Certificate of Need Laws Are Failing You The West Virginia Hospital Association’s recent op-ed defending West Virginia’s Certificate of Need (CON) laws is a masterclass in elite protectionism, dressed in concern, framed as a noble stand for community health. Make no mistake—the heart of the piece is about hospital bottom lines rather than how [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com/west-virginias-certificate-of-need-laws-are-failing-you/"&gt;West Virginia’s Certificate of Need Laws Are Failing You&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com"&gt;Cardinal Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 16:22:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Colorado’s AI Catastrophe: A Cautionary Tale</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/colorados-ai-catastrophe-a-cautionary-tale/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On May 27, 2024, Colorado became the unfortunate pioneer in a troubling new frontier of government overreach. The...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/colorados-ai-catastrophe-a-cautionary-tale/"&gt;Colorado&amp;#8217;s AI Catastrophe: A Cautionary Tale&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 15:20:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] In child care, as in housing, maybe the government’s doing a bit too much?</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/08/in-child-care-as-in-housing-maybe-the-governments-doing-a-bit-too-much/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Surging child care prices have grabbed the media’s attention here in New Hampshire, and rightly so. The price of full-time care in a licensed center “jumped 48 percent between 2013 and 2023,” landing at nearly $32,000 a year, according to an analysis last year by the Carsey School of Public Policy at UNH.   Child [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/08/in-child-care-as-in-housing-maybe-the-governments-doing-a-bit-too-much/"&gt;In child care, as in housing, maybe the government’s doing a bit too much?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 17:00:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF in National Review: The Return of Car Choice, Hopefully</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-in-national-review-the-return-of-car-choice-hopefully/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following appeared in National Review&amp;#8217;s Capital Matters on August 20, 2025. Whatever happens to the future of EVs, they should compete on an even playing field with other vehicles. While the courts have yet to have their say, one of the Trump administration’s most important accomplishments, perhaps second only to his successful crackdown on illegal [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-in-national-review-the-return-of-car-choice-hopefully/"&gt;RGF in National Review: The Return of Car Choice, Hopefully&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 17:56:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] SEPTA’s Manufactured Crisis Has Delayed State Budget Long Enough</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/08/22/septas-manufactured-crisis-has-delayed-state-budget-long-enough/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Harrisburg, Pa., August 22, 2025 — This Sunday, after eight consecutive weeks of public fearmongering, the Southeastern Pennsylvania Transportation Authority (SEPTA) will enact self-imposed service cuts. Though completely avoidable, these cuts aim to extract yet another taxpayer-funded bailout. This is not a true emergency; it is a manufactured crisis, fueled and exploited by Gov. Josh [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/08/22/septas-manufactured-crisis-has-delayed-state-budget-long-enough/"&gt;SEPTA’s Manufactured Crisis Has Delayed State Budget Long Enough&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 16:12:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Rifreedom] After Federal Action, Rhode Island Desperately Needs a Realistic Energy Strategy</title><link>https://rifreedom.org/2025/08/after-federal-action-rhode-island-desperately-needs-a-realistic-energy-strategy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Cranston, RI – The Rhode Island Center for Freedom &amp;#38; Prosperity advises state policymakers to immediately begin work to construct a new and realistic energy strategy that will put the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org/2025/08/after-federal-action-rhode-island-desperately-needs-a-realistic-energy-strategy/"&gt;After Federal Action, Rhode Island Desperately Needs a Realistic Energy Strategy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org"&gt;RI Center for Freedom and Prosperity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 15:41:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Humanity and Abortion</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/humanity-and-abortion/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/humanity-and-abortion/" rel="nofollow" title="Humanity and Abortion"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1350" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/Cream-Neutral-Minimalist-New-Business-Pitch-Deck-Presentation-6.jpg" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="2400" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Idaho has one of the most comprehensive abortion laws in the United States, effectively banning the procedure at all stages of pregnancy with narrow exceptions. The state's framework consists of multiple overlapping statutes, primarily enacted or triggered after the U.S. Supreme Court's 2022 decision in Dobbs v. Jackson Women's Health Organization, which overturned Roe v. [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2025 19:43:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Public Recommendations to Idaho's DOGE Task Force to Increase Government Efficiency</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/public-recommendations-to-idahos-doge-task-force-to-increase-government-efficiency/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/public-recommendations-to-idahos-doge-task-force-to-increase-government-efficiency/" rel="nofollow" title="Public Recommendations to Idaho&amp;#039;s DOGE Task Force to Increase Government Efficiency"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Article-Headers-2025-09-01T114655.975.png" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Dear Members of the Idaho DOGE Task Force,&amp;#160; At the request of members of this Task Force, we have attached our analysis and recommendations for the committee's consideration. Each proposed reduction, consolidation, or elimination falls within the committee's stated purpose and offers realistic options for waste reduction.&amp;#160; The Idaho DOGE Task Force is positioned to [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 18:06:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] Beyond the Beach: Honoring the Dignity of Work</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/09/01/labor-day-honoring-the-dignity-of-work/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A free and prosperous society is built on a foundation of responsible, creative, and purposeful work. When government is limited and economic freedom is upheld, individuals are empowered to pursue their callings, provide for their families, and contribute to the common good. Labor Day, therefore, becomes a day to honor not just the physical act of labor, but the sacred dignity of work—the opportunity we have to use our gifts to create, serve, and build, all while reflecting the image of our Creator. It is a day to be grateful for the freedom to work and to be a part of a society where that freedom is protected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/09/01/labor-day-honoring-the-dignity-of-work/"&gt;Beyond the Beach: Honoring the Dignity of Work&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 19:46:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Revenue-neutral law is helping; additional property tax reform is needed</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/revenue-neutral-helps-more-tax-reform-needed/</link><description>The Revenue-Neutral law that went into effect in 2021 is helping many Kansans, with nearly two-thirds of taxing entities deciding NOT to raise property taxes this year. It requires cities, counties, school districts, and other local taxing authorities to notify taxpayers if they want to collect more property tax revenue the following year, hold a [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 12:49:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Mississippi's Progress and the Push for School Choice</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/mississippis-progress-and-the-push-for-school-choice/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This week, I’ll be traveling to Washington, D.C. talking about Mississippi’s remarkable progress, including our elimination of the income tax and how we might best advance school choice in our state. Mississippi is gaining national attention for our transformative public policies. Once seen as a perennial underdog, our state is now recognized as a leader in free-market [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/mississippis-progress-and-the-push-for-school-choice/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi&amp;#039;s Progress and the Push for School Choice&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 17:09:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Non-working adults concentrated in Georgia’s distressed communities</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/adults-not-working-in-georgia/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Many Georgia counties face high rates of non-working adults, fueling distress and limiting opportunities in struggling communities. See the percentages for your county. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/adults-not-working-in-georgia/"&gt;Non-working adults concentrated in Georgia’s distressed communities&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 18:51:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Attorney General Lynn Fitch: Breaking Barriers &amp; Defending Life</title><link>https://empowerms.org/attorney-general-lynn-fitch-breaking-barriers-defending-life/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Attorney General Lynn Fitch: Breaking Barriers &amp;#38; Defending Life  On this episode, host Grant Callen sits down with Mississippi’s 40th Attorney General Lynn Fitch. A Holly Springs native, General Fitch has 35 years in public and private legal service, made history as the state’s first female Attorney General, and earned national recognition for her leadership.&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/attorney-general-lynn-fitch-breaking-barriers-defending-life/"&gt;Attorney General Lynn Fitch: Breaking Barriers &amp; Defending Life &lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 20:00:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Florida’s John Kirtley on School Choice</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/floridas-john-kirtley-on-school-choice/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In this week’s episode of The Learning Curve, co-hosts U-Arkansas Prof. Albert Cheng and American Federation for Children Senior Fellow Shaka Mitchell interview John Kirtley, Managing Partner and co-founder of Keswick Partners, and founder and Chairman of Step Up for Students, a nonprofit that manages Florida’s state-funded K-12 scholarship programs serving over half a million students. Kirtley shares his journey from the private sector into education reform in the late 1990s, and why business leaders must actively engage in shaping K-12 policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/floridas-john-kirtley-on-school-choice/"&gt;Florida&amp;#8217;s John Kirtley on School Choice&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 13:51:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Separate but Equitable at Portland Public Schools</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/education/separate-but-equitable-at-portland-public-schools/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By John A. Charles, Jr. In 1954 the U.S. Supreme Court ruled that...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/education/separate-but-equitable-at-portland-public-schools/"&gt;Separate but Equitable at Portland Public Schools&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 14:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] New Poll: Inflation, Economy, Taxes, and Crime Top Voter Concerns, Pennsylvanians Hold Shapiro Responsible for Budget Impasse</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/09/03/new-poll-inflation-economy-taxes-and-crime-top-voter-concerns-pennsylvanians-hold-shapiro-responsible-for-budget-impasse/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Harrisburg, Pa., September 3, 2025 — Fewer than 4-in-10 Pennsylvania voters believe the state is on the right track, according to new polling released today by the Commonwealth Foundation. Inflation, the economy, taxes, and crime top their list of concerns facing the state, with nearly two-thirds of Pennsylvanians saying economic conditions are worsening for them [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/09/03/new-poll-inflation-economy-taxes-and-crime-top-voter-concerns-pennsylvanians-hold-shapiro-responsible-for-budget-impasse/"&gt;New Poll: Inflation, Economy, Taxes, and Crime Top Voter Concerns, Pennsylvanians Hold Shapiro Responsible for Budget Impasse &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 15:24:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] A conversation on New Mexico’s health care provider shortage w/ RGF’s Paul Gessing &amp; Think New Mexico’s Fred Nathan</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/a-conversation-on-new-mexicos-health-care-provider-shortage-w-rgfs-paul-gessing-think-new-mexicos-fred-nathan/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Most New Mexicans are abundantly aware of the dire medical provider shortage facing our state. The Rio Grande Foundation has been researching and discussing solutions to this problem for several years. The same is true for Think New Mexico which is led by Fred Nathan. While we don&amp;#8217;t always agree with the approach of Think [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/a-conversation-on-new-mexicos-health-care-provider-shortage-w-rgfs-paul-gessing-think-new-mexicos-fred-nathan/"&gt;A conversation on New Mexico&amp;#8217;s health care provider shortage w/ RGF&amp;#8217;s Paul Gessing &amp;#038; Think New Mexico&amp;#8217;s Fred Nathan&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 15:42:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] Distinctions Between Social Justice and Biblical Justice</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/09/04/distinctions-between-social-justice-and-biblical-justice/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The use of governmental imposition to force social justice on its people is a path that leads to more government, less freedom, and deeper division. The true path forward can be found in a return to the principles of biblical justice—impartiality, righteousness, and individual responsibility. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/09/04/distinctions-between-social-justice-and-biblical-justice/"&gt;Distinctions Between Social Justice and Biblical Justice&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 06:49:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Fact Checking Claims on Enrollment Declines</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/fact-checking-claims-on-enrollment-declines/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=fact-checking-claims-on-enrollment-declines</link><description>Despite declining enrollment occurring all across the nation, recent news reports have claimed that the problem is specific to Tennessee because of the state's new Education Freedom Scholarships (EFS) program. Not only do these accusations wrongly place blame, many critics simply get the basics of the EFS program wrong. Let’s set the record straight.</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 16:04:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] SEIU 1000 negotiates pay raise that really isn’t</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/california/seiu-1000-negotiates-pay-raise-that-really-isnt/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;SEIU Local 1000 just cut a backroom deal with California Gov. Gavin Newsom that leaves state workers holding the bag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/california/seiu-1000-negotiates-pay-raise-that-really-isnt/" rel="nofollow"&gt;SEIU 1000 negotiates pay raise that really isn’t&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 16:14:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] The hills are alive with the, well, approval of leftist politicians</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/wisconsin-rights-of-nature-law/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;State Rep. Joy Goeben and state Sen. Steve Nass have introduced a bill that would prohibit local governments from enacting a “rights of nature” ordinance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/wisconsin-rights-of-nature-law/"&gt;The hills are alive with the, well, approval of leftist politicians&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 20:45:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] New Hampshire rated the least corrupt state</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/09/new-hampshire-rated-the-least-corrupt-state/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;America’s freest state has just been rated its least corrupt too. Using U.S. Department of Justice data on corruption convictions in all 94 federal judicial districts from 2003-2024, the Cato Institute calculated the rate of corruption convictions per 10,000 government employees, then recently ranked states by their conviction rates. New Hampshire ranked dead last, with [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/09/new-hampshire-rated-the-least-corrupt-state/"&gt;New Hampshire rated the least corrupt state&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 00:17:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] School Choice Improves Public School Performance</title><link>https://empowerms.org/school-choice-improves-public-school-performance/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#8217;s an argument going around that deserves a response: The Parents’ Campaign has repeatedly claimed that Mississippi is gaining academically while the &amp;#8220;top choice states&amp;#8221; plummeted. This is naive, lacking any academic rigor, and a dishonest interpretation of the data.   First, the phrase &amp;#8220;top choice states&amp;#8221; is misleading. Half the states in their top 10&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/school-choice-improves-public-school-performance/"&gt;School Choice Improves Public School Performance&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 15:41:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] First Principles Series: The Plight of Property Taxes</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/first-principles-series-the-plight-of-property-taxes/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=first-principles-series-the-plight-of-property-taxes</link><description>Tennessee joins Hawaii, Vermont, and New Hampshire as the outliers where property taxes can go up without limit.</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 16:02:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] From Waterloo to Keokuk: Where Property Taxes Hit Hardest in Iowa</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/from-waterloo-to-keokuk-where-property-taxes-hit-hardest-in-iowa/</link><description>&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="630" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/effective-property-tax-rates.jpg" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="From Waterloo to Keokuk: Where Property Taxes Hit Hardest in Iowa" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/effective-property-tax-rates-600x315.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Property taxes in Iowa are unpredictable and burdensome, driven by many layers of government that often leave homeowners frustrated as bills rise faster than their ability to pay.&lt;br /&gt;
Effective property tax rates vary widely across the state, with homeowners in places like Eldridge and Le Mars paying under 1.3%, while residents in Waterloo and Keokuk face rates above 2%.&lt;br /&gt;
 Without meaningful reform to limit local government spending, these disparities and rising bills will continue, making property tax relief one of the most pressing issues for Iowa families and businesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/from-waterloo-to-keokuk-where-property-taxes-hit-hardest-in-iowa/"&gt;From Waterloo to Keokuk: Where Property Taxes Hit Hardest in Iowa&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 16:59:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/09/the-outstater-287/</link><description>&amp;#8216;Chicago Is Indiana&amp;#8217;s Fault&amp;#8217; iT CAN BE HOPED that Mayor Brandon Johnson, who this week blamed Indiana for Chicago crime, will be thrown from office the next election cycle. I have my doubts, though, realizing that his message of envy and resentment is a powerful one with a large constituency. Envy, please know, is a&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/09/the-outstater-287/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 20:55:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Cost of Democrat-Supported Carbon Tax Reaches $500 Million Per Year</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/cost-of-democrat-supported-carbon-tax-reaches-500-million-per-year/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="630" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Democrats-Carbon-Tax-Virginia.jpg" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the&amp;#160;most recent&amp;#160;carbon tax imposed on the member states of the Regional Greenhouse Gas Initiative (RGGI), Virginians will pay about $500 million more per year for electricity if Virginia again becomes one of those member states.&amp;#160;Your vote in November may determine that.&amp;#160; Democratic nominee for governor Abigail Spanberger&amp;#160;has pledged&amp;#160;to rejoin the RGGI compact and [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/cost-of-democrat-supported-carbon-tax-reaches-500-million-per-year/"&gt;Cost of Democrat-Supported Carbon Tax Reaches $500 Million Per Year&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 23:20:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] ‘Workforce housing’ fees make homes more expensive for everyone</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/workforce-housing-fees-make-homes-more-expensive-for-everyone</link><description>The most expensive county in Wyoming to build a house thinks everyone should pay more to build a house. Does that make sense? In Teton...</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 14:26:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] Commonwealth Foundation Urges Legal Protection of State’s Rainy Day Fund</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/09/08/commonwealth-foundation-urges-legal-protection-of-states-rainy-day-fund/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Letter calls on Treasurer Garrity to withhold any transfer from the budget stabilization reserve fund, pending legal adjudication. Harrisburg, Pa., September 8, 2025 — Today, the Commonwealth Foundation sent a letter to leaders of the General Assembly and Pennsylvania State Treasurer Stacy Garrity, urging the legal protection of the commonwealth’s Rainy Day Fund. Gov. Josh [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/09/08/commonwealth-foundation-urges-legal-protection-of-states-rainy-day-fund/"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation Urges Legal Protection of State&amp;#8217;s Rainy Day Fund&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 15:28:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Massachusetts’ Capital Investment Plan Earmarks $415 Million for Housing in FY2026</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/massachusetts-capital-investment-plan-earmarks-415-million-for-housing-in-fy2026/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This edition of The House Call breaks down the housing items in Massachusetts' FY2026-FY2030 Capital Investment Plan. It also explains a new policy ordered by the Department of Public Utilities that would require natural gas customers to pay more for new hookups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/massachusetts-capital-investment-plan-earmarks-415-million-for-housing-in-fy2026/"&gt;Massachusetts&amp;#8217; Capital Investment Plan Earmarks $415 Million for Housing in FY2026&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 20:13:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Set standards on manufactured housing to ramp up homebuilding</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/09/set-standards-on-manufactured-housing-to-ramp-up-homebuilding/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Maui County Council on September 8, 2025._____________ Sept. 8, 2025, 9 a.m.Kalana O Maui Building To: Maui County Council       Alice Lee, Chair       Yuki Lei Sugimura, Vice Chair From: Grassrot Institute of Hawaii            Jonathan Helton, Policy Analyst RE: Bill 122 (2025) [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/09/set-standards-on-manufactured-housing-to-ramp-up-homebuilding/"&gt;Set standards on manufactured housing to ramp up homebuilding&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 20:35:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Bill 123 crucial to economic recovery of bed and breakfasts in Lahaina</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/09/bill-123-crucial-to-economic-recovery-of-bed-and-breakfasts-in-lahaina/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Maui County Council on September 8, 2025._____________ Sept. 8, 2025, 9 a.m.Kalana O Maui Building To: Maui County Council&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Alice Lee, Chair&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Yuki Lei Sugimura, Vice Chair From: Grassrot Institute of Hawaii&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Jonathan Helton, Policy Analyst RE: Bill 123 (2025) [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/09/bill-123-crucial-to-economic-recovery-of-bed-and-breakfasts-in-lahaina/"&gt;Bill 123 crucial to economic recovery of bed and breakfasts in Lahaina&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 20:37:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] How Much Does Private School Really Cost in Mississippi?</title><link>https://empowerms.org/how-much-does-private-school-really-cost-in-mississippi/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For many Mississippi families, private school feels financially out of reach. However new research shows that private education may be more affordable than most people think—and that smart policy could make it accessible to thousands more students.  Research conducted by Empower Mississippi reveals that the average tuition for private schools varies from approximately $6,710 for&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/how-much-does-private-school-really-cost-in-mississippi/"&gt;How Much Does Private School Really Cost in Mississippi?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 21:15:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Research Note: current efforts to address ag zoning issues</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/research-note-current-efforts-to-address-ag-zoning-issues/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;[Note: This is the final in a series of Research Notes by Platte’s intern, focusing on county zoning and agriculture issues. A full paper dealing with these issues will be published later this fall.] Over the past decade, Nebraska’s legislature has repeatedly sought to address issues related to the Conditional Use Permits (CUPs) and Special...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/research-note-current-efforts-to-address-ag-zoning-issues/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Research Note: current efforts to address ag zoning issues&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 12:59:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] WILL Applauds Wisconsin State Assembly for Tackling Education Priorities</title><link>https://will-law.org/will-applauds-wisconsin-state-assembly-for-tackling-education-priorities/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL supports new efforts by WI legislators to tackle these pressing issues in education. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/will-applauds-wisconsin-state-assembly-for-tackling-education-priorities/"&gt;WILL Applauds Wisconsin State Assembly for Tackling Education Priorities&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 17:11:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] The ITD Money Pit of Idaho: Stop Digging!</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/the-itd-money-pit-of-idaho-stop-digging/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/the-itd-money-pit-of-idaho-stop-digging/" rel="nofollow" title="The ITD Money Pit of Idaho: Stop Digging!"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Article-Headers-2025-09-09T110039.106.png" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Want to save the state nearly $100 million and help fix the budget hole created by years of overspending? Stop digging the money pit of the Idaho Transportation Department (ITD) headquarters on State Street.&amp;#160;&amp;#160; A couple of weeks ago, the governor’s office of the Division of Financial Management revised its tax collections forecast and reported [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 18:15:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Avon Rep. Eleni Kavros Degraw Calls Non-Degree Workers a ‘Burden’ at Debt Relief Meeting</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/09/09/avon-rep-eleni-kavros-degraw-calls-non-degree-workers-a-burden-at-debt-relief-meeting/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="tf_svg_lazy attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="578" src="data:image/svg+xml,%3Csvg%20xmlns=%27http://www.w3.org/2000/svg%27%20width='1016'%20height='578'%20viewBox=%270%200%201016%20578%27%3E%3C/svg%3E" width="1016" /&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="578" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Screenshot-2025-09-09-at-2.13.19-PM.png" width="1016" /&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A legislative working group created to explore student debt relief in Connecticut took an unexpected turn last week when one of its co-chairs, Rep. Eleni Kavros DeGraw (D-Avon), suggested that [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/09/09/avon-rep-eleni-kavros-degraw-calls-non-degree-workers-a-burden-at-debt-relief-meeting/"&gt;Avon Rep. Eleni Kavros Degraw Calls Non-Degree Workers a ‘Burden’ at Debt Relief Meeting&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 18:20:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] National Poverty Rate Fails to Capture the Problem of Poverty Concentration in Georgia and Beyond</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/press-release-poverty-rate-2024/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/press-release-poverty-rate-2024/"&gt;National Poverty Rate Fails to Capture the Problem of Poverty Concentration in Georgia and Beyond&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 18:26:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] Wong: The Abuse of Intercity Bus Subsidies</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/09/wong-the-abuse-of-intercity-bus-subsidies/</link><description>by J.D. Wong Since 1978, a federal subsidy program (49 U.S.C. 5311) has funneled taxpayer money into intercity bus routes. Fast forward to today&amp;#160;and this initiative has failed. Instead of attracting riders, politicians have often crafted routes to win votes. As a result, subsidized buses have been squandering taxpayer money for 46 years. Meanwhile, unsubsidized&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/09/wong-the-abuse-of-intercity-bus-subsidies/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 18:55:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] As PEEHIP Faces Funding Shortfall, it is Time for Healthcare and Pension Reforms</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/09/10/as-peehip-faces-funding-shortfall-it-is-time-for-healthcare-and-pension-reforms/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This week, the Retirement Systems of Alabama’s (RSA) Public Education Employees’ Health Insurance Plan (PEEHIP) Control Board met to discuss rising healthcare costs for state employees. The discussion highlights a stark reality: Alabama’s taxpayer funded benefit system for public employees is on an unsustainable path. PEEHIP and RSA, which includes the Teachers’ Retirement System (TRS) and Employees’ Retirement System (ERS), are consuming billions annually while carrying massive unfunded liabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/09/10/as-peehip-faces-funding-shortfall-it-is-time-for-healthcare-and-pension-reforms/"&gt;As PEEHIP Faces Funding Shortfall, it is Time for Healthcare and Pension Reforms&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 02:32:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] WILL &amp; IRG File Suit to Allow IRG to Disclose Request for Investigation Brought Against Judge</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/will-irg-file-suit-to-allow-irg-to-disclose-request-for-investigation-brought-against-judge/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL &amp;#38; IRG File Suit to Allow IRG to Disclose Request for Investigation Brought Against Judge Wisconsin Law Bars Release of Denied Requests, Violates First Amendment The News: The Institute for Reforming Government, represented by the Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;#38; Liberty, filed a lawsuit against the Wisconsin Judicial Commission challenging a statute that prohibits [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/will-irg-file-suit-to-allow-irg-to-disclose-request-for-investigation-brought-against-judge/"&gt;WILL &amp;#038; IRG File Suit to Allow IRG to Disclose Request for Investigation Brought Against Judge&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 13:05:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] UK’s Dr. Kathryn Hughes on George Eliot, Middlemarch, &amp; Victorian Novels</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/uks-dr-kathryn-hughes-on-george-eliot-middlemarch-victorian-novels/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In this week’s episode of The Learning Curve, co-hosts U-Arkansas Prof. Albert Cheng and Great Hearts Academies’ Dr. Helen Baxendale interview Dr. Kathryn Hughes, academic historian and award-winning author of George Eliot: The Last Victorian. Dr. Hughes discusses the significance of 19th-century novelist Mary Ann Evans, better known by her pen name George Eliot, in shaping British literature and capturing the societal tensions of the Victorian era.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/uks-dr-kathryn-hughes-on-george-eliot-middlemarch-victorian-novels/"&gt;UK&amp;#8217;s Dr. Kathryn Hughes on George Eliot, Middlemarch, &amp;#038; Victorian Novels&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 13:41:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Tightening Nebraska’s Property Tax Caps for Real Relief</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/tightening-nebraskas-property-tax-caps-for-real-relief/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Nebraska lawmakers can deliver stronger transparency and greater tax relief by consolidating and tightening Nebraska’s property tax caps. Nebraska has both a Truth-In-Taxation (TNT) transparency law and property tax caps for K-12 school districts and then separate caps for all other local governments.  By comparison, several less-fiscally-responsible states impose more strict property tax caps. Nebraska...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/tightening-nebraskas-property-tax-caps-for-real-relief/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Tightening Nebraska’s Property Tax Caps for Real Relief&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 13:43:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] As an LIRR Strike Looms, the Empire Center Publishes the Disputed Contracts</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/as-an-lirr-strike-looms-the-empire-center-publishes-the-disputed-contracts/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;With Long Island Rail Road workers threatening a strike that could strand hundreds of thousands of commuters, the Empire Center....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/as-an-lirr-strike-looms-the-empire-center-publishes-the-disputed-contracts/"&gt;As an LIRR Strike Looms, the Empire Center Publishes the Disputed Contracts&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 13:59:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] WILL &amp; IRG File Suit to Allow IRG to Disclose Request for Investigation Brought Against Judges</title><link>https://will-law.org/will-irg-file-suit-to-allow-irg-to-disclose-request-for-investigation-brought-against-judge/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL filed a complaint against the Wisconsin Judicial Commission on behalf of the Institute for Reforming Government (IRG) challenging confidentiality requirements for certain requests for investigation filed with the Commission. The lawsuit alleges that the confidentiality requirements violate the First Amendment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/will-irg-file-suit-to-allow-irg-to-disclose-request-for-investigation-brought-against-judge/"&gt;WILL &amp;#038; IRG File Suit to Allow IRG to Disclose Request for Investigation Brought Against Judges&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 14:02:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Teachers Unions to Blame for Nation’s Plummeting Test Scores</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/education/teachers-unions-to-blame-for-nations-plummeting-test-scores/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In response to the latest Nation’s Report Card, which shows reading and math scores at multi-decade lows, Freedom Foundation CEO Aaron Withe released the following statement condemning teachers’ unions for putting politics ahead of education and driving the systematic failure of public schools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/education/teachers-unions-to-blame-for-nations-plummeting-test-scores/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Teachers Unions to Blame for Nation’s Plummeting Test Scores&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 14:18:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Kansas Needs a Reality Check—It’s Time to Relearn Econ 101</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/kansas-needs-econ-101/</link><description>When I recently published Econ 101: A Compass for a Lost Country at The Daily Economy, I aimed to remind Americans—especially policymakers—that prosperity is rooted in simple, timeless truths. Economics isn’t about government programs or political slogans. It’s about human behavior, the way people respond to incentives, and the trade-offs we all face in a [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 14:44:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Cost for Seattle’s Sound Transit rail program balloons to $185 billion -  $55,000 per person within the tax district</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/cost-for-seattle-s-sound-transit-rail-program-balloons-to-185-billion-55-000-per-person-within</link><description>Sound Transit, the agency in charge of Seattle’s rail program , recently announced a shocking, $35 billion  cost overrun on the ST3...</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 15:31:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] IRG v. Wisconsin Judicial Commission</title><link>https://will-law.org/irg-v-wisconsin-judicial-commission/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL filed a lawsuit against the Wisconsin Judicial Commission challenging a statute that prohibits publicly revealing denied requests for investigation of Wisconsin judges on First Amendment grounds. IRG filed a request for investigation, asking the Commission to open an investigation into alleged judicial misconduct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/irg-v-wisconsin-judicial-commission/"&gt;IRG v. Wisconsin Judicial Commission&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 17:06:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Student Excellence for Every Portland Public School</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/education/student-excellence-for-every-portland-public-school/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By John Charles On September 9th, the Portland Public School (PPS) board was...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/education/student-excellence-for-every-portland-public-school/"&gt;Student Excellence for Every Portland Public School&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 17:49:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] KASB tries to whitewash new lower proficiency standards with deception and false claims</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/kasb-tries-to-whitewash-new-lower-proficiency-standards-with-deception-and-false-claims/</link><description>When something sounds too good to be true, it often is…like the State School Board and the Kansas Department of Education claiming that skyrocketing proficiency levels are not related to the state dumbing down proficiency standards. Now, the Kansas Association of School Boards (KASB) is joining the chorus with a new video denying that proficiency [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 19:45:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Phoenix to Face AZ Supreme Court Scrutiny over Public Records Refusal</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/phoenix-to-face-supreme-court-scrutiny-over-public-records-refusal/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Arizona Supreme Court yesterday agreed to review a lawsuit brought by the Goldwater Institute against the City of Phoenix,..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/phoenix-to-face-supreme-court-scrutiny-over-public-records-refusal/"&gt;Phoenix to Face AZ Supreme Court Scrutiny over Public Records Refusal&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 20:02:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] 1,065 Illinoisans laid off in August, with 276 at Diverse Facility Solutions</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/1065-illinoisans-laid-off-in-august-with-276-at-diverse-facility-solutions/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Illinois companies announced 1,065 mass layoffs in August. Minority-owned Diverse Facility Solutions, headquartered in Alsip, Illinois, and two other janitorial services companies accounted for nearly half of the jobs lost. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/1065-illinoisans-laid-off-in-august-with-276-at-diverse-facility-solutions/"&gt;1,065 Illinoisans laid off in August, with 276 at Diverse Facility Solutions&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 20:56:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Virginiainstitute] In memory of Charlie Kirk (1993-2025)</title><link>https://virginiainstitute.org/in-memory-of-charlie-kirk-1993-2025/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=in-memory-of-charlie-kirk-1993-2025</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Virginia Institute for Public Policy tonight remembers Charlie Kirk, his beautiful wife Erika, and his young daughter and son who will grow up without a father&amp;#8217;s loving care and&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org/in-memory-of-charlie-kirk-1993-2025/"&gt;In memory of Charlie Kirk (1993-2025)&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org"&gt;Virginia Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 02:59:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] The Gordon Chang Report–China’s Car Industry Slams Into the World</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/the-gordon-chang-report-chinas-car-industry-slams-into-the-world/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;READ THE PDF China’s Car Industry Slams Into the World BYD Co., the world’s largest maker of electric vehicles, reported that sales in August increased 0.2% from the same month last year. That rate was down from July’s year-on-year increase of 0.6% and the 12.0% jump in June. The company’s car production in August dropped [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/the-gordon-chang-report-chinas-car-industry-slams-into-the-world/"&gt;The Gordon Chang Report–China’s Car Industry Slams Into the World&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 09:00:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Freedom notes U.S.A.: Trash business fights The Man in Arkansas court</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/freedom-notes-usa-trash-business-fights-the-man-in-arkansas-court</link><description>Kansas homeowners get tax relief under 2021 law; Illinois gets little for massive college spending</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 09:59:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] McGowan: The Advantage of Biological Parents</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/09/14136/</link><description>by Richard McGowan, Ph.D. When I taught ethics at Butler, there were with ethical issues that did not exist when I previously taught at the now-defunct St. Joseph’s College in Rensselaer. &amp;#160; In the late 1980s and early 1990s, technological innovation was not nearly so developed as it was a mere ten years later. For&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/09/14136/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 12:48:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Aaron Withe Honors Charlie Kirk, Condemns Political Violence</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/press-release/aaron-withe-honors-charlie-kirk-condemns-political-violence/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Charlie Kirk was somebody that was brave and unapologetically stood up for the same values that we all fight for each day. I had the privilege of knowing him, and he was someone I respected. We are around the same age, had our first kids around the same time, believe the same things, and are both leaders of right-leaning organizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/press-release/aaron-withe-honors-charlie-kirk-condemns-political-violence/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Aaron Withe Honors Charlie Kirk, Condemns Political Violence&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Job Opening: Policy Analyst</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/job-opening-policy-analyst/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Policy Analyst About the Position Maine Policy Institute is seeking an energetic, organized, and detail-oriented full-time policy analyst to conduct the organization’s research, legislative testimony, blog posts and public policy outreach. This position will report directly to the chief executive officer and work closely with the director of legislative affairs and director of civic engagement [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/job-opening-policy-analyst/"&gt;Job Opening: Policy Analyst&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] John Charles’ Sept. 9 Testimony for PPS Board Meeting Re: Purchase Agreement for Center for Black Student Excellence</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/education/john-charles-sept-9-testimony-for-pps-board-meeting-re-purchase-agreement-for-center-for-black-student-excellence/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Executive Summary: On September 9th, the Portland Public School (PPS) board met to...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/education/john-charles-sept-9-testimony-for-pps-board-meeting-re-purchase-agreement-for-center-for-black-student-excellence/"&gt;John Charles’ Sept. 9 Testimony for PPS Board Meeting Re: Purchase Agreement for Center for Black Student Excellence&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 14:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Joy Cometh in the Morning</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/uncategorized/joy-cometh-in-the-morning/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Joy cometh in the morning. So the Psalmist tells us. Each day it seems we find ourselves weeping more in the night than anything else. The unthinkable events of yesterday cannot help but merge into the still all-too-raw memories that come with another arrival of September 11, even 24 years on. The evil can be...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/uncategorized/joy-cometh-in-the-morning/"&gt;Joy Cometh in the Morning&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 14:11:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Government Spending Does Not Drive Economic Growth</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/editorial-template-copy/</link><description>&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="80" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/daily-signal.jpg" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;" width="300" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Government Spending Does Not Drive Economic Growth " src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/daily-signal.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iowa has been rated as one of the most fiscally prudent states for several years running, due to sound tax and spending policies. Yet thanks in part to a recent downturn in the agricultural economy, economic growth in the state has slowed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the state has been losing residents to other states every year since 2013 and has one of the highest outflows of young residents with bachelor’s degrees, leading to some concern over a potential “brain drain.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/editorial-template-copy/"&gt;Government Spending Does Not Drive Economic Growth &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 14:26:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Third-Grade Retention and Early Literacy Policies</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/education/third-grade-retention-and-early-literacy-policies/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Reading scores in Missouri continue to fall, relative to both past performance and other states. But this trend doesn&amp;#8217;t have [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/education/third-grade-retention-and-early-literacy-policies/"&gt;Third-Grade Retention and Early Literacy Policies&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 15:03:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Never Again Means Action: Why We Must Treat the Cartels as the Terrorists They Are</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/never-again-means-action-why-we-must-treat-the-cartels-as-the-terrorists-they-are/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Each year on September 11th, the nation pauses to honor the lives lost—ringing bells, reading names, and recalling faces forever etched in our collective memory. But remembrance without resolve is hollow. The pledge of “never again” demands action: fortifying the legal, geographic, and bureaucratic seams that our adversaries exploit so that grief never again revisits...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/never-again-means-action-why-we-must-treat-the-cartels-as-the-terrorists-they-are/"&gt;Never Again Means Action: Why We Must Treat the Cartels as the Terrorists They Are&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 15:16:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Pelican Institute Files Amicus Briefs at U.S. Supreme Court to  Confront Trial-Lawyer Driven Lawfare Against American Energy Production</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/press-release/pelican-institute-files-amicus-briefs-at-u-s-supreme-court-to-confront-trial-lawyer-driven-lawfare-against-american-energy-production/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Today, the Pelican Institute for Public Policy filed amicus briefs in two landmark cases now before the United States Supreme Court, each raising urgent questions about major distortions of the U.S. legal system to wage war on American energy production. “These cases are about more than the energy industry—they are about the integrity of our...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/press-release/pelican-institute-files-amicus-briefs-at-u-s-supreme-court-to-confront-trial-lawyer-driven-lawfare-against-american-energy-production/"&gt;Pelican Institute Files Amicus Briefs at U.S. Supreme Court to  Confront Trial-Lawyer Driven Lawfare Against American Energy Production&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 17:42:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Goldwater: AZ Supreme Court Should Strike Down Donor-Doxxing Law</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/goldwater-az-supreme-court-should-strike-down-donor-doxxing-law/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Today, attorneys for the Goldwater Institute and Andrew Gould at Holtzman Vogel made a crucial stand for the freedom of..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/goldwater-az-supreme-court-should-strike-down-donor-doxxing-law/"&gt;Goldwater: AZ Supreme Court Should Strike Down Donor-Doxxing Law&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 18:44:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] In Memory of Charlie Kirk: Why Political Violence Demands A Better Response</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/in-memory-of-charlie-kirk-why-political-violence-demands-a-better-response/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The staff at Maine Policy Institute joins millions across the country in mourning the tragic and senseless killing of Charlie Kirk, founder of Turning Point USA. We offer our heartfelt condolences to his wife, children, and colleagues, and we stand in solidarity with those across the political spectrum who are grieving this immense loss. No [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/in-memory-of-charlie-kirk-why-political-violence-demands-a-better-response/"&gt;In Memory of Charlie Kirk: Why Political Violence Demands A Better Response&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 19:05:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] How Immigrants Became a Cash Cow for New York’s Essential Plan</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/how-immigrants-became-a-cash-cow-for-new-yorks-essential-plan/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Hochul administration&amp;#8217;s move to shrink the Essential Plan in response to federal budget cuts has exposed a surprising reality:....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/how-immigrants-became-a-cash-cow-for-new-yorks-essential-plan/"&gt;How Immigrants Became a Cash Cow for New York&amp;#8217;s Essential Plan&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 19:38:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Is Consumer-Regulated Electricity Going Worldwide?</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/energy/is-consumer-regulated-electricity-going-worldwide/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Electricity demand from data centers is exploding. This surge has spurred an intense buildout of new generation capacity, as businesses [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/energy/is-consumer-regulated-electricity-going-worldwide/"&gt;Is Consumer-Regulated Electricity Going Worldwide?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 19:48:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Job Licensing Reviews: Judiciary, Natural Resources and Urban Affairs Committees</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/job-licensing-reviews-judiciary-natural-resources-and-urban-affairs-committees/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Occupational Board Reform Act (OBRA) was passed in 2018 and became effective in 2019. It requires legislative committees of jurisdiction to review all occupational licenses in the state, roughly 20% per year, on a five-year rotation. These reviews examine whether the licensing requirements are adequate or excessive by current standards. The committees then submit...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/job-licensing-reviews-judiciary-natural-resources-and-urban-affairs-committees/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Job Licensing Reviews: Judiciary, Natural Resources and Urban Affairs Committees&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 21:18:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Remembering Charlie Kirk</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/remembering-charlie-kirk/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;No American should be attacked for voicing their opinion, for speaking their mind, or for standing up for what they..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/remembering-charlie-kirk/"&gt;Remembering Charlie Kirk&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 21:59:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Tony Evers’ puzzlingly swift rejection of more education money</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/tony-evers-puzzlingly-swift-rejection-of-more-education-money/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When asked about whether Evers would wave his hand to let Wisconsin taxpayers use a new federal tax credit for education-related donations, the governor slammed the door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/tony-evers-puzzlingly-swift-rejection-of-more-education-money/"&gt;Tony Evers’ puzzlingly swift rejection of more education money&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 22:26:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Evers administration pigs out on livestock fees</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/wi-evers-administration-pigs-out-on-livestock-fees/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;State agencies have begun their rush through a regulatory back door that will almost certainly cost owners of businesses large and small in Wisconsin tens of millions of dollars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/wi-evers-administration-pigs-out-on-livestock-fees/"&gt;Evers administration pigs out on livestock fees&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 22:26:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Panning Obama’s response to the Kirk killing</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/panning-obamas-response-to-the-kirk-killing/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Mark Hemingway of the Federalist responds to former President Barack Obama’s statement about the murder of Charlie Kirk. I didn’t really snap until I saw Obama put out a statement: “We don’t yet know what motivated the person who shot and killed Charlie Kirk, but this kind of despicable violence has no place in our...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/panning-obamas-response-to-the-kirk-killing/"&gt;Panning Obama’s response to the Kirk killing&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 09:36:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Political violence as essential element of leftist ideology</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/political-violence-as-essential-element-of-leftist-ideology/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;J.R. Dunn writes for the American Thinker about an underreported piece of political history. The assassination of Charlie Kirk is a horrific reminder that the left is based on nothing other than terror, violence, and aggression. This has been true since Karl howled to Friedrich that the bourgeois would someday pay for his plague of skin...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/political-violence-as-essential-element-of-leftist-ideology/"&gt;Political violence as essential element of leftist ideology&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 09:39:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Charlotte transit victim depicted as ‘lamb to the slaughter’</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/charlotte-transit-victim-depicted-as-lamb-to-the-slaughter/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Albin Sadar writes for the American Thinker about the Charlotte public transportation murder. The biggest emotion that we should feel about the senseless and needless tragedy on the light-rail train in Charlotte, North Carolina—after the outrage has faded just a bit—is incredible sadness. How can it be that in a nation that calls itself “The...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/charlotte-transit-victim-depicted-as-lamb-to-the-slaughter/"&gt;Charlotte transit victim depicted as ‘lamb to the slaughter’&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 09:42:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Je suis Charlie</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/je-suis-charlie/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On Wednesday, September 10, Charlie Kirk went to Utah and was killed. He went there to visit the campus of Utah Valley University (UVU) as part of his role as president of Turning Point USA – a conservative student organization he founded that boasts over 800 chapters and tens of thousands of members. His visit [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/je-suis-charlie/"&gt;Je suis Charlie&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 10:00:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] ‘Freedom, horrible freedom,’ districts cry as House budget raises school funding</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/freedom-horrible-freedom-districts-cry-as-house-budget-raises-school-funding</link><description>Moving money from categorical grants to general fund would leave more for superintendents to spend</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 11:59:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Listen: Charlie Kirk’s Death and Political Violence on WGAN</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/listen-charlie-kirks-death-and-political-violence-on-wgan/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Policy analyst, Harris Van Pate, joined the WGAN Morning News to discuss the political response to the assassination of Charlie Kirk, including what lawmakers on both sides of the aisle have shared in response and what the political temperature in Augusta feels like. Listen to the full segment below. Newsradio WGAN · Maine Policy Institute&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/listen-charlie-kirks-death-and-political-violence-on-wgan/"&gt;Listen: Charlie Kirk&amp;#8217;s Death and Political Violence on WGAN&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 12:27:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Michigan Court to Hear Mackinac Center Challenge to Hidden Earmarks in State Budget</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/pressroom/2025/michigan-court-to-hear-mackinac-center-challenge-to-hidden-earmarks-in-state-budget</link><description>Lawsuit seeks to restore accountability in the budget process</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 14:28:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] How AI can help take regulatory reforms to the next level</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/how-ai-can-help-take-regulatory-reforms-to-the-next-level</link><description>Across our region, policymakers have been taking action that significantly moves the economic needle: cutting waste and trimming red...</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 15:00:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Food aid feeds almost 2M statewide in May, 1-in-3 in southern counties</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/food-aid-feeds-almost-2m-statewide-in-may-1-in-3-in-southern-counties/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Enrollment in the Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program dropped by 3.2% in May. Still, nearly 2 million Illinoisans relied on federal food aid, with participation rates exceeding 30% in some Southern Illinois counties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/food-aid-feeds-almost-2m-statewide-in-may-1-in-3-in-southern-counties/"&gt;Food aid feeds almost 2M statewide in May, 1-in-3 in southern counties&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 15:01:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] When It Comes to Attendance, Hartford Schools Hold Students Accountable — But Not Staff</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/09/12/when-it-comes-to-attendance-hartford-schools-hold-students-accountable-but-not-staff/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Connecticut, students who miss more than 10 percent of school days in a year are labeled “chronically absent.” That designation triggers a series of interventions: districts must notify families, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/09/12/when-it-comes-to-attendance-hartford-schools-hold-students-accountable-but-not-staff/"&gt;When It Comes to Attendance, Hartford Schools Hold Students Accountable — But Not Staff&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 15:35:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Texas Children Will Now Learn the True Story of Freedom</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/texas-children-will-now-learn-the-true-story-of-freedom/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This week marks a turning point in Texas history and in the future of our nation’s children. The State Board of Education has officially passed the Comprehensive 3-5-1 Model — the only framework that ensures our kids will learn the true story of freedom: where it began, how it grew, and how Texas stands as...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/texas-children-will-now-learn-the-true-story-of-freedom/"&gt;Texas Children Will Now Learn the True Story of Freedom&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 16:09:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] The Court and the Computer: When a Judge Underestimated Technological Innovation</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/the-court-and-the-computer-when-a-judge-underestimated-technological-innovation/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The antitrust case against Google was filed in 2020 and did not conclude until the beginning of this month. The last five years have been a case study in the differing paces of the judiciary and technological progress. Judge Mehta, who presided over the case, ruled on the remedies last week and his decision acknowledges...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/the-court-and-the-computer-when-a-judge-underestimated-technological-innovation/"&gt;The Court and the Computer: When a Judge Underestimated Technological Innovation&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 16:15:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Pre‑Shocks on the Fault Line: City of Hayward Needs More Than Cosmetic Fixes to Stay Solvent</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/hayward-needs-fixes/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=hayward-needs-fixes</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Hayward, the Bay Area’s sixth largest city, is facing a self-inflicted financial crisis. By failing to responsibly budget, municipal leaders are failing the 162,000 residents who pay the city’s high taxes and rely on municipal services. At its June 17, 2025, meeting, the Hayward City Council adopted the city’s operating budget for Fiscal Year 2025-26.1...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/hayward-needs-fixes/"&gt;Pre‑Shocks on the Fault Line: City of Hayward Needs More Than Cosmetic Fixes to Stay Solvent&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 16:35:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] CT’s Bond Rating Upgrades Prove Fiscal Guardrails Are Working — So Why Undermine Them?</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/09/12/cts-bond-rating-upgrades-prove-fiscal-guardrails-are-working-so-why-undermine-them/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="1438" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/shutterstock_2376193717-scaled.jpg" width="2560" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connecticut’s recent bond rating upgrades are a clear sign that the state’s fiscal guardrails are delivering results. Yet, even as these reforms strengthen our long-term financial outlook, lawmakers continue to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/09/12/cts-bond-rating-upgrades-prove-fiscal-guardrails-are-working-so-why-undermine-them/"&gt;CT&amp;#8217;s Bond Rating Upgrades Prove Fiscal Guardrails Are Working — So Why Undermine Them?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 17:58:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Business Policy CMS Shouldn’t Expand Its Broken Competitive Bidding Model</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/business-policy-cms-shouldnt-expand-its-broken-competitive-bidding-model/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Durable medical equipment (DME) such as CPAP machines and hospital beds helps keep many patients out of expensive nursing home care and in their own homes. Unfortunately, creating the right payment model has long eluded the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services (CMS). Disconcertingly, they now plan to expand a flawed bidding process to include [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/business-policy-cms-shouldnt-expand-its-broken-competitive-bidding-model/"&gt;Business Policy CMS Shouldn’t Expand Its Broken Competitive Bidding Model&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 18:14:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Students Who Can’t Read Benefit from Third-Grade Retention</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/performance/students-who-cant-read-benefit-from-third-grade-retention/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This is the headline from a recent study I conducted in Indiana with my coauthor NaYoung Hwang. We study a [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/performance/students-who-cant-read-benefit-from-third-grade-retention/"&gt;Students Who Can’t Read Benefit from Third-Grade Retention&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 19:14:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Kent calls for more transparency regarding Aloha Stadium project</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/09/kent-calls-for-more-transparency-regarding-aloha-stadium-project/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A developer has been chosen for the Aloha Stadium project, but the state has yet to reveal contract details or even how much it might cost. Joe Kent, executive vice president of the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii, talked this past Sunday with H. Hawaii Media radio host Johnny Miro about the lack of transparency surrounding [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/09/kent-calls-for-more-transparency-regarding-aloha-stadium-project/"&gt;Kent calls for more transparency regarding Aloha Stadium project&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 19:34:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] The Clock is Ticking on Charter School Bills</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/the-clock-is-ticking-on-charter-school-bills/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=the-clock-is-ticking-on-charter-school-bills</link><description>&lt;p&gt;SACRAMENTO — As charter school advocates wait for the California legislature to complete their work before session ends this weekend, the following is a summary of the most important developments regarding charter school bills in the California legislature. Since the Senate Pro Tem waived Joint Rule 61, any bill that was amended within 72-hours will...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/the-clock-is-ticking-on-charter-school-bills/"&gt;The Clock is Ticking on Charter School Bills&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 19:36:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Join us in reviving the free exchange of ideas in New Hampshire</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/09/join-us-in-reviving-the-free-exchange-of-ideas-in-new-hampshire/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On September 9, the Foundation for Individual Rights and Expression (FIRE) released its 2026 campus free speech rankings, concluding that “America’s colleges get an ‘F’ for poor free speech climate.”  “More students than ever think violence and chaos are acceptable alternatives to peaceful protest,” FIRE Chief Research Advisor Sean Stevens said on the report’s release. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/09/join-us-in-reviving-the-free-exchange-of-ideas-in-new-hampshire/"&gt;Join us in reviving the free exchange of ideas in New Hampshire&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 20:08:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Inside the classroom: Is “equitable” grading effective?</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/inside-the-classroom-is-equitable-grading-effective/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Recent data published by the Fordham Institute suggests that teachers want to revisit “equitable” grading practices.&amp;#160; What is “equitable” grading? “Equitable” grading arises from mastery-based grading practice, which has been discussed in the educational world for some time. Mastery-based learning is an individually-based method of instruction that values blended instruction and self-pacing over a structured...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/inside-the-classroom-is-equitable-grading-effective/"&gt;Inside the classroom: Is “equitable” grading effective?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 21:07:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Tinley Park teachers union may strike Sept. 22</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/tinley-park-teachers-union-may-strike-sept-22/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;District 146 Educators Council has voted to authorize a strike. If an agreement is not reached, teachers in Tinley Park could strike as soon as Sept. 22. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/tinley-park-teachers-union-may-strike-sept-22/"&gt;Tinley Park teachers union may strike Sept. 22&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 22:11:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Winners &amp; Losers: A Very Big Loss in America</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/winners-losers-a-very-big-loss-in-america/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Every Friday morning, I join the Cardle &amp;#38; Woolley Show on 1370 Talk Radio in Austin to announce the week’s Winners &amp;#38; Losers. This week, the day before the 24th anniversary of September 11, the country experienced a political assassination that will also be remembered as a day of infamy. Many are calling the murder...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/winners-losers-a-very-big-loss-in-america/"&gt;Winners &amp; Losers: A Very Big Loss in America&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 22:12:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] A Reflection on the Life of Charlie Kirk and a Call to Prayer at Noon on Friday</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/a-reflection-on-the-life-of-charlie-kirk-and-a-call-to-prayer-at-noon-on-friday/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="630" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/IMG_3776.jpeg" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Friend of TJI, While we are all still processing yesterday’s tragic news of the assassination of Charlie&amp;#160;Kirk, I find great comfort in knowing that Charlie is in a better place.&amp;#160;Charlie wasn’t just an evangelist for freedom, he was a cultural missionary, of sorts, calling people to know and love God, and to know and [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/a-reflection-on-the-life-of-charlie-kirk-and-a-call-to-prayer-at-noon-on-friday/"&gt;A Reflection on the Life of Charlie Kirk and a Call to Prayer at Noon on Friday&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 23:16:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Minnesota’s Economic News — W/E 9/12/25</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/minnesotas-economic-news-w-e-9-12-25/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Regulation Duluth News Tribune: Our View: Minnesota&amp;#8217;s wild rice standard demands compromise Grand Forks Herald: At Iron Range hearing, miners warn of closures if wild rice rule enforced St. Cloud Times: How much will Minnesota&amp;#8217;s minimum wage go up in 2026? Here&amp;#8217;s what to know State and local taxes and spending Duluth News Tribune: Duluth...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/minnesotas-economic-news-w-e-9-12-25/"&gt;Minnesota’s Economic News — W/E 9/12/25&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 05:01:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] All Measures Passed in September Special Election—But Few Iowans Voted</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/all-measures-passed-in-september-special-electionbut-few-iowans-voted/</link><description>&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1179" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Table.jpg" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;" width="2250" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="All Measures Passed in September Special Election—But Few Iowans Voted" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Table-600x314.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results are in: every public measure on September 9, 2025, ballot passed across the state. That is notable, but the real headline should be the persistently low voter turnout in these September special elections—and whether it’s time to eliminate them altogether. On September 9, seven public measures appeared statewide. Three renewed the Physical Plant and Equipment Property Tax Levy (PPEL) for another ten years, while others asked whether districts could continue using the one-cent sales tax for school infrastructure (RPS) and whether the City of Swan should remain incorporated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/all-measures-passed-in-september-special-electionbut-few-iowans-voted/"&gt;All Measures Passed in September Special Election—But Few Iowans Voted&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 14:38:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Charter Bill Results Roll in as Legislative Session Ends</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/charter-bill-results-roll-in-as-legislative-session-ends/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=charter-bill-results-roll-in-as-legislative-session-ends</link><description>&lt;p&gt;SACRAMENTO — The California Legislature has officially wrapped up the first year of the legislative session, going a day into overtime to finish voting on a plethora of bills. Last night on September 12th, AB 84 and SB 494 — two concerning bills for charter schools that CPC has been monitoring — were put in...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/charter-bill-results-roll-in-as-legislative-session-ends/"&gt;Charter Bill Results Roll in as Legislative Session Ends&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 00:29:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Mahomes Can’t Evade New York’s Licensing Blitz</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/mahomes-cant-evade-new-yorks-licensing-blitz/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The National Football League kicked off its new season this month and fans tuning in to television broadcasts this fall....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/mahomes-cant-evade-new-yorks-licensing-blitz/"&gt;Mahomes Can&amp;#8217;t Evade New York&amp;#8217;s Licensing Blitz&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 11:56:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Election 2025: Virginia’s Energy Future Is on the Ballot: Will Voters Choose Reliability or Risk?</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/election-2025-virginias-energy-future-is-on-the-ballot-will-voters-choose-reliability-or-risk/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="630" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Reliable-vs-Unreliable-Power-for-Virginia.jpg" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For several years now, Virginians have been told that the&amp;#160;Virginia Clean Economy Act (VCEA) is necessary to save Virginia&amp;#160;and is a necessary step to save the planet. We’ve been told that rising seas, worsening storms, and other supposedly catastrophic impacts of man-made climate change justify a radical restructuring of Virginia’s entire energy system. But what [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/election-2025-virginias-energy-future-is-on-the-ballot-will-voters-choose-reliability-or-risk/"&gt;Election 2025: Virginia&amp;#8217;s Energy Future Is on the Ballot: Will Voters Choose Reliability or Risk?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 15:14:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Joe Thompson is turning the tide</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/joe-thompson-is-turning-the-tide/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;One newspaper columnist at a time. Rochelle Olson writes in the Star Tribune this weekend, U.S. Attorney Joe Thompson: Fraud is stealing Minnesota’s way of life Olson reports about her feelings on the subject, I’ve finally been persuaded that this [fraud] is more than a pandemic-era blip. After listening to Thompson, I’m convinced we need...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/joe-thompson-is-turning-the-tide/"&gt;Joe Thompson is turning the tide&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 18:37:36 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>