<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>State-Policy Think-Tank Digest</title><link>https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml</link><description>Latest posts from free-market policy institutes across the U.S.</description><atom:link href="https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 21:03:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>[Mspolicy] Reflecting on a Grim Week</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/reflecting-on-a-grim-week/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The past few days have been deeply unsettling. &amp;#160;The assassination of Charlie Kirk, gunned down while addressing young Americans on a Utah college campus, was horrifying. It seems clear that Charlie was targeted for his beliefs, which he expressed with remarkable clarity and conviction. Over the past decade, Charlie Kirk emerged as one of a [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/reflecting-on-a-grim-week/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Reflecting on a Grim Week&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 21:18:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] In defense of murder</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/09/17/in-defense-of-murder/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The alarming responses to the cold-blooded assassination of Charlie Kirk from both sides of the political aisle are derived from the same source: false worldview.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/09/17/in-defense-of-murder/"&gt;In defense of murder&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 18:52:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Hugh Hewitt to headline Libertas Award Dinner; Frank Edelblut to receive 2025 Libertas Award</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/09/hugh-hewitt-to-headline-libertas-award-dinner-frank-edelblut-to-receive-2025-libertas-award/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Josiah Bartlett Center for Public Policy is proud to announce our 2025 Libertas Award Dinner on Monday, Nov. 10, featuring special guest Hugh Hewitt and recognizing Frank Edelblut with our 2025 Libertas Award.  “At a time when fair, honest, and open discourse is so important for New Hampshire and the nation, we’re thrilled to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/09/hugh-hewitt-to-headline-libertas-award-dinner-frank-edelblut-to-receive-2025-libertas-award/"&gt;Hugh Hewitt to headline Libertas Award Dinner; Frank Edelblut to receive 2025 Libertas Award&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 18:31:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] Sec. McMahon, TPUSA, AFPI, API, and Partners Launch National Civics Coalition</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/09/18/sec-mcmahon-tpusa-afpi-api-and-partners-launch-national-civics-coalition/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Department of Education (the Department), in partnership the America First Policy Institute (AFPI), Turning Point USA, Hillsdale College and more than 40 leading national and state-based organizations, today announced the launch of the America 250 Civics Education Coalition. This landmark initiative is dedicated to renewing patriotism, strengthening civic knowledge, and advancing a shared understanding of America’s founding principles in schools across the nation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/09/18/sec-mcmahon-tpusa-afpi-api-and-partners-launch-national-civics-coalition/"&gt;Sec. McMahon, TPUSA, AFPI, API, and Partners Launch National Civics Coalition&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 23:19:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] Governor Shapiro Again Blames PJM for High Energy Prices, Ignores True Culprit: His Policies</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/09/22/governor-shapiro-again-blames-pjm-for-high-energy-prices-ignores-true-culprit-his-policies/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Harrisburg, Pa., September 22, 2025 — This week, Gov. Josh Shapiro is speaking as Pennsylvania hosts PJM governors for the Multi-State Technical Conference in Philadelphia. The conference comes on the heels of rising criticism of PJM from certain governors, expressing concerns over rising electricity costs, reliability of the electric grid, and project delays. Gov. Shapiro [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/09/22/governor-shapiro-again-blames-pjm-for-high-energy-prices-ignores-true-culprit-his-policies/"&gt;Governor Shapiro Again Blames PJM for High Energy Prices, Ignores True Culprit: His Policies&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 20:11:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Freedom Wins: The Future of Education is Here</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/freedom-wins-the-future-of-education-is-here/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=freedom-wins-the-future-of-education-is-here</link><description>While the EFS success is a great reason to celebrate, there is more work to be done to unlock education freedom for all Tennesseans.</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 16:17:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Mississippi Leadership Academy Kicks Off 2025 Program with State Leaders</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/mississippi-leadership-academy-kicks-off-2025-program-with-state-leaders/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For Immediate Release Jackson, MS – September 23, 2025&amp;#160;— Students from across Mississippi gathered in Jackson on Saturday for the&amp;#160;opening session of the 2025 Mississippi Leadership Academy, a program that equips high school and college students with leadership training, civic knowledge, and direct access to state leaders. This year’s kickoff featured&amp;#160;State Auditor Shad White, Representative [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/mississippi-leadership-academy-kicks-off-2025-program-with-state-leaders/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Leadership Academy Kicks Off 2025 Program with State Leaders&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 20:50:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Nebraskanomics: Governor Jim Pillen on Moving Nebraska Forward</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/nebraskanomics-governor-jim-pillen-on-moving-nebraska-forward/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Tune in to the latest episode of Nebraskanomics as we welcome the 41st Governor of the State of Nebraska, Governor Jim Pillen. During the episode Governor Pillen and Platte Institute Chief Executive Officer Jim Vokal discuss how we provide property tax reform for Nebraskans, the importance of making the most of federal funds, and what’s...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/nebraskanomics-governor-jim-pillen-on-moving-nebraska-forward/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Nebraskanomics: Governor Jim Pillen on Moving Nebraska Forward&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 14:43:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Nebraska Property Taxes Keep Rising Despite Tax Caps</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-property-taxes-keep-rising-despite-tax-caps/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Nebraska’s Truth-in-Taxation season brings surprises each year, shining a light on local government tax increases. That’s because Nebraska’s Truth-in-Taxation law requires local governments to notify property owners of proposed tax increases as a prelude to public hearings about the tax proposals.  Residents of Omaha were hit with another set of unsustainable tax increases in 2025, as...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-property-taxes-keep-rising-despite-tax-caps/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Nebraska Property Taxes Keep Rising Despite Tax Caps&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 15:30:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] Test Scores Changes Backfire on Education Establishment</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/test-scores-changes-backfire-on-education-establishment/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Test Scores Changes Backfire on Education Establishment Test score changes display widening gaps Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government (IRG) released the following statement following the release of Forward Exam and ACT test scores on Thursday showing mixed performance of K-12 schools in Wisconsin.  WHAT HAPPENED: Under Superintendent of Public Instruction Jill Underly’s [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/test-scores-changes-backfire-on-education-establishment/"&gt;Test Scores Changes Backfire on Education Establishment&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 17:52:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] The ‘I do not care about your economics’ approach to housing</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/09/the-i-do-not-care-about-your-economics-approach-to-housing/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;With a single heated remark to a developer, a Portsmouth Planning Board member last week showed exactly how the municipal development process is broken. Developer Mark McNabb has proposed converting a property he owns on Congress Street to a 125-unit co-living apartment building. Co-living units, once common, were zoned nearly out of existence in U.S. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/09/the-i-do-not-care-about-your-economics-approach-to-housing/"&gt;The &amp;#8216;I do not care about your economics&amp;#8217; approach to housing&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 13:47:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Idaho’s Parental Choice Tax Credit Is Constitutional</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/idahos-parental-choice-tax-credit-is-constitutional/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/idahos-parental-choice-tax-credit-is-constitutional/" rel="nofollow" title="Idaho’s Parental Choice Tax Credit Is Constitutional"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Article-Headers-2025-09-26T132715.417.png" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;A coalition of Leftist activists, including the Idaho Education Association, the Moscow School District, and Rep. Stephanie Mickelsen (R), has filed a challenge to block the implementation of Idaho’s parental choice tax credit. However, petitioners’ frivolous claims lack any basis in either our state constitution or Idaho Supreme Court precedent. Idaho’s school choice program is [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 19:54:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] The Silent Decline of Hillcrest Christian School: When Private Doesn’t Mean Privileged</title><link>https://empowerms.org/the-silent-decline-of-hillcrest-christian-school-when-private-doesnt-mean-privileged/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In the heart of Mississippi sits Hillcrest Christian School, a beacon of faith-based education serving predominantly African-American students in south Jackson. Once bustling with 1,200 students, today the halls echo with just over 200 enrolled children. This steep decline is more than just numbers—it’s a story of a community at risk of losing a vital&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/the-silent-decline-of-hillcrest-christian-school-when-private-doesnt-mean-privileged/"&gt;The Silent Decline of Hillcrest Christian School: When Private Doesn’t Mean Privileged&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 18:00:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Why Affordable Housing is Unaffordable</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/land-use/why-affordable-housing-is-unaffordable/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Randal O’Toole Last week KGW news reported that Portland area rents are...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/land-use/why-affordable-housing-is-unaffordable/"&gt;Why Affordable Housing is Unaffordable&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 12:48:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Jere Nash: Reconstruction in Mississippi</title><link>https://empowerms.org/jere-nash-reconstruction-in-mississippi/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Jere Nash: Reconstruction in Mississippi On this episode, host Grant Callen sits down with historian Jere Nash, a Greenville native, retired political consultant, and co-author of award-winning books. Jere’s latest work, Reconstruction in Mississippi, 1862-1877, offers a definitive look at a pivotal era. We discuss why Jere chose to explore Reconstruction, debunk common myths, and examine&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/jere-nash-reconstruction-in-mississippi/"&gt;Jere Nash: Reconstruction in Mississippi&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 22:00:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Recasting Lawrenceville as a resilient, connected community</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/recast-lawrenceville-josiah-story/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Through our partnership with the ReCAST initiative, residents in Lawrenceville are finding purpose, hope, and connection through employment.   One powerful example is Josiah, who found a path forward by participating in our Jobs for Life class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/recast-lawrenceville-josiah-story/"&gt;Recasting Lawrenceville as a resilient, connected community&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:04:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] Hours Away from Federal Government Shutdown, Pennsylvania Remains Vulnerable</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/09/30/governor-shapiros-failed-leadership-resulting-in-a-monthslong-state-budget-impasse-has-left-pennsylvanians-more-vulnerable-in-the-event-of-a-federal-shutdown/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Harrisburg, Pa., September 30, 2025 —&amp;#160;A federal government shutdown is set to begin at midnight, barring a last-minute deal.&amp;#160;For Pennsylvania residents, the commonwealth remains in a dangerously precarious position, with a looming federal shutdown overlapping with its four-month-long state budget impasse. Despite reporting that a budget deal was “very, very close” in June, Gov. Josh [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/09/30/governor-shapiros-failed-leadership-resulting-in-a-monthslong-state-budget-impasse-has-left-pennsylvanians-more-vulnerable-in-the-event-of-a-federal-shutdown/"&gt;Hours Away from Federal Government Shutdown, Pennsylvania Remains Vulnerable &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 01:50:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Nebraska Property Taxes Now 4th Highest Nationwide</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-property-taxes-now-4th-highest-nationwide/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Nebraska’s property taxes have risen to fourth highest in the United States, according to a 2025 study from the Tax Foundation using 2023 tax data. Illinois (1.83%) has the highest taxes as a share of home value, followed closely by New Jersey (1.77%). Following New Jersey is Connecticut (1.48%) which is only slightly higher than...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-property-taxes-now-4th-highest-nationwide/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Nebraska Property Taxes Now 4th Highest Nationwide&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 13:48:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Why New York’s Health Premiums Keep Going Up</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/why-new-yorks-health-premiums-keep-going-up/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New Yorkers continue to face some of the costliest health premiums in the U.S., and the insurance industry&amp;#8217;s recently finalized....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/why-new-yorks-health-premiums-keep-going-up/"&gt;Why New York&amp;#8217;s Health Premiums Keep Going Up&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 16:29:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] First Principles Series: The Importance of Protecting our First Amendment Rights</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/first-amendment-fp/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=first-amendment-fp</link><description>Beacon tirelessly advocates for the principles of liberty whether government officials like them or not. Thanks to the First Amendment, all Americans are free to do the same.</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 18:16:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] Alabama Fights for Freedom</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/10/02/alabama-fights-for-freedom/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Defending higher education means defending SB 129. The core of SB 129 is not to censor but to restore balance between individual liberty and government overreach in education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/10/02/alabama-fights-for-freedom/"&gt;Alabama Fights for Freedom&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 16:48:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] BERGEN RECORD: The NJEA’s funding of Sean Spiller’s campaign was wrong. We need accountability | Opinion</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/10/bergen-record-the-njeas-funding-of-sean-spillers-campaign-was-wrong-we-need-accountability-opinion/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The NJEA&amp;#8217;s funding of Sean Spiller&amp;#8217;s campaign was wrong. We need accountability &amp;#124; Opinion &amp;#160; By: Rosemary Becchi October 2, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/10/bergen-record-the-njeas-funding-of-sean-spillers-campaign-was-wrong-we-need-accountability-opinion/"&gt;BERGEN RECORD: The NJEA’s funding of Sean Spiller’s campaign was wrong. We need accountability | Opinion&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 18:19:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] SPOTLIGHT NJ: NJ teachers sue over $40 million campaign boost for union president</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/10/spotlight-nj-nj-teachers-sue-over-40-million-campaign-boost-for-union-president/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;NJ teachers sue over $40 million campaign boost for union president NJEA used member dues to get its president elected [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/10/spotlight-nj-nj-teachers-sue-over-40-million-campaign-boost-for-union-president/"&gt;SPOTLIGHT NJ: NJ teachers sue over $40 million campaign boost for union president&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 18:24:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] First Principles Series: The Practical Case for Protecting Free Speech</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/free-speech-fp/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=free-speech-fp</link><description>Our “First Principles Series” is an ongoing awareness effort by Beacon to restore our nation’s commitment to those principles of free markets, individual liberty, and limited government that have made America the best nation in the history of the world. Often, politicians eager to appease constituents can stray from these principles. And voters can be misled...</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 19:21:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] New York’s Immigrant Health Coverage Becomes a National Flash Point</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/new-yorks-immigrant-health-coverage-becomes-a-national-flash-point/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A little-noticed New York program that provides Medicaid coverage to elderly undocumented immigrants was thrust onto the national stage this....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/new-yorks-immigrant-health-coverage-becomes-a-national-flash-point/"&gt;New York&amp;#8217;s Immigrant Health Coverage Becomes a National Flash Point&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 17:22:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Unleash home builders to fight socialism</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/10/unleash-home-builders-to-fight-socialism/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On Monday, a young woman from New Hampshire was featured prominently in a front-page Wall Street Journal story. She didn’t found a company or create a valuable new product. Quite the opposite; she spent the summer canvassing for the Democratic Socialists of America in New York City, where she hopes to get socialist Zohran Mamdani [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/10/unleash-home-builders-to-fight-socialism/"&gt;Unleash home builders to fight socialism&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 20:36:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cardinalinstitute] One Big Beautiful Opportunity to Reconnect West Virginians with Stable Work</title><link>https://cardinalinstitute.com/one-big-beautiful-opportunity-to-reconnect-west-virginians-with-work/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;One Big Beautiful Bill is One Big Beautiful Opportunity to Reconnect West Virginians with Stable Work On July 4, President Donald Trump signed the latest congressional reconciliation package, known colloquially as the One Big Beautiful Bill Act (OBBB), a sweeping package of federal budget measures including extension of the 2017 tax cuts, spending cuts and [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com/one-big-beautiful-opportunity-to-reconnect-west-virginians-with-work/"&gt;One Big Beautiful Opportunity to Reconnect West Virginians with Stable Work&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com"&gt;Cardinal Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 17:57:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] Arp:  The IEDC Chickens Have Roosted</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/10/arp-the-iedc-chickens-have-roosted/</link><description>by JASON ARP Nearly 10  years ago, I published an article in The Indiana Policy Review(Backgrounder: Regional Cities Plans, Jan. 1, 2016) describing some of the issues related to the State of Indiana’s plan to institute a Regional Development Authority (RDA) to fund what were deemed to be multi-county economic development projects. The concerns expressed in that article focused&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/10/arp-the-iedc-chickens-have-roosted/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 13:08:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Kansas Can Learn from Washington’s Shutdown Mistakes</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/kansas-can-learn-shutdown-mistakes/</link><description>The federal government shutdown on October 1 because Congress couldn’t agree on how much more of our money to spend. It’s become routine in Washington: wait until the last minute, pass a short-term fix, and promise to deal with the problem later. That’s how we ended up with a national debt of more than $37.4 [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 17:00:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/10/the-outstater-292/</link><description>The House of Bayh WITH BEAU BAYH&amp;#160;crossing three state lines to begin his ancestral run for high office here, what better time to reconstitute&amp;#160;Indiana as a&amp;#160;sovereign&amp;#160;kingdom?&amp;#160; The state already owes fealty to the Bayh family, this being the third generation of their civic reign. No, none&amp;#160;has been particularly distinguished&amp;#160;but achievement is not the justification of&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/10/the-outstater-292/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 17:31:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Teachers allege union president diverted $40 million into his own gubernatorial campaign</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/new-jersey/teachers-allege-union-president-diverted-40-million-into-his-own-gubernatorial-campaign/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Their claim? The NJEA secretly funneled more than $40 million of teachers’ dues to political groups supporting Spiller’s failed run for governor — money that was never approved, never disclosed, and never meant for politics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/new-jersey/teachers-allege-union-president-diverted-40-million-into-his-own-gubernatorial-campaign/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Teachers allege union president diverted $40 million into his own gubernatorial campaign&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 20:43:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] WILL Lawsuit Challenges “Cream City Carve Out”</title><link>https://will-law.org/will-lawsuit-challenges-cream-city-carve-out/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL has filed a new lawsuit against Milwaukee County to end an unconstitutional carve out allowing Milwaukee County withhold millions from Wisconsin’s Common School Fund.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/will-lawsuit-challenges-cream-city-carve-out/"&gt;WILL Lawsuit Challenges “Cream City Carve Out”&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 13:45:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Idaho is powering up its nuclear efforts</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/idaho-is-powering-up-its-nuclear-efforts</link><description>The future of nuclear power in Idaho is looking strong. The Gem State recently took two important steps demonstrating its commitment to unleashing the potential of nuclear energy. These efforts are  w orking hard alongside other government al  and private partners to meet the need and promote Idaho as a viable state to fill the energy demand of the future.   The first step was taken on September 18 as Idaho released the Advanced Nuclear Strategic Framework.   This is a comprehensive plan to...</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 14:20:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Stueland v. Cullen</title><link>https://will-law.org/stueland-v-cullen/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL has filed a new lawsuit against Milwaukee County to end an unconstitutional carve out allowing Milwaukee County to withhold millions from Wisconsin’s Common School Fund. This fund, mandated by the Wisconsin Constitution, supports libraries in schools and communities across Wisconsin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/stueland-v-cullen/"&gt;Stueland v. Cullen&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 14:45:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG Report: Federal Bureaucrats Are Quietly Shaping Wisconsin Policy</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-report-federal-bureaucrats-are-quietly-shaping-wisconsin-policy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;IRG Report: Federal Bureaucrats Are Quietly Shaping Wisconsin Policy Guidance documents bypass legislature and voters, change state policy &amp;#160; Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government (IRG) released a new report on Wednesday detailing how federal agencies are quietly steering Wisconsin policy through informal “guidance documents,” often bypassing state legislative oversight. &amp;#160; READ THE [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-report-federal-bureaucrats-are-quietly-shaping-wisconsin-policy/"&gt;IRG Report: Federal Bureaucrats Are Quietly Shaping Wisconsin Policy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 15:11:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Corporate Welfare: Picking Winners and Creating Losers</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/tax-budget/corporate-welfare-picking-winners-and-creating-losers/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Politicians love to announce “big wins” when a new factory breaks ground or a large company pledges to bring jobs to town. The photo ops are flashy, the headlines are positive, and taxpayers are told it’s all part of a smart economic development strategy. Some may even point to these announcements as evidence that our...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/tax-budget/corporate-welfare-picking-winners-and-creating-losers/"&gt;Corporate Welfare: Picking Winners and Creating Losers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 15:27:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Give Me Your Innovators, Your AI: The Promise of America for European Technology</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/give-me-your-innovators-your-ai-the-promise-of-america-for-european-technology/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;There is a growing disconnect between America’s technology industry and America’s technology legislation. The dissonance between a culture where competition is driving profound feats of innovation and one wherein risk-aversion trumps all has become more pronounced with the proliferation of artificial intelligence (AI). Uniting policy and practice will be essential to maintaining American leadership in...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/give-me-your-innovators-your-ai-the-promise-of-america-for-european-technology/"&gt;Give Me Your Innovators, Your AI: The Promise of America for European Technology&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 16:30:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] In the Fight Over ACA Tax Credits, the Stakes Are Lowest for New York</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/in-the-fight-over-aca-tax-credits-the-stakes-are-lowest-for-new-york/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As Washington skirmishes over the future of enhanced tax credits under the Affordable Care Act, New York has relatively little....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/in-the-fight-over-aca-tax-credits-the-stakes-are-lowest-for-new-york/"&gt;In the Fight Over ACA Tax Credits, the Stakes Are Lowest for New York&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 18:14:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Vapes of Wrath: Fighting E-Cigarette Censorship at the Oregon Supreme Court</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/vapes-of-wrath-fighting-e-cigarette-censorship-at-the-oregon-supreme-court/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;All business owners have the right — and the need — to communicate truthfully with their customers. But even though..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/vapes-of-wrath-fighting-e-cigarette-censorship-at-the-oregon-supreme-court/"&gt;Vapes of Wrath: Fighting E-Cigarette Censorship at the Oregon Supreme Court&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 21:41:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] Day 100 of State Budget Impasse</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/10/08/day-100-of-state-budget-impasse/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On Hundredth Day of the Shapiro Shutdown, PA Democrats Push Spending &amp;#38; Tax Hikes  Harrisburg, Pa., October 8, 2025 — Day 100 of the state budget shutdown brought chaos to the Capitol rotunda, with partisan political theater from Pennsylvania House and Senate Democrats placing parties even farther apart at the negotiating&amp;#160;table.&amp;#160; After previously rejecting and [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/10/08/day-100-of-state-budget-impasse/"&gt;Day 100 of State Budget Impasse&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 00:25:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Decarceration’s Disconnect: Corrections spending rises in Georgia even as prison population declines</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/georgia-prison-spending-and-reform/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Prison reform debates often focus on reducing prison populations to save taxpayers money. But is that actually possible? In a new report for the Manhattan Institute, Joshua Crawford, Public Safety Fellow at the Georgia Center for Opportunity, reveals some surprising answers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/georgia-prison-spending-and-reform/"&gt;Decarceration’s Disconnect: Corrections spending rises in Georgia even as prison population declines&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 04:09:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Should Austin Get a Raise?</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/should-austin-get-a-raise/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Austin is just one of a handful of cities across Texas trying to raise taxes on already overburdened taxpayers, but it represents perhaps the most egregious example of a city that doesn’t deserve it. The property tax increase included in its $6.3 billion budget for 2026 is so high that it requires voter approval this...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/should-austin-get-a-raise/"&gt;Should Austin Get a Raise?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 19:49:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] VIDEO: California Caregiver Exposes SEIU 2015 for Coercion and Silencing Members</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/litigation/video-california-caregiver-exposes-seiu-2015-for-coercion-and-silencing-members/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In a video released today by the Freedom Foundation, Chaquan May, a California mother and in-home healthcare provider for her medically fragile daughter, exposes how SEIU 2015 has ignored, coerced, and trapped her in union membership against her will.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/litigation/video-california-caregiver-exposes-seiu-2015-for-coercion-and-silencing-members/" rel="nofollow"&gt;VIDEO: California Caregiver Exposes SEIU 2015 for Coercion and Silencing Members &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 20:19:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] A housing victory: zoning to match community plan</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/a-housing-victory-zoning-to-match-community-plan/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Wisconsin Assembly voted largely along party lines this week in support of a crucial housing bill, AB453, that will rein in NIMBYism — the “not in my back yard” outcry that greets developers trying to increase housing supply in communities where elected officials want the same thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/a-housing-victory-zoning-to-match-community-plan/"&gt;A housing victory: zoning to match community plan&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 21:06:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Announcing The Freedom Agenda: Goldwater’s State Policy Handbook</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/announcing-the-freedom-agenda-goldwaters-state-policy-handbook/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;You can view and download the PDF of The Freedom Agenda here. For decades, the Goldwater Institute has led the..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/announcing-the-freedom-agenda-goldwaters-state-policy-handbook/"&gt;Announcing The Freedom Agenda: Goldwater’s State Policy Handbook&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 21:28:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Fight over Obamacare is fight worth having</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/fight-over-obamacare-is-fight-worth-having/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Wisconsin taxpayers ought to be rooting hard for conservatives to hold the line during this current federal government shutdown and let the pandemic-era super-subsidies for the Affordable Care Act run out at the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/fight-over-obamacare-is-fight-worth-having/"&gt;Fight over Obamacare is fight worth having&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 21:35:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Fixing regulatory rampage will require amendment, say observers</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/fixing-regulatory-rampage-will-require-amendment-say-observers/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;But reforms via statute might help Wisconsin avoid a still more onerous environment Fixing the damage wreaked by the Wisconsin Supreme Court when it stripped the Legislature of its power to halt bureaucrats’ regulations will take a constitutional amendment, say legal experts — though reforms in statute can help in the interim. That damage so [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/fixing-regulatory-rampage-will-require-amendment-say-observers/"&gt;Fixing regulatory rampage will require amendment, say observers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 22:09:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] The Center for Black Student Excellence Should Be a Private Venture</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/education/the-center-for-black-student-excellence-should-be-a-private-venture/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By John A. Charles, Jr. In September, the Portland Public Schools Board voted...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/education/the-center-for-black-student-excellence-should-be-a-private-venture/"&gt;The Center for Black Student Excellence Should Be a Private Venture&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 07:06:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] WILL Urges Dismissal of New Attempt to Overturn Congressional Maps</title><link>https://will-law.org/will-urges-dismissal-of-new-attempt-to-overturn-congressional-maps/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The News: WILL is once again defending Wisconsin’s congressional maps, filing briefs in opposition to an overtly political, nonsensical, and last-minute attempt to redraw Wisconsin’s maps on the eve of the midterm election.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/will-urges-dismissal-of-new-attempt-to-overturn-congressional-maps/"&gt;WILL Urges Dismissal of New Attempt to Overturn Congressional Maps&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 14:35:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Voters Should Judge Candidate Character</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/voters-should-judge-candidate-character/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="720" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/Jay-Jones-Controversey-New-Background-v4.jpg" width="1280" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The measure of your character is what you do and say when you think no one is looking or listening. But what does it say about you when you declare horrible intentions even when people&amp;#160;are&amp;#160;listening? The latest spin from his fellow Virginia Democratic candidates wants us to believe the text-messaged fantasies of Attorney General candidate Jay Jones to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/voters-should-judge-candidate-character/"&gt;Voters Should Judge Candidate Character&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 16:59:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Avoid the D.C. Dysfunction: Iowa Needs a “No Shutdown” Rule</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/avoid-the-d-c-dysfunction-iowa-needs-a-no-shutdown-rule/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Avoid the D.C. Dysfunction: Iowa Needs a “No Shutdown” Rule" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/AdobeStock_329581775-600x400.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Federal Dysfunction, Local Lesson: As Washington’s government shutdown drags on, it highlights the risk of partisan gridlock — something Iowa must guard against in its own budgeting process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Budget Continuity Needed: Without clear rules, an Iowa budget impasse could threaten key services. A budget-continuation or automatic continuing resolution would ensure government operations continue smoothly until a new budget is passed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Limit Political Games: Establishing a budget-continuity policy would prevent Iowa from mirroring the fiscal dysfunction seen in Washington and other states. Neither a governor nor the legislature could use the threat of a shutdown as political leverage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/avoid-the-d-c-dysfunction-iowa-needs-a-no-shutdown-rule/"&gt;Avoid the D.C. Dysfunction: Iowa Needs a “No Shutdown” Rule&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 18:44:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Government spending does not drive economic growth</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/government-spending-does-not-drive-economic-growth/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Government spending does not drive economic growth" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/Corridor-Business.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iowa has been rated as one of the most fiscally prudent states for several years running, due to sound tax and spending policies. Yet thanks in part to a recent downturn in the agricultural economy, economic growth in the state has slowed. Additionally, the state has been losing residents to other states every year since 2013, and has one of the highest outflows of young residents with bachelor’s degrees, leading to some concern over a potential “brain drain.” Though government spending is often lauded as a tool for addressing these sorts of trends, Iowa will be better served by continuing to follow a path of fiscal conservatism. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/government-spending-does-not-drive-economic-growth/"&gt;Government spending does not drive economic growth&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 19:46:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Clear Losers in Last Night’s Gubernatorial Debate and a Summary of Key Positions Taken</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/clear-losers-in-last-nights-gubernatorial-debate-and-a-summary-of-key-positions-taken/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/Virginia-Governors-Debate-v3.jpg" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last night’s first and final Virginia gubernatorial debate between Winsome Earle-Sears and Abigail Spanberger had one clear loser &amp;#8212; the approximately 446,000 Commonwealth voters who had already cast their early ballots.&amp;#160;&amp;#160; For a state that has such a storied civic heritage, relying on a single, late-stage debate fails the test of responsible governance. The increase [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/clear-losers-in-last-nights-gubernatorial-debate-and-a-summary-of-key-positions-taken/"&gt;Clear Losers in Last Night&amp;#8217;s Gubernatorial Debate and a Summary of Key Positions Taken&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 20:17:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Week in Review: Vaporizing Oregon Censorship</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-vaporizing-oregon-censorship/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Walk into any store in America, and you’ll see labels describing everything under the sun. But in Oregon, the state..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-vaporizing-oregon-censorship/"&gt;Week in Review: Vaporizing Oregon Censorship&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 22:02:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Winners &amp; Losers: Giving Peace a Chance</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/winners-losers-giving-peace-a-chance/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Every Friday morning, I join the Cardle &amp;#38; Wooley Show on Talk 1370 Radio in Austin to announce the week’s Winners &amp;#38; Losers. The government is still shut down and members of the military won’t be getting their paychecks next week, but in case you were worried, the members of Congress (the same people who won’t...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/winners-losers-giving-peace-a-chance/"&gt;Winners &amp; Losers: Giving Peace a Chance&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 01:30:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Kansas City’s Stadium Fumble: Denver Shows How to Play by Free-Market Rules</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/kansas-citys-stadium-fumble/</link><description>Jackson County residents voted overwhelmingly to recall County Executive Frank White Jr. in a historic election—the first successful recall in county history. The message was loud and clear: voters are tired of politicians wasting their money. For months, Kansas City leaders have fought over who should pay for new stadiums for the Kansas City Royals [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 14:00:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF discusses opposition to Albuquerque Public Schools’ $350 million bond with KOAT 7</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-discusses-opposition-to-albuquerque-public-schools-350-million-bond-with-koat-7/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As noted in a recent post on Errors of Enchantment.com Albuquerque Public Schools is looking for a $350 million bond on this fall&amp;#8217;s ballot. While RGF doesn&amp;#8217;t necessarily oppose the uses of the bond we have looked closely at the APS budget and have seen a steep decline in the student population while the District&amp;#8217;s [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-discusses-opposition-to-albuquerque-public-schools-350-million-bond-with-koat-7/"&gt;RGF discusses opposition to Albuquerque Public Schools&amp;#8217; $350 million bond with KOAT 7&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 15:15:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/10/the-outstater-293/</link><description>War of the Worlds II A LEARNED PROFESSOR of my acquaintance argues that we have become an “unserious” people. I not been sure how to test his theory — COVID, AOC and the Obama Library being indicative but not decisive. That was until the arrival of 31/ATLAS.  I am referring of course to an interstellar object, possibly&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/10/the-outstater-293/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 17:07:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Avery Nichols named 2025 Sawtooth Leadership Academy scholarship recipient</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/avery-nichols-named-2025-sawtooth-leadership-academy-scholarship-recipient</link><description>After months of rigorous coursework, mentorship, and public voting, Avery Nichols has been selected as the first-place scholar, earning the $5,000 Tim Hennessey &amp;#38; Holly Harrison Scholarship.</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 17:36:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Among Large Massachusetts Cities, Lawrence Had the Highest Home Value to Income Ratio in 2024</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/among-large-massachusetts-cities-lawrence-had-the-highest-home-value-to-income-ratio-in-2024/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This edition of The House Call explores new American Community Survey data comparing home values and rents to household incomes in Massachusetts cities. It also discusses a proposed rezoning in Boston that would allow for taller buildings downtown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/among-large-massachusetts-cities-lawrence-had-the-highest-home-value-to-income-ratio-in-2024/"&gt;Among Large Massachusetts Cities, Lawrence Had the Highest Home Value to Income Ratio in 2024&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 19:48:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] PRiME Summit Celebrates Schools with Impressive Test Score Growth</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/performance/prime-summit-celebrates-schools-with-impressive-test-score-growth/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I was fortunate to attend an event in late September celebrating Missouri schools that demonstrate high test score growth. The [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/performance/prime-summit-celebrates-schools-with-impressive-test-score-growth/"&gt;PRiME Summit Celebrates Schools with Impressive Test Score Growth&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 19:54:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] New Report: Corrections spending rises in Georgia even as prison population declines</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/new-report-corrections-spending-rises-in-georgia/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A new report by Joshua Crawford, Public Safety Fellow at the Georgia Center for Opportunity, shows that the decreasing number of inmates hasn’t translated to meaningful savings or improvements in public safety for Georgians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/new-report-corrections-spending-rises-in-georgia/"&gt;New Report: Corrections spending rises in Georgia even as prison population declines&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 23:02:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Michigan finally has a realistic internet plan</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/michigan-finally-has-a-realistic-internet-plan</link><description>Michigan High Speed Internet Office drops impediments for quick broadband rollout</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Progressive Bills Youngkin Vetoed Will Kickstart Agenda if Spanberger Wins</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/progressive-bills-youngkin-vetoed-will-kickstart-agenda-if-spanberger-wins/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="630" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/Spanberger-erasing-Youngkin-Vetoes.jpg" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Predicting how Democrats will transform Virginia should they gain full control of state government in November’s election is easy. Just look through the list of 400 plus bills vetoed by Republican Governor Glenn Youngkin, most of them from 2024 and 2025. The progressive bills which reached Youngkin’s desk with unanimous or near unanimous Democratic votes and then died will [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/progressive-bills-youngkin-vetoed-will-kickstart-agenda-if-spanberger-wins/"&gt;Progressive Bills Youngkin Vetoed Will Kickstart Agenda if Spanberger Wins&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Portland’s Tower and the Limits of ReCode Portland</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/portlands-tower-and-the-limits-of-recode-portland/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Portland may soon be home to the tallest building in Maine, outpacing the current tallest, Saint Joseph’s Church in Biddeford, by almost 150 feet. A proposed 30-story tower in the Old Port would bring hundreds of new housing units, commercial space, and mixed-use vitality to the city’s downtown. Furthermore, this project is a product of [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/portlands-tower-and-the-limits-of-recode-portland/"&gt;Portland&amp;#8217;s Tower and the Limits of ReCode Portland&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Gov. Mills exaggerates the ‘cost’ of federal tax conformity</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/gov-mills-exaggerates-the-cost-of-federal-tax-conformity/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Governor Janet Mills has claimed that conforming Maine’s laws to tax changes passed in the federal One Big Beautiful Bill Act (OBBBA) would “cost the state over $400 million.” A new 2025 Maine law empowered her to proactively comply with federal tax changes this year before the legislature reconvenes in January, but Gov. Mills has [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/gov-mills-exaggerates-the-cost-of-federal-tax-conformity/"&gt;Gov. Mills exaggerates the &amp;#8216;cost&amp;#8217; of federal tax conformity&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 13:29:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Shasta County Board of Supervisors to Appeal Ruling in Free Speech Case Against California Public Employment Relations Board</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/press-release/shasta-county-board-of-supervisors-to-appeal-ruling-in-free-speech-case-against-california-public-employment-relations-board/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Shasta County Board of Supervisors will appeal a recent court ruling against the California Public Employment Relations Board (PERB), continuing its fight to defend free speech rights for public employers and employees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/press-release/shasta-county-board-of-supervisors-to-appeal-ruling-in-free-speech-case-against-california-public-employment-relations-board/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Shasta County Board of Supervisors to Appeal Ruling in Free Speech Case Against California Public Employment Relations Board&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 14:12:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Tariffs – why we will hear a lot more about them</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/tariffs-why-we-will-hear-a-lot-more-about-them/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Remember the tariff debates that dominated Washington just a few months ago?&amp;#160; For a while it was the only thing anyone seemed to talk about.&amp;#160;First tariffs were raised by eyewatering amounts.&amp;#160; Then they weren’t.&amp;#160;&amp;#160;Eventually, after all sorts of back and forth, we saw tariffs imposed at the highest rates in decades. Free trade advocates warned [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/tariffs-why-we-will-hear-a-lot-more-about-them/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Tariffs – why we will hear a lot more about them&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 16:00:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] For Non-Partisan California Voters, Prop 50 is a Questionable Proposition</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/for-non-partisan-california-voters-prop-50-is-a-questionable-proposition/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=for-non-partisan-california-voters-prop-50-is-a-questionable-proposition</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For partisan Democrats and Republicans, deciding how to vote on Proposition 50 is simple, since it is likely to shift five House seats into the Democratic column in what promises to be a closely fought 2026 Congressional election. But for decline-to-state and third-party voters, as well as less passionate major party registrants, the choice will...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/for-non-partisan-california-voters-prop-50-is-a-questionable-proposition/"&gt;For Non-Partisan California Voters, Prop 50 is a Questionable Proposition&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 16:54:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Over-Sized, Over-Priced Schools Accelerate PPS’ Fiscal Crisis</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/reports/over-sized-over-priced-schools-accelerate-pps-fiscal-crisis/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Naomi Inman Cascade&amp;#8217;s President and CEO, John Charles, emailed a Memo Monday...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/reports/over-sized-over-priced-schools-accelerate-pps-fiscal-crisis/"&gt;Over-Sized, Over-Priced Schools Accelerate PPS’ Fiscal Crisis&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 16:57:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Dubuque Roundtable Highlights Demand for Property Tax Reform</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/dubuque-roundtable-highlights-demand-for-property-tax-reform/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Dubuque Roundtable Highlights Demand for Property Tax Reform" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/Dubuque-ITR-Luncheon-600x336.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Property taxes remain the most pressing concern for Iowans, and that sentiment was clear during a recent roundtable discussion held at Stone Cliff Winery in Dubuque. Community members, business owners, and elected officials gathered to confront a growing frustration: rising property taxes that stretch family budgets and threaten the ability of many Iowans to remain in their homes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/dubuque-roundtable-highlights-demand-for-property-tax-reform/"&gt;Dubuque Roundtable Highlights Demand for Property Tax Reform&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 17:56:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Moody’s reaffirms Idaho’s strong credit rating</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/moody-s-reaffirms-idaho-s-strong-credit-rating</link><description>Moody’s Ratings, one of the major global credit review companies, has reaffirmed its highest credit rating for Idaho while saying the state’s credit “outlook remains stable.” This good fiscal news is a reflection of Idaho’s sound fiscal management and helps save money for taxpayers by keeping government borrowing costs low with favorable terms. According to Moody’s October 9 update : “Idaho's Aaa issuer rating reflects its strong credit position supported by continued higher than average...</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 18:03:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF opinion piece: Voters should be skeptical of $350 million bond for APS</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-opinion-piece-voters-should-be-skeptical-of-350-million-bond-for-aps/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following appeared in the Albuquerque Journal on Sunday October 12, 2025. On this fall’s ballots in addition to votes for mayor, city council and school board, local voters will be asked to decide on a $350 million bond for Albuquerque Public Schools. These bonds (another name for debt which is typically used to pay [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-opinion-piece-voters-should-be-skeptical-of-350-million-bond-for-aps/"&gt;RGF opinion piece: Voters should be skeptical of $350 million bond for APS&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 18:49:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] CTA violent crime nears decade high as feds threaten funding cuts</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/cta-violent-crime-nears-decade-high-as-feds-threaten-funding-cuts/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Chicago Transit Authority violent crime hit its second-highest level since 2015, while the arrest rate dropped. CTA crime is threatening federal funding. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/cta-violent-crime-nears-decade-high-as-feds-threaten-funding-cuts/"&gt;CTA violent crime nears decade high as feds threaten funding cuts&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 19:04:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Political Targeting? The Valley School District’s Purported Vendetta Against Levy Opponents</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/political-targeting-the-valley-school-districts-purported-vendetta-against-levy-opponents/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/political-targeting-the-valley-school-districts-purported-vendetta-against-levy-opponents/" rel="nofollow" title="Political Targeting? The Valley School District’s Purported Vendetta Against Levy Opponents"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/Article-Headers-2025-10-13T182323.858.png" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Nothing says small-town charm quite like political retaliation. On one side, we have the Valley School District #262 trying to pass a $600,000 levy in the May 2025 election. On the other is a local farmer who dared to oppose it. When the levy failed by a mere seven votes, things escalated quickly. Cue a [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 19:17:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Stop the Municipal Budget Scramble: Make FY2026‑27 Easier by Acting Now</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/stop-the-municipal-budget-scramble-make-fy2026%e2%80%9127-easier-by-acting-now/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=stop-the-municipal-budget-scramble-make-fy2026%25e2%2580%259127-easier-by-acting-now</link><description>&lt;p&gt;About four months have passed since most local government agencies adopted FY2025‑26 budgets, and roughly four months remain before leaders begin planning FY2026‑27. But waiting to think about budget decisions until the official start of the budget process is a costly mistake. Every day that passes with inaction is a lost opportunity to improve both...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/stop-the-municipal-budget-scramble-make-fy2026%e2%80%9127-easier-by-acting-now/"&gt;Stop the Municipal Budget Scramble: Make FY2026‑27 Easier by Acting Now&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 20:52:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Meet the Leftist Organization That’s Been Influencing Texas History Courses</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/meet-the-leftist-organization-thats-been-influencing-texas-history-courses/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Great news! The State Board of Education voted this September to teach students history in grades 3-8. You would think that Texas schools are teaching history now, but, sadly, you would be mistaken: the current Texas framework only contains two years of actual history content in Kindergarten through 8th grade. One would think that a...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/meet-the-leftist-organization-thats-been-influencing-texas-history-courses/"&gt;Meet the Leftist Organization That’s Been Influencing Texas History Courses&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 21:26:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Lousy Medicare Insurance Is Worsening Outcomes For All Patients</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/lousy-medicare-insurance-is-worsening-outcomes-for-all-patients/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Medicare’s long-term financial outlook is in dire straits. While spending is already historically high, the Congressional Budget Office (CBO) projects that, without fundamental reform, things will only get worse. According to the CBO, total government spending will grow from 23.3% of GDP in 2025 to 26.6% in 2055. Almost two-thirds of this growth is expected [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/lousy-medicare-insurance-is-worsening-outcomes-for-all-patients/"&gt;Lousy Medicare Insurance Is Worsening Outcomes For All Patients&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 21:54:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Lower proficiency standards lead to phony student achievement gains</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/lower-proficiency-standards-phony-gains/</link><description>In the fable of the Emperor’s New Clothes, two con men convinced the Emperor they had woven a magnificent set of clothes that were invisible to incompetent people. Everyone went along with the ruse to avoid being considered stupid, but they knew he was naked. A similar con is being pulled by the Kansas State Board [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 22:02:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Dr. Steven Skultety: Freedom, Rights, and Civil Disagreement</title><link>https://empowerms.org/dr-steven-skultety-freedom-rights-and-civil-disagreement/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Dr. Steven Skultety: Freedom, Rights, and Civil Disagreement On this episode of the Empower Podcast, Grant Callen sits down with Dr. Steven Skultety, Director of the Declaration of Independence Center for the Study of American Freedom at the University of Mississippi. They explore the foundations of American democracy, the origins of rights, and why civil disagreement&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/dr-steven-skultety-freedom-rights-and-civil-disagreement/"&gt;Dr. Steven Skultety: Freedom, Rights, and Civil Disagreement&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 23:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Extend tax waiver for properties destroyed in 2023 Maui wildfires</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/10/extend-tax-waiver-for-properties-destroyed-in-2023-maui-wildfires/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Maui County Council Special Committee on Real Property Tax Reform on Oct. 14, 2025._____________ Oct. 14, 2025, 1:30 p.m.Maui Council Chamber, Kalana O Maui Building To: Maui County Council, Special Committee on Real Property Tax Reform       Alice Lee, Chair       Keani [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/10/extend-tax-waiver-for-properties-destroyed-in-2023-maui-wildfires/"&gt;Extend tax waiver for properties destroyed in 2023 Maui wildfires&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 01:24:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Abolish price threshold, liberalize tax rules for low-income rentals</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/10/abolish-purchase-price-threshold-amend-rules-for-low-income-rentals/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Honolulu City Council Committee on Budget on Oct. 14, 2025._____________ Oct. 14, 2025, 9 a.m.Honolulu Hale To: Honolulu City Council Committee on Budget       Val Okimoto, Chair       Scott Nishimoto, Vice Chair From: Grassroot Institute of Hawaii            Ted Kefalas, Director of Strategic Campaigns RE: [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/10/abolish-purchase-price-threshold-amend-rules-for-low-income-rentals/"&gt;Abolish price threshold, liberalize tax rules for low-income rentals&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 01:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Allow destroyed Lahaina structures to be rebuilt to original heights</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/10/allow-destroyed-lahaina-structures-to-be-rebuilt-to-original-heights/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Maui Planning Commission on Oct. 14, 2025._____________ Oct. 14, 2025, 9 a.m.Planning Department conference room To: Maui Planning Commission       Kim Thayer, Chair       Ashley Lindsey, Vice Chair From: Grassroot Institute of Hawaii            Jonathan Helton, Policy Analyst RE: Item B(1) — RELATING TO BUILDING HEIGHT [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/10/allow-destroyed-lahaina-structures-to-be-rebuilt-to-original-heights/"&gt;Allow destroyed Lahaina structures to be rebuilt to original heights&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 01:33:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Army goes nuclear to break ‘tyranny of fuel’</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/army-goes-nuclear-to-break-tyranny-of-fuel/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Morgan Phillips writes for FoxNews.com about a significant shift for the American military. The Army is launching a sweeping new nuclear program to generate power for bases across the globe, particularly in remote or contested locations where fuel might be difficult to obtain, Fox News Digital has learned. &amp;#8220;Hundreds of millions&amp;#8221; of dollars will be...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/army-goes-nuclear-to-break-tyranny-of-fuel/"&gt;Army goes nuclear to break &amp;#8216;tyranny of fuel&amp;#8217;&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 09:42:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] ‘Tax the Rich’ would hurt the rest of us</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/tax-the-rich-would-hurt-the-rest-of-us</link><description>Why the Mackinac Center cares about a possible constitutional amendment to hike taxes on high earners</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 09:57:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Michigan bill would make it easier to be a school librarian</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/michigan-bill-would-make-it-easier-to-be-a-school-librarian</link><description>Help schools carry their books</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Stacy Davis Gates makes over $273,000 but doesn’t pay her water bills</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/stacy-davis-gates-makes-over-273000-but-doesnt-pay-her-water-bills/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Chicago Teachers Union president demands the “wealthy” pay their fair share but doesn’t apply that same principle to herself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/stacy-davis-gates-makes-over-273000-but-doesnt-pay-her-water-bills/"&gt;Stacy Davis Gates makes over $273,000 but doesn’t pay her water bills&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 10:00:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] San José Mayor Shows Market-Based Ideas Can Improve Urban Quality of Life</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/san-jose-mayor-shows-market-based-ideas-can-improve-urban-quality-of-life/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Major cities in California have decayed in recent years as elected officials and city bureaucrats have doubled down on a mix of government mandates, excessive regulations, high fees and lax enforcement of public safety laws that have created an unattractive quality of life driving away businesses, jobs, tax revenue and residents. Fed up residents desiring [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/san-jose-mayor-shows-market-based-ideas-can-improve-urban-quality-of-life/"&gt;San José Mayor Shows Market-Based Ideas Can Improve Urban Quality of Life&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 10:00:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] JMI Releases New Property Tax Reform Study</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/jmi-releases-new-property-tax-reform-study/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE October 15, 2025 CONTACT Logan Elizabeth Padgett lpadgett@jamesmadison.org (850) 386-3131 JMI Releases New Property Tax...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/jmi-releases-new-property-tax-reform-study/"&gt;JMI Releases New Property Tax Reform Study&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Listen: Gov. Mills Announces for Senate</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/listen-gov-mills-announces-for-senate/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Policy analyst, Harris Van Pate, joined the WGAN Morning News to discuss Gov. Janet Mills&amp;#8217; announcement to run for the Senate against Sen. Susan Collins and what the path forward looks like for Mills in the democratic primary. He also talked about CMP&amp;#8217;s most recent rate hike proposal and shared some insights on Maine Policy&amp;#8217;s [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/listen-gov-mills-announces-for-senate/"&gt;Listen: Gov. Mills Announces for Senate&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 12:31:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] New Report Finds Most New Jersey School Districts Lack  Clear Academic Goals or Accountability in Strategic Plans</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/10/new-report-finds-most-new-jersey-school-districts-lack-clear-academic-goals-or-accountability-in-strategic-plans/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 14:52:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] ¡Adiós, Nicolas, adiós!</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/adios-nicolas-adios/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Nicolas Lopez-Juarez appears to be heading back to Guatemala after his felony conviction yesterday in federal court in downtown St. Paul. Lopez had earned Minnesota Man of the Week honors early last month, with a legal history (mostly drunk driving) so complex that I needed to create a spreadsheet to track it all. Lopez, age...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/adios-nicolas-adios/"&gt;¡Adiós, Nicolas, adiós!&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 15:05:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] UNC policy discussions must be held in the open</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/unc-policy-discussions-must-be-held-in-the-open/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A former provost has&amp;#160;accused&amp;#160;the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill Board of Trustees of holding closed sessions to discuss policy matters and destroying records. If proven true, those would be serious violations of state law. Complaint claims transparency law violations Chris Clemens, a physics professor who served as executive vice chancellor and provost at...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/unc-policy-discussions-must-be-held-in-the-open/"&gt;UNC policy discussions must be held in the open&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 15:40:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] AZ Trinity Arch Prep’s Jack Johnson Pannell on Educating Boys</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/az-trinity-arch-preps-jack-johnson-pannell-on-educating-boys/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In this week’s episode of The Learning Curve, co-hosts U-Arkansas Prof. Albert Cheng and Center for Public Schools’ Alisha Searcy interview Jack Johnson Pannell, founder and head of Trinity Arch Preparatory School for Boys in Phoenix. Mr. Pannell discusses his career as an educational leader, including founding a nationally recognized charter school in Baltimore, and shares how his background in the liberal arts and law has informed his approach to schooling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/az-trinity-arch-preps-jack-johnson-pannell-on-educating-boys/"&gt;AZ Trinity Arch Prep&amp;#8217;s Jack Johnson Pannell on Educating Boys&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 15:48:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Legal Advocates Ask Supreme Court to End Home Equity Seizures in Tax Foreclosures</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/legal-advocates-ask-supreme-court-to-end-home-equity-seizures-in-tax-foreclosures/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;BOSTON, MA — The Pioneer New England Legal Foundation (Legal Foundation), Greater Boston Legal Services (GBLS), and law firm Greenberg Traurig filed an amicus brief with the U.S. Supreme Court in support of homeowners in two Michigan cases that could determine how far governments can go in taking property for unpaid taxes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/legal-advocates-ask-supreme-court-to-end-home-equity-seizures-in-tax-foreclosures/"&gt;Legal Advocates Ask Supreme Court to End Home Equity Seizures in Tax Foreclosures &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 16:12:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] American Independence = Financial Independence</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/tax-budget/american-independence-financial-independence/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When America declared its independence nearly 250 years ago, it was not only a political revolution but also an assertion of self-reliance. The Founders of our country believed that Americans ought to be able to self-govern without dependence on a distant power. Today, that spirit of independence is under strain—not from a foreign monarch, but...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/tax-budget/american-independence-financial-independence/"&gt;American Independence = Financial Independence&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 16:31:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] 2026 Naples Annual Dinner</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/naples/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Join The James Madison Institute (JMI) in Naples, Florida, on February 17th, 2026, for the 2026 Naples Annual...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/naples/"&gt;2026 Naples Annual Dinner&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 16:34:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Red, White, &amp; Bluegrass</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/tallahassee/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Grab a new calendar for 2026, and block off January 14 to join us for The James Madison...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/tallahassee/"&gt;Red, White, &amp;amp; Bluegrass&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 16:38:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF provides comments in support of unlocking new water supplies for New Mexicans</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-provides-comments-in-support-of-unlocking-new-water-supplies-for-new-mexicans/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;They say &amp;#8220;agua es vida&amp;#8221; in New Mexico (water is life). In the desert southwest water is critical to human flourishing and the broader economy of the state and region. So, when we were presented with an opportunity to put water that is produced alongside oil and gas, we had only one question: &amp;#8220;Is it [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-provides-comments-in-support-of-unlocking-new-water-supplies-for-new-mexicans/"&gt;RGF provides comments in support of unlocking new water supplies for New Mexicans&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 16:38:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Vallas: How to improve Chicago’s billion-dollar transit crisis</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/vallas-how-to-improve-chicagos-billion-dollar-transit-crisis/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Chicago Transit Authority ridership is still below pre-pandemic levels. Crime and a budget shortfall make matters worse, but there are cost-effective ways to make it safer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/vallas-how-to-improve-chicagos-billion-dollar-transit-crisis/"&gt;Vallas: How to improve Chicago’s billion-dollar transit crisis&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 17:08:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Springfield Voters Should Be Skeptical About Convention Center Claims</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/subsidies/springfield-voters-should-be-skeptical-about-convention-center-claims/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A version of this commentary appeared in the Springfield Business Journal. On November 4, Springfield voters will decide on a proposal [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/subsidies/springfield-voters-should-be-skeptical-about-convention-center-claims/"&gt;Springfield Voters Should Be Skeptical About Convention Center Claims&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 17:38:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Fraud is Evergreen in Minnesota</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/fraud-is-evergreen-in-minnesota/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Minnesota Star Tribune digs deeper into the overlapping frauds plaguing the state, Minnesota investigating more companies linked to those charged with Medicaid fraud Specifically, the Star Tribune dug into the corporate holdings of five of the eight defendants indicted last month in the Housing Stabilization Services (HSS) scandal. They found, Minnesota officials are investigating...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/fraud-is-evergreen-in-minnesota/"&gt;Fraud is Evergreen in Minnesota&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 17:54:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Jefferson City Residents Should Be Skeptical of Conference Center Project</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/subsidies/jefferson-city-residents-should-be-skeptical-of-conference-center-project/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A version of this commentary appeared in the News-Tribune. On November 4, Jefferson City voters will decide on a proposal to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/subsidies/jefferson-city-residents-should-be-skeptical-of-conference-center-project/"&gt;Jefferson City Residents Should Be Skeptical of Conference Center Project&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 18:01:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] If Health Insurance Premiums Rise Next Year, Blame Democrats</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/if-health-insurance-premiums-rise-next-year-blame-democrats/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In the ongoing government shutdown saga, Democrats continue to cast themselves as defenders of affordable health insurance&amp;#8230; Premiums have been on a steady upward trajectory for more than a decade. Obamacare&amp;#8217;s own diktats are why premiums have risen. Read the op-ed here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/if-health-insurance-premiums-rise-next-year-blame-democrats/"&gt;If Health Insurance Premiums Rise Next Year, Blame Democrats&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 18:10:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] The $8.25 Billion San Francisco Train that Couldn’t (or at least Shouldn’t)</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/the-8-25-billion-san-francisco-train-that-couldnt-or-at-least-shouldnt/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=the-8-25-billion-san-francisco-train-that-couldnt-or-at-least-shouldnt</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The California High-Speed Rail Authority has finally recognized the obvious: there is no path to connecting Los Angeles and San Francisco with trains running at 220mph. With state rail officials now accepting reality, the question is whether northern California transit planners will do so as well by cancelling their plan to extend California High-Speed Rail...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/the-8-25-billion-san-francisco-train-that-couldnt-or-at-least-shouldnt/"&gt;The $8.25 Billion San Francisco Train that Couldn’t (or at least Shouldn’t)&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 19:42:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG: New School Choice Enrollment Numbers Show Growth Slowing Statewide</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-new-school-choice-enrollment-numbers-show-growth-slowing-statewide/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;IRG: New School Choice Enrollment Numbers Show Growth Slowing Statewide Baby bust rears its head in school enrollment numbers Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government (IRG) released the following statement following the Department of Public Instruction’s release of 2025-2026 school choice and charter enrollment numbers. WHY IT MATTERS: While traditional schools continue to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-new-school-choice-enrollment-numbers-show-growth-slowing-statewide/"&gt;IRG: New School Choice Enrollment Numbers Show Growth Slowing Statewide&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 19:51:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] It Is Time to Tackle Idaho’s Public Spending Addiction</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/it-is-time-to-tackle-idahos-public-spending-addiction/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/it-is-time-to-tackle-idahos-public-spending-addiction/" rel="nofollow" title="It Is Time to Tackle Idaho’s Public Spending Addiction"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/Article-Headers-2025-10-15T135522.813.png" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Idaho officials are addicted. The standard dictionary definition of addiction is “a strong inclination to do, use, or indulge in something repeatedly,” and there is nothing that matches this description more than the Idaho state government’s inability to curb the growth of spending.&amp;#160; Mind you, it is not just Idaho. The shutdown of the federal [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 20:19:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Mandating statewide bail guidelines and background checks</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/mandating-statewide-bail-guidelines-and-background-checks/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On August 22, 2025, a 23-year-old Ukrainian refugee was murdered on the Charlotte light rail. The victim, Iryna Zarutska, was repeatedly stabbed and left to bleed out. The exceptional brutality of it captured national attention. Just weeks before, on May 3, a 22-year-old aspiring teacher from Waxhaw was shot and killed during a home robbery in Columbia, South Carolina. Logan...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/mandating-statewide-bail-guidelines-and-background-checks/"&gt;Mandating statewide bail guidelines and background checks&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 20:24:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Democratic Socialists — “major insurgent wing” of the DFL — mourn end of war in Gaza</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/democratic-socialists-major-insurgent-wing-of-the-dfl-mourn-end-of-war-in-gaza/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This week, a deal brokered by President Trump brought an end to Israel&amp;#8217;s military campaign in the Gaza Strip. Not all observers welcomed the end of this war. The Democratic Socialists of America (DSA) released a statement titled “Until Palestinian Liberation” which “acknowledges and welcomes the relief that may be afforded to Palestinians under the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/democratic-socialists-major-insurgent-wing-of-the-dfl-mourn-end-of-war-in-gaza/"&gt;Democratic Socialists — &amp;#8220;major insurgent wing&amp;#8221; of the DFL — mourn end of war in Gaza&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 20:53:41 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>