<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>State-Policy Think-Tank Digest</title><link>https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml</link><description>Latest posts from free-market policy institutes across the U.S.</description><atom:link href="https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 08:04:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>[Beacontn] Freedom Wins: The Future of Education is Here</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/freedom-wins-the-future-of-education-is-here/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=freedom-wins-the-future-of-education-is-here</link><description>While the EFS success is a great reason to celebrate, there is more work to be done to unlock education freedom for all Tennesseans.</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 16:17:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Mississippi Leadership Academy Kicks Off 2025 Program with State Leaders</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/mississippi-leadership-academy-kicks-off-2025-program-with-state-leaders/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For Immediate Release Jackson, MS – September 23, 2025&amp;#160;— Students from across Mississippi gathered in Jackson on Saturday for the&amp;#160;opening session of the 2025 Mississippi Leadership Academy, a program that equips high school and college students with leadership training, civic knowledge, and direct access to state leaders. This year’s kickoff featured&amp;#160;State Auditor Shad White, Representative [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/mississippi-leadership-academy-kicks-off-2025-program-with-state-leaders/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Leadership Academy Kicks Off 2025 Program with State Leaders&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 20:50:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Nebraska Property Taxes Keep Rising Despite Tax Caps</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-property-taxes-keep-rising-despite-tax-caps/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Nebraska’s Truth-in-Taxation season brings surprises each year, shining a light on local government tax increases. That’s because Nebraska’s Truth-in-Taxation law requires local governments to notify property owners of proposed tax increases as a prelude to public hearings about the tax proposals.  Residents of Omaha were hit with another set of unsustainable tax increases in 2025, as...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-property-taxes-keep-rising-despite-tax-caps/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Nebraska Property Taxes Keep Rising Despite Tax Caps&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 15:30:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Idaho’s Parental Choice Tax Credit Is Constitutional</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/idahos-parental-choice-tax-credit-is-constitutional/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/idahos-parental-choice-tax-credit-is-constitutional/" rel="nofollow" title="Idaho’s Parental Choice Tax Credit Is Constitutional"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Article-Headers-2025-09-26T132715.417.png" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;A coalition of Leftist activists, including the Idaho Education Association, the Moscow School District, and Rep. Stephanie Mickelsen (R), has filed a challenge to block the implementation of Idaho’s parental choice tax credit. However, petitioners’ frivolous claims lack any basis in either our state constitution or Idaho Supreme Court precedent. Idaho’s school choice program is [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 19:54:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Recasting Lawrenceville as a resilient, connected community</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/recast-lawrenceville-josiah-story/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Through our partnership with the ReCAST initiative, residents in Lawrenceville are finding purpose, hope, and connection through employment.   One powerful example is Josiah, who found a path forward by participating in our Jobs for Life class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/recast-lawrenceville-josiah-story/"&gt;Recasting Lawrenceville as a resilient, connected community&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:04:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Nebraska Property Taxes Now 4th Highest Nationwide</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-property-taxes-now-4th-highest-nationwide/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Nebraska’s property taxes have risen to fourth highest in the United States, according to a 2025 study from the Tax Foundation using 2023 tax data. Illinois (1.83%) has the highest taxes as a share of home value, followed closely by New Jersey (1.77%). Following New Jersey is Connecticut (1.48%) which is only slightly higher than...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-property-taxes-now-4th-highest-nationwide/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Nebraska Property Taxes Now 4th Highest Nationwide&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 13:48:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] First Principles Series: The Importance of Protecting our First Amendment Rights</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/first-amendment-fp/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=first-amendment-fp</link><description>Beacon tirelessly advocates for the principles of liberty whether government officials like them or not. Thanks to the First Amendment, all Americans are free to do the same.</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 18:16:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] Alabama Fights for Freedom</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/10/02/alabama-fights-for-freedom/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Defending higher education means defending SB 129. The core of SB 129 is not to censor but to restore balance between individual liberty and government overreach in education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/10/02/alabama-fights-for-freedom/"&gt;Alabama Fights for Freedom&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 16:48:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] First Principles Series: The Practical Case for Protecting Free Speech</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/free-speech-fp/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=free-speech-fp</link><description>Our “First Principles Series” is an ongoing awareness effort by Beacon to restore our nation’s commitment to those principles of free markets, individual liberty, and limited government that have made America the best nation in the history of the world. Often, politicians eager to appease constituents can stray from these principles. And voters can be misled...</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 19:21:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Unleash home builders to fight socialism</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/10/unleash-home-builders-to-fight-socialism/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On Monday, a young woman from New Hampshire was featured prominently in a front-page Wall Street Journal story. She didn’t found a company or create a valuable new product. Quite the opposite; she spent the summer canvassing for the Democratic Socialists of America in New York City, where she hopes to get socialist Zohran Mamdani [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/10/unleash-home-builders-to-fight-socialism/"&gt;Unleash home builders to fight socialism&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 20:36:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cardinalinstitute] One Big Beautiful Opportunity to Reconnect West Virginians with Stable Work</title><link>https://cardinalinstitute.com/one-big-beautiful-opportunity-to-reconnect-west-virginians-with-work/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;One Big Beautiful Bill is One Big Beautiful Opportunity to Reconnect West Virginians with Stable Work On July 4, President Donald Trump signed the latest congressional reconciliation package, known colloquially as the One Big Beautiful Bill Act (OBBB), a sweeping package of federal budget measures including extension of the 2017 tax cuts, spending cuts and [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com/one-big-beautiful-opportunity-to-reconnect-west-virginians-with-work/"&gt;One Big Beautiful Opportunity to Reconnect West Virginians with Stable Work&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com"&gt;Cardinal Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 17:57:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG Report: Federal Bureaucrats Are Quietly Shaping Wisconsin Policy</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-report-federal-bureaucrats-are-quietly-shaping-wisconsin-policy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;IRG Report: Federal Bureaucrats Are Quietly Shaping Wisconsin Policy Guidance documents bypass legislature and voters, change state policy &amp;#160; Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government (IRG) released a new report on Wednesday detailing how federal agencies are quietly steering Wisconsin policy through informal “guidance documents,” often bypassing state legislative oversight. &amp;#160; READ THE [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-report-federal-bureaucrats-are-quietly-shaping-wisconsin-policy/"&gt;IRG Report: Federal Bureaucrats Are Quietly Shaping Wisconsin Policy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 15:11:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] Day 100 of State Budget Impasse</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/10/08/day-100-of-state-budget-impasse/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On Hundredth Day of the Shapiro Shutdown, PA Democrats Push Spending &amp;#38; Tax Hikes  Harrisburg, Pa., October 8, 2025 — Day 100 of the state budget shutdown brought chaos to the Capitol rotunda, with partisan political theater from Pennsylvania House and Senate Democrats placing parties even farther apart at the negotiating&amp;#160;table.&amp;#160; After previously rejecting and [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/10/08/day-100-of-state-budget-impasse/"&gt;Day 100 of State Budget Impasse&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 00:25:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Decarceration’s Disconnect: Corrections spending rises in Georgia even as prison population declines</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/georgia-prison-spending-and-reform/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Prison reform debates often focus on reducing prison populations to save taxpayers money. But is that actually possible? In a new report for the Manhattan Institute, Joshua Crawford, Public Safety Fellow at the Georgia Center for Opportunity, reveals some surprising answers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/georgia-prison-spending-and-reform/"&gt;Decarceration’s Disconnect: Corrections spending rises in Georgia even as prison population declines&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 04:09:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Fixing regulatory rampage will require amendment, say observers</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/fixing-regulatory-rampage-will-require-amendment-say-observers/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;But reforms via statute might help Wisconsin avoid a still more onerous environment Fixing the damage wreaked by the Wisconsin Supreme Court when it stripped the Legislature of its power to halt bureaucrats’ regulations will take a constitutional amendment, say legal experts — though reforms in statute can help in the interim. That damage so [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/fixing-regulatory-rampage-will-require-amendment-say-observers/"&gt;Fixing regulatory rampage will require amendment, say observers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 22:09:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] The Center for Black Student Excellence Should Be a Private Venture</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/education/the-center-for-black-student-excellence-should-be-a-private-venture/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By John A. Charles, Jr. In September, the Portland Public Schools Board voted...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/education/the-center-for-black-student-excellence-should-be-a-private-venture/"&gt;The Center for Black Student Excellence Should Be a Private Venture&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 07:06:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF discusses opposition to Albuquerque Public Schools’ $350 million bond with KOAT 7</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-discusses-opposition-to-albuquerque-public-schools-350-million-bond-with-koat-7/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As noted in a recent post on Errors of Enchantment.com Albuquerque Public Schools is looking for a $350 million bond on this fall&amp;#8217;s ballot. While RGF doesn&amp;#8217;t necessarily oppose the uses of the bond we have looked closely at the APS budget and have seen a steep decline in the student population while the District&amp;#8217;s [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-discusses-opposition-to-albuquerque-public-schools-350-million-bond-with-koat-7/"&gt;RGF discusses opposition to Albuquerque Public Schools&amp;#8217; $350 million bond with KOAT 7&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 15:15:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] New Report: Corrections spending rises in Georgia even as prison population declines</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/new-report-corrections-spending-rises-in-georgia/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A new report by Joshua Crawford, Public Safety Fellow at the Georgia Center for Opportunity, shows that the decreasing number of inmates hasn’t translated to meaningful savings or improvements in public safety for Georgians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/new-report-corrections-spending-rises-in-georgia/"&gt;New Report: Corrections spending rises in Georgia even as prison population declines&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 23:02:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Progressive Bills Youngkin Vetoed Will Kickstart Agenda if Spanberger Wins</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/progressive-bills-youngkin-vetoed-will-kickstart-agenda-if-spanberger-wins/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="630" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/Spanberger-erasing-Youngkin-Vetoes.jpg" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Predicting how Democrats will transform Virginia should they gain full control of state government in November’s election is easy. Just look through the list of 400 plus bills vetoed by Republican Governor Glenn Youngkin, most of them from 2024 and 2025. The progressive bills which reached Youngkin’s desk with unanimous or near unanimous Democratic votes and then died will [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/progressive-bills-youngkin-vetoed-will-kickstart-agenda-if-spanberger-wins/"&gt;Progressive Bills Youngkin Vetoed Will Kickstart Agenda if Spanberger Wins&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Tariffs – why we will hear a lot more about them</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/tariffs-why-we-will-hear-a-lot-more-about-them/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Remember the tariff debates that dominated Washington just a few months ago?&amp;#160; For a while it was the only thing anyone seemed to talk about.&amp;#160;First tariffs were raised by eyewatering amounts.&amp;#160; Then they weren’t.&amp;#160;&amp;#160;Eventually, after all sorts of back and forth, we saw tariffs imposed at the highest rates in decades. Free trade advocates warned [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/tariffs-why-we-will-hear-a-lot-more-about-them/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Tariffs – why we will hear a lot more about them&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 16:00:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Over-Sized, Over-Priced Schools Accelerate PPS’ Fiscal Crisis</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/reports/over-sized-over-priced-schools-accelerate-pps-fiscal-crisis/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Naomi Inman Cascade&amp;#8217;s President and CEO, John Charles, emailed a&amp;#160;Memo&amp;#160;on Monday to...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/reports/over-sized-over-priced-schools-accelerate-pps-fiscal-crisis/"&gt;Over-Sized, Over-Priced Schools Accelerate PPS’ Fiscal Crisis&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 16:57:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Moody’s reaffirms Idaho’s strong credit rating</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/moody-s-reaffirms-idaho-s-strong-credit-rating</link><description>Moody’s Ratings, one of the major global credit review companies, has reaffirmed its highest credit rating for Idaho while saying the state’s credit “outlook remains stable.” This good fiscal news is a reflection of Idaho’s sound fiscal management and helps save money for taxpayers by keeping government borrowing costs low with favorable terms. According to Moody’s October 9 update : “Idaho's Aaa issuer rating reflects its strong credit position supported by continued higher than average...</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 18:03:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF opinion piece: Voters should be skeptical of $350 million bond for APS</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-opinion-piece-voters-should-be-skeptical-of-350-million-bond-for-aps/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following appeared in the Albuquerque Journal on Sunday October 12, 2025. On this fall’s ballots in addition to votes for mayor, city council and school board, local voters will be asked to decide on a $350 million bond for Albuquerque Public Schools. These bonds (another name for debt which is typically used to pay [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-opinion-piece-voters-should-be-skeptical-of-350-million-bond-for-aps/"&gt;RGF opinion piece: Voters should be skeptical of $350 million bond for APS&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 18:49:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Political Targeting? The Valley School District’s Purported Vendetta Against Levy Opponents</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/political-targeting-the-valley-school-districts-purported-vendetta-against-levy-opponents/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/political-targeting-the-valley-school-districts-purported-vendetta-against-levy-opponents/" rel="nofollow" title="Political Targeting? The Valley School District’s Purported Vendetta Against Levy Opponents"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/Article-Headers-2025-10-13T182323.858.png" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Nothing says small-town charm quite like political retaliation. On one side, we have the Valley School District #262 trying to pass a $600,000 levy in the May 2025 election. On the other is a local farmer who dared to oppose it. When the levy failed by a mere seven votes, things escalated quickly. Cue a [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 19:17:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Lower proficiency standards lead to phony student achievement gains</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/lower-proficiency-standards-phony-gains/</link><description>In the fable of the Emperor’s New Clothes, two con men convinced the Emperor they had woven a magnificent set of clothes that were invisible to incompetent people. Everyone went along with the ruse to avoid being considered stupid, but they knew he was naked. A similar con is being pulled by the Kansas State Board [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 22:02:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Dr. Steven Skultety: Freedom, Rights, and Civil Disagreement</title><link>https://empowerms.org/dr-steven-skultety-freedom-rights-and-civil-disagreement/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Dr. Steven Skultety: Freedom, Rights, and Civil Disagreement On this episode of the Empower Podcast, Grant Callen sits down with Dr. Steven Skultety, Director of the Declaration of Independence Center for the Study of American Freedom at the University of Mississippi. They explore the foundations of American democracy, the origins of rights, and why civil disagreement&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/dr-steven-skultety-freedom-rights-and-civil-disagreement/"&gt;Dr. Steven Skultety: Freedom, Rights, and Civil Disagreement&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 23:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] JMI Releases New Property Tax Reform Study</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/jmi-releases-new-property-tax-reform-study/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE October 15, 2025 CONTACT Logan Elizabeth Padgett lpadgett@jamesmadison.org (850) 386-3131 JMI Releases New Property Tax...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/jmi-releases-new-property-tax-reform-study/"&gt;JMI Releases New Property Tax Reform Study&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] AZ Trinity Arch Prep’s Jack Johnson Pannell on Educating Boys</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/az-trinity-arch-preps-jack-johnson-pannell-on-educating-boys/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In this week’s episode of The Learning Curve, co-hosts U-Arkansas Prof. Albert Cheng and Center for Public Schools’ Alisha Searcy interview Jack Johnson Pannell, founder and head of Trinity Arch Preparatory School for Boys in Phoenix. Mr. Pannell discusses his career as an educational leader, including founding a nationally recognized charter school in Baltimore, and shares how his background in the liberal arts and law has informed his approach to schooling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/az-trinity-arch-preps-jack-johnson-pannell-on-educating-boys/"&gt;AZ Trinity Arch Prep&amp;#8217;s Jack Johnson Pannell on Educating Boys&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 15:48:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Legal Advocates Ask Supreme Court to End Home Equity Seizures in Tax Foreclosures</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/legal-advocates-ask-supreme-court-to-end-home-equity-seizures-in-tax-foreclosures/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;BOSTON, MA — The Pioneer New England Legal Foundation (Legal Foundation), Greater Boston Legal Services (GBLS), and law firm Greenberg Traurig filed an amicus brief with the U.S. Supreme Court in support of homeowners in two Michigan cases that could determine how far governments can go in taking property for unpaid taxes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/legal-advocates-ask-supreme-court-to-end-home-equity-seizures-in-tax-foreclosures/"&gt;Legal Advocates Ask Supreme Court to End Home Equity Seizures in Tax Foreclosures &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 16:12:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] American Independence = Financial Independence</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/tax-budget/american-independence-financial-independence/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When America declared its independence nearly 250 years ago, it was not only a political revolution but also an assertion of self-reliance. The Founders of our country believed that Americans ought to be able to self-govern without dependence on a distant power. Today, that spirit of independence is under strain—not from a foreign monarch, but...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/tax-budget/american-independence-financial-independence/"&gt;American Independence = Financial Independence&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 16:31:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] 2026 Naples Annual Dinner</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/naples/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Join The James Madison Institute (JMI) in Naples, Florida, on February 17th, 2026, for the 2026 Naples Annual...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/naples/"&gt;2026 Naples Annual Dinner&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 16:34:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Red, White, &amp; Bluegrass</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/tallahassee/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Mark your calendars for our 2026 Red, White, &amp;#38; Bluegrass event in Tallahassee. Join us January 14, 2025...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/tallahassee/"&gt;Red, White, &amp;amp; Bluegrass&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 16:38:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF provides comments in support of unlocking new water supplies for New Mexicans</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-provides-comments-in-support-of-unlocking-new-water-supplies-for-new-mexicans/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;They say &amp;#8220;agua es vida&amp;#8221; in New Mexico (water is life). In the desert southwest water is critical to human flourishing and the broader economy of the state and region. So, when we were presented with an opportunity to put water that is produced alongside oil and gas, we had only one question: &amp;#8220;Is it [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-provides-comments-in-support-of-unlocking-new-water-supplies-for-new-mexicans/"&gt;RGF provides comments in support of unlocking new water supplies for New Mexicans&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 16:38:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Inside Connecticut’s Amistad Awards: The Activist Network Behind the Ceremony</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/10/15/inside-connecticuts-amistad-awards-the-activist-network-behind-the-ceremony/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="984" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/Screenshot-2025-10-15-at-3.24.12-PM.png" width="1578" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Connecticut People’s World Committee — a group aligned with the Communist Party USA — has announced the recipients of its annual Amistad Awards, to be presented on December 14 [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/10/15/inside-connecticuts-amistad-awards-the-activist-network-behind-the-ceremony/"&gt;Inside Connecticut’s Amistad Awards: The Activist Network Behind the Ceremony&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 19:35:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG: New School Choice Enrollment Numbers Show Growth Slowing Statewide</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-new-school-choice-enrollment-numbers-show-growth-slowing-statewide/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;IRG: New School Choice Enrollment Numbers Show Growth Slowing Statewide Baby bust rears its head in school enrollment numbers Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government (IRG) released the following statement following the Department of Public Instruction’s release of 2025-2026 school choice and charter enrollment numbers. WHY IT MATTERS: While traditional schools continue to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-new-school-choice-enrollment-numbers-show-growth-slowing-statewide/"&gt;IRG: New School Choice Enrollment Numbers Show Growth Slowing Statewide&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 19:51:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] It Is Time to Tackle Idaho’s Public Spending Addiction</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/it-is-time-to-tackle-idahos-public-spending-addiction/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/it-is-time-to-tackle-idahos-public-spending-addiction/" rel="nofollow" title="It Is Time to Tackle Idaho’s Public Spending Addiction"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/Article-Headers-2025-10-15T135522.813.png" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Idaho officials are addicted. The standard dictionary definition of addiction is “a strong inclination to do, use, or indulge in something repeatedly,” and there is nothing that matches this description more than the Idaho state government’s inability to curb the growth of spending.&amp;#160; Mind you, it is not just Idaho. The shutdown of the federal [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 20:19:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Considering Coal-to-Nuclear Transitions in Missouri</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/energy/considering-coal-to-nuclear-transitions-in-missouri/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Kansas’s Department of Commerce and Evergy (the state’s largest utility) are partnering with TerraPower, a leading nuclear developer, to explore [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/energy/considering-coal-to-nuclear-transitions-in-missouri/"&gt;Considering Coal-to-Nuclear Transitions in Missouri&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 21:30:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Randy Watson’s legacy: 10 years of declining college readiness on ACT</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/watson-10-years-declining-college-readiness-act/</link><description>Kansas Education Commissioner Randy Watson took office in July of 2015 and immediately began de-emphasizing academic improvement in favor of social-emotional learning (SEL). He convinced the State Board of Education to adopt his gimmicky “Kansans Can” program, featuring a tagline of “Kansas leads the world in the success of each student.” At the time of [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 12:06:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Why we focus on economic growth</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/10/why-we-focus-on-economic-growth/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When testifying at the Statehouse, Josiah Bartlett Center staff are sometimes surprised by questions legislators ask. We don’t expect lawmakers to know the research on how certain policies worked or didn’t work in other states. Finding and presenting that information is our job. The surprises come when lawmakers ask more basic questions. We are fairly [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/10/why-we-focus-on-economic-growth/"&gt;Why we focus on economic growth&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 13:48:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Accountability and Action: The Path to Safer Communities</title><link>https://empowerms.org/accountability-and-action-the-path-to-safer-communities/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This past weekend, our state was rocked by a wave of violent crime. Over the course of twenty-four hours, five shootings claimed the lives of at least nine Mississippians. While these horrific acts do not appear to be connected, they are alarming nevertheless. Words like horrific, tragic, and avoidable all come to mind. First and&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/accountability-and-action-the-path-to-safer-communities/"&gt;Accountability and Action: The Path to Safer Communities&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 14:16:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Wisconsin Artist Battles Utility in Landmark Property Rights Case</title><link>https://will-law.org/wisconsin-artist-battles-utility-in-landmark-property-rights-case/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL issued a warning to the American Transmission Company (ATC) regarding its plan to build a massive new transmission line across the property of Tom and Mary Uttech in Saukville, WI, for the sole benefit of a new AI data center in Port Washington, WI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/wisconsin-artist-battles-utility-in-landmark-property-rights-case/"&gt;Wisconsin Artist Battles Utility in Landmark Property Rights Case&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 14:46:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] How to reform the property tax to protect taxpayers and services</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/how-to-reform-wyoming-s-property-tax-to-protect-taxpayers-and-services</link><description>Calls to abolish the property tax are growing louder across the country as elected representatives respond to constituents' increasing concerns about rising property assessments and tax bills. Wyoming is one of the states currently having this debate. What happens there next could be a lesson for lawmakers in other states. In the last year, Wyoming legislators passed stopgap measures to lower residents’ bills in the short term. The lack of meaningful and long-term reform, plus increasing...</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 15:55:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] A Winning Playbook: How Louisiana can Continue to Attract the Tech Industry</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/a-winning-playbook-how-louisiana-can-continue-to-attract-the-tech-industry/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Anyone following the drama of football season can attest to the fact that recruiting never stops. Savvy coaches and general managers understand that every game, press conference, and handshake is helping potential players answer the question of “which team do I want to play for?” In Louisiana, a state known for championship football teams and...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/a-winning-playbook-how-louisiana-can-continue-to-attract-the-tech-industry/"&gt;A Winning Playbook: How Louisiana can Continue to Attract the Tech Industry&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 17:11:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] The Up-Down Coalition Is Turning Red</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/the-up-down-coalition-is-turning-red/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=the-up-down-coalition-is-turning-red</link><description>&lt;p&gt;While the progressive candidates in America rely on millions of college-educated liberals as its base, it depends on two additional sources of political power. The loss of either one could be fatal to the party’s ability to win elections. The first is America’s financial elites, providing money and institutional support. The second is America’s low-income...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/the-up-down-coalition-is-turning-red/"&gt;The Up-Down Coalition Is Turning Red&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 17:36:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Reform First, Dollars Second</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/free-market-reform/reform-first-dollars-second/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;If policymakers were worried about the One Big Beautiful Bill’s impact on healthcare in Missouri, they may soon find it’s [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/free-market-reform/reform-first-dollars-second/"&gt;Reform First, Dollars Second&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 19:45:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Arkansas teachers union’s dues revenue drops 36 percent in one year</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/labor/arkansas-teachers-unions-dues-revenue-drops-36-percent-in-one-year/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A new Freedom Foundation analysis shows the Arkansas Education Association's annual revenue from member dues plummeted 36 percent after school districts stopped deducting dues from teachers' paychecks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/labor/arkansas-teachers-unions-dues-revenue-drops-36-percent-in-one-year/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Arkansas teachers union’s dues revenue drops 36 percent in one year&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 19:50:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] DOH Ducks a Simple Question on Covid in Nursing Homes</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/doh-ducks-a-simple-question-on-covid-in-nursing-homes/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Five years after the coronavirus pandemic, the state Department of Health is pleading ignorance about one of its most hotly....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/doh-ducks-a-simple-question-on-covid-in-nursing-homes/"&gt;DOH Ducks a Simple Question on Covid in Nursing Homes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 20:05:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Bill would use tax credit to lower cost barrier to new nuclear in Wisconsin</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/bill-would-use-tax-credit-to-lower-cost-barrier-to-new-nuclear-in-wisconsin/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New nuclear measure in Wisconsin includes shifts in state’s priorities in law for ‘only way we keep lights on.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/bill-would-use-tax-credit-to-lower-cost-barrier-to-new-nuclear-in-wisconsin/"&gt;Bill would use tax credit to lower cost barrier to new nuclear in Wisconsin&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 22:06:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Claims of data center water use are laughably wrong</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/claims-of-data-center-water-use-are-laughably-wrong/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The biggest data centers planned for Wisconsin are not a threat to local water systems or to Lake Michigan — a fact opponents either can’t believe or won’t admit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/claims-of-data-center-water-use-are-laughably-wrong/"&gt;Claims of data center water use are laughably wrong&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 22:06:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] NH voters want to cut regulations to build more housing, polling confirms</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/10/nh-voters-want-to-cut-regulations-to-build-more-housing-polling-confirms/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On New Hampshire’s top economic issue, a broad consensus has formed. Voters want more housing, and they want government to make it easier to build, according to new polling. St. Anselm College’s 2025 statewide housing survey, released this week, shows that opinions have settled overwhelmingly in favor of deregulating the housing market to let builders [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/10/nh-voters-want-to-cut-regulations-to-build-more-housing-polling-confirms/"&gt;NH voters want to cut regulations to build more housing, polling confirms&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 11:30:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Government Shouldn’t Pick Winners and Losers—Especially on Your Utility Bill</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/government-shouldnt-pick-winners-and-losers/</link><description>Panasonic’s special rate deal shows how corporate favoritism quietly shifts costs onto Kansans &amp;#160; Kansas taxpayers have already given Panasonic nearly $829 million in incentives to build its massive electric-vehicle battery plant in De Soto—the largest economic-development deal in state history. Now, as Sunflower State Journal reports, Kansans could soon be paying again—this time through [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 15:00:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Listen: Charter school analysis on WGAN</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/listen-charter-school-analysis-on-wgan/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Policy analyst, Harris Van Pate, joined the WGAN Morning News to discuss Maine Policy&amp;#8217;s new report, Accountability Gap, which measures charter schools and public schools using the accountability metrics used to judge the success of charter schools and renew their charters. The report found that if all public schools had to abide by the standards [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/listen-charter-school-analysis-on-wgan/"&gt;Listen: Charter school analysis on WGAN&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 15:54:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] The Most Watched AG Debate in History?</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/the-most-watched-ag-debate-in-history/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="720" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/Virgina-AG-Debate.jpg" width="1280" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last night’s only debate for Attorney General of Virginia between incumbent AG Jason Miyares and Delegate Jay Jones was spirited, well-moderated, and covered dozens of key topics. Sadly, the debate occurred after over 600,000 Virginians had already cast their ballots and before over half of those early voters had heard of the news of the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/the-most-watched-ag-debate-in-history/"&gt;The Most Watched AG Debate in History?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 18:16:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Listen: Charter &amp; Public School Standards on WVOM</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/listen-charter-public-school-standards-on-wvom/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Policy analyst, Harris Van Pate, joined the George Hale Ric Tyler Show on WVOM to discuss the double standard in accountability for charter schools and public schools as identified in Maine Policy&amp;#8217;s new research, Accountability Gap. Listen to the full segment below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/listen-charter-public-school-standards-on-wvom/"&gt;Listen: Charter &amp;amp; Public School Standards on WVOM&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 19:10:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Connecticut’s Homeschool Debate: What the Facts Actually Show</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/10/17/connecticuts-homeschool-debate-what-the-facts-actually-show/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the wake of the tragic discovery of an 11-year-old girl’s body in New Britain, many Connecticut officials and commentators rushed to frame the incident as evidence of a “homeschooling [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/10/17/connecticuts-homeschool-debate-what-the-facts-actually-show/"&gt;Connecticut’s Homeschool Debate: What the Facts Actually Show &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 20:51:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Winners &amp; Losers: Peacemaker, Icebreakers &amp; Ballot Bans</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/winners-losers-peacemaker-icebreakers-ballot-bans/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Every Friday morning, I join the Cardle &amp;#38; Wooley Show on Talk 1370 Radio in Austin to announce the week’s Winners &amp;#38; Losers. In a week marked by an historic peace accord in the Middle East and Portland, Oregon’s naked bike ride to protest the National Guard in their city, here’s who made the list: WINNER:...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/winners-losers-peacemaker-icebreakers-ballot-bans/"&gt;Winners &amp; Losers: Peacemaker, Icebreakers &amp; Ballot Bans &lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 21:56:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Behind the Rallies, Slogans and Rhetoric, Clean Virginia Pushes Its Energy Agenda with Voters</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/behind-the-rallies-slogans-and-rhetoric-clean-virginia-pushes-its-energy-agenda-with-voters/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="720" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/Energy-Bills.jpg" width="1280" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The energy bills are…” shouts the emcee on the stage. “Too damn high,” comes the immediate response from a crowded meeting room in the east end of Richmond, October 16. That call and response mantra constantly punctuated a long and creative presentation on Virginia’s energy dilemma from the point of view of the activist group Clean Virginia. The point of view [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/behind-the-rallies-slogans-and-rhetoric-clean-virginia-pushes-its-energy-agenda-with-voters/"&gt;Behind the Rallies, Slogans and Rhetoric, Clean Virginia Pushes Its Energy Agenda with Voters&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 21:22:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] New Statewide Ad Calls Out Governor Shapiro For Budget Impasse</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/10/19/new-statewide-ad-end-the-impasse-governor-shapiro/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Harrisburg, Pa., October 19, 2025 —&amp;#160;The Commonwealth Foundation has launched a new statewide ad calling on Gov. Josh Shapiro to end the state budget impasse by getting to work negotiating a bipartisan, fiscally responsible compromise that protects Pennsylvania taxpayers. Pennsylvania remains the only state in the nation without a state budget. The new ad calls [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/10/19/new-statewide-ad-end-the-impasse-governor-shapiro/"&gt;New Statewide Ad Calls Out Governor Shapiro For Budget Impasse&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 23:35:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Road funding is now at record levels</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/road-funding-is-now-at-record-levels</link><description>Mostly without raising taxes</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] WILL Warns States About New Risks Federal Highway Funding if Woke Policies Remain</title><link>https://will-law.org/will-warns-states-about-new-risks-federal-highway-funding-if-woke-policies-remain/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL, a conservative law firm with a proven track record of winning discrimination-in-contracting cases, is threatening legal action against Illinois Governor JB Pritzker’s Department of Transportation (ILDOT) as well as several other states who are refusing to comply with a recent Trump Administration directive to suspend all race- and gender quotas in the federally funded “Disadvantaged Business Enterprise” (DBE) program.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/will-warns-states-about-new-risks-federal-highway-funding-if-woke-policies-remain/"&gt;WILL Warns States About New Risks Federal Highway Funding if Woke Policies Remain&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 12:58:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] WILL Warns Gov. Pritzker Not to Jeopardize Billions in Federal Highway Funding</title><link>https://will-law.org/will-warns-gov-pritzker-not-to-jeopardize-billions-in-federal-highway-funding/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL, a conservative law firm with a proven track record of winning discrimination-in-contracting cases, is threatening legal action against Illinois Governor JB Pritzker’s Department of Transportation (ILDOT).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/will-warns-gov-pritzker-not-to-jeopardize-billions-in-federal-highway-funding/"&gt;WILL Warns Gov. Pritzker Not to Jeopardize Billions in Federal Highway Funding&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 14:29:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] State Ownership Isn’t the Cure for Connecticut’s Health Care Challenges</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/10/20/state-ownership-isnt-the-cure-for-connecticuts-health-care-challenges/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="1696" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/shutterstock_1913716633-scaled.jpg" width="2560" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connecticut is again poised to take a costly step deeper into the business of health care.   On Oct. 14, the CT Mirror reported the state is preparing to borrow nearly [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/10/20/state-ownership-isnt-the-cure-for-connecticuts-health-care-challenges/"&gt;State Ownership Isn’t the Cure for Connecticut’s Health Care Challenges&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 14:50:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Idaho cities are experimenting with AI tools to improve services</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/idaho-cities-are-experimenting-with-ai-tools-to-improve-services</link><description>Discussions about government use of artificial intelligence (AI) often begin with a simple question: "Is this tool going to help the taxpayer that is funding it, or is it just another fad?” Municipalities across the Treasure Valley in Idaho are already experimenting with AI  in small, practical ways, whether it is admin efficiency, search tool utilization, or for Garden City “googly eyes” experiments. The main question we are all wondering is, can these AI tools save government employees...</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 15:00:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Bond supporters say they ‘won’t raise taxes,’ but the claim doesn’t add up</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/bond-supporters-say-they-wont-raise-taxes-but-the-claim-doesnt-add-up-2/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Bond supporters say they &amp;#8216;won&amp;#8217;t raise taxes,&amp;#8217; but the claim doesn&amp;#8217;t add up" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/bonds-600x314.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Across Iowa, local officials are asking voters to approve more than $1 billion in new bond debt this November — often with the soothing assurance that these projects “won’t raise your taxes.” But that promise deserves scrutiny. It’s like paying off your car loan, immediately financing the purchase of a new one, and insisting it doesn’t cost more — just because the monthly payment stayed the same. What about the savings you could have enjoyed if you hadn’t taken on new debt at all?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/bond-supporters-say-they-wont-raise-taxes-but-the-claim-doesnt-add-up-2/"&gt;Bond supporters say they &amp;#8216;won&amp;#8217;t raise taxes,&amp;#8217; but the claim doesn&amp;#8217;t add up&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 15:15:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] An Eerie Silence About the State of Education in New York</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/an-eerie-silence-about-the-state-of-education-in-new-york/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A recent analysis by National Assessment of Educational Progress (NAEP) lamented the declining state of U.S. education by highlighting how....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/an-eerie-silence-about-the-state-of-education-in-new-york/"&gt;An Eerie Silence About the State of Education in New York&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 15:57:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] The Future of Federal Education Policy with Christy Wolfe</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/education/the-future-of-federal-education-policy-with-christy-wolfe/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Susan Pendergrass speaks with Christy Wolfe, director of K–12 policy at the Bipartisan Policy Center, about major shifts in federal [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/education/the-future-of-federal-education-policy-with-christy-wolfe/"&gt;The Future of Federal Education Policy with Christy Wolfe&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 17:10:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Pelican Center for Justice Challenges Unconstitutional Mandates on Faith-Based Prekindergarten Programs in Louisiana</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/legal-regulatory/pelican-center-for-justice-challenges-unconstitutional-mandates-on-faith-based-prekindergarten-programs-in-louisiana/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On October 20, the Pelican Institute for Public Policy and Center for American Rights filed a lawsuit on behalf of Providence Classical Academy, The Dunham School, and parents Joshua and Claire Cox, in the U.S. District Court for the Western District of Louisiana (Shreveport Division), challenging Act 409 of the 2025 Regular Session which imposes...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/legal-regulatory/pelican-center-for-justice-challenges-unconstitutional-mandates-on-faith-based-prekindergarten-programs-in-louisiana/"&gt;Pelican Center for Justice Challenges Unconstitutional Mandates on Faith-Based Prekindergarten Programs in Louisiana&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 18:10:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/10/14197/</link><description>The Indiana Daily Student, RIP? “Congress shall make no law respecting an establishment of religion, or prohibiting the free exercise thereof; or abridging the freedom of speech, or of the press . . .” — First Amendment of the U.S. Constitution THE FIRST AMENDMENT is written as clearly as humanly possible. That won’t matter, of course,&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/10/14197/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 19:47:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Pennsylvania Sees Record Opt-Outs — Highest Since 2022</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/pennsylvania-sees-record-opt-outs-highest-since-2022/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;September marked the highest number of opt-outs in a single month since May 2022, with opt-outs surging by nearly 40 percent compared to previous months. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/pennsylvania-sees-record-opt-outs-highest-since-2022/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Pennsylvania Sees Record Opt-Outs — Highest Since 2022&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 20:42:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/10/the-outstater-295/</link><description>Millions Gather To Express Total Ignorance About Political System Regarding this weekend&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8220;No Kings&amp;#8221; marches, we cannot do better than the satirical Babylon Bee: &amp;#8220;Millions of Americans took to the streets today in order to express to the world their total and absolute ignorance about the political system they live in. &amp;#8220;Several major cities including&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/10/the-outstater-295/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 20:49:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] States win in corporate welfare pact</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/states-win-in-corporate-welfare-pact</link><description>Other states should agree with Michigan to stop offering selective business subsidies</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Try, Try Again: Local Governments Bring Back Bond Proposals</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/try-try-again-local-governments-bring-back-bond-proposals/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Try, Try Again: Local Governments Bring Back Bond Proposals" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/try-fail-600x300.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet despite the high cost of borrowing, 55 bond proposals totaling more than $1.6 billion will be on the ballot for Iowa voters this November.  Even more striking in this interest rate environment is that 18 local governments — 15 school districts, two counties, and one community college — are returning with repeat bond requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/try-try-again-local-governments-bring-back-bond-proposals/"&gt;Try, Try Again: Local Governments Bring Back Bond Proposals&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 12:52:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Time to Rely Less on D.C.? Nebraska’s Path to Independence</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/time-to-rely-less-on-d-c-nebraskas-path-to-independence/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As the federal debt approaches $38 trillion, the federal government is shut down, and some states are asking whether it might be time to get control of their dependence on federal funding and declare a greater level of independence.  &amp;#8220;Federalism&amp;#8221; is the foundation of our system of government, establishing a multi-layered approach to divided and...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/time-to-rely-less-on-d-c-nebraskas-path-to-independence/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Time to Rely Less on D.C.? Nebraska’s Path to Independence&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 12:54:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] NJ ED REPORT: New Report: Most NJ School Districts Lack Smart Student-Centered Strategic Plans</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/10/nj-ed-report-new-report-most-nj-school-districts-lack-smart-student-centered-strategic-plans/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New Report: Most NJ School Districts Lack Smart Student-Centered Strategic Plans By  NJER Newsroom  October 15, 2025 Study of 50 district [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/10/nj-ed-report-new-report-most-nj-school-districts-lack-smart-student-centered-strategic-plans/"&gt;NJ ED REPORT: New Report: Most NJ School Districts Lack Smart Student-Centered Strategic Plans&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 13:12:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] WALL STREET JOURNAL: A Teachers Union Candidate Took My Money and Ran for Office</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/10/wall-street-journal-a-teachers-union-candidate-took-my-money-and-ran-for-office/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A Teachers Union Candidate Took My Money and Ran for Office By Marie Dupont Oct. 17, 2025 As the New [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/10/wall-street-journal-a-teachers-union-candidate-took-my-money-and-ran-for-office/"&gt;WALL STREET JOURNAL: A Teachers Union Candidate Took My Money and Ran for Office&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 13:16:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Blueprint for Federalism: Goldwater Launches Civics Initiative to Add the 10th Amendment to State Constitutions</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/blueprint-for-federalism-goldwater-launches-civics-initiative-to-add-the-10th-amendment-to-state-constitutions/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;America’s founders wisely recognized it from the beginning—the best chance for a sprawling young republic to survive would be for..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/blueprint-for-federalism-goldwater-launches-civics-initiative-to-add-the-10th-amendment-to-state-constitutions/"&gt;Blueprint for Federalism: Goldwater Launches Civics Initiative to Add the 10th Amendment to State Constitutions  &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 15:43:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Decision Time for TriMet’s 82nd Ave. Road Diet</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/transportation/decision-time-for-trimets-82nd-ave-road-diet/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By John A. Charles, Jr. TriMet’s “Road Diet” planned for 82nd Avenue is...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/transportation/decision-time-for-trimets-82nd-ave-road-diet/"&gt;Decision Time for TriMet’s 82nd Ave. Road Diet&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 17:34:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] UC Unions Exposed: Fear, Intimidation, and a Growing Antisemitism Problem</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/uc-unions-exposed-fear-intimidation-and-a-growing-antisemitism-problem/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Freedom Foundation canvassers have been on University of California-Los Angeles (UCLA) campuses talking with employees about their rights, and what we’ve seen from union leadership is disturbing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/uc-unions-exposed-fear-intimidation-and-a-growing-antisemitism-problem/" rel="nofollow"&gt;UC Unions Exposed: Fear, Intimidation, and a Growing Antisemitism Problem&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 18:28:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Big hospitals are gaming the rural healthcare system, and Congress is helping</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/big-hospitals-are-gaming-the-rural-healthcare-system-and-congress-is-helping/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Congress has handed hospital giants a new line of taxpayer-funded credit. This summer, Congress included a $50 billion “rural health fund” in the multitrillion-dollar One Big Beautiful Bill Act. The fund’s supporters are touting it as a lifeline for struggling community hospitals. But small-town emergency rooms will not be the primary beneficiaries. Instead, politically connected [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/big-hospitals-are-gaming-the-rural-healthcare-system-and-congress-is-helping/"&gt;Big hospitals are gaming the rural healthcare system, and Congress is helping&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 19:03:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Legalize more mixed-use zoning to expand Big Isle housing options</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/10/legalize-more-mixed-use-zoning-to-expand-big-isle-housing-options/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Hawai’i County Council Committee on Oct. 22, 2025._____________ Oct. 22, 2025, 9 a.m.Hawai‘i County Council Chambers in Hilo To: Hawai‘i County Council       Holeka Goro Inaba, Chair       Dennis “Fresh” Onishi, Vice Chair From: Grassroot Institute of Hawaii            Jonathan Helton, Policy Analyst [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/10/legalize-more-mixed-use-zoning-to-expand-big-isle-housing-options/"&gt;Legalize more mixed-use zoning to expand Big Isle housing options&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 19:06:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Remove ‘noncommercial’ wording from backyard henneries measure</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/10/remove-noncommercial-wording-from-backyard-henneries-measure/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Hawai’i County Council Committee on Oct. 22, 2025._____________ Oct. 22, 2025, 9 a.m.Hawai‘i County Council Chambers in Hilo To: Hawai‘i County Council       Holeka Goro Inaba, Chair       Dennis “Fresh” Onishi, Vice Chair From: Grassroot Institute of Hawaii            Jonathan Helton, Policy Analyst RE: Bill [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/10/remove-noncommercial-wording-from-backyard-henneries-measure/"&gt;Remove &amp;#8216;noncommercial&amp;#8217; wording from backyard henneries measure&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 19:13:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] The Federal Shutdown Explained: What it Means for Maine</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/the-federal-shutdown-explained-what-it-means-for-maine/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Congress isn’t known as the place for bipartisan cooperation, but since October 1, inter-party arguing has led to a shutdown of the federal government. This has caused the closing of offices, the suspension of services, and the placing of hundreds of thousands of workers on furlough. The reason, as usual, is infuriating but straightforward: Congress [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/the-federal-shutdown-explained-what-it-means-for-maine/"&gt;The Federal Shutdown Explained: What it Means for Maine&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 19:26:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Leftists Overwhelm Small Farm With Death Threats For Hosting Conservative Think Tank</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/leftists-overwhelm-small-farm-with-death-threats-for-hosting-conservative-think-tank/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;If Austin’s farm fiasco teaches us anything, it’s that the left’s words aren’t harmless — they’re harbingers of dehumanization and violence. In my Oct. 2 article for The Federalist, I detailed a chilling 2,500 percent spike in indexed internet content pairing “Trump” with “fascist” over the past 10 years, with the biggest surge happening since mid-2024. This...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/leftists-overwhelm-small-farm-with-death-threats-for-hosting-conservative-think-tank/"&gt;Leftists Overwhelm Small Farm With Death Threats For Hosting Conservative Think Tank&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 20:15:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Hospital Strikes Show Why Healthcare Is NOT a Right</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/hospital-strikes-show-why-healthcare-is-not-a-right/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=hospital-strikes-show-why-healthcare-is-not-a-right</link><description>&lt;p&gt;During this month’s government shutdown, Bernie Sanders has been repeating the standard Progressive shibboleth: “Healthcare is a Right!” While this slogan appears to be sufficient to silence opposition, it does not receive sufficient examination. But as this month’s strike at Kaiser Permanente shows, union rights, another major Progressive cause, can and does trump the alleged...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/hospital-strikes-show-why-healthcare-is-not-a-right/"&gt;Hospital Strikes Show Why Healthcare Is NOT a Right&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 22:51:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Kent lauds Lahaina recovery efforts, laments Jones Act and Honolulu rail</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/10/kent-lauds-lahaina-recovery-efforts-laments-jones-act-and-honolulu-rail/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Efforts by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii to speed up the rebuilding of Lahaina are paying off, Grassroot Executive Vice President Joe Kent said on a recent episode of “The Rick Hamada Program” on KHVH News Radio 830. He said upwards of 500 building permits have been issued for Lahaina residents and businesses whose homes [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/10/kent-lauds-lahaina-recovery-efforts-laments-jones-act-and-honolulu-rail/"&gt;Kent lauds Lahaina recovery efforts, laments Jones Act and Honolulu rail&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 00:01:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] The PRI All Stars Election 2025 Preview</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/the-pri-all-stars-election-2025-preview/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This week, Tim Anaya and Matt Fleming preview the 2025 election, starting with a deep dive on Prop. 50, where we are just a few days before the election, and how the outcome will impact California policy and Gavin Newsom&amp;#8217;s political future. Plus, they discuss the wild campaign for Mayor of New York City and [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/the-pri-all-stars-election-2025-preview/"&gt;The PRI All Stars Election 2025 Preview&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 04:34:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Dem senators fear impact of No Kings furor</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/dem-senators-fear-impact-of-no-kings-backlash/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Ward Clark writes for RedState.com about one interesting reaction to the recent No Kings rallies. The &amp;#8220;No Kings&amp;#8221; weekend of absurdity has ended, and many of us are still pointing and laughing at videos of aging Boomer hippies and Gen Z nitwits, both of which groups are shrieking incoherently about &amp;#8220;tyranny&amp;#8221; when in a real...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/dem-senators-fear-impact-of-no-kings-backlash/"&gt;Dem senators fear impact of No Kings furor&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 09:42:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Free speech requires discomfort</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/free-speech-requires-discomfort</link><description>If you can’t handle normal college dorm squabbles, are you ready for grownup life?</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] It Was A Cruel, Cruel Summer For California Teens</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/it-was-a-cruel-cruel-summer-for-california-teens/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;California has a jobs problem. It’s not only failing to create them, it’s been destroying existing ones. Unemployment sits at 5.5%, the worst among the states. Only in the District of Columbia is the situation more grim. The jobless rate in the nation’s capital is 6%. This isn’t due to a run of bad luck. It’s the greasy residue of poor public policy that has produced a punishing regulatory [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/it-was-a-cruel-cruel-summer-for-california-teens/"&gt;It Was A Cruel, Cruel Summer For California Teens&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 10:00:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/10/the-outstater-296/</link><description>Oops, Budgets Require Priorities HERE&amp;#8217;S HOW&amp;#160;my city is going to meet the challenges of taxpayer-friendly changes in how property taxes are applied: It’s going to pretend nothing happened.&amp;#160; The Legislature has reformed the state&amp;#8217;s property tax system to provide relief for&amp;#160;homeowners and businesses through phased increases in homestead deductions, new tax credits and expanded business&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/10/the-outstater-296/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 13:49:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Accounting for Growth: Human capital and experience</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/accounting-for-growth-human-capital-and-experience/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I wrote about Minnesota&amp;#8217;s performance on the raw labor components of human capital; the number of people employed and the average number of hours each of them works annually. But I concluded that: This is only half of the story with human capital growth and, perhaps, not the most interesting half. Both of these...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/accounting-for-growth-human-capital-and-experience/"&gt;Accounting for Growth: Human capital and experience&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 14:00:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Empire Center Calls for Release of PPL Records</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/empire-center-calls-for-release-of-ppl-records/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Empire Center is calling on the Hochul administration to promptly release records of its spring 2024 communications with Public....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/empire-center-calls-for-release-of-ppl-records/"&gt;Empire Center Calls for Release of PPL Records&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 15:03:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] North Dakota is paying the price for Minnesota’s climate virtue</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/north-dakota-is-paying-the-price-for-minnesotas-climate-virtue/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;From the Minnesota Star Tribune, North Dakota wants to block Minnesota power lines in fight over clean energy. The fight is in front of a national energy regulator, North Dakota, Montana, Mississippi, Louisiana and Arkansas lodged their complaint in July with the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC). The states argued MISO’s calculations of benefits from...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/north-dakota-is-paying-the-price-for-minnesotas-climate-virtue/"&gt;North Dakota is paying the price for Minnesota&amp;#8217;s climate virtue&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 15:58:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Stanford’s Anna Lembke, MD, on Dopamine Nation &amp; Addiction</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/stanfords-anna-lembke-md-on-dopamine-nation-addiction/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In this week’s episode of The Learning Curve, co-hosts U-Arkansas Prof. Albert Cheng and Center for Public Schools’ Alisha Searcy interview Dr. Anna Lembke, MD, professor of psychiatry at the Stanford University School of Medicine, chief of the Stanford Addiction Medicine Dual Diagnosis Clinic, and author of the NYT bestselling book, Dopamine Nation: Finding Balance in the Age of Indulgence. Dr. Lembke explains how dopamine functions in the human brain and contributes to addictive behaviors. She explores how modern American life fuels a culture of addiction, drawing parallels between past waves of opioid and alcohol abuse and today’s dependence on the internet and smart phones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/stanfords-anna-lembke-md-on-dopamine-nation-addiction/"&gt;Stanford&amp;#8217;s Anna Lembke, MD, on Dopamine Nation &amp;#038; Addiction&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 16:16:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Just 18% of Chicago Teachers Union spending is on representing teachers</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/just-18-of-chicago-teachers-union-spending-is-on-representing-teachers/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Chicago Teachers Union’ own federal reporting shows its members are not priority No.1. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/just-18-of-chicago-teachers-union-spending-is-on-representing-teachers/"&gt;Just 18% of Chicago Teachers Union spending is on representing teachers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 17:39:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Be like Charlie</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/be-like-charlie/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Note: This is an abridged version of a talk I presented last month at an event called “A Tribute to Charlie Kirk, Champion of the Constitution.” The event was organized by Moms for Liberty and took place in Hillsborough, NC. Charlie Kirk and his killer represent two sides of an ancient philosophical, ethical, and political divide....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/be-like-charlie/"&gt;Be like Charlie&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 17:46:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Nuclear IS the answer</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/nuclear-is-the-answer/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Last week, the Pew Research Center issued a report on popular support for nuclear power, Support for expanding nuclear power is up in both parties since 2020 It&amp;#8217;s not just up, but stands at 59 percent overall support, the highest number tracked by Pew going back at least a decade. Even a majority of Democrats...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/nuclear-is-the-answer/"&gt;Nuclear IS the answer&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 17:48:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] Pennsylvania Senate Passes Budget Plan, RGGI Abrogation, Regulatory Reform</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/10/22/pennsylvania-senate-passes-budget-plan/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Harrisburg, Pa., October 22, 2025&amp;#160;— This week, the Pennsylvania Senate advanced legislation, including a spending bill (Senate Bill 160), that protects taxpayers and fosters economic growth. The commonwealth remains the only state in the country without an operating budget or stop gap plan. Now weeks into a federal government shutdown, Pennsylvania’s four-month-long impasse holds the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/10/22/pennsylvania-senate-passes-budget-plan/"&gt;Pennsylvania Senate Passes Budget Plan, RGGI Abrogation, Regulatory Reform&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 18:11:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] The disingenuous fearmongering of Josh Stein on Medicaid</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/the-disingenuous-fearmongering-of-josh-stein-on-medicaid/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Stein is putting care for North Carolina’s most needy at risk in a cynical ploy to score political points. We shouldn’t let him get away with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/the-disingenuous-fearmongering-of-josh-stein-on-medicaid/"&gt;The disingenuous fearmongering of Josh Stein on Medicaid&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 18:31:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Podcast: How This Pastor Rebuilt a Community—Without DEI</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/podcast-how-this-pastor-rebuilt-a-community-without-dei/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On Chicago’s South Side, the old O-Block once carried a reputation as the most dangerous stretch of pavement in the..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/podcast-how-this-pastor-rebuilt-a-community-without-dei/"&gt;Podcast: How This Pastor Rebuilt a Community—Without DEI&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 18:38:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG CIO Submits Request to DPI Seeking Teacher Licensing and Misconduct Scandal Public Records</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-cio-submits-request-to-dpi-seeking-teacher-licensing-and-misconduct-scandal-public-records/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government’s (IRG) Center for Investigative Oversight (CIO) submitted a public records request to the Wisconsin Department of Public Instruction (DPI), seeking to uncover details surrounding the Department’s handling of teacher licenses for educators accused of misconduct and grooming. Recent reporting by The Capital Times revealed serious concerns surrounding [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-cio-submits-request-to-dpi-seeking-teacher-licensing-and-misconduct-scandal-public-records/"&gt;IRG CIO Submits Request to DPI Seeking Teacher Licensing and Misconduct Scandal Public Records&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 19:07:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Efficiency, Consolidation, and Spending Control: DOGE Task Force’s Final Report</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/efficiency-consolidation-and-spending-control-doge-task-forces-final-report/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Efficiency, Consolidation, and Spending Control: DOGE Task Force’s Final Report" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/iowa-capitol-fall-600x302.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Governor Kim Reynolds’ effort to make government more efficient took another major step forward with the release of the final report from the Iowa Department of Government Efficiency (DOGE) Task Force. Announced during her 2025 Condition of the State Address, the Task Force was charged with finding new ways to streamline government, modernize operations, and ultimately reduce Iowa’s property tax burden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/efficiency-consolidation-and-spending-control-doge-task-forces-final-report/"&gt;Efficiency, Consolidation, and Spending Control: DOGE Task Force’s Final Report&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 19:13:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Using Microsoft, Salesforce, ChatGPT will cost more under Johnson’s Cloud Tax</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/using-microsoft-salesforce-chatgpt-will-cost-more-under-johnsons-cloud-tax/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Microsoft, Salesforce, ChatGPT, Amazon Web Services and Zoom would all come with higher prices under Chicago Mayor Brandon Johnson’s cloud tax. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/using-microsoft-salesforce-chatgpt-will-cost-more-under-johnsons-cloud-tax/"&gt;Using Microsoft, Salesforce, ChatGPT will cost more under Johnson’s Cloud Tax&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 19:26:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] New Jersey’s Bag Ban Backfired. Repeal It—and Cut Waste the Smart Way.</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/10/new-jerseys-bag-ban-backfired-repeal-it-and-cut-waste-the-smart-way/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Wells Winegar, Executive Director, New Jersey Policy Institute (NJPI) &amp;#160; Walk into any New Jersey kitchen and open the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/10/new-jerseys-bag-ban-backfired-repeal-it-and-cut-waste-the-smart-way/"&gt;New Jersey’s Bag Ban Backfired. Repeal It—and Cut Waste the Smart Way.&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 19:51:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] What Do Travis County Homeowners Pay in Property Taxes?</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/what-do-travis-county-homeowners-pay-in-property-taxes/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On Election Day, the city of Austin will ask voters to approve a massive 20% tax rate hike that many worry will spur further economic hardship, force families to flee, and grow government unnecessarily. Austin’s extraordinary ask—which appears to be the city’s largest-ever proposed tax increase—raises an obvious question: How much do Austinites currently pay...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/what-do-travis-county-homeowners-pay-in-property-taxes/"&gt;What Do Travis County Homeowners Pay in Property Taxes?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 20:53:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Goldwater Warns Wyoming Officials to Stop Illegal Taxpayer-Funded Electioneering</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/goldwater-warns-wyoming-officials-to-stop-illegal-taxpayer-funded-electioneering/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When leaders of the Evanston Parks and Recreation District in Uinta County, Wyoming determined that the community’s aging pool needed..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/goldwater-warns-wyoming-officials-to-stop-illegal-taxpayer-funded-electioneering/"&gt;Goldwater Warns Wyoming Officials to Stop Illegal Taxpayer-Funded Electioneering&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 21:25:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Every Illinois metro has fewer homes for sale than in 2018</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/every-illinois-metro-has-fewer-homes-for-sale-than-in-2018/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Illinois home prices have jumped 48% since 2018 while available housing inventory has plummeted across all 26 tracked metro areas, creating a housing crisis driven largely by restrictive zoning laws and the nation’s highest property taxes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/every-illinois-metro-has-fewer-homes-for-sale-than-in-2018/"&gt;Every Illinois metro has fewer homes for sale than in 2018&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 21:49:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Oil Extraction Reduces Methane Seepage</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/oil-extraction-reduces-methane-seepage/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=oil-extraction-reduces-methane-seepage</link><description>&lt;p&gt;An opinion piece in the Santa Barbara Independent, published last week, heralded the decision by the Santa Barbara County board of supervisors to phase out oil drilling, which as the authors put it, “will save lives, reduce air pollution, and help meet our climate goals.” Meanwhile, a study about to be publicly released by James Rector,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/oil-extraction-reduces-methane-seepage/"&gt;Oil Extraction Reduces Methane Seepage&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 22:39:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] If Lawmakers Are Trying to Defund Public Education, They Aren’t Very Good at It</title><link>https://empowerms.org/if-lawmakers-are-trying-to-defund-public-education-they-arent-very-good-at-it/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;You’ve probably heard the claim that Mississippi’s Republican leaders are “defunding” public education, and that school choice is just another way to siphon dollars away from public schools. But if that’s true, they’re doing a remarkably bad job of it.  Over the past decade, Mississippi has dramatically increased its investment in public education. According to&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/if-lawmakers-are-trying-to-defund-public-education-they-arent-very-good-at-it/"&gt;If Lawmakers Are Trying to Defund Public Education, They Aren’t Very Good at It&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 02:00:12 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>