<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>State-Policy Think-Tank Digest</title><link>https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml</link><description>Latest posts from free-market policy institutes across the U.S.</description><atom:link href="https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 12:05:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>[Foropportunity] Georgia candidates for governor should make welfare reform a top priority</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/georgia-candidates-for-governor-should-make-welfare-reform-a-top-priority/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/georgia-candidates-for-governor-should-make-welfare-reform-a-top-priority/"&gt;Georgia candidates for governor should make welfare reform a top priority&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 16:58:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] Empty Schools, Empty Wallets: How ESSER Pandemic Aid Led to More School Referenda</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/empty-schools-empty-wallets-how-esser-pandemic-aid-led-to-more-school-referenda/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Empty Schools, Empty Wallets: How ESSER Pandemic Aid Led to More School Referenda New IRG analysis reveals hiring sprees and poor financial decisions as Wisconsin schools fall behind national leaders Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government released a new report on Tuesday, “Empty Schools, Empty Wallets: What Happened to $1.49 Billion in ESSER [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/empty-schools-empty-wallets-how-esser-pandemic-aid-led-to-more-school-referenda/"&gt;Empty Schools, Empty Wallets: How ESSER Pandemic Aid Led to More School Referenda&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 15:02:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Massachusetts Subsidized Housing Inventory Update Shows Record Number of Communities Exceed Critical Threshold</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/massachusetts-subsidized-housing-inventory-update-shows-record-number-of-communities-exceed-critical-threshold/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This edition of The House Call explores the 2025 update to Massachusetts&amp;#8217; Subsidized Housing Inventory, showing a spike in the number of communities that have at least 10% of their housing stocks in the Inventory. It also explains the housing-related ballot questions that could...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/massachusetts-subsidized-housing-inventory-update-shows-record-number-of-communities-exceed-critical-threshold/"&gt;Massachusetts Subsidized Housing Inventory Update Shows Record Number of Communities Exceed Critical Threshold&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 20:35:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Commissioner Andy Gipson: Family, Food Security, and Mississippi’s Future</title><link>https://empowerms.org/commissioner-andy-gipson-family-food-security-and-mississippis-future/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Commissioner Andy Gipson: Family, Food Security, and Mississippi’s Future On this episode of The Empower Podcast, host Grant Callen sits down with Commissioner Andy Gipson—Mississippi’s Commissioner of Agriculture and Commerce, former state legislator, Baptist minister, cattleman, and announced candidate for governor. Gipson shares how his journey into public service began with a desire to secure&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/commissioner-andy-gipson-family-food-security-and-mississippis-future/"&gt;Commissioner Andy Gipson: Family, Food Security, and Mississippi’s Future&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:49:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Nebraska Zoning Permitting Process: Recommended Adjustments in Nebraska</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-zoning-permitting-process-recommended-adjustments-in-nebraska/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Nebraska’s zoning and permitting process for livestock operations is inconsistent, unpredictable, and varies widely from county to county. This report examines how Nebraska’s Conditional Use Permit (CUP) system works, the origins and goals of the Livestock Siting Assessment Matrix created under LB106, and why the Matrix remains underused nearly a decade later. Drawing on survey...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-zoning-permitting-process-recommended-adjustments-in-nebraska/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Nebraska Zoning Permitting Process: Recommended Adjustments in Nebraska&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 15:17:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] WILL Hires Associate Counsel to Grow Legal and Policy Capacity in Wisconsin and Beyond</title><link>https://will-law.org/will-hires-associate-counsel-to-grow-legal-and-policy-capacity-in-wisconsin-and-beyond/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL has announced Erin Gamble as our new Associate Counsel. Her hire reflects our organization’s commitment to fighting back against bureaucratic overreach in Wisconsin and across the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/will-hires-associate-counsel-to-grow-legal-and-policy-capacity-in-wisconsin-and-beyond/"&gt;WILL Hires Associate Counsel to Grow Legal and Policy Capacity in Wisconsin and Beyond&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 15:23:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Creating links that change lives: Georgia Center for Opportunity partners with Connect to Work GA</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/gco-partners-with-connect-to-work-ga/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This collaboration will help lift job seekers above the poverty line by providing opportunities for successful careers and upward mobility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/gco-partners-with-connect-to-work-ga/"&gt;Creating links that change lives: Georgia Center for Opportunity partners with Connect to Work GA&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 20:09:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Legislature balks as Evers demands millions for more food aid bureaucrats</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/legislature-balks-as-evers-demands-millions-for-more-food-aid-bureaucrats/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Gov. Tony Evers is pressing the Legislature for $70 million to process FoodShare applications to stave off federal penalties that could cost state taxpayers as much as $225 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/legislature-balks-as-evers-demands-millions-for-more-food-aid-bureaucrats/"&gt;Legislature balks as Evers demands millions for more food aid bureaucrats&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 21:58:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] “Fully Funded Schools” Are a Moving Goal Post</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/education/fully-funded-schools-are-a-moving-goal-post/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Kathryn Hickok How much money does it take to “fully fund” Oregon’s...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/education/fully-funded-schools-are-a-moving-goal-post/"&gt;“Fully Funded Schools” Are a Moving Goal Post&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 17:22:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Taxpayers Asked to Fund a Hospital Takeover They’re Not Allowed to See</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/12/12/taxpayers-asked-to-fund-a-hospital-takeover-theyre-not-allowed-to-see/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Connecticut lawmakers pushed the UConn Health hospital acquisition bill through the November special session — without a public hearing — it was clear transparency was not the priority.   [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/12/12/taxpayers-asked-to-fund-a-hospital-takeover-theyre-not-allowed-to-see/"&gt;Taxpayers Asked to Fund a Hospital Takeover They’re Not Allowed to See&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 18:13:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Would you invest in Massachusetts or New Hampshire?</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/12/would-you-invest-in-massachusetts-or-new-hampshire/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;If U.S. states were companies that traded on the stock market, the only New England state with a “buy” rating would probably be New Hampshire.  Massachusetts could be called “Big Blue,” the tradition-bound leader cruising on its prior reputation, but falling behind smaller upstarts that have embraced innovation and rapid growth.  New Hampshire would be [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/12/would-you-invest-in-massachusetts-or-new-hampshire/"&gt;Would you invest in Massachusetts or New Hampshire?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 21:10:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Arkansaspolicyfoundation] ARKANSAS GOV. SARAH HUCKABEE SANDERS &amp; STATE INCOME TAX CUTS</title><link>https://arkansaspolicyfoundation.org/arkansas-gov-sarah-huckabee-sanders-state-income-tax-cuts/</link><description>(4Q-2025) Arkansas Gov. Sarah Huckabee Sanders is the Natural State’s first female governor. Since taking office in January 2023, Sanders has also distinguished herself by advancing three separate reductions in Arkansas’ top income tax rate from 4.9 to 3.9 percent. The income tax was reduced from 7.0% to 6.9% in 2013 under Democratic Gov. Mike [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 14:33:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Todd Schaible: The Importance of Career and Technical Education in Tennessee Schools</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/todd-schaible-the-importance-of-career-technical-education-in-tennessee-schools/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=todd-schaible-the-importance-of-career-technical-education-in-tennessee-schools</link><description>By elevating CTE in Tennessee schools, we can increase support for employers and improve workforce readiness for students across the state.</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 15:34:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] Albuquerque Journal editorializes in defense of free speech, Rio Grande Foundation in “hoodie-gate”</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/albuquerque-journal-editorializes-in-defense-of-free-speech-rio-grande-foundation-in-hoodie-gate/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Rio Grande Foundation has received a great deal of publicity from all corners of Albuquerque&amp;#8217;s political scene due to our involvement in reporting on the I ♥ Tim Keller &amp;#8220;hoodies for the homeless&amp;#8221; effort. As we&amp;#8217;ve discussed at length here and in other locations the Mayor&amp;#8217;s campaign has reacted to our reporting and refusal [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/albuquerque-journal-editorializes-in-defense-of-free-speech-rio-grande-foundation-in-hoodie-gate/"&gt;Albuquerque Journal editorializes in defense of free speech, Rio Grande Foundation in &amp;#8220;hoodie-gate&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 16:53:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Mississippi's Free-Market Turnaround: A Model for America</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/mississippis-free-market-turnaround-a-model-for-america/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For decades, Mississippi has been the punchline in national discussions about economic performance - often ranked at the bottom in income, education, and opportunity. But something remarkable has happened in recent years: the Magnolia State is undergoing a genuine resurgence, driven not by federal handouts or gimmicks, but by principled free-market reforms. A major national [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/mississippis-free-market-turnaround-a-model-for-america/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi&amp;#039;s Free-Market Turnaround: A Model for America&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 21:13:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Enrollment and Employment: Is Tennessee Preparing K-12 Students for Today’s Economy?</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/enrollment-and-employment-is-tennessee-preparing-k-12-students-for-todays-economy/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=enrollment-and-employment-is-tennessee-preparing-k-12-students-for-todays-economy</link><description>Tennessee is doing well in providing Career and Technical Education (CTE) opportunities to students, but policymakers should recognize that improvements can be made.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 02:17:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Florida Politics: Bedrock, We Have a Problem</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/florida-politics-bedrock-we-have-a-problem/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A funny thing happened in the Legislature last week. While the House was holding an “AI Week” to...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/florida-politics-bedrock-we-have-a-problem/"&gt;Florida Politics: Bedrock, We Have a Problem&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 16:05:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Introducing EPIC: A New Investment in Solution Development</title><link>https://empowerms.org/introducing-epic-a-new-investment-in-solution-development/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For more than a decade, Empower Mississippi has worked to advance opportunity-focused policy at the State Capitol. Many of you have been partners in that work — meeting with lawmakers, investing financially, and championing reforms that help Mississippians live free, work meaningfully, and learn effectively. From the beginning, our advocacy has been grounded in research&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/introducing-epic-a-new-investment-in-solution-development/"&gt;Introducing EPIC: A New Investment in Solution Development&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 16:08:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Research Note: Changes in AI Regulations</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/research-note-changes-in-ai-regulations/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On Thursday, December 11, President Trump signed an executive order aimed at limiting state-level regulations on artificial intelligence (AI). The order is the latest in a series of efforts by the administration to centralize AI governance at the federal level. While it takes a distinctive approach, the order also introduces several practical and legal challenges.  ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/research-note-changes-in-ai-regulations/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Research Note: Changes in AI Regulations&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 15:29:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Pioneer New England Legal Foundation and Sullivan &amp; Worcester Sue Boston Over Retaliatory Tax Scheme</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/pioneer-legal-foundation-sullivan-worcester-sue-boston-over-retaliatory-tax-scheme/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Class action challenges city’s unlawful penalties against commercial taxpayers who exercised their right to appeal; seeks court intervention to end this retaliatory scheme in next fiscal year BOSTON, MA — Pioneer New England Legal Foundation (the Legal Foundation) and Sullivan &amp;#38; Worcester...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/pioneer-legal-foundation-sullivan-worcester-sue-boston-over-retaliatory-tax-scheme/"&gt;Pioneer New England Legal Foundation and Sullivan &amp;amp; Worcester Sue Boston Over Retaliatory Tax Scheme&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 18:43:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Youngkin Proposes More Tax Relief in His Final Budget, Which Still Sets New Records for Revenue, Spending</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/youngkin-proposes-more-tax-relief-in-his-final-budget-which-still-sets-new-records-for-revenue-spending/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="720" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Glenn-Youngkin-Closeup.jpg" width="1280" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Governor Glenn Youngkin has proposed that Virginia conform its tax rules to most of the changes in federal taxes adopted by Congress last summer, including recognizing a state tax deduction for tip income, overtime pay and interest payments on car loans. Those tax policy recommendations are part of the Republican’s final introduced state budget package, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/youngkin-proposes-more-tax-relief-in-his-final-budget-which-still-sets-new-records-for-revenue-spending/"&gt;Youngkin Proposes More Tax Relief in His Final Budget, Which Still Sets New Records for Revenue, Spending&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 06:49:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Florida Politics: The Ghost (Students) of Public School Future?</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/florida-politics-the-ghost-students-of-public-school-future/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;U.S. Secretary of Education Linda McMahon announced last week that her department plans to step up efforts to...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/florida-politics-the-ghost-students-of-public-school-future/"&gt;Florida Politics: The Ghost (Students) of Public School Future?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 14:49:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Marquette poll finds 80 percent of Americans trust government ‘only some of the time’ or ‘never’</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/marquette-poll-finds-80-percent-of-americans-trust-government-only-some-of-the-time-or-never/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Widespread, intergenerational skepticism of government is not merely the result of America’s increasingly cutthroat politics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/marquette-poll-finds-80-percent-of-americans-trust-government-only-some-of-the-time-or-never/"&gt;Marquette poll finds 80 percent of Americans trust government ‘only some of the time’ or ‘never’&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 16:58:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Santa aids Freedom Foundation outreach for another holiday season</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/santa-aids-freedom-foundation-outreach-for-another-holiday-season/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;To cut through the holiday and end-of-year chaos, we took a familiar twist. As they do every year, our outreach team members suited up as Santa Claus and his helpers to spark conversations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/santa-aids-freedom-foundation-outreach-for-another-holiday-season/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Santa aids Freedom Foundation outreach for another holiday season&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 21:05:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Albany’s School Speed Zone Camera Summer Daze</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/albanys-school-speed-zone-camera-summer-daze/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This fall, Governor Kathy Hochul signed into law bills containing the state’s permission for three cities — Mount Vernon, Schenectady....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/albanys-school-speed-zone-camera-summer-daze/"&gt;Albany’s School Speed Zone Camera Summer Daze&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 21:59:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] U.S. House defangs federal protection of gray wolves in Wisconsin</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/us-house-defangs-federal-protection-of-gray-wolves-in-wisconsin/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The U.S. House of Representatives Thursday passed a bill that would remove the state’s rapidly expanding and aggressive gray wolf population from the endangered species list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/us-house-defangs-federal-protection-of-gray-wolves-in-wisconsin/"&gt;U.S. House defangs federal protection of gray wolves in Wisconsin&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 22:32:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Ugly Math for Taxpayers</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/ugly-math-for-taxpayers/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=ugly-math-for-taxpayers</link><description>Taxpayer-funded lobbying (TFL) is nothing new in Tennessee, but it is almost universally frowned upon.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 22:52:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Senator Bill Cassidy Champions Pro-Worker Policies</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/legal-regulatory/senator-bill-cassidy-champions-pro-worker-policies/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Last month, United States Senator Bill Cassidy (R-Louisiana) and his colleagues on the Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions (HELP) Committee introduced a package of bills intended to modernize labor law, protect workers’ paychecks and privacy rights, and ensure that workers are empowered to decide whether their union is working for them. Sen. Cassidy explained...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/legal-regulatory/senator-bill-cassidy-champions-pro-worker-policies/"&gt;Senator Bill Cassidy Champions Pro-Worker Policies&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 23:00:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] The Public Purpose Program: California’s Hidden Tax Driving Up Utility Bills</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/17209-2/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=17209-2</link><description>&lt;p&gt;After several rate hikes implemented in the last few years alone, Californians are asking why their energy bills keep climbing when they use the same amount of electricity or gas. According to a 2023 report from the Transparency Foundation, residents of California pay up to 67% more for electricity and 30% more for natural gas...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/17209-2/"&gt;The Public Purpose Program: California’s Hidden Tax Driving Up Utility Bills&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 23:58:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Oregon’s “Prosperity Roadmap” Must Follow the Path of Liberty</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/economic-opportunity/oregons-prosperity-roadmap-must-follow-the-path-of-liberty/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Naomi Inman Early this December, Governor Tina Kotek’s newsroom unveiled “Oregon’s Prosperity...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/economic-opportunity/oregons-prosperity-roadmap-must-follow-the-path-of-liberty/"&gt;Oregon’s “Prosperity Roadmap” Must Follow the Path of Liberty&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 00:20:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Ninety New York Educators Receive $300k+ in Annual Pay</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/ninety-new-york-educators-receive-300k-in-annual-pay/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Ninety employees from New York’s school districts (outside New York City) received more than $300,000 during fiscal year 2025, according....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/ninety-new-york-educators-receive-300k-in-annual-pay/"&gt;Ninety New York Educators Receive $300k+ in Annual Pay&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 14:27:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] CDC Labels Minority Neighborhoods as “Vulnerable,” Encouraging the Spread of DEI Spending Nationwide</title><link>https://will-law.org/cdc-labels-minority-neighborhoods-as-vulnerable-encouraging-the-spread-of-dei-spending-nationwide/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In new findings provided to the Trump Administration’s Health and Human Services (HHS) agency, WILL has uncovered that the Center for Disease Control (CDC) uses a race-based criteria to declare whole communities and neighborhoods as “socially vulnerable” based on the number of minorities living there. Cities and states around the country rely on the CDC’s “social vulnerability index” (SVI) to allocate taxpayer funding for parks, drinking water, and disaster assistance.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/cdc-labels-minority-neighborhoods-as-vulnerable-encouraging-the-spread-of-dei-spending-nationwide/"&gt;CDC Labels Minority Neighborhoods as “Vulnerable,” Encouraging the Spread of DEI Spending Nationwide&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 18:18:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Housing Advocates Acknowledge New Law Shifts Authority Away from Towns</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/12/19/housing-advocates-acknowledge-new-law-shifts-authority-away-from-towns/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When H.B.8002 was passed during November’s special session, Democratic leaders and the bill’s supporters promoted it under the slogan “Towns Take the Lead.”   Signed into law by Gov. Ned [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/12/19/housing-advocates-acknowledge-new-law-shifts-authority-away-from-towns/"&gt;Housing Advocates Acknowledge New Law Shifts Authority Away from Towns&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 18:47:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Parental Freedom Update</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/parental-freedom-update/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=parental-freedom-update</link><description>&lt;p&gt;According to EdChoice, about 1.5 million students are now enrolled in voucher, educational savings account (ESA), and tax-credit programs, nearly doubling the number from just three years ago. Education Week reports that 30 states and the District of Columbia now have at least one private school choice program. Of those, 19 states have at least...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/parental-freedom-update/"&gt;Parental Freedom Update&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 19:05:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Louisiana’s Toxic Relationship with Lawsuit Abuse</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/legal-regulatory/lawsuit-abuse/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For years, lawsuit abuse has dragged down Louisiana’s competitiveness, acting as a hidden tax on families, consumers, and businesses across the state. Frivolous claims, inflated damage awards, and politically motivated lawsuits undermine justice and contribute to Louisiana’s long struggle with excessive and opportunistic litigation, especially against important job-creating industries like energy, manufacturing, and insurance. This...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/legal-regulatory/lawsuit-abuse/"&gt;Louisiana’s Toxic Relationship with Lawsuit Abuse&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 22:40:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Modernizing Financial Oversight: Senator Tim Scott’s STREAMLINE Act and the Case for Reducing Regulatory Burden</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/modernizing-financial-oversight-senator-tim-scotts-streamline-act-and-the-case-for-reducing-regulatory-burden/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Streamlining Transaction Reporting and Ensuring Anti-Money Laundering Improvements for a New Era Act (STREAMLINE Act), introduced by...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/modernizing-financial-oversight-senator-tim-scotts-streamline-act-and-the-case-for-reducing-regulatory-burden/"&gt;Modernizing Financial Oversight: Senator Tim Scott’s STREAMLINE Act and the Case for Reducing Regulatory Burden&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] California Home Care Workers Take on Union Abuse in Court</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/litigation/california-home-care-workers-take-on-union-abuse-in-court/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, the Freedom Foundation filed a class-action lawsuit against United Domestic Workers of America, AFSCME Local 3930 (UDW) on behalf of in-home supportive services (IHSS) workers across California. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/litigation/california-home-care-workers-take-on-union-abuse-in-court/" rel="nofollow"&gt;California Home Care Workers Take on Union Abuse in Court&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 15:50:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] In Case You Missed It: WILL Raised Key Voter Roll Concerns Ahead of DOJ Lawsuit</title><link>https://will-law.org/in-case-you-missed-it-will-raised-key-voter-roll-concerns-ahead-of-doj-lawsuit/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Department of Justice has filed a lawsuit against the Wisconsin Election Commission’s (WEC) for refusing to comply with their investigation into the state’s voter rolls. The request from USDOJ was for a copy of Wisconsin’s computerized registration list including information necessary to audit the list for ineligible voters, including driver’s license number and/or the last 4 digits of the social security number. The lawsuit also comes after an investigation from our organization released earlier this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/in-case-you-missed-it-will-raised-key-voter-roll-concerns-ahead-of-doj-lawsuit/"&gt;In Case You Missed It: WILL Raised Key Voter Roll Concerns Ahead of DOJ Lawsuit&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 15:57:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Bellows Trying to Block Routine Federal Oversight of Voter Lists</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/bellows-trying-to-block-routine-federal-oversight-of-voter-lists/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On December 12th, Secretary of State Shenna Bellows asked a federal court to throw out the U.S. Department of Justice lawsuit challenging Maine’s refusal to provide electronic copies of its voter registration list and basic information about how that list is maintained. This dispute isn’t about ballot secrecy or voter intimidation; it’s about whether states [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/bellows-trying-to-block-routine-federal-oversight-of-voter-lists/"&gt;Bellows Trying to Block Routine Federal Oversight of Voter Lists&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 16:16:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] Civic Foundations: Are we Properly Preparing the Next Generation of Citizens?</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/12/civic-foundations-are-we-properly-preparing-the-next-generation-of-citizens/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;by Aiden DeMarsey – Evesham Twp. Board of Ed. Member &amp;#38; NJPI Junior Education Policy Fellow The state of New [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/12/civic-foundations-are-we-properly-preparing-the-next-generation-of-citizens/"&gt;Civic Foundations: Are we Properly Preparing the Next Generation of Citizens?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 18:30:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] The Economic and Legal Risks of New Jersey’s Proposed Climate Superfund Act</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/12/the-economic-and-legal-risks-of-new-jerseys-proposed-climate-superfund-act/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Sean Barry, NJPI Junior Energy Policy Fellow For the past several months, New Jersey lawmakers have been considering Assembly [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/12/the-economic-and-legal-risks-of-new-jerseys-proposed-climate-superfund-act/"&gt;The Economic and Legal Risks of New Jersey’s Proposed Climate Superfund Act&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 18:35:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF discusses MLG National Guard deployment as they depart</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-discusses-mlg-national-guard-deployment-as-they-depart/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In a unique example of the Rio Grande Foundation being more positive about the Gov.&amp;#8217;s policy than the Gov. herself, the Rio Grande Foundation was asked to comment on whether MLG&amp;#8217;s deployment of the National Guard to Albuquerque was &amp;#8220;a disappointment.&amp;#8221; On the one hand, while we 100% agree with the Gov. that &amp;#8220;lax engagement [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-discusses-mlg-national-guard-deployment-as-they-depart/"&gt;RGF discusses MLG National Guard deployment as they depart&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 18:49:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] From Magna Carta to Mass Arrests: Britain’s Warning to America</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/from-magna-carta-to-mass-arrests-britains-warning-to-america/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Imagine facing arrest simply for posting sharp or critical comments online. Picture police at your door for expressing opposition to mass immigration. Envision a country where you could be imprisoned for years without a jury ever deciding your guilt. This isn't dystopian fiction - it's the reality unfolding in Britain today, my former home and [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/from-magna-carta-to-mass-arrests-britains-warning-to-america/" rel="nofollow"&gt;From Magna Carta to Mass Arrests: Britain’s Warning to America&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 20:01:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Trump’s Pause on Offshore Wind: A Chance for Reform, or a Step Towards Cancellation</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/trumps-pause-on-offshore-wind-a-chance-for-reform-or-a-step-towards-cancellation/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="720" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Trump-Offshore.jpg" width="1280" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;President Trump’s decision to suspend Dominion Energy’s massive Coastal Virginia Offshore Wind (CVOW) project is sure to stir up another gale of political fights across the Commonwealth.  While some will hail it as a triumph for fiscal and national security; others will see it as an assault on clean energy. Both sides are worthy of debate before [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/trumps-pause-on-offshore-wind-a-chance-for-reform-or-a-step-towards-cancellation/"&gt;Trump’s Pause on Offshore Wind: A Chance for Reform, or a Step Towards Cancellation&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 15:30:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Guest Editorial: The role of Credit Unions in Nebraska</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/guest-editorial-the-role-of-credit-unions-in-nebraska/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Credit unions have always stood apart from other financial services providers because of how and why they were first built starting in 1864. Credit Unions are formed by people — workers such as manufacturing employees, farmers, teachers,firefighters, church groups and more to pool their resources and provide low-cost credit to one another. That origin story...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/guest-editorial-the-role-of-credit-unions-in-nebraska/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Guest Editorial: The role of Credit Unions in Nebraska&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 16:46:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] What Is the School Choice Situation in Kansas?</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/what-is-the-school-choice-situation-in-kansas/</link><description>The debate over school choice in Kansas often gets bogged down in politics and process. But the latest data make the stakes clear. The 2026 ABCs of School Choice from EdChoice is the most comprehensive inventory of private school choice programs in the country. After 25 years of tracking these policies, EdChoice doesn’t just catalog [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:00:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] A $500 Million Temporary Emergency Fund Is Starting to Look Like an Open-Ended Obligation</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/12/23/a-500-million-temporary-emergency-fund-is-starting-to-look-like-an-open-ended-obligation/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connecticut’s new half-billion-dollar emergency relief fund, passed during the legislature’s November special session, was presented to the public as a short-term solution — a two-month bridge to prevent families from [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/12/23/a-500-million-temporary-emergency-fund-is-starting-to-look-like-an-open-ended-obligation/"&gt;A $500 Million Temporary Emergency Fund Is Starting to Look Like an Open-Ended Obligation&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 18:46:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Federal Judge Issues Permanent Injunction Against Parental Exclusion Policies  in California Schools</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/mirabelli-olson-federal-judge-issues-permanent-injunction/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=mirabelli-olson-federal-judge-issues-permanent-injunction</link><description>&lt;p&gt;SAN DIEGO &amp;#8211; In a landmark victory for parental rights, a federal judge in Southern California ruled Monday that parents have a constitutional right to be informed if their minor child socially transitions their gender at school and that teachers have a constitutional right to inform parents of the transition. U.S. District Judge Roger Benitez...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/mirabelli-olson-federal-judge-issues-permanent-injunction/"&gt;Federal Judge Issues Permanent Injunction Against Parental Exclusion Policies  in California Schools&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 18:55:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] New York’s Education Shows Improvement, but Questions Remain</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/new-yorks-education-shows-improvement-but-questions-remain/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In the effort to improve transparency and accountability of New York’s education system, the Empire Center has systematized and published....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/new-yorks-education-shows-improvement-but-questions-remain/"&gt;New York&amp;#8217;s Education Shows Improvement, but Questions Remain&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 14:15:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] Allen Mendenhall: API’s Christmas wish list</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/12/26/allen-mendenhall-apis-christmas-wish-list/</link><description>&lt;p&gt; The Alabama Policy Institute (API) has delivered its "Blueprint for 2026: Building a Stronger Alabama" with the seasonal timing of a policy wonk’s Christmas morning, complete with 30 wrapped proposals arranged beneath three conceptual ornaments: free markets, limited government, and strong families.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/12/26/allen-mendenhall-apis-christmas-wish-list/"&gt;Allen Mendenhall: API&amp;#8217;s Christmas wish list&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 18:50:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Winners &amp; Losers: The Sermon on the “Mound” &amp; Religious Illiteracy</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/winners-losers-the-sermon-on-the-mound-religious-illiteracy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;After a year of debating and finally passing a new curriculum for Texas public schools, it seems like the day after Christmas is a good time to re-visit this piece I wrote in 2024 about cultural illiteracy and the importance of understanding the role Christianity plays in the foundation of our western culture. “Sermon on...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/winners-losers-the-sermon-on-the-mound-religious-illiteracy/"&gt;Winners &amp; Losers: The Sermon on the “Mound” &amp; Religious Illiteracy&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 03:24:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Child Protection or Child Profit? Parental Rights at Stake</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/child-protection-or-child-profit-parental-rights-at-stake/</link><description>Every year, parental rights are trampled as hundreds of children are taken from their families in the state of Idaho without due process. What is often presented as “child protection” has quietly evolved into a multi-million-dollar industry in which hospitals, government agencies, contractors, and courts are financially incentivized to separate families.&amp;#160; Under the banner of [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 23:15:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Week in Review: Protecting Idaho Families and Children</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/week-in-review-protecting-idaho-families-and-children/</link><description>Idaho families are struggling. For the past five years, they have been under attack by the burdens of outrageous inflation, hostile policies carried out by Child Protective Services, a judicial system that is completely opposed to protecting the traditional family, abortion petitions by far-left globalist interest groups, and completely unaffordable housing, as new home starts [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:44:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF president discusses massive cost of MLG’s “free” childcare plans on KOAT 7</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-president-discusses-massive-cost-of-mlgs-free-childcare-plans-on-koat-7/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;RGF has raised concerns about the impact of the Gov&amp;#8217;s plans to expand &amp;#8220;free&amp;#8221; child care to those New Mexico families who make MORE THAN 400% of the federal poverty level (about $128,000 for a family of four). Is the program financially sustainable at a time of moderating oil revenues? According to the Legislative Finance [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-president-discusses-massive-cost-of-mlgs-free-childcare-plans-on-koat-7/"&gt;RGF president discusses massive cost of MLG&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8220;free&amp;#8221; childcare plans on KOAT 7&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 16:18:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] $2 billion Chiefs stadium deal won’t fix the Kansas economy, but property tax relief would help</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/chiefs-stadium-deal-wont-fix-kansas-economy/</link><description>Kansas Governor Laura Kelly declared it a “once-in-a-generation opportunity” to transform the state’s economy by delivering thousands of new jobs and billions of dollars in new business activity. That was in 2022, when she announced the state would give Panasonic $829 million to build an electric battery plant in Johnson County. Her hoped-for economic transformation [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 17:03:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] 2025, Wrapped (And Looking Ahead to 2026)</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/2025-wrapped-and-looking-ahead-to-2026/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This year was a massively impactful year for Maine Policy Institute. From testifying on more than 230 bills, to stopping a new fee hike for vehicle inspections, to producing a first-of-its-kind comprehensive Maine-specific analysis of how land use regulations affect housing development,&amp;#160;MPI has seen the fruits of its work materialize into real, tangible effects in [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/2025-wrapped-and-looking-ahead-to-2026/"&gt;2025, Wrapped (And Looking Ahead to 2026)&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 18:07:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] 2025 Was A Year of Liberty in Action</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/2025-was-a-year-of-liberty-in-action/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;If there&amp;#8217;s one thing we know for sure, it&amp;#8217;s that woke activists, leftist leaders, and entrenched bureaucrats will stop at..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/2025-was-a-year-of-liberty-in-action/"&gt;2025 Was A Year of Liberty in Action&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 18:37:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Libertas] A Year of Impact: 1.3+ Million Families</title><link>https://libertas.org/2025-report/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In early 2025 we set out an ambitious &amp;#8220;Vivid Vision&amp;#8221; for our team to grow our impact and scale up our work, and the end-of-year results demonstrate significant progress across all our initiatives. In total, we positively impacted more than 1.3 million families! Below, watch a 15-minute update sharing our 2025 impact, presented by our [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://libertas.org/2025-report/"&gt;A Year of Impact: 1.3+ Million Families&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://libertas.org"&gt;The Libertas Network: Changing Hearts, Minds, and Laws&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 01:49:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Federal Appellate Court Upholds Educators’ Rights Against Unconstitutional DEI “Training”</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/federal-appellate-court-upholds-educators-rights-against-unconstitutional-dei-training/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Eighth Circuit Court of Appeals this morning ruled in favor of a group of school employees who argued that..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/federal-appellate-court-upholds-educators-rights-against-unconstitutional-dei-training/"&gt;Federal Appellate Court Upholds Educators’ Rights Against Unconstitutional DEI “Training”&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 17:35:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Shrinking 82nd Avenue: John Charles Responds to Tyler Frisbee</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/transportation/shrinking-82nd-avenue-john-charles-responds-to-tyler-frisbee/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By John A. Charles, Jr. At TriMet’s December 10 board meeting, director Tyler...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/transportation/shrinking-82nd-avenue-john-charles-responds-to-tyler-frisbee/"&gt;Shrinking 82nd Avenue: John Charles Responds to Tyler Frisbee&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 23:06:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Louisiana’s 2025 Comeback Agenda: A Year in Review</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/principles-of-liberty/louisianas-2025-comeback-agenda-a-year-in-review/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As 2025 ends, the Pelican Institute assesses Louisiana’s progress on its Comeback Agenda, a blueprint for prosperity rooted in limited government, free enterprise, individual liberty, and economic opportunity.  Major Progress On the heels of significant fiscal reforms passed in late 2024, this year brought continued progress on tax reform and notable victories to rein in...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/principles-of-liberty/louisianas-2025-comeback-agenda-a-year-in-review/"&gt;Louisiana’s 2025 Comeback Agenda: A Year in Review&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 23:09:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] New year a good time to ditch harmful old ideas</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/12/new-year-a-good-time-to-ditch-harmful-old-ideas/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;At the dawn of a new year, it’s always nice to take stock of where we have been and where we are going. It’s also a good time to identify harmful old ideas that have done nothing to help and should be sent to the scrapyard. One of those is that more government regulations or [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/12/new-year-a-good-time-to-ditch-harmful-old-ideas/"&gt;New year a good time to ditch harmful old ideas&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 00:55:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Federalist Society honors a guardian of liberty</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/federalist-society-honors-a-guardian-of-liberty</link><description>Mackinac Center’s Patrick J. Wright earns a Grano Award</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] MSPC policy recommendations were a huge hit in 2025</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/a-successful-2025-mspc-policy-year-in-review</link><description>As we prepare for the start of the 2026 Legislative Session in a few weeks in Idaho, Washington and Wyoming (there’s no legislative session next year in Montana), it’s a good time to look back and reflect on the many exciting things that occurred in 2025. Here are just a few that stand out</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 15:14:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Matt’s Top Stories of 2025</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/matts-top-stories-of-2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On Matt&amp;#8217;s last WGAN show of 2025, he reflects on significant events of the year: Listen here: Newsradio WGAN · Matt&amp;#x27;s Top Stories Of 2025 Listen to Matt discuss what to anticipate in 2026: Newsradio WGAN · Looking At 2026&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/matts-top-stories-of-2025/"&gt;Matt&amp;#8217;s Top Stories of 2025&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 18:08:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Waste watch: Illinois spends $1M to rethink capitalism</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/waste-watch-illinois-spends-1m-to-rethink-capitalism/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Illinois progressives want to reimagine capitalism and hand out free money with the tax dollars you worked for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/waste-watch-illinois-spends-1m-to-rethink-capitalism/"&gt;Waste watch: Illinois spends $1M to rethink capitalism&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 11:00:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Questions Come as Twin Falls School District Protects Teacher’s Explicit Content Instead of Children</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/questions-come-as-twin-falls-school-district-protects-teachers-explicit-content-instead-of-children/</link><description>For any reasonable individual, protecting children from people who engage in sexual deviance and celebrate political violence should be a no-brainer. Yet the events that unfolded in Twin Falls, Idaho, involving one concerned mother and substitute teacher, leave us wondering.&amp;#160; On October 1, 2025, Cierra Clarke — a substitute teacher and parent of a 1st [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 23:25:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Whitmer should form a commission to review pandemic response</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2026/whitmer-should-form-a-commission-to-review-pandemic-response</link><description>Time to stop ignoring mistakes</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Illinois local governments lose out on $10.9B in state taxes</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/illinois-local-governments-lose-out-on-10-9b-in-state-taxes/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Illinois local governments have been denied more than $10.9 billion in state income tax revenue since fiscal year 2012 because state lawmakers cut their share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/illinois-local-governments-lose-out-on-10-9b-in-state-taxes/"&gt;Illinois local governments lose out on $10.9B in state taxes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 11:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Listen: True Cost of Chiefs Stadium Subsidies with Neil deMause</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/corporate-welfare/listen-true-cost-of-chiefs-stadium-subsidies-with-neil-demause/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;#160; Guest hosting Mundo in the Morning on KCMO Talk Radio, Patrick Tuohey speaks with Neil deMause, editor of FieldofSchemes.com [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/corporate-welfare/listen-true-cost-of-chiefs-stadium-subsidies-with-neil-demause/"&gt;Listen: True Cost of Chiefs Stadium Subsidies with Neil deMause&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 14:28:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Rifreedom] Stenhouse Challenges Zurier’s Special Senate Energy Commission to “Act” on the Act On Climate</title><link>https://rifreedom.org/2026/01/stenhouse-challenges-zuriers-special-senate-energy-commission-to-act-on-the-act-on-climate/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;With "affordability" top of mind for Ocean State residents, the CEO of the RI Center for Freedom &amp;#038; Prosperity  today called upon  Senator  Sam Zurier  and all members of the special Senate Energy Commission he chairs to take a w holistic and realistic look at Rhode Island's net-zero policies and Act On Climate  mandates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org/2026/01/stenhouse-challenges-zuriers-special-senate-energy-commission-to-act-on-the-act-on-climate/"&gt;Stenhouse Challenges Zurier&amp;#8217;s Special Senate Energy Commission to &amp;#8220;Act&amp;#8221; on the Act On Climate&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org"&gt;RI Center for Freedom and Prosperity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 15:02:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] NJPI Urges Lawmakers Not to Advance Bill Targeting Homeschooling Families</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/01/njpi-urges-lawmakers-not-to-advance-bill-targeting-homeschooling-families/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;by Wells Winegar, NJPI Executive Director The New Jersey Policy Institute has formally urged members of the Assembly Health Committee [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/01/njpi-urges-lawmakers-not-to-advance-bill-targeting-homeschooling-families/"&gt;NJPI Urges Lawmakers Not to Advance Bill Targeting Homeschooling Families&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 15:07:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Week in Review: The Year Freedom Fought Back</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-the-year-freedom-fought-back/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;They told parents to stay silent. They told patients to wait. They told taxpayers to pay up. In 2025, the..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-the-year-freedom-fought-back/"&gt;Week in Review: The Year Freedom Fought Back&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 16:57:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] When “Good News” Becomes Bad Policy: The Hidden Costs of Washington’s Minimum Wage Hike</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/when-good-news-becomes-bad-policy-the-hidden-costs-of-washington-s-minimum-wage-hike</link><description>Good headlines don’t make good policy — especially when the real effects rip through the labor market and everyday life.</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 19:20:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] The Rot in Library Associations</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/the-rot-in-library-associations/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In late January, the State Board of Education will begin the process of reversing decades of declining literacy by considering a preliminary list of required readings for Texas public schools. This charge was delivered to the SBOE by the Legislature in response to disappointing state and national assessment results and university educators sounding the alarm...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/the-rot-in-library-associations/"&gt;The Rot in Library Associations&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 21:08:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Gov. Green’s proposed budget calls for $1.8B election-year tax increase</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/01/gov-greens-proposed-budget-calls-for-1-8b-election-year-tax-increase/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following is a news release issued by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii on Jan. 2, 2026._____________ The state budget department confirms that the increase would come from&amp;#160;a &amp;#8220;pause&amp;#8220; of the remaining historic 2024 income tax reductions HONOLULU, Jan. 2, 2026 &gt;&gt; Gov. Josh Green’s latest budget proposal includes a tax increase of $1.8 billion [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/01/gov-greens-proposed-budget-calls-for-1-8b-election-year-tax-increase/"&gt;Gov. Green&amp;#8217;s proposed budget calls for $1.8B election-year tax increase&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 08:14:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] How Kansas STAR Bonds Work for Stadium Projects</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/corporate-welfare/how-kansas-star-bonds-work-for-stadium-projects/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Guest hosting Mundo in the Morning on KCMO Talk Radio, Patrick Tuohey speaks with Thomas Friestad of the Kansas City [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/corporate-welfare/how-kansas-star-bonds-work-for-stadium-projects/"&gt;How Kansas STAR Bonds Work for Stadium Projects&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 14:31:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Leaked email sent to Robbinsdale school board suggests a public bait-and-switch</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/leaked-email-sent-to-robbinsdale-school-board-suggests-a-public-bait-and-switch/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Reeling from dramatic dysfunction on the school board, an accounting error that cost the district $20 million, and a hasty school closure process racked with controversy, Robbinsdale School District will now hold a public hearing on January 5 to discuss the potential closure of another school building: FAIR School Pilgrim Lane Elementary, which would effectively...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/leaked-email-sent-to-robbinsdale-school-board-suggests-a-public-bait-and-switch/"&gt;Leaked email sent to Robbinsdale school board suggests a public bait-and-switch&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 02:22:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] The autism fraud</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/the-autism-fraud/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I did a little bit of citizen-journalist-style research into the ballooning autism-clinic scandal this weekend. The results were eye-opening. Just before Christmas, the U.S. Attorney for Minnesota announced a new indictment and a new guilty plea, respectively, in the autism fraud scandal: Abdinajib Hassan Yussuf and Asha Farhan Hassan. This scandal involves a Medicaid program,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/the-autism-fraud/"&gt;The autism fraud&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 19:01:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Using Idaho’s budget gap to attack education choice is irresponsible</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/using-idaho-s-budget-gap-to-attack-education-choice-is-irresponsible</link><description>Yet that’s exactly what’s happening. Longtime opponents of education choice are now claiming that Idaho’s education choice law is responsible for the state’s fiscal challenges. That claim may be convenient, but it is not grounded in facts — and it’s irresponsible to suggest otherwise.</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 05:05:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] America’s flirtation with socialism</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2026/americas-flirtation-with-socialism</link><description>We won’t fix a problem caused by big government with a bigger government</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] How Illinois has changed under Pritzker</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/presidential-profile-how-illinois-has-changed-under-pritzker/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Illinois Gov. J.B. Pritzker is acting like the 2028 Democratic candidate for president. But what does Pritzker’s Illinois resume say about his leadership?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/presidential-profile-how-illinois-has-changed-under-pritzker/"&gt;How Illinois has changed under Pritzker&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 11:00:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] What’s Killing Our Kids? It’s Not Alcohol.</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/whats-killing-our-kids-its-not-alcohol/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Four decades later, the promised benefits are difficult to find. In California, arrests of underage drivers for driving under the influence are exceedingly rare. In 2024, just 45 juveniles were arrested for driving under the influence—a figure that has remained consistently low for years. Rather than eliminating youth drinking, the 21-and-over mandate has driven it [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/whats-killing-our-kids-its-not-alcohol/"&gt;What’s Killing Our Kids? It’s Not Alcohol.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 11:00:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Minnesota’s Fraud Is Blowing the Lid Off a Broken Election System</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/minnesotas-fraud-is-blowing-the-lid-off-a-broken-election-system/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Fraud investigations are engulfing Minnesota Gov. Tim Walz, but that isn’t the only issue demanding attention in that state. The state’s election system is being exposed for vulnerabilities that undermine transparency and confidence in democracy. Recent reporting has brought renewed attention to just how permissive Minnesota’s election framework has become. The state allows voters to...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/minnesotas-fraud-is-blowing-the-lid-off-a-broken-election-system/"&gt;Minnesota’s Fraud Is Blowing the Lid Off a Broken Election System&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 14:02:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] If California is an economic powerhouse, then where are the jobs?</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/if-california-is-an-economic-powerhouse-then-where-are-the-jobs/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;It’s a new year, a time for resolutions and fresh starts. Of course, only 9 percent of people who declare New year’s resolutions ultimately fulfill them. Most will give up before January ends. Such a dour outlook is a bit of a wet blanket, but it is apropos for California’s economic prospects in the coming [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/if-california-is-an-economic-powerhouse-then-where-are-the-jobs/"&gt;If California is an economic powerhouse, then where are the jobs?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 17:11:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Freedom Foundation Sues to Block Oregon Law Silencing Worker Rights Speech</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/press-release/freedom-foundation-sues-to-block-oregon-law-silencing-worker-rights-speech/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Freedom Foundation filed a federal lawsuit challenging Oregon House Bill 3789, a law that hands public-sector unions the power to sue the organization into oblivion for doing what it's done for years: informing public employees about their constitutional rights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/press-release/freedom-foundation-sues-to-block-oregon-law-silencing-worker-rights-speech/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation Sues to Block Oregon Law Silencing Worker Rights Speech &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 17:59:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Can Minnesotans trust the state government with their hard earned money?</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/can-minnesotans-trust-the-state-government-with-their-hard-earned-money/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Minnesotans are some of the hardest working people in the United States. Using the measures of &amp;#8220;raw&amp;#8221; labor in the American Experiment United States Tables — employment and average hours worked annually — we can calculate that in 2024, the amount of raw labor provided per capita in Minnesota ranked 7th out of 50 states,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/can-minnesotans-trust-the-state-government-with-their-hard-earned-money/"&gt;Can Minnesotans trust the state government with their hard earned money?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 19:25:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Three simple resolutions for Hawaii lawmakers in 2026:</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/01/three-simple-resolutions-for-hawaii-lawmakers-in-2026/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The first day of 2026 was two days ago, but it’s never too late to make resolutions about how we can improve ourselves. This applies as well to our state lawmakers, who will gather later this month for another legislative session that, for good or bad, will affect all of us who live in these [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/01/three-simple-resolutions-for-hawaii-lawmakers-in-2026/"&gt;Three simple resolutions for Hawaii lawmakers in 2026:&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 20:28:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] ACA Subsidies, Parks Policy, and Open Enrollment in Missouri</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/health-care/aca-subsidies-parks-policy-and-open-enrollment-in-missouri/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;David Stokes, Elias Tsapelas, and Avery Frank join Zach Lawhorn to discuss the expiration of enhanced Affordable Care Act subsidies, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/health-care/aca-subsidies-parks-policy-and-open-enrollment-in-missouri/"&gt;ACA Subsidies, Parks Policy, and Open Enrollment in Missouri&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 21:03:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Why the approved Chiefs deal is bad economics</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/why-the-approved-chiefs-deal-is-bad-economics/</link><description>In December 2025, the deal to bring the Kansas City Chiefs across the state line was agreed upon. Supporters called it a historic win. In reality, it locked Kansas into a multi-decade financial commitment that violates one of the most basic principles of good economics: government should not pick winners and losers. This deal is [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 21:43:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Dominion Describes Efforts to Limit Turbine Radar Interference</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/dominion-describes-efforts-to-limit-turbine-radar-interference/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="720" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Turbine-Radar-Inteference.jpg" width="1280" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dominion Energy Virginia’s team building its offshore wind facility spent years working with the U.S. Navy and the air defense agency NORAD on ways to mitigate the problems that would be caused by the 836-foot-tall turbines, reaching several agreements, the utility has told a federal court. The company – meaning ultimately the company’s customers – [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/dominion-describes-efforts-to-limit-turbine-radar-interference/"&gt;Dominion Describes Efforts to Limit Turbine Radar Interference&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 03:15:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] How New State Law Will Be Another Costly Business Burden</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/how-new-state-law-will-be-another-costly-business-burden/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On October 13th, 2025, the California legislature passed into law AB692, a bill which would void any contract that requires employees to repay their employer, training provider, or debt collector upon termination of their employment. These training repayment agreement provisions, colloquially known as TRAPs, allow employers to recoup investment and training costs, but are outlawed [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/how-new-state-law-will-be-another-costly-business-burden/"&gt;How New State Law Will Be Another Costly Business Burden&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 11:00:35 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>