<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>State-Policy Think-Tank Digest</title><link>https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml</link><description>Latest posts from free-market policy institutes across the U.S.</description><atom:link href="https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 13:12:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] Pennsylvania Senate Passes Budget Plan, RGGI Abrogation, Regulatory Reform</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/10/22/pennsylvania-senate-passes-budget-plan/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Harrisburg, Pa., October 22, 2025&amp;#160;— This week, the Pennsylvania Senate advanced legislation, including a spending bill (Senate Bill 160), that protects taxpayers and fosters economic growth. The commonwealth remains the only state in the country without an operating budget or stop gap plan. Now weeks into a federal government shutdown, Pennsylvania’s four-month-long impasse holds the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/10/22/pennsylvania-senate-passes-budget-plan/"&gt;Pennsylvania Senate Passes Budget Plan, RGGI Abrogation, Regulatory Reform&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 18:11:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] If Lawmakers Are Trying to Defund Public Education, They Aren’t Very Good at It</title><link>https://empowerms.org/if-lawmakers-are-trying-to-defund-public-education-they-arent-very-good-at-it/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;You’ve probably heard the claim that Mississippi’s Republican leaders are “defunding” public education, and that school choice is just another way to siphon dollars away from public schools. But if that’s true, they’re doing a remarkably bad job of it.  Over the past decade, Mississippi has dramatically increased its investment in public education. According to&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/if-lawmakers-are-trying-to-defund-public-education-they-arent-very-good-at-it/"&gt;If Lawmakers Are Trying to Defund Public Education, They Aren’t Very Good at It&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 02:00:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Nebraska’s Tax Treatment of Non-Profits</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/nebraskas-tax-treatment-of-non-profits/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The origins of favorable tax treatment for nonprofit and not-for-profit organizations in the United States were based on the admirable ideals promoting community service and public good.    However, today the United States’ federally tax-exempt economy makes up 15% of gross domestic output (GDP) and spans 1.8 million organizations. A total of $3.3 trillion dollars of...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/nebraskas-tax-treatment-of-non-profits/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Nebraska&amp;#8217;s Tax Treatment of Non-Profits&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 19:37:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] The Good, Bad, and Ugly of 2nd Session Bill Requests</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/the-good-bad-and-ugly-of-2nd-session-bill-requests/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Legislative Council has released the list of bill titles under consideration for the Maine Legislature’s 2026 legislative session, and on October 23, the Council met for an initial bill screening. The full list of results is available here.&amp;#160; The Legislative Council is made up of 10 members of legislative leadership. For a bill request [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/the-good-bad-and-ugly-of-2nd-session-bill-requests/"&gt;The Good, Bad, and Ugly of 2nd Session Bill Requests&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 19:40:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] Court ratifies City of Albuquerque donation to Planned Parenthood</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/court-ratifies-city-of-albuquerque-donation-to-planned-parenthood/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In what can only be described as a ruling based on twisted logic a New Mexico District Judge (Denise Barela Shepherd) has decided that it is somehow NOT a violation of New Mexico&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8220;anti-donation clause&amp;#8221; for the City of Albuquerque to explicitly donation $250,000 of our tax dollars to Planned Parenthood.  Our friends at the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/court-ratifies-city-of-albuquerque-donation-to-planned-parenthood/"&gt;Court ratifies City of Albuquerque donation to Planned Parenthood&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 22:24:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] New Video Exposes How Unions Trap Public Employees in Membership</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/press-release/new-video-exposes-how-unions-trap-public-employees-in-membership/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Freedom Foundation today released a new video exposing the deliberate obstacles unions place in front of public employees trying to exercise their constitutional right to leave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/press-release/new-video-exposes-how-unions-trap-public-employees-in-membership/" rel="nofollow"&gt;New Video Exposes How Unions Trap Public Employees in Membership&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 15:22:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Frightfully pricey treats: Why Halloween fun is costing Georgia families more</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/georgia-halloween-candy-prices/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As Halloween approaches, Georgia families look forward to making great memories involving adorable costumes and fun candy hauls. But candy prices have become nothing short of scary for families trying to make ends meet. Here's why prices are on the rise for Georgia's favorite Halloween treats. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/georgia-halloween-candy-prices/"&gt;Frightfully pricey treats: Why Halloween fun is costing Georgia families more&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 16:01:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Mayor John Horhn: Jackson Rising</title><link>https://empowerms.org/mayor-john-horhn-jackson-rising/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Mayor John Horhn: Jackson Rising What does it take to turn around a city? In this special episode recorded at Jackson City Hall, host Grant Callen talks with Mayor John Horhn about his love for Jackson, the lessons from his childhood and career in public service, and his mission to restore trust, safety, and opportunity&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/mayor-john-horhn-jackson-rising/"&gt;Mayor John Horhn: Jackson Rising&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 01:00:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG Court Watch: Options for Structural Reforms for our Courts</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-court-watch-options-for-structural-reforms-for-our-courts/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;IRG Court Watch: Options for Structural Reforms for our Courts Voters Open to Reform after Multi-Million Dollar, Partisan Judicial Elections Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government’s (IRG)‘s Court Watch initiative released a report, Structural Reform of Judicial Selection in Wisconsin, detailing potential structural reforms to strengthen judicial integrity and public trust in Wisconsin [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-court-watch-options-for-structural-reforms-for-our-courts/"&gt;IRG Court Watch: Options for Structural Reforms for our Courts&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 13:38:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Parsing the Impact of Mamdani’s Tax Hike Plans</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/parsing-the-impact-of-mamdanis-tax-hike-plans/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The front-running candidate for New York City mayor, Zohran Mamdani, has said he can finance his costly campaign promises –....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/parsing-the-impact-of-mamdanis-tax-hike-plans/"&gt;Parsing the Impact of Mamdani&amp;#8217;s Tax Hike Plans&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 20:28:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Maine’s 2025 Ballot Questions: What Voters Should Know</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/maines-2025-ballot-questions-what-voters-should-know/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As Maine heads into the 2025 election, voters will face two ballot questions that cut to the heart of the state’s debates over election integrity and gun rights. Both questions resurrect legislative fights that failed in Augusta and are now placed directly before the people. Ballot Question 1: Election Integrity Ballot Summary:“Do you want to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/maines-2025-ballot-questions-what-voters-should-know/"&gt;Maine’s 2025 Ballot Questions: What Voters Should Know&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 21:09:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Beacon Wins Final Approval in $1.4 Million Stormwater Settlement, Bringing Justice to Nashville Homeowners</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/beacon-wins-final-approval-in-1-4-million-stormwater-settlement-bringing-justice-to-nashville-homeowners/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=beacon-wins-final-approval-in-1-4-million-stormwater-settlement-bringing-justice-to-nashville-homeowners</link><description>This ruling is a landmark win for property owners and sends a clear message that government overreach will not go unchecked.</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 21:26:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] WI Speaks Polling Results</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/wi-speaks-survey-results/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WI 1023 Toplines (1) WI 1023 Summary of Key Findings (2) WI 1023 Summary of Key Findings (2)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/wi-speaks-survey-results/"&gt;WI Speaks Polling Results&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 00:18:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Virginiainstitute] Examining HJ6007 and Its Implications for Virginia’s Redistricting Process</title><link>https://virginiainstitute.org/examining-hj6007/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=examining-hj6007</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As lawmakers consider HJ6007, Virginians are asking how the proposal aligns with the 2020 constitutional amendment supporting fair maps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org/examining-hj6007/"&gt;Examining HJ6007 and Its Implications for Virginia’s Redistricting Process&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org"&gt;Virginia Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 01:53:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] NYC Employees Receive $300k+ in Overtime</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/nyc-employees-receive-300k-in-overtime/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Two New York City employees received more than $300,000 in overtime payouts, according to fiscal year 2025 payroll data posted....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/nyc-employees-receive-300k-in-overtime/"&gt;NYC Employees Receive $300k+ in Overtime&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 13:20:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] PRESS RELEASE: MISSISSIPPI CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY HONORS LEGISLATIVE HEROES AT ANNUAL GALA CELEBRATING STATE SUCCESS</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/press-release-mississippi-center-for-public-policy-honors-legislative-heroes-at-annual-gala-celebrating-state-success/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASEOctober 30, 2025 MISSISSIPPI CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY HONORS LEGISLATIVE HEROES AT ANNUAL GALA CELEBRATING STATE SUCCESS JACKSON, MS – October 30, 2025 –Six of Mississippi’s leading lawmakers were presented with award to honor them for championing principled conservative policy. Rich Lowry, editor of the National Review, presented each of the winners. HealthcareRep. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/press-release-mississippi-center-for-public-policy-honors-legislative-heroes-at-annual-gala-celebrating-state-success/" rel="nofollow"&gt;PRESS RELEASE: MISSISSIPPI CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY HONORS LEGISLATIVE HEROES AT ANNUAL GALA CELEBRATING STATE SUCCESS&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 19:21:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Virginiainstitute] Press Release – HJ 6007: “one of the worst ideas” passed by the General Assembly</title><link>https://virginiainstitute.org/press-release-hj6007/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=press-release-hj6007</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Virginia Institute for Public Policy has expressed concern over HJ6007, a proposed amendment to Virginia’s Constitution that would alter the state’s current redistricting process. The Institute emphasized that Virginia voters approved a bipartisan approach in 2020 to ensure fair and transparent elections for all citizens. Citing constitutional and procedural issues surrounding HJ6007, the Institute encourages lawmakers to uphold established safeguards that protect the integrity and balance of Virginia’s electoral system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org/press-release-hj6007/"&gt;Press Release – HJ 6007: “one of the worst ideas” passed by the General Assembly&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org"&gt;Virginia Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 00:15:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Tallahassee Democrat: Florida’s Established Approach to Kids’ Online Safety Doesn’t Need Tweaking</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/floridas-established-approach-to-kids-online-safety-doesnt-need-tweaking-opinion/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In the ongoing debate about how to best protect children online, a new proposal gaining traction would force...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/floridas-established-approach-to-kids-online-safety-doesnt-need-tweaking-opinion/"&gt;Tallahassee Democrat: Florida’s Established Approach to Kids’ Online Safety Doesn’t Need Tweaking&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 14:55:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] Average Twin Cities Commuter = 73 Hours Stuck in Traffic</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/average-twin-cities-commuter-73-hours-stuck-in-traffic/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Every year, the Texas A&amp;#38;M Transportation Institute issues a report documenting the price of road congestion on American roads. This 2025 report is notable for Minnesota commuters because it documented that the “average Twin Cities car commuter now spends a record 73 hours a year stuck in traffic.” This is an increase after a COVID-pandemic [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/average-twin-cities-commuter-73-hours-stuck-in-traffic/"&gt;Average Twin Cities Commuter = 73 Hours Stuck in Traffic&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 18:14:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Week in Review: Everything Should Be Smaller in Taxes</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/week-in-review-everything-should-be-smaller-in-taxes/</link><description>That’s right, the title says “Taxes,” not “Texas.” Even in Idaho, taxes are out of control. Please enjoy — if that’s the right word — this mini-series on Idaho taxes. But, before you read, one word of reminder: high taxes are merely the symptom of the true disease: out-of-control government spending. This symptom inflicts real [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 20:04:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF in National Review: New Mexico’s ‘Free’ Child Care an Attempt to Cover for Past Failures</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-in-national-review-new-mexicos-free-child-care-an-attempt-to-cover-for-past-failures/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following appeared at National Review on November 11, 2025. Child care isn’t cheap, especially once the government gets involved. Recently, New Mexico’s Democratic Governor Michelle Lujan Grisham announced a new plan for taxpayers to fund “free” child care for all New Mexicans, regardless of their income levels. The announcement generated favorable news coverage in [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-in-national-review-new-mexicos-free-child-care-an-attempt-to-cover-for-past-failures/"&gt;RGF in National Review: New Mexico’s ‘Free’ Child Care an Attempt to Cover for Past Failures&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 21:15:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] AEA Has Shown Alabamians Who They Are: Believe Them</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/11/04/aea-has-shown-alabamians-who-they-are-believe-them/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;AEA has worked for decades to stop school choice legislation. AEA actively worked against the passage of the AAA Scholarship program, the PRICE Act, and the CHOOSE Act. AEA used political influence and political contributions to people and parties to weaken parental rights in the CHOOSE Act and then tried to kill the CHOOSE Act unless they could “control the spending” with a cap. Further, AEA worked last legislative session to minimize funding for special needs kids, military kids, and kids whose families are living in poverty; they are currently working against future CHOOSE Act schoolchildren. AEA is trying to render void the promises legislators made to Alabama parents when they passed the law in 2024. They are attempting to undercut the work and the word of Governor Kay Ivey, Lt. Governor Will Ainsworth, Speaker Nathaniel Ledbetter, Chairman Danny Garrett, Chairman Arthur Orr, and each of the ninety-two legislators who voted on behalf of the people they represent for universal school choice for Alabama’s children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/11/04/aea-has-shown-alabamians-who-they-are-believe-them/"&gt;AEA Has Shown Alabamians Who They Are: Believe Them&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 05:04:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] SNAP in Nebraska: Current Rules, Economic Impact, and What’s Next</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/snap-in-nebraska-current-rules-economic-impact-and-whats-next/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Program Overview  The Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP), formerly known as the Food Stamp Program, is the most extensive federal nutrition assistance program in the United States. It serves as a &amp;#8220;safety net&amp;#8221; program that helpslow-income individuals and families access and purchase healthy food. The program is funded by the Department of Agriculture (USDA) and...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/snap-in-nebraska-current-rules-economic-impact-and-whats-next/" rel="nofollow"&gt;SNAP in Nebraska: Current Rules, Economic Impact, and What’s Next&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 16:16:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Nebraska lost $300 million from tax migration in 2022</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-lost-300-million-from-tax-migration-in-2022/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Elections occur every other November. But taxpayers vote with their feet every day, and these votes should be counted and tallied just like the votes for a November election.  A “Great Pandemic Wealth Migration” began when the coronavirus pandemic caused Americans to move to work-from-home employment. This meant workers were no longer tied to aphysical...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-lost-300-million-from-tax-migration-in-2022/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Nebraska lost $300 million from tax migration in 2022&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 19:03:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Obamacare’s Policy Failures Come To Idaho</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/obamacares-policy-failures-come-to-idaho/</link><description>As the shutdown of the federal government extends beyond 30 days, the key reasons become apparent: it is about healthcare costs and who pays them. The debate over temporarily expanded healthcare premium subsidies and Medicaid eligibility is really about who pays what. You see, the notion that the Affordable Care Act (often referred to as [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 22:45:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] State Board of Education gets bad legal guidance from the Kansas Department of Education</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/state-board-of-education-bad-legal-guidance/</link><description>The October meeting of the Kansas State Board of Education contained another déjà vu moment: attempting to cover up another violation of state laws designed to improve student outcomes (see here and here for past examples.) State Board Chair Cathy Hopkins commented on a Kansas Policy Institute discovery that school districts were not complying with [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 23:33:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] November 2025 Beacon Poll Results</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/november-2025-beacon-poll/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=november-2025-beacon-poll</link><description>Today, we released the latest installment of the Beacon Poll, a statewide survey of 1,200 Tennessee voters featuring questions about voters&amp;#8217; views on socialism versus capitalism, the National Guard in Memphis, political violence, and more. In a surprising result that could have a national impact, a majority of Democrats in Tennessee hold a favorable view...</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 13:00:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] The Atlanta Journal-Constitution: Georgia Leaders Should Not Vilify Technology. Social Media and AI Hold Promise.</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/georgia-leaders-should-not-vilify-technology-social-media-and-ai-hold-promise/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In the waning hours of Georgia&amp;#8217;s brief 40-day legislative session this past April, state senators quietly passed Senate...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/georgia-leaders-should-not-vilify-technology-social-media-and-ai-hold-promise/"&gt;The Atlanta Journal-Constitution: Georgia Leaders Should Not Vilify Technology. Social Media and AI Hold Promise.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 16:04:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] California Just Blew Past Last Year’s Record — And We’re Still Climbing</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/california-just-blew-past-last-years-record-and-were-still-climbing/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;California public employees are opting out of their unions in record numbers thanks to the work of the Freedom Foundation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/california-just-blew-past-last-years-record-and-were-still-climbing/" rel="nofollow"&gt;California Just Blew Past Last Year’s Record — And We’re Still Climbing&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 23:30:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] NH’s youngest lawmakers to discuss civility in politics at Civil Discourses kickoff event</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/11/nhs-youngest-lawmakers-to-discuss-civility-in-politics-at-civil-discourses-kickoff-event/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Josiah Bartlett Center for Public Policy will bring a bipartisan group of New Hampshire’s youngest state representatives together on Dec. 1 for a frank and open conversation on the importance of civility in public life.  Josiah Bartlett Center President Andrew Cline will moderate a conversation among:: Rep. Jessica Grill, Democrat of Manchester; Rep. Sam [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/11/nhs-youngest-lawmakers-to-discuss-civility-in-politics-at-civil-discourses-kickoff-event/"&gt;NH&amp;#8217;s youngest lawmakers to discuss civility in politics at Civil Discourses kickoff event&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 13:31:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] ROI-NJ: A blueprint for abundant, affordable energy for New Jersey families | Op-Ed</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/11/roi-nj-a-blueprint-for-abundant-affordable-energy-for-new-jersey-families-op-ed/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A blueprint for abundant, affordable energy for New Jersey families &amp;#124; Op-Ed By Erica Jedynak, New Jersey Policy Institute November [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/11/roi-nj-a-blueprint-for-abundant-affordable-energy-for-new-jersey-families-op-ed/"&gt;ROI-NJ: A blueprint for abundant, affordable energy for New Jersey families | Op-Ed&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 16:11:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] WFSE loses 1,000 members for second consecutive year</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/washington/wfse-loses-1000-members-for-second-consecutive-year/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For the second year in a row, the largest union representing Washington state employees has lost more than 1,000 members, thanks in large part to the ongoing outreach efforts of the Freedom Foundation to help of workers understand their right to opt out of paying union dues.&amp;#160; With annual union dues averaging around $1,000 per [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/washington/wfse-loses-1000-members-for-second-consecutive-year/" rel="nofollow"&gt;WFSE loses 1,000 members for second consecutive year&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 17:55:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] State Tax Competitiveness Index: Minnesota Falls to 44th out of 50!</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/state-tax-competitiveness-index-minnesota-falls-to-44th-out-of-50/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For 20 years, the Tax Foundation has released an annual report evaluating state tax codes – everything from income to property to sales taxes. Each state has its own summary including an interactive map that includes suggestions on how the state could become more competitive. Minnesota state leadership, however appears to be determined for our [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/state-tax-competitiveness-index-minnesota-falls-to-44th-out-of-50/"&gt;State Tax Competitiveness Index: Minnesota Falls to 44th out of 50!&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 19:06:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] UW students turning away from gender and ethnic studies degrees</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/uw-students-turning-away-from-gender-and-ethnic-studies-degrees/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;About half as many students in the Universities of Wisconsin system are getting bachelor’s degrees in ethnic and gender studies as did at their peak in 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/uw-students-turning-away-from-gender-and-ethnic-studies-degrees/"&gt;UW students turning away from gender and ethnic studies degrees&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 20:47:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Budget Update Paints Less Alarming Picture of Federal Health Cuts</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/budget-update-paints-less-alarming-picture/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A new fiscal report from the state Budget Division suggests federal funding cuts will hit New York&amp;#8217;s health-care budget less....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/budget-update-paints-less-alarming-picture/"&gt;Budget Update Paints Less Alarming Picture of Federal Health Cuts&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 14:23:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Will Concord or Laconia reap the rewards of creating NH’s first social district?</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/11/will-concord-or-laconia-reap-the-rewards-of-creating-nhs-first-social-district/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The term “economic growth” seldom pops up in local news stories. But there it was in the third paragraph of the Concord Monitor’s story on Tuesday’s election results.  After quoting a former teacher who complained about the slow pace of change in Concord due to “a lot of governmental, bureaucratic red tape,” the Monitor described [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/11/will-concord-or-laconia-reap-the-rewards-of-creating-nhs-first-social-district/"&gt;Will Concord or Laconia reap the rewards of creating NH&amp;#8217;s first social district?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 17:30:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] Minnesotans Cannot Afford Four More Years of Walz Energy Policy</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/minnesotans-cannot-afford-four-more-years-of-walz-energy-policy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;What happens when working families see electric bills climb to meet the governor’s idealistic demands? By Annette Meeks Gov. Tim Walz officially announced that he wants to serve four more years leading Minnesota. He did not make this announcement in a public meeting, rally or policy speech, but with a carefully crafted video. It was a politically manufactured [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/minnesotans-cannot-afford-four-more-years-of-walz-energy-policy/"&gt;Minnesotans Cannot Afford Four More Years of Walz Energy Policy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 19:02:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] News Release: Cascade Identifies Purchase Risk for PPS One North Building</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/education/news-release-cascade-identifies-purchase-risk-for-pps-one-north-building/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;11/06/2025 FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE Cascade Policy Institute4850 SW Scholls Ferry Rd., Ste 103Portland...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/education/news-release-cascade-identifies-purchase-risk-for-pps-one-north-building/"&gt;News Release: Cascade Identifies Purchase Risk for PPS One North Building&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 23:23:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Six Years Later, Massachusetts Active Home Listings Remain 35% Below Pre-COVID Level</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/economic_opportunity/six-years-later-massachusetts-active-home-listings-remain-35-below-pre-covid-level/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Our November edition of The House Call covers the dwindling availability of homes on the market in Massachusetts since 2019, even as many other states have seen full recoveries in the number of market listings after COVID. It discusses the implications of lower home availability for buyers and sellers alike and identifies a couple of major solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/economic_opportunity/six-years-later-massachusetts-active-home-listings-remain-35-below-pre-covid-level/"&gt;Six Years Later, Massachusetts Active Home Listings Remain 35% Below Pre-COVID Level&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 13:30:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Kansas’s Tax Competitiveness Moment</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/kansas-tax-competitiveness/</link><description>Kansas stands in a better position today than it did just a few years ago. According to the Tax Foundation’s 2026 State Tax Competitiveness Index, the state now ranks 23rd overall in the nation. That’s respectable progress, but in a country where states are competing aggressively for people, jobs, and investment, “respectable” isn’t enough. The [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 16:00:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] The fantasy that cutting prison populations saves a lot of money</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/the-fantasy-that-cutting-prison-populations-saves-a-lot-of-money/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/the-fantasy-that-cutting-prison-populations-saves-a-lot-of-money/"&gt;The fantasy that cutting prison populations saves a lot of money&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 16:02:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Those Dark Clouds are the Debt</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/those-dark-clouds-are-the-debt/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The future for our state looks bright.  In just the past five years, Mississippi has seen more economic growth than in the entire fifteen years before that combined. We’re on track to phase out the state income tax entirely, allowing families to keep more of what they earn.  Mississippi has attracted a surge of new investment, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/those-dark-clouds-are-the-debt/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Those Dark Clouds are the Debt&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 18:39:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] New Report: Shapiro’s ‘Get Sh*t Done’ Slogan Doesn’t Match His Record</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/11/10/shapiro-get-sht-done-slogan-doesnt-match-record/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Gov. Josh Shapiro remains Pennsylvania’s least legislatively productive governor in the past 50 years. Harrisburg, Pa., November 10, 2025 — As presidential ambitions of Pennsylvania’s 48th governor become increasingly prominent, many question: Is Governor Shapiro as productive as he claims? A new report from the Commonwealth Foundation found Gov. Josh Shapiro to be the least [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/11/10/shapiro-get-sht-done-slogan-doesnt-match-record/"&gt;New Report: Shapiro’s ‘Get Sh*t Done’ Slogan Doesn’t Match His Record&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 19:58:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Lamont’s Hospital Takeover Plan is a Gamble Connecticut Cannot Afford</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/11/10/lamonts-hospital-takeover-plan-is-a-gamble-connecticut-cannot-afford/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="630" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/uconn_fb_1200x630.png" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UConn Health — the state’s public medical center that includes the UConn School of Medicine, the School of Dental Medicine, and John Dempsey Hospital — is now at the center [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/11/10/lamonts-hospital-takeover-plan-is-a-gamble-connecticut-cannot-afford/"&gt;Lamont’s Hospital Takeover Plan is a Gamble Connecticut Cannot Afford&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 21:10:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Shutdown Endgame: What the Deal Means for Maine and the Nation</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/shutdown-endgame-what-the-deal-means-for-maine-and-the-nation/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;After more than 40 days, the longest government shutdown in American history appears to be nearing an end. The Senate voted 60–40 on a short-term funding bill that would reopen shuttered federal agencies and extend operations through late January. In a rare show of bipartisanship, eight Democrats, including Senator Angus King, joined Republicans to advance [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/shutdown-endgame-what-the-deal-means-for-maine-and-the-nation/"&gt;Shutdown Endgame: What the Deal Means for Maine and the Nation&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 01:28:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Analysis: Wisconsin’s School Report Cards Show Persistent Gaps and Inflated Ratings</title><link>https://will-law.org/wisconsins-school-report-cards-show-persistent-gaps-and-inflated-ratings/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL reacts to new report cards released by DPI for the 2024-25 school year. Once again, the agency has quietly changed the standards that determine how schools are rated—making it easier to appear successful without actually improving student performance. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/wisconsins-school-report-cards-show-persistent-gaps-and-inflated-ratings/"&gt;Analysis: Wisconsin’s School Report Cards Show Persistent Gaps and Inflated Ratings&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 15:36:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] What You Need To Know For Special Session</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/11/11/what-you-need-to-know-for-special-session/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="1216" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/Screenshot-2025-08-19-134951.jpg" width="1736" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connecticut lawmakers are moving quickly in a special session — tackling housing, emergency spending, and healthcare policy from Nov. 12-13. Some proposals represent steps in the right direction. Others risk [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/11/11/what-you-need-to-know-for-special-session/"&gt;What You Need To Know For Special Session&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 15:50:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] DPI Rates 0 Districts 1 Star, Half of All Schools 4 or 5 Stars on New School Report Cards</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/dpi-rates-0-districts-1-star-half-of-all-schools-4-or-5-stars-on-new-school-report-cards/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;DPI Rates 0 Districts 1 Star, Half of All Schools 4 or 5 Stars on New School Report Cards DPI’s rankings make report cards mostly meaningless  Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government (IRG) released the following statement following the release of 2025 district and school report cards using a lenient formula, resulting in [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/dpi-rates-0-districts-1-star-half-of-all-schools-4-or-5-stars-on-new-school-report-cards/"&gt;DPI Rates 0 Districts 1 Star, Half of All Schools 4 or 5 Stars on New School Report Cards&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 17:31:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] NJBIZ: OPINION: Why New Jersey should repeal its bag ban</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/11/njbiz-opinion-why-new-jersey-should-repeal-its-bag-ban-wells-winegar/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;OPINION: Why New Jersey should repeal its bag ban by Wells Winegar November 10, 2025 &amp;#160; Walk into any New [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/11/njbiz-opinion-why-new-jersey-should-repeal-its-bag-ban-wells-winegar/"&gt;NJBIZ: OPINION: Why New Jersey should repeal its bag ban&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 18:56:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] You Don’t Make Housing More Affordable by Making It More Expensive</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/making-housing-more-affordable/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=making-housing-more-affordable</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Let me tell you something that shouldn’t need to be said: If you want housing to be affordable, you shouldn’t start by making it more expensive. Nationally, approximately 5% of the cost of building a new home is attributed to regulatory costs. That includes permits, compliance with zoning rules, environmental reviews, fees, studies, and the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/making-housing-more-affordable/"&gt;You Don’t Make Housing More Affordable by Making It More Expensive&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 19:50:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] TriMet Retreat Should Focus on Crisis, Not Expansion</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/transportation/trimet-retreat-should-focus-on-crisis-not-expansion/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By John A. Charles, Jr. On November 12, the TriMet Board will hold...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/transportation/trimet-retreat-should-focus-on-crisis-not-expansion/"&gt;TriMet Retreat Should Focus on Crisis, Not Expansion &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 22:56:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Dr. Brad Wilcox: Get Married</title><link>https://empowerms.org/dr-brad-wilcox-get-married/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Dr. Brad Wilcox: Get Married On this episode of The Empower Podcast, host Grant Callen talks with Dr. Brad Wilcox, Director of the National Marriage Project at the University of Virginia and author of Get Married: Why Americans Must Defy the Elites, Forge Strong Families, and Save Civilization. Dr. Wilcox shares striking research on how&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/dr-brad-wilcox-get-married/"&gt;Dr. Brad Wilcox: Get Married&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 00:00:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] UK Uni. of St Andrews’ Sir Hew Strachan on the First World War</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/uk-uni-of-st-andrews-sir-hew-strachan-on-the-first-world-war/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In this week’s episode of The Learning Curve, co-hosts U-Arkansas Prof. Albert Cheng and Center for Strong Public Schools’ Alisha Searcy speak with Sir Hew Strachan, Professor of International Relations at the University of St Andrews, Scotland, and recipient of the 2016 Pritzker Literature Award for Lifetime Achievement in Military Writing. Prof. Sir Hew, author of numerous award-winning books, including The First World War, the basis of the definitive 10-part Channel 4/BBC documentary, discusses how World War I shaped the 20th century and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/uk-uni-of-st-andrews-sir-hew-strachan-on-the-first-world-war/"&gt;UK Uni. of St Andrews&amp;#8217; Sir Hew Strachan on the First World War&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 16:56:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] Rio Grande Foundation Soiree a Huge Success!</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rio-grande-foundation-soiree-a-huge-success/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;What do you call 175 freedom loving New Mexicans gathered in one place? A good start! In all seriousness the Rio Grande Foundation hosted its 25th anniversary Laissez Faire Soiree this past Saturday night and we are pleased to report  the event was a smashing success with 175 attendees and lots of fun. Thanks to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rio-grande-foundation-soiree-a-huge-success/"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation Soiree a Huge Success!&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 19:40:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] Despite Shapiro’s Failed Leadership, 2025-26 Budget Secures Key Permitting Wins, Ends Threat of RGGI</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/11/12/pennsylvania-2025-26-budget-secures-key-permitting-wins-ends-rggi/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Harrisburg, Pa., November 12,&amp;#160;2025 —&amp;#160;Despite Gov. Josh Shapiro’s failed leadership and a 135-day stalemate, Pennsylvania lawmakers passed a compromise budget for the 2025–2026 fiscal year. The Commonwealth Foundation has released a comprehensive analysis of the newly passed budget, available here. The budget, totaling $50.09 billion, includes a 5.1 percent spending increase. While the agreement includes [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/11/12/pennsylvania-2025-26-budget-secures-key-permitting-wins-ends-rggi/"&gt;Despite Shapiro&amp;#8217;s Failed Leadership, 2025-26 Budget Secures Key Permitting Wins, Ends Threat of RGGI&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 19:42:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Volunteering for Higher Taxes? Assessing Tennessee’s Uncapped Property Taxes</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/volunteering-for-higher-taxes-assessing-tennessees-uncapped-property-taxes/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=volunteering-for-higher-taxes-assessing-tennessees-uncapped-property-taxes</link><description>If Tennessee wants to protect its residents in all aspects and truly take claim to being a low-tax state, lawmakers should look around the nation and see that we are in the small minority that fails to protect citizens from unjust property tax hikes.</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 19:52:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alaskapolicyforum] Is Anchorage’s New Proposed “Short-Term Rental-Only” Tax Really the Answer?</title><link>https://alaskapolicyforum.org/2025/11/is-anchorages-new-proposed-short-term-rental-only-tax-really-the-answer/#utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=is-anchorages-new-proposed-short-term-rental-only-tax-really-the-answer</link><description>&lt;div style="margin: 5px 5% 10px 5%;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" height="675" src="https://alaskapolicyforum.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/jon-tyson-XS_o-Iuf9Go-unsplash-scaled-e1762980183585.jpg" title="" width="506" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This blog looks at an urgent issue for Anchorage, which is considering a new short-term rental tax next week. That may seem like an easy fix for housing, but in reality, it raises seriousRead More&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alaskapolicyforum.org/2025/11/is-anchorages-new-proposed-short-term-rental-only-tax-really-the-answer/"&gt;Is Anchorage’s New Proposed “Short-Term Rental-Only” Tax Really the Answer?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://alaskapolicyforum.org"&gt;Alaska Policy Forum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 21:06:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Now that the Feds are done subsidizing EVs, sanity is rapidly returning to the U.S. auto market</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/now-that-the-feds-are-done-subsidizing-evs-sanity-is-rapidly-returning-to-the-u-s-auto-market/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Now that Congress and President Turmp have ended subsidies and regulatory favors that amounted to tens of thousands of dollars per EV, the U.S. auto market is pivoting back to physical and economic realities. The latest sign in the return to sanity is a rapid shift in emphasis from electric vehicles to hybrids. As reported...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/now-that-the-feds-are-done-subsidizing-evs-sanity-is-rapidly-returning-to-the-u-s-auto-market/"&gt;Now that the Feds are done subsidizing EVs, sanity is rapidly returning to the U.S. auto market&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 17:29:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Property Rights Victory! Prescott Hotel Greenlighted Thanks to Goldwater’s Permit Freedom Act</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/property-rights-victory-prescott-hotel-greenlighted-thanks-to-goldwaters-permit-freedom-act/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Jim Griset had a simple dream: to build a small, boutique hotel in the heart of downtown Prescott, Ariz.  He..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/property-rights-victory-prescott-hotel-greenlighted-thanks-to-goldwaters-permit-freedom-act/"&gt;Property Rights Victory! Prescott Hotel Greenlighted Thanks to Goldwater’s Permit Freedom Act&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 20:37:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] WILL Defends Rights of Christian Parent in Charter School Curriculum Controversy</title><link>https://will-law.org/will-defends-rights-of-christian-parent-in-charter-school-curriculum-controversy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On behalf of a Wisconsin parent, WILL has notified Lighthouse Learning Academy that it is prepared to take legal action over the school's refusal to provide certain curriculum materials, even though most of the items requested were non-religious, simply because some were created by a Christian publisher or contained a few religious references.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/will-defends-rights-of-christian-parent-in-charter-school-curriculum-controversy/"&gt;WILL Defends Rights of Christian Parent in Charter School Curriculum Controversy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 21:07:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Money now more important than Milton or Macbeth at UW schools</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/money-now-more-important-than-milton-or-macbeth-at-uw-schools/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Dramatically fewer University of Wisconsin System students are pursuing degrees in the humanities than a decade ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/money-now-more-important-than-milton-or-macbeth-at-uw-schools/"&gt;Money now more important than Milton or Macbeth at UW schools&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 21:10:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Most UW System schools’ enrollments are stagnant as tech colleges flourish</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/most-uw-system-schools-enrollments-are-stagnant-as-tech-colleges-flourish/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;While undergraduate enrollment in most University of Wisconsin System schools trends downward, there has been a dramatic increase in students choosing the state’s technical colleges since the pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/most-uw-system-schools-enrollments-are-stagnant-as-tech-colleges-flourish/"&gt;Most UW System schools’ enrollments are stagnant as tech colleges flourish&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 22:08:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Liberty v. the Leviathan: Senator Kennedy Champions Financial Freedom with the STREAMLINE Act</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/tax-budget/liberty-v-the-leviathan-senator-kennedy-champions-financial-freedom-with-the-streamline-act/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For over half a century, American banks and credit unions have operated under financial reporting requirements frozen in time. From 1970, to be exact. While the economy has transformed, inflation has soared, and technology has revolutionized banking, the Bank Secrecy Act&amp;#8217;s reporting thresholds have remained stubbornly unchanged. This bureaucratic inertia hasn&amp;#8217;t just created inefficiency; it&amp;#8217;s...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/tax-budget/liberty-v-the-leviathan-senator-kennedy-champions-financial-freedom-with-the-streamline-act/"&gt;Liberty v. the Leviathan: Senator Kennedy Champions Financial Freedom with the STREAMLINE Act&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 14:28:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Age Verification Comes for Artificial Intelligence</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/age-verification-comes-for-artificial-intelligence/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Artificial intelligence (AI) has long been treated as a convenient backdrop for apocalypse scenarios. When tools like ChatGPT entered the mainstream a few years ago, predictions of a looming robot takeover were rampant. With the technology’s rapid development and stunning capabilities, it&amp;#8217;s easy to imagine extreme outcomes. When these speculations drive policy, “precautionary legislation” that...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/age-verification-comes-for-artificial-intelligence/"&gt;Age Verification Comes for Artificial Intelligence&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 14:49:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] The Regulatory Burden that Prevents Abundance</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/the-regulatory-burden-that-prevents-abundance/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=the-regulatory-burden-that-prevents-abundance</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The cost-of-living has become a national issue, a favored topic of partisan debate. The debate is governed by emotions, ideology, and widely divergent economic theories, probably in that order. Our contribution to this debate, drawing on all three of those influences, is simple: Abundance lowers prices, and deregulation enables abundance. Conversely, scarcity increases prices, and...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/the-regulatory-burden-that-prevents-abundance/"&gt;The Regulatory Burden that Prevents Abundance&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 16:26:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Multnomah Audit Finds Fraud in Construction Recycling</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/economic-opportunity/multnomah-audit-finds-fraud-in-construction-recycling/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Naomi Inman What happens to all that construction debris on public works...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/economic-opportunity/multnomah-audit-finds-fraud-in-construction-recycling/"&gt;Multnomah Audit Finds Fraud in Construction Recycling&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 17:13:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Loving parents will always triumph over angry agitators</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/loving-parents-will-always-triumph-over-these-angry-agitators</link><description>A small group of agitators may be determined to intimidate parents, but the rest of Idaho shouldn’t let them. These meetings belong to families. The conversation belongs to the community.</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 17:53:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] The 4-Day School Week Doesn’t Improve Teacher Recruitment or Retention</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/education/the-4-day-school-week-doesnt-improve-teacher-recruitment-or-retention/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This is the headline finding from a recent study I conducted with researchers from several universities. The four-day school week [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/education/the-4-day-school-week-doesnt-improve-teacher-recruitment-or-retention/"&gt;The 4-Day School Week Doesn’t Improve Teacher Recruitment or Retention&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 19:44:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Week in Review: Dreams Shouldn’t Depend on Government’s Whims</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-dreams-shouldnt-depend-on-governments-whims/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When Jim Griset proposed to build a small, boutique hotel in downtown Prescott, Ariz.’s historic district, the project met every requirement..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-dreams-shouldnt-depend-on-governments-whims/"&gt;Week in Review: Dreams Shouldn’t Depend on Government’s Whims&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 20:09:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Will N.H. be the second state to leave RGGI?</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/11/will-n-h-be-the-second-state-to-leave-rggi/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Pennsylvania shocked Northeast energy policy nerds this week by withdrawing from the Regional Greenhouse Gas Initiative (RGGI). To get a state budget passed, Gov. Josh Shapiro agreed to remove Pennsylvania from the 11-state carbon cap-and-trade program, making it the first state to exit since RGGI was created in 2005.  RGGI is supposed to reduce regional [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/11/will-n-h-be-the-second-state-to-leave-rggi/"&gt;Will N.H. be the second state to leave RGGI?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 20:15:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Before the Ink Dried, the Union Was Already Calling the Shots at Waterbury Hospital</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/11/14/before-the-ink-dried-the-union-was-already-calling-the-shots-at-waterbury-hospital/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bill authorizing UConn Health to purchase Waterbury Hospital wasn’t even written when one of Connecticut’s most politically influential healthcare unions began issuing demands.   On Oct. 17 — weeks before [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/11/14/before-the-ink-dried-the-union-was-already-calling-the-shots-at-waterbury-hospital/"&gt;Before the Ink Dried, the Union Was Already Calling the Shots at Waterbury Hospital&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 20:33:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Winners and Losers: Shutdown Losers &amp; College Winners</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/winners-and-losers-shutdown-losers-college-winners/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Every Friday morning, I join the Cardle &amp;#38; Woolley Show on Talk 1370 Radio in Austin to announce the week’s Winners &amp;#38; Losers. Now that the shutdown is finally over, three Texas football teams are in the Top 10 and the Northern Lights are blasting out all over the Lone Star State, here’s who made...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/winners-and-losers-shutdown-losers-college-winners/"&gt;Winners and Losers: Shutdown Losers &amp; College Winners&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 22:18:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Discipline in Iowa income tax reform is the way forward for property tax relief</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/discipline-in-iowa-income-tax-reform-is-the-way-forward-for-property-tax-relief/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Discipline in Iowa income tax reform is the way forward for property tax relief" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/DMR-1200x630-1.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To provide sustainable tax relief, Iowa must ensure that local government budgets grow no faster than taxpayers’ ability to pay. Limiting spending, coupled with responsible budgeting, is the cornerstone of true reform. Additional steps should also be considered. Local governments can improve efficiency by consolidating services, adopting zero-based budgeting, and regularly reviewing services to eliminate duplication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/discipline-in-iowa-income-tax-reform-is-the-way-forward-for-property-tax-relief/"&gt;Discipline in Iowa income tax reform is the way forward for property tax relief&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 22:54:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Freedom notes U.S.A.: South Carolina goes farther with charters</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/freedom-notes-usa-south-carolina-goes-farther-with-charters</link><description>Oklahoma mulls property-tax reforms; Josh Shapiro didn’t get [squat] done</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Take Your Kids to Poland to Confront the Terrible History of Communism and Naziism</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/take-your-kids-to-poland-to-confront-the-terrible-history-of-communism-and-naziism/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Skip Italy and France on your next European family vacation—and go to Poland instead. Paris, Rome, and Venice don’t want you there anyway and their sights, while beautiful and romantic, are overcrowded and—if we’re being honest—pretty boring for most kids. Besides, there’s less to see at the Louvre than there used to be. Seriously, Poland should be...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/take-your-kids-to-poland-to-confront-the-terrible-history-of-communism-and-naziism/"&gt;Take Your Kids to Poland to Confront the Terrible History of Communism and Naziism&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:42:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] A legacy of healing — Documentary tells ReCAST Lawrenceville’s journey through residents’ stories</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/recast-lawrenceville-documentary/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/recast-lawrenceville-documentary/"&gt;A legacy of healing — Documentary tells ReCAST Lawrenceville’s journey through residents’ stories&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:43:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] Franke: The Thankful Month</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/11/franke-the-thankful-month/</link><description>by Mark Franke Thanksgiving Day seems late this year and by the calendar it is. Contrast that with my general sense of time’s moving much too fast, especially as I am looking at leaves still on the trees and thinking in terms of mid-October. If I am not confused enough, I have four and one-half&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/11/franke-the-thankful-month/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 13:28:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] 3 Things to Know About the Lawsuit Challenging Louisiana’s Act 409</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/legal-regulatory/3-things-to-know-about-the-lawsuit-challenging-louisianas-act-409/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;1. What Is Louisiana’s Act 409 (“Charlie’s Law”)? Everyone can agree that child safety matters—especially for three- and four-year-olds in pre-K programs. Act 409, a.k.a Charlie’s Law was intended to strengthen safety by adding new licensing and operational requirements to certain prekindergarten programs. What changed: Schools covered by Act 409 must now meet many of...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/legal-regulatory/3-things-to-know-about-the-lawsuit-challenging-louisianas-act-409/"&gt;3 Things to Know About the Lawsuit Challenging Louisiana’s Act 409&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 14:31:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Idaho should embrace performance-based funding for higher education</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/idaho-should-embrace-performance-based-funding-for-higher-education</link><description>Whether and where to attend college can be a life-changing decision with significant impacts on an individual's future job opportunities and potential debt liabilities. Students, parents, and policymakers all have a vested interest in ensuring the return on investment is worth the considerable expense.  This is why there's  a need for states to focus on performance-based funding formulas for higher education. States across the country currently differ on their ap proach to funding higher...</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 15:22:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/11/the-outstater-305/</link><description>A Defense of &amp;#8216;Christian Nationalism&amp;#8217; THE GENERATION&amp;#160;now managing our words — the activist journalists and social-media influencers — seem to think nothing happened before they were born. No, they can’t really believe that on mature reflection, but they do act like that in practice. And with that state of mind comes the compulsion to rename&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/11/the-outstater-305/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 18:13:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] New Jersey Policy Institute Announces Inaugural Class of 2026 Junior Fellows</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/11/new-jersey-policy-institute-announces-inaugural-class-of-2026-junior-fellows/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Parsippany, NJ – The New Jersey Policy Institute (NJPI) is proud to announce the inaugural class of its 2026 Junior Fellowship [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/11/new-jersey-policy-institute-announces-inaugural-class-of-2026-junior-fellows/"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute Announces Inaugural Class of 2026 Junior Fellows&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 18:43:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] New WILL Lawsuit Targets the Beating Heart of Federal DEI Programs</title><link>https://will-law.org/new-will-lawsuit-targets-the-beating-heart-of-federal-dei-programs/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL and the Center for Individual Rights (CIR) filed a major lawsuit against the Trump Administration today, targeting the foundation for many of the remaining federal DEI programs: the preference for so-called “socially disadvantaged individuals.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/new-will-lawsuit-targets-the-beating-heart-of-federal-dei-programs/"&gt;New WILL Lawsuit Targets the Beating Heart of Federal DEI Programs&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 20:38:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] We’re Destroying Meritocracy</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/education/were-destroying-meritocracy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A report released earlier this month by the University of California at San Diego (UCSD) gives some startling numbers. UCSD [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/education/were-destroying-meritocracy/"&gt;We’re Destroying Meritocracy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 21:43:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Tax relief extension critical to properties destroyed in wildfires</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/11/tax-relief-extension-critical-to-properties-destroyed-in-wildfires/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Maui County Council Special Committee on Real Property Tax Reform on Nov. 13, 2025._____________ Nov. 13, 2025, 9 a.m.Kalana O Maui Building To: Maui County Council, Special Committee on Real Property Tax Reform&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Alice Lee, Chair&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Keani Rawlins-Fernandez, Vice Chair [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/11/tax-relief-extension-critical-to-properties-destroyed-in-wildfires/"&gt;Tax relief extension critical to properties destroyed in wildfires&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 21:57:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Allow property tax exemptions to take effect the same year of filing</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/11/allow-property-tax-exemptions-to-take-effect-the-same-year-of-filing/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Maui County Council Special Committee on Real Property Tax Reform on Nov. 13, 2025._____________ Nov. 13, 2025, 9 a.m.Kalana O Maui Building To: Maui County Council, Special Committee on Real Property Tax Reform&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Alice Lee, Chair&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Keani Rawlins-Fernandez, Vice Chair [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/11/allow-property-tax-exemptions-to-take-effect-the-same-year-of-filing/"&gt;Allow property tax exemptions to take effect the same year of filing&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 21:58:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Kansas Doesn’t Need to Play Ball With Corporate Welfare</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/kansas-doesnt-need-to-play-ball/</link><description>Taxpayers want markets, not handouts, to drive growth A new SurveyUSA poll of Overland Park and Leawood residents confirms what many Kansans already feel in their gut: people love their teams, but their desire to spend tax dollars on it declines as the taxes hit closer to home.  When asked if the state should use [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 22:00:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Mississippi Voters Demand Universal School Choice – New Poll Shows Overwhelming Support</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/mississippi-voters-demand-universal-school-choice-new-poll-shows-overwhelming-support/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Big news on School Choice this week!&amp;#160; A fresh poll shows massive support in Mississippi to have&amp;#160;families, not government, control their child’s education.&amp;#160; Mississippi voters say they’ll reward lawmakers who make it happen. The brand-new statewide survey (October 27-30, 2025) conducted by The Tarrance Group shows&amp;#160;rock-solid support&amp;#160;for expanding education freedom.&amp;#160; There is massive bipartisan support [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/mississippi-voters-demand-universal-school-choice-new-poll-shows-overwhelming-support/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Voters Demand Universal School Choice – New Poll Shows Overwhelming Support&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 22:06:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] In Memory of Joseph Forshaw IV</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/uncategorized/in-memory-of-joseph-forshaw-iv/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;It is with deep sadness that I share the news of the passing of Joseph Forshaw IV, longtime member of [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/uncategorized/in-memory-of-joseph-forshaw-iv/"&gt;In Memory of Joseph Forshaw IV&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 22:18:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] After 2,500 days, Whitmer ignores her open government promise</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/after-2500-days-whitmer-ignores-her-open-government-promise</link><description>Governor has yet to apply Freedom of Information Act to her own office</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Small lots lower Illinois housing prices, even for big homes</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/small-lots-lower-illinois-housing-prices-even-for-big-homes/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A Lombard housing project shows how smaller lots can lower costs, boost development and help Illinois address its housing shortage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/small-lots-lower-illinois-housing-prices-even-for-big-homes/"&gt;Small lots lower Illinois housing prices, even for big homes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 11:00:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Illinois police pensions lock up local property taxes</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/illinois-police-pensions-lock-up-local-property-taxes/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Across Illinois, police pensions are taking an ever-greater share of property tax dollars, leaving fewer resources for public safety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/illinois-police-pensions-lock-up-local-property-taxes/"&gt;Illinois police pensions lock up local property taxes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 11:00:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Will California Finally Overhaul CEQA?</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/will-california-finally-overhaul-ceqa/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In response,  state lawmakers passed AB130 and SB131 this session, a package of bills which exempted various housing developments from California Environmental Quality Act (CEQA) review and provided streamlined review for developments which would have qualified for exemption but for one disqualifying condition. Luis Quiñonez, President of the California Foundation for Commerce and Education, heralded [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/will-california-finally-overhaul-ceqa/"&gt;Will California Finally Overhaul CEQA?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 11:00:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Washington employers are sounding the alarm. Will lawmakers listen?</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/washington-employers-are-sounding-the-alarm-will-lawmakers-listen</link><description>If you have ever wondered how many warning flares Washington policymakers need before they stop piling new taxes on employers, the answer is always, “At least one more.” An Association of Washington Business (AWB) survey  of more than 400 employers is just the latest indicator that Washington’s tax climate is stifling confidence, investment, and growth. Sixty-five percent of employers now list taxes as their top concern, up from 58 percent just months ago. Roughly three out of four businesses...</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 15:27:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Minnesota Man of the Day</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/minnesota-man-of-the-day-4/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Israel Jose Amaya-Romero, of Mexico, is our Minnesota Man of the Day. The other two contestants this Tuesday have previously earned Minnesota Man honors and are thus ineligible for repeat prizes. No matter, Mr. Amaya certainly has earned this award on the merits. He was indicted back in late April, along with a confederate, both...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/minnesota-man-of-the-day-4/"&gt;Minnesota Man of the Day&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:20:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Iowans Want Lower Property Taxes—Local Governments Must Change Course</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/iowans-want-lower-property-taxes-local-governments-must-change-course/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Iowans Want Lower Property Taxes—Local Governments Must Change Course" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="337" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/direction.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iowans overwhelmingly want property tax relief, with 72% supporting a 2% cap on total property tax collections, signaling broad bipartisan demand for reform. Local government spending is the primary driver of rising property taxes, meaning any effective reform must focus on controlling spending and improving efficiency. Governor Reynolds is urging local governments to follow the state’s example by consolidating services, modernizing operations, and adopting cost-saving measures—because without meaningful spending restraint, tax relief will remain out of reach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/iowans-want-lower-property-taxes-local-governments-must-change-course/"&gt;Iowans Want Lower Property Taxes—Local Governments Must Change Course&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:56:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Proposition 36 will work if given a chance</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/proposition-36-will-work-if-given-a-chance/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Proposition 36 was approved just one year ago, yet its detractors are already calling it a failure and urging its repeal. This is despite overwhelming support from California voters, who passed the measure in every one of the state’s 58 counties. Their message was clear: Californians want accountability and treatment for drug offenders. When properly [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/proposition-36-will-work-if-given-a-chance/"&gt;Proposition 36 will work if given a chance&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 18:01:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] 7 years in prison for fraud</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/7-years-in-prison-for-fraud/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Tezzaree El Amin Champion, age 28, was sentenced to seven years in prison for fraud yesterday at the federal courthouse in downtown Minneapolis. Prosecutors had asked for a 12-year sentence. In pre-sentence filings, the defense didn&amp;#8217;t suggest a number other than &amp;#8220;less.&amp;#8221; MPR News reports, COVID loan fraudster gets 7 years, ordered to repay $3.5M...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/7-years-in-prison-for-fraud/"&gt;7 years in prison for fraud&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 18:43:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Update tax deduction eligibility for affordable rentals</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/11/amend-tax-deduction-eligibility-for-affordable-rentals/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Honolulu City Council Committee on Budget on Nov. 18, 2025._____________ Nov. 18, 2025, 9 a.m.Honolulu Hale To: Honolulu City Council Committee on Budget       Val Okimoto, Chair        Scott Nishimoto, Vice Chair From: Grassroot Institute of Hawaii            Ted Kefalas, Director of Strategic [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/11/amend-tax-deduction-eligibility-for-affordable-rentals/"&gt;Update tax deduction eligibility for affordable rentals&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 18:52:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Fighting For Government Transparency at the Arizona Supreme Court</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/fighting-for-government-transparency-at-the-arizona-supreme-court/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Transparency is the rule for public records in Arizona, and for good reason: sunshine, as the saying goes, is the..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/fighting-for-government-transparency-at-the-arizona-supreme-court/"&gt;Fighting For Government Transparency at the Arizona Supreme Court&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 19:38:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Walz’s Texas-Sized LIES</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/walzs-texas-sized-lies/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome back to the American Experiment Podcast!&amp;#160; This week, Bill Walsh joins Grace and Kathryn to stop the tape on Governor Walz’s trip down to Texas. In an event with the Texas Tribune, Governor Walz claims the old state flag was “racist,” and it doesn’t matter who’s “using the urinal next to you.” After that, John...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/walzs-texas-sized-lies/"&gt;Walz&amp;#8217;s Texas-Sized LIES&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 20:14:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] CPC board promotes Will Swaim to CEO, Jackson Reese to President</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/cpc-board-promotes/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=cpc-board-promotes</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The California Policy Center is pleased to announce that Will Swaim has been named Chief Executive Officer of the organization, and longtime Executive Vice President Jackson Reese has been promoted to President. The board approved the promotions to ensure CPC’s continued growth and long-term mission. Swaim will continue leading CPC as CEO, advancing the organization’s...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/cpc-board-promotes/"&gt;CPC board promotes Will Swaim to CEO, Jackson Reese to President&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 20:50:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] A blueprint for property tax reform in Iowa</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/a-blueprint-for-property-tax-reform-in-iowa/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="A blueprint for property tax reform in Iowa" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/the-gazette-1200x630-1.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just a few years ago, the Tax Foundation ranked Iowa among the worst states for business tax climates. In 2020, Iowa placed 43rd in the State Tax Competitiveness Index. Thanks to the pro-growth policies of Gov. Kim Reynolds and the Legislature, Iowa has since climbed to 17th — a remarkable improvement. Yet despite this progress, Iowa still ranks 33rd nationally in property tax burden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/a-blueprint-for-property-tax-reform-in-iowa/"&gt;A blueprint for property tax reform in Iowa&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 20:53:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] The High Class Problem of Too Much Broadband Money</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/the-high-class-problem-of-too-much-broadband-money/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Broadband Equity, Access, and Deployment (BEAD) program, established by Congress in 2021, set aside an unprecedented $42.45...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/the-high-class-problem-of-too-much-broadband-money/"&gt;The High Class Problem of Too Much Broadband Money&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 21:53:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] McGowan:  Other Pitchers Who Could Hit</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/11/mcgowan-other-pitchers-who-could-hit/</link><description>by Richard McGowan, Ph.D. Now that the final 2025 MLB baseball game has been played, fans can start dissecting the past season.&amp;#160; Of course, that also means examining the media coverage of the season, especially during the&amp;#160; playoffs. Some observations easily avail themselves.&amp;#160; If Ohtani’s greatness is owed in part to his being a two-way&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/11/mcgowan-other-pitchers-who-could-hit/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 22:37:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Repealing Medicaid Expansion Is the Right Move for Idaho</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/repealing-medicaid-expansion-is-the-right-move-for-idaho/</link><description>The term cognitive dissonance is applied to people who hold two conflicting beliefs in their heads at the same time. In no other public policy is this more apparent than how Idaho has handled the topic of Medicaid expansion to able-bodied adults in Idaho. Let’s provide some details: Right out of the gate, in its [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 22:57:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Soros supported British group seeking to censor conservatives</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/soros-supported-british-group-seeking-to-censor-conservatives/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Chuck Ross writes for the Washington Free Beacon about the controversial funding source of a group fighting against free speech. The left-wing philanthropy funded by George Soros, Open Society Foundations (OSF), bankrolls a British nonprofit that works to censor conservative news websites and social media companies, including through a plot to &amp;#8220;kill&amp;#8221; Elon Musk’s X...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/soros-supported-british-group-seeking-to-censor-conservatives/"&gt;Soros supported British group seeking to censor conservatives&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 10:36:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] New WOTUS rule would stop federal regulation of puddles</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/new-wotus-rule-would-stop-federal-regulation-of-puddles/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Beth Brelje writes for the Federalist about a significant federal environmental rule change. The Trump administration is about to curb an overzealous Obama-era environmental regulation by revising the definition of “Waters of the United States” (WOTUS) under the Clean Water Act. U.S. Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) Administrator Lee Zeldin and Adam Telle, assistant secretary of...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/new-wotus-rule-would-stop-federal-regulation-of-puddles/"&gt;New WOTUS rule would stop federal regulation of puddles&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 10:39:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Hanson argues reality caught up with climate alarmists</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/hanson-argues-reality-caught-up-with-climate-alarmists/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Victor Davis Hanson writes about the latest setbacks for climate alarmists. For decades, the monolithic and sacrosanct international climate change hierarchy went unquestioned. Western nations in particular spent trillions of dollars over the past half-century to subsidize expensive but erratic wind and solar energy while demonizing carbon fuels as toxic threats to the planet. Like...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/hanson-argues-reality-caught-up-with-climate-alarmists/"&gt;Hanson argues reality caught up with climate alarmists&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 10:42:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Michigan can easily handle adding data centers</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/michigan-can-easily-handle-adding-data-centers</link><description>Do you realize how much more water we use in other activities?</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] 5 ways to end Chicago’s stagnant growth</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/5-ways-to-end-chicagos-stagnant-growth/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;High taxes, red tape and fiscal mismanagement have stalled Chicago’s economy, but smart reform could get it growing again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/5-ways-to-end-chicagos-stagnant-growth/"&gt;5 ways to end Chicago’s stagnant growth&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 11:00:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] The BASIC Fund Gives Hope for a Better Education to Low-Income Children</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/the-basic-fund-gives-hope-for-a-better-education-to-low-income-children/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;According to the organization, “Scholarships are awarded on a sliding scale, covering 25%, 50%, or 75% of the Family Portion of the school’s tuition up to a maximum of $2,750 annually per child.”  Thus, parents are asked to fund part of their child’s private school costs to ensure that the family has a stake in [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/the-basic-fund-gives-hope-for-a-better-education-to-low-income-children/"&gt;The BASIC Fund Gives Hope for a Better Education to Low-Income Children&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 11:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Study: Accessory Dwelling Units Now Legal Statewide, but Construction Still Lags</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/economic_opportunity/study-accessory-dwelling-units-now-legal-statewide-but-construction-still-lags/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;BOSTON – Even after statewide legalization in 2024, production of accessory dwelling units (ADUs) in Massachusetts remains far from that of other states due to local zoning and permitting practices that continue to discourage development, according to a new Pioneer Institute study. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/economic_opportunity/study-accessory-dwelling-units-now-legal-statewide-but-construction-still-lags/"&gt;Study: Accessory Dwelling Units Now Legal Statewide, but Construction Still Lags&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 12:51:47 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>