<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>State-Policy Think-Tank Digest</title><link>https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml</link><description>Latest posts from free-market policy institutes across the U.S.</description><atom:link href="https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 18:13:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Nebraska’s Tax Code Lets It Compete for Data Center Investment</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/nebraskas-tax-code-lets-it-compete-for-data-center-investment/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Midwest grows many things—including, increasingly, data centers. That’s good news, generating substantial local tax revenue, creating high-paying jobs, and expanding economic opportunities.  With 39 data centers (about 19 per 1 million people), Nebraska punches above its weight nationally, while trailing neighboring Iowa, which boasts the second-highest number of data centers per capita at 32...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/nebraskas-tax-code-lets-it-compete-for-data-center-investment/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Nebraska’s Tax Code Lets It Compete for Data Center Investment&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 17:26:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Shaping Georgia’s future: Opportunities for the year ahead</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/top-issues-shaping-georgia-future/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The well-being of many Georgians, their families, and their communities is at stake as pressing concerns like welfare reform, the cost of living, educational opportunities, and public safety take center stage in 2026. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/top-issues-shaping-georgia-future/"&gt;Shaping Georgia’s future: Opportunities for the year ahead&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 23:49:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] HB2 – Mississippi’s School Choice Bill is Here!</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/hb2-mississippis-school-choice-bill-is-here/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Last week, House Speaker Jason White unveiled&amp;#160;HB2, the&amp;#160;Mississippi Education Freedom Act - the most exciting and ambitious advancement for school choice in our state in years, perhaps ever!&amp;#160;This comprehensive bill delivers everything supporters of parental power have long hoped for, and it aligns perfectly with President Trump’s strong commitment to education freedom.&amp;#160;This isn’t some minor [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/hb2-mississippis-school-choice-bill-is-here/" rel="nofollow"&gt;HB2 – Mississippi’s School Choice Bill is Here!&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 17:31:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] ABQ Journal opinion piece: More investigative journalism is a must</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/abq-journal-opinion-piece-more-investigative-journalism-is-a-must/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following appeared in Albuquerque Journal on January 11, 2026. The Albuquerque Journal recently made appeals on its pages for donations to increase investigative journalism efforts. Even though the Rio Grande Foundation is in direct competition for limited donor dollars, we applaud the paper for focusing attention on investigative journalism currently. The issue of investigative journalism is [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/abq-journal-opinion-piece-more-investigative-journalism-is-a-must/"&gt;ABQ Journal opinion piece: More investigative journalism is a must&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 19:54:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] ABQ Ethics Board Dismisses frivolous “sweatshirt-gate” ethics complaint made by Keller campaign against RGF’s Paul Gessing</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/abq-ethics-board-dismisses-frivolous-sweatshirt-gate-ethics-complaint-made-by-keller-campaign-against-rgfs-paul-gessing/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This afternoon in a hearing, the Albuquerque Board of Ethics (BOE) unanimously dismissed a complaint filed by Daymon Ely for the Tim Keller campaign that was made against Rio Grande Foundation president Paul Gessing. The complaint arose out of the Foundation’s reporting over the purchase and delivery of yellow hoodie sweatshirts to members of Albuquerque’s [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/abq-ethics-board-dismisses-frivolous-sweatshirt-gate-ethics-complaint-made-by-keller-campaign-against-rgfs-paul-gessing/"&gt;ABQ Ethics Board Dismisses frivolous “sweatshirt-gate” ethics complaint made by Keller campaign against RGF’s Paul Gessing&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 22:08:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cardinalinstitute] 2026 State of the State Response</title><link>https://cardinalinstitute.com/2026-state-of-the-state-response/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;2026 State of the State Response On Wednesday evening, Governor Patrick Morrisey delivered his annual State of the State address, outlining his priorities for the year ahead and offering a window into his governing philosophy. As is customary, the speech functioned as both pep rally and agenda-setting exercise. State of the state addresses tend to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com/2026-state-of-the-state-response/"&gt;2026 State of the State Response&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com"&gt;Cardinal Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 15:07:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF opinion piece: Data centers are coming: How to handle them</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-opinion-piece-data-centers-are-coming-how-to-handle-them/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following appeared in the Santa Fe New Mexican on January 10, 2026. It has appeared in several other publications as well. &amp;#160; After years of failure to land a “big fish” business for New Mexico’s economy (or effectively use the oil and gas revenues to grow the economy) Gov. Michelle Lujan Grisham, with the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-opinion-piece-data-centers-are-coming-how-to-handle-them/"&gt;RGF opinion piece: Data centers are coming: How to handle them&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 15:48:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Bothfield v. WEC &amp; WBLD v WEC</title><link>https://will-law.org/bothfield-v-wec-wbld-v-wec/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On behalf of Wisconsin voters in all 8 of the state's congressional districts, WILL filed motions to intervene in two lawsuits seeking to overturn Wisconsin’s Congressional Maps. Seeking again to defend those maps on behalf of a group of Wisconsin voters, WILL argues that these new lawsuits are time-barred, the three-judge panel lacks authority to overrule the Wisconsin Supreme Court, and any attempt to impose new maps in this manner would violate federal law and the U.S. Constitution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/bothfield-v-wec-wbld-v-wec/"&gt;Bothfield v. WEC &amp;#038; WBLD v WEC&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 21:19:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Rifreedom] “Doc” Skoly Stepping Down as Center’s Chair to Pursue Congressional Seat</title><link>https://rifreedom.org/2026/01/doc-skoly-stepping-down-as-centers-chair-to-pursue-congressional-seat/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The  Rhode Island Center for Freedom &amp;#038; Prosperity announced today that Dr. Stephen "Doc" Skoly has stepped down as Chairman of its Board of Directors to pursue a run for the US House of Representatives in Rhode Island's second Congressional district.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org/2026/01/doc-skoly-stepping-down-as-centers-chair-to-pursue-congressional-seat/"&gt;&amp;#8220;Doc&amp;#8221; Skoly Stepping Down as Center&amp;#8217;s Chair to Pursue Congressional Seat&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org"&gt;RI Center for Freedom and Prosperity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 15:10:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Policy Pathway for Principled Tax Reform</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/policy-pathway-for-principled-tax-reform/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Policy Pathway for Principled Tax Reform outlines a framework for evaluating tax policy through the lens of sound tax principles including transparency, simplicity, stability, neutrality, and economic efficiency. The report examines Nebraska’s major tax types including property, income, and sales and offers practical, principle-based recommendations to improve affordability, competitiveness, and long-term fiscal sustainability. While designed...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/policy-pathway-for-principled-tax-reform/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Policy Pathway for Principled Tax Reform&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 19:40:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cardinalinstitute] Healthcare in West Virginia</title><link>https://cardinalinstitute.com/healthcare-in-west-virginia/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Healthcare in West Virginia Healthcare policy is complicated. These resources make it understandable. If you are trying to make sense of West Virginia’s latest healthcare debates, you are not alone. PBM regulation, PEIA’s recurring funding crises, and Certificate of Need laws all affect what care costs, where it is available, and who has choices. We [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com/healthcare-in-west-virginia/"&gt;Healthcare in West Virginia&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com"&gt;Cardinal Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 15:44:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Wisconsin Senate Passes WILL-Backed ﻿Amendment to End Tax-Veto Loopholes</title><link>https://will-law.org/wisconsin-senate-passes-will-backed-amendment-to-end-tax-veto-loopholes/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL issued a statement applauding the Wisconsin State Senate for passing Senate Joint Resolution 116 (SJR 116). This proposed amendment to the Wisconsin Constitution curbs executive overreach by prohibiting the governor from using the partial veto to create or increase taxes or fees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/wisconsin-senate-passes-will-backed-amendment-to-end-tax-veto-loopholes/"&gt;Wisconsin Senate Passes WILL-Backed ﻿Amendment to End Tax-Veto Loopholes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 17:40:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] WILL-Backed Equality Amendment ﻿On November 2026 Ballot</title><link>https://will-law.org/will-backed-equality-amendment-on-november-2026-ballot/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The “Equality Amendment,” otherwise known as Assembly Joint Resolution 102 (AJR 102) will be on the November 2026 ballot after the Wisconsin State Senate voted in favor today. The Wisconsin State Assembly passed the amendment last week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/will-backed-equality-amendment-on-november-2026-ballot/"&gt;WILL-Backed Equality Amendment ﻿On November 2026 Ballot&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 20:58:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Cascade Policy Institute is Hiring – Development Assistant</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/news/cascade-policy-institute-is-hiring-development-assistant/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;We are seeking a detail-oriented, organized, part-time Development Assistant to support Cascade Policy...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/news/cascade-policy-institute-is-hiring-development-assistant/"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute is Hiring &amp;#8211; Development Assistant&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 23:07:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Understanding welfare work requirements: new eligibility rules for SNAP and Medicaid</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/understanding-snap-and-medicaid-work-requirements/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Big changes are in process for some recipients of Medicaid and Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP or food stamps) benefits and for the state governments that administer the programs. See a breakdown of the changes and who they will actually affect. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/understanding-snap-and-medicaid-work-requirements/"&gt;Understanding welfare work requirements: new eligibility rules for SNAP and Medicaid&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 18:53:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Prospect of open enrollment is already prompting talk of improving public schools’ appeal</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2026/01/prospect-of-open-enrollment-is-already-prompting-talk-of-improving-public-schools-appeal/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A bill to create universal open enrollment for New Hampshire public schools is already prompting school boards to consider marketing their districts to families. And the bill hasn&amp;#8217;t passed either chamber of the Legislature yet. Senate Bill 101, sponsored by Sen. Tim Lang, R-Sanbornton, would require all school districts to &amp;#8220;establish an open enrollment policy [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2026/01/prospect-of-open-enrollment-is-already-prompting-talk-of-improving-public-schools-appeal/"&gt;Prospect of open enrollment is already prompting talk of improving public schools&amp;#8217; appeal&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 20:45:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] If You Want Parent Power, Only HB2 Will Do</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/if-you-want-parent-power-only-hb2-will-do/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past few years, Mississippi lawmakers have passed some critical conservative reforms.&amp;#160;Last year, Mississippi became the first state in America to legislate to eliminate the income tax in 40 years.&amp;#160; In 2022, we implemented flat tax reform.&amp;#160; A few years before that, we passed important labor market reforms.&amp;#160; In 2024, we reformed school funding [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/if-you-want-parent-power-only-hb2-will-do/" rel="nofollow"&gt;If You Want Parent Power, Only HB2 Will Do&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 16:09:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] A Trillion Dollar Energy Law – HB2021: Watch John Charles on PDX Real</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/environment/a-trillion-dollar-energy-law-hb2021-watch-john-charles-on-pdx-real/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;“All we want as consumers is reliable, affordable energy.” ~John A. Charles, Jr.,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/environment/a-trillion-dollar-energy-law-hb2021-watch-john-charles-on-pdx-real/"&gt;A Trillion Dollar Energy Law &amp;#8211; HB2021: Watch John Charles on PDX Real&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 00:12:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Rifreedom] MEDIA RELEASE: Center Launches Petition Calling for Affordable Energy Policies</title><link>https://rifreedom.org/2026/01/media-release-center-launches-petition-calling-for-affordable-energy-policies/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Rhode Island Center for Freedom &amp;#038; Prosperity today announced that it has launched an online petition drive calling for policymakers to support a fundamental pivot away from our state's current energy strategy, which will lead to staggeringly high electricity prices and potentially dangerous blackouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org/2026/01/media-release-center-launches-petition-calling-for-affordable-energy-policies/"&gt;MEDIA RELEASE: Center Launches Petition Calling for Affordable Energy Policies&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org"&gt;RI Center for Freedom and Prosperity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 14:19:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Orlando Sentinel: Will the Legislature Keep Its Eye on the Ball?</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/orlando-sentinel-will-the-legislature-keep-its-eye-on-the-ball/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As the curtain fell on 2025 and I looked at the coming legislative session with my team, a...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/orlando-sentinel-will-the-legislature-keep-its-eye-on-the-ball/"&gt;Orlando Sentinel: Will the Legislature Keep Its Eye on the Ball?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 17:43:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Connecticut’s Census Numbers: Impressively Average</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/01/28/connecticuts-census-numbers-impressively-average/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="1024" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/ChatGPT-Image-Jan-28-2026-at-01_40_11-PM.png" width="1536" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Jan. 21, the U.S. Census Bureau released its 2024 State-to-State Migration Flows, offering a clearer picture of how Connecticut’s population is shifting. The data confirms what many suspected: the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/01/28/connecticuts-census-numbers-impressively-average/"&gt;Connecticut’s Census Numbers: Impressively Average &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 18:40:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] California’s Drought is Over, But We Still Must Invest in Water Supply Projects</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/californias-drought-is-over-but-we-still-must-invest-in-water-supply-projects/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=californias-drought-is-over-but-we-still-must-invest-in-water-supply-projects</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For the last 25 years, the US Drought Monitor (USDM), a collaborative effort by the University of Nebraska, NOAA, the USDA, and other experts throughout the country, has released a weekly map that shows the location and intensity of drought across the United States. On January 8, for the first time ever, USDM’s weekly map showed the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/californias-drought-is-over-but-we-still-must-invest-in-water-supply-projects/"&gt;California’s Drought is Over, But We Still Must Invest in Water Supply Projects&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 19:25:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Open enrollment: Know the basics</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2026/01/open-enrollment-know-the-basics/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In 2025, New Hampshire legislators passed a law allowing students to enroll in any public school within their assigned district, as long as the school had room. This year, lawmakers might allow students to enroll in any New Hampshire public school that has room. This policy brief answers six core questions commonly raised about open [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2026/01/open-enrollment-know-the-basics/"&gt;Open enrollment: Know the basics&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 19:28:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] The Hill: School Choice in Florida Offers Wild and Imaginative Learning Options</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/the-hill-school-choice-in-florida-offers-wild-and-imaginative-learning-options/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Of the thousands of events commemorating this year’s National School Choice Week, the wildest and most imaginative may...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/the-hill-school-choice-in-florida-offers-wild-and-imaginative-learning-options/"&gt;The Hill: School Choice in Florida Offers Wild and Imaginative Learning Options&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 20:07:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Poll Finds Massachusetts Residents Overwhelmingly Support Expanding Vocational Schools</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/poll-finds-massachusetts-residents-overwhelmingly-support-expanding-vocational-schools/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A new statewide poll finds overwhelming support among Massachusetts adults for expanding vocational-technical high school capacity, along with broad backing for school choice options, including the new Federal Tax Credit Scholarship Program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/poll-finds-massachusetts-residents-overwhelmingly-support-expanding-vocational-schools/"&gt;Poll Finds Massachusetts Residents Overwhelmingly Support Expanding Vocational Schools&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 14:37:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] Day One, Energy First: Governor Mikie Sherrill’s Opening Strategy on Affordability</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/01/day-one-energy-first-governor-mikie-sherrills-opening-strategy-on-affordability/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Sean Barry, NJPI Jr. Fellow When Governor Mikie Sherrill was sworn in as New Jersey’s 57th governor, she did [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/01/day-one-energy-first-governor-mikie-sherrills-opening-strategy-on-affordability/"&gt;Day One, Energy First: Governor Mikie Sherrill’s Opening Strategy on Affordability&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 19:08:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] A New Governor Takes Office. Will She Deliver on Education?</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/01/a-new-governor-takes-office-will-she-deliver-on-education/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;by Aiden DeMarsey, NJPI Jr. Fellow &amp;#160; Governor Mikie Sherrill, sworn into office last week, enters her term with a [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/01/a-new-governor-takes-office-will-she-deliver-on-education/"&gt;A New Governor Takes Office. Will She Deliver on Education?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 19:10:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] A foolish law wages war against homemade shindigs</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/a-foolish-law-wages-war-against-homemade-shindigs/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The law, passed in 2023, decrees that venues rented for private events at which the people holding the party bring their own alcohol can host only six such events a year, and only one a month — unless they prohibit bring-your-own drinks and instead get a liquor license like a tavern. Those are subject to strict quotas. Town board can simply refuse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/a-foolish-law-wages-war-against-homemade-shindigs/"&gt;A foolish law wages war against homemade shindigs&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 19:33:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Weingarten’s answer ignores her painful reality</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/teachers-unions/weingartens-answer-ignores-her-painful-reality/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Randi Weingarten didn’t ascend to the presidency of the powerful American Federation of Teachers (AFT) without learning how to mask lies in half-truth. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/teachers-unions/weingartens-answer-ignores-her-painful-reality/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Weingarten’s answer ignores her painful reality&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 22:32:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2026/01/the-outstater-324/</link><description>Return of the 1-Room Schoolhouse SCHOOL CHOICE,&amp;#160;an issue championed by the Indiana Policy Review Foundation since its beginning, has taken root. Thirty-four states&amp;#160;including Indiana have adopted some form of school choice, with 1.5 million students participating. Now another of the foundation’s early recommendations, micro schools, is gaining attention&amp;#160;as well — a high-tech version of the&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2026/01/the-outstater-324/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 13:14:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] New housing permits are highest since 2006, but single-family homes lag</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2026/01/new-housing-permits-are-highest-since-2006-but-single-family-homes-lag/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New Hampshire towns and cities are permitting more residential housing units than they have in years, which is great news. But the new units are skewed heavily toward rentals, suggesting that local restrictions on small, single-family homes remain a significant barrier. Local governments issued permits for 5,822 new housing units in 2024, the highest number [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2026/01/new-housing-permits-are-highest-since-2006-but-single-family-homes-lag/"&gt;New housing permits are highest since 2006, but single-family homes lag&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:16:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Gotta Know When to Fold ‘Em: the FTC Resumes Its Antitrust Aggression</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/ftc-antitrust-agresssion/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Last week, the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) appealed a federal court ruling that Meta antitrust does not have an unlawful social media monopoly. The agency’s decision to persist ignores a highly competitive social media landscape, a well-supported judicial opinion, and the cost to taxpayers. In doing so, it gambles with the legitimacy of the FTC...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/ftc-antitrust-agresssion/"&gt;Gotta Know When to Fold ‘Em: the FTC Resumes Its Antitrust Aggression&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:47:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Approved in the Shadows: Connecticut’s Next Electric Rate Hike Is Already Locked In</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/01/30/approved-in-the-shadows-connecticuts-next-electric-rate-hike-is-already-locked-in/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connecticut residents don’t need to wait for their next utility bill to know electricity is about to get more expensive. The policy framework driving higher costs has already been approved [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/01/30/approved-in-the-shadows-connecticuts-next-electric-rate-hike-is-already-locked-in/"&gt;Approved in the Shadows: Connecticut’s Next Electric Rate Hike Is Already Locked In&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:55:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] The Denial of Distinctions</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/the-denial-of-distinctions/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Denial of Distinctions By Abe Greenwald Yesterday, I wrote about the return of American disorder in the form of mobs that obstruct ICE raids. Part of what makes anti-ICE/open-border activism so strange is that it attacks the most fundamental aspect of what it means to be a country: its physical boundaries. When leftists repeat, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/the-denial-of-distinctions/"&gt;The Denial of Distinctions&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:37:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Crime is down, and it should end ‘root cause’ excuse-making for good</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/crime-is-down-and-it-should-end-root-cause-excuse-making-for-good/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/crime-is-down-and-it-should-end-root-cause-excuse-making-for-good/"&gt;Crime is down, and it should end ‘root cause’ excuse-making for good&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 22:13:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Federal Investigation Finds California Department of Education Violated FERPA by Keeping Secrets from Parents</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/federal-investigation-finds-california-department-of-education-violated-ferpa-by-keeping-secrets-from-parents/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=federal-investigation-finds-california-department-of-education-violated-ferpa-by-keeping-secrets-from-parents</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Department of Education announced this week that its investigation into the California Department of Education found that state policies that pressure schools to keep secrets from parents violate federal law. Specifically, the DOE said the “California Department of Education (CDE) is in continued violation of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA)—a federal law...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/federal-investigation-finds-california-department-of-education-violated-ferpa-by-keeping-secrets-from-parents/"&gt;Federal Investigation Finds California Department of Education Violated FERPA by Keeping Secrets from Parents&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 23:34:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] From a Mother’s Struggle to a Thriving Academy: The Story of Knox Academy</title><link>https://empowerms.org/from-a-mothers-struggle-to-a-thriving-academy-the-story-of-knox-academy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When Julie Gilliland first sat in doctors’ offices years ago, hearing predictions about her son John Knox, the words felt heavy and discouraging. Again and again, she was told that his autism was severe and that traditional paths might not offer him the support he would need to thrive in school or everyday settings.  But Julie refused to&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/from-a-mothers-struggle-to-a-thriving-academy-the-story-of-knox-academy/"&gt;From a Mother’s Struggle to a Thriving Academy: The Story of Knox Academy&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 14:50:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Sedgwick County Commissioners use scare tactics and false claim to oppose property tax assessment limit</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/sedgwick-assessment-limit-scare-tactics/</link><description>Neutral testimony from the Kansas Association of Counties on the proposed 3% valuation assessment limit says, “The major benefit for taxpayers is predictability,” and notes that predictability could also help counties by having fewer disputes over valuations. Sedgwick County Commissioners, on the other hand, are taking a ‘sky is falling’ approach replete with scare tactics [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 16:56:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] Keating: Drama at the Federal Reserve</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2026/02/keating-drama-at-the-federal-reserve/</link><description>by Maryann O. Keating, Ph.D. The Trump-Powell feud over the interest rate is Shakespearean. Who knew that monetary policy could be so riveting? At this point, Kevin Warsh has emerged from a list of pretenders as President Trump’s nominee for the next Chairman of the Federal Reserve (Fed), replacing Jerome Powell. &amp;#160; The big question&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2026/02/keating-drama-at-the-federal-reserve/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 12:53:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Introducing TennSight, Tennessee’s only hub for voter insights</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/introducing-tennsight-tennessees-only-hub-for-voter-insights/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=introducing-tennsight-tennessees-only-hub-for-voter-insights</link><description>We hope that TennSight will become the go-to source for you to learn what matters most to your fellow Tennesseans, why it matters, and what can be done about it.</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 13:08:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Professor Illegally Forced into DEI Training Deserves His Day in Court</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/professor-illegally-forced-into-dei-training-deserves-his-day-in-court/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When Arizona State University professor Owen Anderson was illegally forced to take a diversity, equity, and inclusion (DEI) training to..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/professor-illegally-forced-into-dei-training-deserves-his-day-in-court/"&gt;Professor Illegally Forced into DEI Training Deserves His Day in Court&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 14:57:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] A Steady-State Budget in a Moment of Crisis</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/a-steady-state-budget-in-a-moment-of-crisis/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Governor Maura Healey’s fiscal year 2027 budget totals $62.8 billion, a 3.8 percent year-over-year increase. The budget avoids sweeping new initiatives and largely preserves existing structures. That might be defensible in a period of stability. It is indefensible now. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/a-steady-state-budget-in-a-moment-of-crisis/"&gt;A Steady-State Budget in a Moment of Crisis &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 16:44:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Idaho schools paying $1.2 million per year for IEA/NEA dues</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/labor/idaho-schools-paying-1-2-million-per-year-for-iea-nea-dues/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;According to a new Freedom Foundation analysis, the Boise and Twin Falls School Districts are spending more than $1.2 million per year on programs to cover the cost of teachers union dues to the Idaho Education Association. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/labor/idaho-schools-paying-1-2-million-per-year-for-iea-nea-dues/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Idaho schools paying $1.2 million per year for IEA/NEA dues&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 17:33:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Beacon Poll: January 2026 Results</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/beacon-poll-january-2026-results/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=beacon-poll-january-2026-results</link><description>Today, we released the latest installment of the Beacon Poll, a statewide survey of 1,200 Tennessee voters featuring questions about voters’ views on property taxes, the federal school choice tax credit included in the One Big Beautiful Bill Act, and political approval ratings at the state and federal level, and more. Tennesseans continue to prioritize key...</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 19:35:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Johnson County superintendents fail 4th-grade math</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/johnson-county-supers-fail-4th-grade-math/</link><description>Today’s math riddle is brought to you by Johnson County school superintendents: How can taxpayers give school districts hundreds of millions of dollars more for special education without increasing total spending or cutting other state funding? The obvious answer is that it’s not possible, but that is what they tell taxpayers, and in their pitch [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 00:15:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] Education Freedom Day held outside Alabama State House</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2026/02/03/education-freedom-day-held-outside-alabama-state-house/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Education Freedom Day was celebrated on the front steps of the Alabama State House to highlight the different school choice options available to Alabamians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2026/02/03/education-freedom-day-held-outside-alabama-state-house/"&gt;Education Freedom Day held outside Alabama State House&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 09:15:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Yankee Institute Releases 2026 Legislative Agenda Focused on Affordability and Fiscal Stability</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/02/03/yankee-institute-releases-2026-legislative-agenda-focused-on-affordability-and-fiscal-stability/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As the 2026 legislative session convenes on Feb. 4, Yankee Institute has released its policy agenda aimed at keeping Connecticut affordable, livable, and workable for families, businesses, and communities across the state.  The agenda focuses on safeguarding long-term fiscal stability and addressing the key cost [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/02/03/yankee-institute-releases-2026-legislative-agenda-focused-on-affordability-and-fiscal-stability/"&gt;Yankee Institute Releases 2026 Legislative Agenda Focused on Affordability and Fiscal Stability&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 14:20:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Arizona Moves to Permanently End DEI Through Constitutional Reform</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/arizona-moves-to-permanently-end-dei-through-constitutional-reform/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Arizona lawmakers are advancing what will be the strongest state-level safeguard in the country against race-based “diversity, equity, and inclusion”..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/arizona-moves-to-permanently-end-dei-through-constitutional-reform/"&gt;Arizona Moves to Permanently End DEI Through Constitutional Reform&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 15:53:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Age Verification Isn’t Parenting</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/age-verification-isnt-parenting/</link><description>Kansas lawmakers are weighing a proposal that would require new age-verification measures for online platforms, part of a growing national effort to address concerns about children’s safety in digital spaces. The goal is understandable. Parents across Kansas want their kids protected online. The harder question is how far government should go—and whether mandates aimed at [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 16:00:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] To the Missouri House Elementary and Secondary Education Committee: We Have a Problem</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/article/education/to-the-missouri-house-elementary-and-secondary-education-committee-we-have-a-problem/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I attended the Missouri House Elementary and Secondary Education Committee hearing on Wednesday, January 28. The hearing covered two bills under current consideration—one on A–F letter grades for schools, and [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/article/education/to-the-missouri-house-elementary-and-secondary-education-committee-we-have-a-problem/"&gt;To the Missouri House Elementary and Secondary Education Committee: We Have a Problem&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 17:54:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Dr. John Dixon: Charter Schools, Choice, and Accountability</title><link>https://empowerms.org/dr-john-dixon-charter-schools-choice-and-accountability/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Dr. John Dixon: Charter Schools, Choice, and Accountability As the 2026 legislative session moves forward, the conversation around school choice continues to intensify. While much of the focus has been on ESAs and public school transfers, one form of public school choice has quietly served thousands of Mississippi families for years: public charter schools. In&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/dr-john-dixon-charter-schools-choice-and-accountability/"&gt;Dr. John Dixon: Charter Schools, Choice, and Accountability&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 18:41:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] The TIF that Keeps Taking</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/article/corporate-welfare/the-tif-that-keeps-taking/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Thomas Friestad at the Kansas City Business Journal wrote recently that an engineering firm (Gannett Fleming TranSystems, formerly GFT) is moving its offices to the H&amp;#38;R Block building in downtown [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/article/corporate-welfare/the-tif-that-keeps-taking/"&gt;The TIF that Keeps Taking&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 19:16:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] A State of the State Built on “You’re Welcome”</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/a-state-of-the-state-built-on-youre-welcome/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Last week Governor Janet Mills delivered her final State of the State address. The hour-long speech was heavy on reflection and self-congratulation. Again and again, the Governor reminded Mainers, sometimes explicitly, that we should be thanking her for her governance. But self gratitude is not a governing philosophy. And after seven years in office, Mainers [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/a-state-of-the-state-built-on-youre-welcome/"&gt;A State of the State Built on “You’re Welcome”&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 20:59:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Prohibit counties from imposing inclusionary zoning mandates</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/02/prohibit-counties-from-imposing-inclusionary-zoning-mandates/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Senate Committee on Housing on Feb. 3, 2026._____________ Feb. 3, 2026, 1 p.m.Hawaii State CapitolConference Room 225 and Videoconference To: Senate Committee on Housing&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Sen. Stanley Chang, Chair&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Sen. Troy N. Hashimoto, Vice-Chair From: Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Ted Kefalas, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/02/prohibit-counties-from-imposing-inclusionary-zoning-mandates/"&gt;Prohibit counties from imposing inclusionary zoning mandates&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 21:58:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Increase number of bedrooms allowed per wastewater system</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/02/increase-number-of-bedrooms-allowed-per-wastewater-system/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii on Feb. 2, 2026, for consideration by the Senate Committees on Agriculture and Environment and Health and Human Services._____________ Feb. 2, 2026, 3 p.m.Hawaii State CapitolConference Room 224 and Videoconference To: Committee on Agriculture and Environment&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Sen. Mike Gabbard, Chair&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Sen. Herbert M. &amp;#8220;Tim&amp;#8221; [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/02/increase-number-of-bedrooms-allowed-per-wastewater-system/"&gt;Increase number of bedrooms allowed per wastewater system&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 22:03:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] Alabama school choice debate collides with football: How popular is the CHOOSE Act?</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2026/02/04/alabama-school-choice-debate-collides-with-football-how-popular-is-the-choose-act/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Alabama leaders spent the last week showcasing students who use publicly-funded vouchers to attend private schools and urging lawmakers to pour millions more into the program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2026/02/04/alabama-school-choice-debate-collides-with-football-how-popular-is-the-choose-act/"&gt;Alabama school choice debate collides with football: How popular is the CHOOSE Act?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 00:18:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Giving Families an Escape Hatch from NYC Public Schools</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/giving-families-an-escape-hatch-from-nyc-public-schools/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Zohran Mamdani&amp;#8217;s stunning election as mayor of New York City marks a watershed moment for the Empire State. As a....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/giving-families-an-escape-hatch-from-nyc-public-schools/"&gt;Giving Families an Escape Hatch from NYC Public Schools&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 14:43:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] </title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2026/02/14432/</link><description>&amp;#8216;Home&amp;#8217; Needs Some Definition COMMUNITY TRUST is breaking down as crime becomes more wanton, the streets are disintegrating in sub-zero temperatures and the city budget is resisting any meaningful spending restraints. So what is our mayor doing? Bringing casino gambling to town and establishing government grocery stores, to repeat complaints of mine, plus some new diversions. Among&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2026/02/14432/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 15:00:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cardinalinstitute] Op-Ed: Hospitals Collect Tax Breaks. West Virginians Collect Medical Debt.</title><link>https://cardinalinstitute.com/op-ed-hospitals-collect-tax-breaks-west-virginians-collect-medical-debt/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;To many West Virginians, healthcare continues to be a burden more than a lifeline as roughly 180,000 residents, or 13.3% of adults, now facing some sort of  medical debt. This is well above the national average of 8.6% and, even worse, nearly one in four of these residents in rural Appalachia have medical debt in [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com/op-ed-hospitals-collect-tax-breaks-west-virginians-collect-medical-debt/"&gt;Op-Ed: Hospitals Collect Tax Breaks. West Virginians Collect Medical Debt.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com"&gt;Cardinal Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 15:16:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Why Portland’s Suggested Statewide Eviction Moratorium Would Hurt Maine’s Housing Market</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/why-portlands-suggested-statewide-eviction-moratorium-would-hurt-maines-housing-market/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Portland city officials are urging Gov. Janet Mills to impose a 60-day statewide eviction moratorium in response to “fear and instability” that they are linking to federal immigration enforcement. While the resolution is framed as an emergency measure that they are claiming is only meant to protect “vulnerable residents,” such a moratorium risks repeating a [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/why-portlands-suggested-statewide-eviction-moratorium-would-hurt-maines-housing-market/"&gt;Why Portland&amp;#8217;s Suggested Statewide Eviction Moratorium Would Hurt Maine’s Housing Market&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 16:38:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Immigration and the Moral Limits of Federalism</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/immigration-and-the-moral-limits-of-federalism/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Lincoln’s natural rights statesmanship should be our guide. If Hayek taught us to inquire about who ought to decide and Lincoln taught us to ask to what end, then the question of immigration compels us toward a third and inescapable question: Where is the line drawn? The principles of subsidiarity and federalism demand that matters should be resolved...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/immigration-and-the-moral-limits-of-federalism/"&gt;Immigration and the Moral Limits of Federalism&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 16:56:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Can California’s Oil Industry Survive?</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/can-californias-oil-industry-survive/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=can-californias-oil-industry-survive</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Even confirmed skeptics should be impressed at the rapid improvement in the price and performance of EVs. A new 2026 Nissan Leaf sells for just under $30,000, and can charge in 30 minutes. That’s still not competitive with affordable gasoline powered vehicles, but the gap is closing fast. But while we may be sanguine about the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/can-californias-oil-industry-survive/"&gt;Can California’s Oil Industry Survive?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 17:57:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Signing Up for Educational Freedom is Easy</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/signing-up-for-educational-freedom-is-easy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Like all parents, my wife and I consider the formation of our children as one of our primary responsibilities. With two in college and two in elementary school, we’ve worked multiple jobs and sacrificed for more than 15 years (and will continue for the next 12) to send our kids to Catholic classical schools. The...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/signing-up-for-educational-freedom-is-easy/"&gt;Signing Up for Educational Freedom is Easy&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 18:08:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Allow dwellings in industrial-commercial mixed-use zones</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/02/allow-dwellings-in-industrial-commercial-mixed-use-zones/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Hawai’i County Council on Feb. 4, 2026._____________ Feb. 4, 2026, 1 p.m.Hawai‘i County Council Chambers in Hilo To: Hawai‘i County Council&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Holeka Goro Inaba, Chair&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Dennis “Fresh” Onishi, Vice Chair From: Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Jonathan Helton, Policy Analyst RE: [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/02/allow-dwellings-in-industrial-commercial-mixed-use-zones/"&gt;Allow dwellings in industrial-commercial mixed-use zones&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 18:29:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Florida Politics: Don’t Hit Pause — Why the Netflix-Warner Bros. Merger Should Proceed</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/florida-politics-dont-hit-pause-why-the-netflix-warner-bros-merger-should-proceed/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;One of 2025’s most closely watched acquisition targets is Warner Bros. Discovery, the media conglomerate that owns HBO...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/florida-politics-dont-hit-pause-why-the-netflix-warner-bros-merger-should-proceed/"&gt;Florida Politics: Don’t Hit Pause — Why the Netflix-Warner Bros. Merger Should Proceed&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 19:22:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] Tim Pawlenty: The Crisis Will Subside in Minnesota, but Trust Will Need to be Rebuilt</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/tim-pawlenty-the-crisis-will-subside-in-minnesota-but-trust-will-need-to-be-rebuilt/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;We’ll all be part of that task. Here’s where efforts could be focused. By Tim Pawlenty For the Star Tribune It’s been said that trust is the glue that holds relationships together. That may well explain why recent events in Minnesota have stretched our relationship with government to the breaking point. Fraudsters stole a ton [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/tim-pawlenty-the-crisis-will-subside-in-minnesota-but-trust-will-need-to-be-rebuilt/"&gt;Tim Pawlenty: The Crisis Will Subside in Minnesota, but Trust Will Need to be Rebuilt&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 19:57:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] The Numbers Don’t Lie: The CHOOSE Act is Empowering Alabama’s Families</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2026/02/04/the-numbers-dont-lie-the-choose-act-is-empowering-alabamas-families/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For decades, the Alabama Policy Institute has championed a simple, powerful idea: every child in Alabama deserves a high-quality education, regardless of their zip code or their size of their parents’ bank account. With the passage and implementation of the CHOOSE Act, that vision is finally becoming a reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2026/02/04/the-numbers-dont-lie-the-choose-act-is-empowering-alabamas-families/"&gt;The Numbers Don’t Lie: The CHOOSE Act is Empowering Alabama’s Families&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 22:48:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] All former governors join Mackinac Center civility panel</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2026/all-former-governors-join-mackinac-center-civility-panel</link><description>Four Michigan execs look back on old debates, suggest ways to increase peace</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 01:17:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Housing costs drove the majority of nation’s fertility drop</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/housing-costs-drove-the-majority-of-nations-fertility-drop/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The top reason ex-Californians cite for leaving is housing costs — 890,000 exiters over the past decade named the cost of housing as their primary reason for leaving, compared to 514,000 for work and 329,000 for family. The National Taxpayers Union estimates outmigration costs California $4.5 billion in lost tax revenue each year, which is substantial for [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/housing-costs-drove-the-majority-of-nations-fertility-drop/"&gt;Housing costs drove the majority of nation’s fertility drop&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 11:00:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Licensing rules make Michigan’s health care problems worse</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2026/licensing-rules-make-michigans-health-care-problems-worse</link><description>Reconsidering regs is a step in the right direction</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] 312 Out of More than 3 Million Votes</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/312-out-of-more-than-3-million-votes/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Federal prosecutors are closing in on prosecuting more than 100 Minnesotans for rampant fraud in several social service programs designed to serve children and low-income residents. By the time the US Attorney’s office is done investigating, charging, convicting, and sentencing these felons, this unchecked fraud will significantly increase Minnesota’s prison population. But there’s one other [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/312-out-of-more-than-3-million-votes/"&gt;312 Out of More than 3 Million Votes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 13:58:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Seven Reasons Not To Raise Taxes in New York</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/seven-reasons-not-to-raise-taxes-in-new-york/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Despite the robust growth of state revenues in recent years, many of New York&amp;#8217;s elected officials are pushing to further....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/seven-reasons-not-to-raise-taxes-in-new-york/"&gt;Seven Reasons Not To Raise Taxes in New York&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 16:08:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Empire Center Report Makes the Case Against Further Tax Hikes</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/empire-center-report-makes-the-case-against-further-tax-hikes/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Adding to New York&amp;#8217;s already high tax burden would be both unnecessary and dangerous for the state&amp;#8217;s economy, according to....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/empire-center-report-makes-the-case-against-further-tax-hikes/"&gt;Empire Center Report Makes the Case Against Further Tax Hikes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 16:12:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Study Urges New K–12 Accountability Framework Following End of MCAS Graduation Requirement</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/study-urges-new-k-12-accountability-framework-following-end-of-mcas-graduation-requirement/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Calls for choices of high school pathways, early and end-of-course exams, and independent district accountability  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/study-urges-new-k-12-accountability-framework-following-end-of-mcas-graduation-requirement/"&gt;Study Urges New K–12 Accountability Framework Following End of MCAS Graduation Requirement&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 16:14:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Habeas 700</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/habeas-700/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This morning, we hit the 700 mark in the number of habeas corpus cases filed in the U.S. District Court of Minnesota for 2026. We now stand at 713. Over the 30 &amp;#8220;business&amp;#8221; days of the year, so far, that works out to almost 24 cases filed per day. That&amp;#8217;s one case filed, every hour,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/habeas-700/"&gt;Habeas 700&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 17:06:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Illinois must keep promise to join nursing group or risk millions</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/illinois-must-keep-promise-to-join-nursing-group-or-risk-millions/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;To get part of $50 billion for a federal health program, Illinois promised to join nurse licensure and physician assistant compacts. Will state lawmakers keep that promise?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/illinois-must-keep-promise-to-join-nursing-group-or-risk-millions/"&gt;Illinois must keep promise to join nursing group or risk millions&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 17:25:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Seven questions for lawmakers proposing an income tax for Washington state</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/post/seven-questions-for-lawmakers-proposing-an-income-tax-for-washington-state</link><description>Despite Washingtonians consistently and overwhelmingly rejecting income taxes and the legislature in 2024 enacting I-2111 to prohibit state or local income taxes, some lawmakers in the Evergreen State are again pushing for an income tax this year.</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 17:43:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Education Is Economic Development: Why Business Leaders Should Support House Bill</title><link>https://empowerms.org/education-is-economic-development-why-business-leaders-should-support-house-bill/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This article was originally published in the February 2026 edition of the Mississippi Business Journal. Mississippi’s business community understands a basic but often overlooked reality: economic development does not begin with tax incentives or site selectors. It begins with people. If we want our state to grow, we must be able to attract, retain, and&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/education-is-economic-development-why-business-leaders-should-support-house-bill/"&gt;Education Is Economic Development: Why Business Leaders Should Support House Bill&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 18:43:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Record-breaking start to 2026: 6,000 employees opt out</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/record-breaking-start-to-2026-6000-employees-opt-out/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Freedom Foundation set an all-time record in January with 6,000 public employees opting out—topping our previous record by nearly 3,000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/record-breaking-start-to-2026-6000-employees-opt-out/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Record-breaking start to 2026: 6,000 employees opt out&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 18:57:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Minnesota’s ‘trans sanctuary’ law puts funding, children’s health at risk</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/minnesotas-trans-sanctuary-law-puts-funding-childrens-health-at-risk/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Minnesota’s state law is being exposed as the most embarrassing and dangerous law of its kind in the nation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/minnesotas-trans-sanctuary-law-puts-funding-childrens-health-at-risk/"&gt;Minnesota&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8216;trans sanctuary&amp;#8217; law puts funding, children&amp;#8217;s health at risk&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 19:39:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Time for UW-Madison to do away with ethnic studies requirement</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/time-for-uw-madison-to-do-away-with-ethnic-studies-requirement/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Time can be better spent on other things like AI Here’s a question I hope somebody asks anyone who applies to be the next chancellor of the University of Wisconsin-Madison: Why in the world in 2026 should we continue to have an ethnic studies requirement for all undergrads? Here’s another one: Do you even know [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/time-for-uw-madison-to-do-away-with-ethnic-studies-requirement/"&gt;Time for UW-Madison to do away with ethnic studies requirement&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 20:05:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Iowa Moves to Restore Health Care Competition</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/iowa-moves-to-restore-health-care-competition/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Iowa Moves to Restore Health Care Competition" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/con-1200x630-1.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iowa’s Certificate of Need law has failed its original purpose, acting as a barrier to access, competition, and innovation by allowing existing providers to block new services and facilities—often to the detriment of patients. Two Senate bills this session represent the most meaningful CON reform in years, easing restrictions on mental health facility expansion and sharply narrowing when CON review is required for health care investments. While the proposals stop short of full repeal, they move Iowa in the right direction, reducing regulatory bottlenecks and signaling a shift toward a health care system driven by patient needs rather than gatekeeping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/iowa-moves-to-restore-health-care-competition/"&gt;Iowa Moves to Restore Health Care Competition&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 20:10:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] A Badger Institute policy report: Character education and teacher retention</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/a-badger-institute-policy-report-character-education-and-teacher-retention/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Wisconsinites should be concerned the state's growing crisis of disappearing educators — a phenomenon the Badger Institute has been taking a closer look at. Multiple studies confirm that retaining good teachers is essential to school effectiveness and student achievement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/a-badger-institute-policy-report-character-education-and-teacher-retention/"&gt;A Badger Institute policy report: Character education and teacher retention&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 20:25:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Testimony: SB 1526 Creates State-Sponsored Nonprofit for Net Zero Projects</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/testimony/testimony-sb-1526-creates-state-sponsored-nonprofit-for-net-zero-projects/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By John A. Charles Jr. PORTLAND, OR – John Charles, President and CEO...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/testimony/testimony-sb-1526-creates-state-sponsored-nonprofit-for-net-zero-projects/"&gt;Testimony: SB 1526 Creates State-Sponsored Nonprofit for Net Zero Projects&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 20:40:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] From Limited Government to “Slowing the Growth”</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/from-limited-government-to-slowing-the-growth/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="From Limited Government to “Slowing the Growth”" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/slow-it-down.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Iowa legislature is currently considering three major property tax reform measures. Each of the proposed measures contains a provision that would cap the growth of property taxes at or around 2%. In response, local governments are sounding the alarm that placing a 2% property tax cap would endanger vital services such as police and fire.&lt;br /&gt;
This argument is nothing new, and the familiar chorus has been repeated by local governments numerous times as a way to prevent any attempt to control their spending. Further, many local government argue that they cannot limit their spending because they are already operating on “bare bones” budgets.&lt;br /&gt;
Limiting government spending may be one of the most difficult policy challenges confronting government at all levels (local, state, and federal). Government bureaucracies and special interests clamor for more spending and fight ruthlessly to protect and extend their budget line items.   Former President Herbert Hoover correctly described government as having “the instincts of a vegetable” which keep spreading and growing. This is why the national debt is $38 trillion and rising. Whether it is the property tax situation in Iowa or the national debt, the problem centers on the inability and outright refusal to limit spending. Even efforts to slow the growth of spending, such as the 2% property tax cap, are viewed as a “cut.”&lt;br /&gt;
Historically, the battle over government spending has always been an aspect of American politics. For fiscal conservatives or “budget hawks” limiting spending has unfortunately become next to impossible. With demands from government continuing to accelerate, the lack of political will from both political parties to address spending, and even the fault of Americans who expect lower taxes but still expect government to do “all of the above” are all contributing problems. It seems like the best outcome is no longer limited government, which has become a slogan, but rather hoping to just slow the growth of government.&lt;br /&gt;
The battle to limit government has never been easy, and it can be accomplished, but it will take both a renewed sense of principles and leadership. Policymakers can look to history as a guide to learn from past fiscal conservatism who truly championed policies that would limit government.&lt;br /&gt;
One example at the state level was Minnesota Governor Theodore Christianson, who served as governor from 1925 until he left office in January 1931. Christianson was the&lt;br /&gt;
During his time as a state legislator and as governor, Christianson made fiscal conservatism, or “economy in government,” a priority. He campaigned on slogans such as “More Ted, Less Taxes” and was given the nickname “Tightwad Ted.” The Farmer’s Independent, which was no supporter of Christianson, sarcastically referred to him as “Watch Dog Ted.”&lt;br /&gt;
As a conservative, Christianson was especially concerned about preventing the socialist agenda from advancing in Minnesota. He realized that the socialist policies of the Nonpartisan League had advanced and taken root in North Dakota, and the Farmer-Labor Party was now trying to accomplish similar policy goals. In 1924, Christianson was “appealing to the voters to save the state from socialism threatened by the Farmer-Labor Party.”&lt;br /&gt;
Christianson’s fiscal policies reflected those of Presidents Warren G. Harding and Calvin Coolidge. During the presidential campaign of 1924, Christianson described Coolidge as extolling “the ancient and time-tested virtues.” While Coolidge was cutting tax rates, reducing spending, and paying down the national debt at the federal level, Christianson was doing the same in Minnesota. In 1924, Christianson argued that the “demand for a halting of the increase in taxation and public indebtedness is making itself felt, not only in Minnesota, but throughout the nation.”&lt;br /&gt;
As a former legislator and chair of the Appropriations Committee, Christianson understood the budget and also the numerous special interests that were clamoring for more spending. He believed that the most urgent economic policy problems consisted of reducing the tax burden, cutting spending, and eliminating debt. As Governor, Christianson even believed that it was a realistic goal that that Minnesota would be “a bondless state in 1935,” that is debt free.&lt;br /&gt;
Christianson later reflected that it was his time as chair of the House Appropriations Committee “that he began to warn the people of the social and economic consequences of excessive taxation.”&lt;br /&gt;
Both Harding and Coolidge placed a priority on limiting spending, lowering tax rates, and paying down debt. In 1921, President Harding reformed the federal budget process with the Budget and Accounting Act, which created Bureau of the Budget with Charles G. Dawes and Herbert Lord serving as the first Directors.&lt;br /&gt;
Both Harding and Coolidge required their administration to attend regular meetings of the Business Organization of the Government, which were orchestrated by both Dawes and Lord. Harding and Coolidge would often attend and even address the meeting. The objective was to get the entire administration aligned with the fiscal policy objectives, which included limiting spending. Dawes would compare the task of cutting spending to having a “toothpick with which to tunnel Pike’s Peak.”&lt;br /&gt;
Christianson was supportive of the fiscal policies of the Harding and Coolidge administrations. He believed that their budget reform efforts should be replicated at the state level to reduce spending. “I said that the states and their municipal subdivisions have been the principal offenders, and that whereas the cost of federal government in this country has been reduced the cost of state government has continued to increase during the last few years,” noted Christianson.&lt;br /&gt;
“Why is it that the federal government can reduce its expenditures or at least keep them from increasing and the states cannot,” asked Christianson? The answer according to Christianson was following the example of Harding and Coolidge.&lt;br /&gt;
In reference to the Budget and Accounting Act, the Bureau of the Budget, and the regular meetings of the Business organization of Government, Christianson argued that governors should follow a similar example. “President Coolidge,” stated Christianson, “stands for a policy of economy he can, by handing his orders down through the members of his cabinet, reach every agency of the government and compel economy.”&lt;br /&gt;
Governor Christianson described his policy as an “economy program,” which would center on reforming state government, lowering spending, reducing taxes, and debt reduction.&lt;br /&gt;
One of the major government reform initiatives that occurred under his watch was the 1925 Reorganization Act, which made the state government more efficient by limiting bureaucracy. The Act created the “Big Three,” which was a three-person commission of Administration and Finance, which centered on reforming statewide accounting systems, reviewing agency and department budget requests, the approval or denial of state funds. Christianson and the “Big Three” also encouraged the use of the veto to limit spending.&lt;br /&gt;
The 1925 Reorganization Act “adopted a new scheme of organization of the government of Minnesota.” However, Christianson argued that consolidating departments and agencies was not enough to limit government or spending. “We consolidated a few departments but don’t believe that the mere consolidation of state departments is going to produce very much economy in itself because all that such consolidation does is to make a regrouping of the activity and all the activity is still there,” noted Christianson.&lt;br /&gt;
To add “teeth” to reorganization, Christianson created a budget system to review spending. Christianson argued that Minnesota’s budget system was “sufficiently unique,” and that the “budget system is not a mere compilation of departmental requests, it isn’t merely an attempt to scale down the departmental requests for legislature. It goes farther than that.”&lt;br /&gt;
Christianson described the process of the Budget Bureau once the legislature had given approval. Once the legislature had approved appropriations the Budget Bureau did not just allow agencies and departments to spend at will. Christianson stated that “we have a string on that money so that before the head of the Bureau or Department that enjoys that appropriation can spend a dollar of it, he must get specific approval for the expenditure from the Budget Board.”&lt;br /&gt;
This provided additional oversight into spending. “In other words, every three months the head of a state department must file with the Budget Board a requisition for the part of its appropriation that it desires to spend during the next three months,” stated Christianson. Also, agencies or departments could not use those dollars until they received approval from the Budget Board.&lt;br /&gt;
Christianson argued that the new budget system would finally elevate the interest of the taxpayers. “Under the new budget system, stated Governor Christianson, “taxpayers will be represented before the legislature when it considers requests for appropriations.”&lt;br /&gt;
“In the past, no one but those wanting to spend the money have been heard,” argued Governor Christianson. As a result, “the tax spenders have been getting judgement against the taxpayers by default.” The new budget system would provide additional oversight to help limit spending and achieve “economy in government.”&lt;br /&gt;
In reviewing spending, Christianson stated that the Budget Board could either approve, allow, or reduce the spending. To illustrate, Christianson described a hypothetical if a department requested to purchase ten new automobiles and specifically requested that they be Cadillacs.&lt;br /&gt;
This request would come before the Budget Board, and it would scrutinize whether the ten Cadillacs were necessary. Christianson stated that after the review the Board would inform the department that the “only business we have is to watch you fellows and we have decided that you will get along with six new automobiles for the present.”&lt;br /&gt;
In addition, Christianson stated that the Board would “have made a survey of the relative efficiency and economy of operation for various motor cars for your inspectors to go around the state with and have concluded they don’t need Cadillacs. We have been standardizing on a cheaper car. Instead of getting ten Cadillacs, we are going to buy six Fords. And you will get six Fords. And you will like it, after a while.”&lt;br /&gt;
Christianson admitted that the Budget Board did not win many friends and the budget system causes friction. This was positive for both government and taxpayers. Christianson argued that “any budget system that is worth the paper the law which created it is written on will cause friction, because if there is no friction between the people who want to spend the taxpayers’ money and those who are charged with the responsibility of saving it, it is a pretty sure thing that it is the tax-spenders and not the taxpayers interests which are being taken care of.”&lt;br /&gt;
In validating his argument, Christianson argued that federal Bureau of the Budget “caused friction in Washington.” Limiting spending in the Harding and Coolidge administrations was not an easy process. “A great many people down there don’t like General Lord. Some of them don’t like Coolidge,” stated Christianson.&lt;br /&gt;
Having friction in a budget system was a sign of good governance according to Christianson. “There is friction in the operation of any budget system that is effective, because the budget is a brake,” noted Christianson.&lt;br /&gt;
The Reorganization Act, Christianson argued, granted the Governor and the “Big Three,” the ability to “exercise an absolute control over the spending of state funds.” This provided Christianson with additional oversight and what he referred to as a “continuing veto on expenditures.”&lt;br /&gt;
Governor Christianson and the “Big Three” were successful in their objective of providing greater oversight of spending. As an example, during the “first year they reduced the state’s printing bill more than $75,000 and its telephone bill $9,000.” The “Big Three” also saved $17,000 by changing the way the state purchased coal and $4,000 in savings by switching from buying “writing paper by the ton instead by the ream.” By negotiating new fuel contracts for state vehicles, the “Big Three” was able to save another $20,000. In addition, the “Department of Agriculture and that of dairy and food together managed to get along on $25,000 less than they had spent the previous year…”&lt;br /&gt;
After the first year, Governor Christianson noted that the “Big Three” Commission “had saved the taxpayers more than $680,000 of the  $14,700,000 appropriated for the departments and activities directly under its financial supervision.” Later Christianson would reflect that both the new budget system and the reorganization  of state government were the “outstanding achievements” of the legislature.&lt;br /&gt;
As Governor, Christianson was unafraid to exercise his executive power, especially regarding the use of the veto. As governor, Christianson was the first executive to use the veto power extensively to limit spending. The Mahnomen Pioneer noted that during the 1925 legislative session the “Governor vetoed 12 bills, many of which would have created new state boards or would have involved future expense.”&lt;br /&gt;
During his 1926 campaign, he celebrated his use of the veto that in one year — 1925 —  saved taxpayers over $1.8 million. During his time in office, Governor Christianson would use the veto 76 times, which accounted for almost $18 million in savings. The veto was instrumental in helping Christianson limit spending. As a result, the legislature in 1925 “appropriated $41.6 million, the 1927 legislature, $40.6 million; and the 1929 legislature, $42.2 million.” Christianson’s overall budget goal for the legislature was to hold appropriations to the “amounts for the prior biennium.”&lt;br /&gt;
Christianson was even mocked by his political opponents for his fiscal conservatism. This was especially true of those allied with the Farmer-Labor Party and Nonpartisan League. The Organized Farmer, a socialist newspaper, compared the Governor to a pouting child if he did not get his way on fiscal matters. “Ted is known to stamp both feet when he can’t get what he wants, just like a three-year old…,” editorialized The Organized Farmer.&lt;br /&gt;
When The Organized Farmer learned that Christianson had read from their paper at a campaign rally, they applauded themselves for provoking the governor in his direct response. “It, of course, is gratifying to the local weekly paper to have the governor of this state carry a real progressive newspaper in his pocket, in order to give him something more to talk about besides the 13 cents that he saved per ton in purchasing coal for the state in his campaign speeches,” noted the sarcastic Organized Farmer.&lt;br /&gt;
The Organized Farmer’s lampooning of Christianson’s efforts to limit government failed to win converts. Minimizing the coal savings did not project the accuracy of what Christianson was able to accomplish. “While nearly every state in 1925 showed increases in appropriations…Minnesota appropriations were held down to the level of 1923…,” stated The Redwood Gazette.&lt;br /&gt;
The Redwood Gazette reported that “Minnesota is one of the few states where the mounting cost of state government has been checked.” Representative Ray J. Quinlivan stated that “Mr. Christianson has redeemed the pledges he made in the 1924 campaign and has not only checked the rising tide of state expenditures but has effected a reorganization which is bringing greater economy.”&lt;br /&gt;
During the 1929 legislative session, Christianson vetoed three appropriations in a budget bill that accounted for over $15 million. In his veto message, Governor Christianson argued that “every additional dollar must come from increased exactions from the owners of real and personal property.” In other words, the increased spending would result in a property tax increase.&lt;br /&gt;
 Another significant veto occurred when Governor Christianson received a $21 million school aid and university maintenance bill from the legislature. The Governor believed that this was too extravagant and “struct out the appropriations for school aid and university maintenance, aggregating $18,000,000…”&lt;br /&gt;
In his Farewell Address, Governor Christianson stated that the use of the veto helped in the reduction of state spending. “The reduction of state spending was accomplished by the veto of appropriation items…,”argued Christianson.&lt;br /&gt;
Just as with Presidents Harding and Coolidge, conservative budgeting and limiting spending were not easy policies for Governor Christianson. “Governor Christianson has not had an easy course, but he has kept the faith with the people of the state,” noted the Kanabec County Times.&lt;br /&gt;
As an example, his exercise of the veto power resulted in conflicts with the legislature. During the 1929 session the legislature passed a $5,000 appropriation for the Hospital for Crippled Children. Christianson believed that the amount was too high and instead of vetoing the entire appropriation he used executive power to lower the amount to $4,000.&lt;br /&gt;
It merits consideration to understand why Governor Christianson would even consider lowering an appropriation directed toward caring for crippled children. Christianson was not cold hearted, but rather the money was directed toward the improvement of the grounds. “Ordinarily, I would not object to appropriations for the Hospital for Crippled Children, for this institution not only is doing much practical good, but has strong sentimental appeal,” stated Governor Christianson in his veto message, which also reflected his ability to review appropriations.&lt;br /&gt;
As Governor, he argued that he should have the ability to reduce appropriations rather than using the veto. The lowering of the Children’s hospital appropriation is just one example of the conflict that he had with the legislature over his use of the veto.&lt;br /&gt;
The Kanabec County Times described Christianson as being “fearless and independent.” “This course may have made some enemies, but it has also made thousands of new friends who admire a man of his uncompromising type.” Certainly, his use of the veto, which often struck down appropriations for public education, was not viewed with popularity. The Mahnomen Pioneer stated that “Governor Christianson by his action set a record for making slashes in appropriations…He also acquired a record for vetoes.”&lt;br /&gt;
Finally, Christianson argued that “economy in government” was not just a responsibility for state government. He argued that it was also imperative that localities also practice fiscal conservatism by limiting spending, lowering tax rates, and paying down debt. The responsibility of the state government was to set an example for local governments. “Economy in state government should set an example for communities,” as Governor Christianson argued.&lt;br /&gt;
At the close of one legislative session, Governor Christianson even lamented the legislature’s failure to enact legislation to force local governments to pay down their debts. “In my opinion the most serious mistake of the session was the failure to enact legislation compelling local units of government to provide definite and irrevocable means for the liquidation of their bonded indebtedness,” stated Governor Christianson.&lt;br /&gt;
Christianson was not always satisfied with the progress of his “economy in government” agenda. He praised the reorganization of government and the budget reforms but also argued that they could have been strengthened. He even lamented that at times the “legislature appropriated too much money.”&lt;br /&gt;
Overall, Governor Christianson would leave a record of fiscal conservatism. He described his six years in office as “eventful, and several distinct trends had been established in state policy:&lt;br /&gt;
•	The state tax levy had been reduced from $27,201,582.30 a biennium to $23,620,012.86, a reduction of 13 percent.&lt;br /&gt;
•	Legislative appropriations had been cut $4,000,000 by executive veto.&lt;br /&gt;
•	The amount of certificates of indebtedness outstanding had been reduced from $15,719,000 to $3,567,758.83, a reduction of 80 percent.&lt;br /&gt;
•	The state trust funds had grown from $53,000,000 to $77,000,000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The New York Times noted that “Minnesota has been making a sincere effort to reduce tax burdens for the last six years” under the leadership of Governor Christianson. Tax reduction was “the chief undertaking of his administration,” reported The New York Times.&lt;br /&gt;
In our current era we clearly need more policymakers who share the fiscal conservatism of Governor Christianson. Christianson would not accept “slowing the growth” as an option nor would he entertain the notion that limiting spending will result in the loss of services.&lt;br /&gt;
Fundamentally, Christianson understood the root cause of the problem was not necessarily with politicians or their spending, but rather it was a cultural problem. “So I suspect if we want to stop this increase in the cost of government the first thing that we will have to decide to do is get along with less government or at least to put a stop to it when somebody tries to increase its functions and activities unduly,” argued Christianson.&lt;br /&gt;
“Now what are we going to do about it? Is there any way in which this increase in public expenditures can be halted or must we face complacently a constant increase in this burden of government,” asked Christianson? Unfortunately, we have become complacent or even numb to the increase in government spending.&lt;br /&gt;
Complacency is dangerous, which is why the national debt is $39 trillion and many state and localities are confronted with a fiscal crisis. Christianson argued that that “there are forces and factors over which the government does have control,” to limit spending. These fiscal tools included reforming and reducing the size and scope of government, budget reforms to scrutinize spending, and limit government debt. Policies such as a 2% spending cap to limit spending. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/from-limited-government-to-slowing-the-growth/"&gt;From Limited Government to “Slowing the Growth”&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 20:58:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Rifreedom] TESTIMONY: Senate Commission to Study the Successful Implementation of the Act on Climate</title><link>https://rifreedom.org/2026/02/senate-commission-act-on-climate/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In this powerful testimony, Mike Stenhouse, CEO of the RI Center for Freedom &amp;#038; Prosperity, explains why energy policy—not taxes, not housing, not government services—is the single most important determinant of Rhode Island’s future prosperity or poverty. Whether one believes in climate change or not, the economic consequences of the Act on Climate are unavoidable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org/2026/02/senate-commission-act-on-climate/"&gt;TESTIMONY: Senate Commission to Study the Successful Implementation of the Act on Climate&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org"&gt;RI Center for Freedom and Prosperity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 21:12:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Three-peat: Illinois’ pension system last place for 3rd year in a row</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/three-peat-illinois-pension-system-last-place-for-3rd-year-in-a-row/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Illinois state pensions have less money to pay retirees than any state according to Equable Institute. It’s the third year in a row for Illinois coming in last.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/three-peat-illinois-pension-system-last-place-for-3rd-year-in-a-row/"&gt;Three-peat: Illinois’ pension system last place for 3rd year in a row&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 21:29:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] COMPLETE VICTORY: Idaho Supreme Court upholds parental choice tax credit</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/post/complete-victory-idaho-supreme-court-upholds-parental-choice-tax-credit</link><description>In a comprehensive opinion, the Court denied the petition for a writ of prohibition, dismissed the case in full, rejected every major constitutional theory advanced by the petitioners, and awarded attorney fees to the State. The result is about as close to a clean sweep as constitutional litigation gets.</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 22:04:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] The Rise of Labor-Based Grading and the Continuing De-emphasis on Skill Development at U.S. Universities</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/article/education/the-rise-of-labor-based-grading-and-the-continuing-de-emphasis-on-skill-development-at-u-s-universities/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Evidence of grade inflation continues to mount in K-12 education and at universities (e.g., see here and here). The rising grades reflect a degradation of academic standards. There is clear [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/article/education/the-rise-of-labor-based-grading-and-the-continuing-de-emphasis-on-skill-development-at-u-s-universities/"&gt;The Rise of Labor-Based Grading and the Continuing De-emphasis on Skill Development at U.S. Universities&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 22:15:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] What’s the Wisconsin Department of Public Instruction Hiding?</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/whats-the-wisconsin-department-of-public-instruction-hiding/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;What&amp;#8217;s the Wisconsin Department of Public Instruction Hiding? Things are rotten in the Wisconsin Department of Public Instruction (DPI). Late last year, a damning report showed hundreds of educational professionals, including aides and teachers, were investigated for sexual misconduct. Many of them were simply allowed to resign and kept their licenses. On top of that, educational standards [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/whats-the-wisconsin-department-of-public-instruction-hiding/"&gt;What&amp;#8217;s the Wisconsin Department of Public Instruction Hiding?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 22:49:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG’s Jake Curtis Joins the Vicki McKenna Show to talk about DPI Spending</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irgs-jake-curtis-joins-the-vicki-mckenna-show-to-talk-about-dpi-spending/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irgs-jake-curtis-joins-the-vicki-mckenna-show-to-talk-about-dpi-spending/"&gt;IRG&amp;#8217;s Jake Curtis Joins the Vicki McKenna Show to talk about DPI Spending&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 22:51:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] Republicans delay Wisconsin DPI funding over water park spending concerns</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/republicans-delay-wisconsin-dpi-funding-over-water-park-spending-concerns/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Republicans delay Wisconsin DPI funding over water park spending concerns The state Legislature&amp;#8217;s Joint Finance Committee delayed voting on the Department of Public Instruction&amp;#8217;s request to release operating funds Feb. 3, following a report from a conservative news outlet that criticized the agency for hosting a four-day event at a water park in Wisconsin Dells. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/republicans-delay-wisconsin-dpi-funding-over-water-park-spending-concerns/"&gt;Republicans delay Wisconsin DPI funding over water park spending concerns&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 23:01:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] A Bible-Shaped Hole in our Children’s Learning</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/a-bible-shaped-hole-in-our-childrens-learning/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Do you tell the young people in your life to follow The Golden Rule? Have you been urged to “turn the other cheek” instead of harming someone who has harmed you? Or maybe Coolio’s “Gangsta’s Paradise” is your favorite song, but you’re not sure where that hard line about “the valley of the shadow of...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/a-bible-shaped-hole-in-our-childrens-learning/"&gt;A Bible-Shaped Hole in our Children’s Learning&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 23:52:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Would an Article V Convention “runaway” from its purpose?</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/post/would-an-article-v-convention-runaway-from-its-purpose</link><description>The Founders of the Constitution would not have provided the Article V option to the states if they were concerned that a “runaway convention” would undo all their hard work.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 00:01:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] A simple few steps to provide more affordable, safer housing</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/a-simple-few-steps-to-provide-more-affordable-safer-housing/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A simple few steps to provide more affordable, safer housing By Sal Rodriguez &amp;#124; February 6, 2026 Over the past few years, states and cities across the country have moved to cut red tape around their housing markets in order to spur greater supply and, in the long run, control or even reduce high housing [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/a-simple-few-steps-to-provide-more-affordable-safer-housing/"&gt;A simple few steps to provide more affordable, safer housing&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 10:21:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Debate exposes Newsom’s failures as Golden State governor</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/debate-exposes-newsoms-failures-as-golden-state-governor/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Ira Stoll writes for the Washington Free Beacon about an interesting aspect of a recent West Coast candidate debate. About an hour and 44 minutes into this week’s debate among seven candidates for governor of California, the moderator asked a question that he said had been sent in by &amp;#8220;Henry in San Bernardino.&amp;#8221; It said,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/debate-exposes-newsoms-failures-as-golden-state-governor/"&gt;Debate exposes Newsom&amp;#8217;s failures as Golden State governor&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 10:36:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Left designates more and more of what it dislikes as ‘hate’</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/left-designates-more-and-more-of-what-it-dislikes-as-hate/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Elle Purnell writes for the Federalist about the “laziest and dumbest virtue-signal yet.” Since the tactic of writing off half the country as “Nazi” “garbage” wasn’t working, the Democrat Party’s unofficial PR team has a new shorthand for everything they don’t like: “hate.” At Sunday’s Grammys, Benito Antonio Martínez Ocasio — a man who looked...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/left-designates-more-and-more-of-what-it-dislikes-as-hate/"&gt;Left designates more and more of what it dislikes as &amp;#8216;hate&amp;#8217;&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 10:39:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Current political divide threatens long-standing ‘center’</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/current-political-divide-threatens-long-standing-center/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Edward Ring writes for American Greatness about a threat to a vital piece of the American political system. [O]ne example of the “center” is millions of friendships that remain strong, held between left-of-center pro-business Democrats who are skeptical about MAGA, and right-of-center Republicans who believe MAGA policies are the best route to our country achieving...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/current-political-divide-threatens-long-standing-center/"&gt;Current political divide threatens long-standing &amp;#8216;center&amp;#8217;&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 10:42:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] ‘A country where opportunity is still possible’</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/podcasts/the-overton-window/justin-callais-discusses-what-helps-states-improve-life-outcomes</link><description>Justin Callais discusses what helps states improve life outcomes</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Waste watch: Illinois gives almost $1.2M to labor activist group</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/waste-watch-illinois-gives-almost-1-2m-to-labor-activist-group/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Illinois lawmakers provided nearly $1.2 million to a political advocacy group promoting progressive labor policies. Little info was offered about how the taxes will be used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/waste-watch-illinois-gives-almost-1-2m-to-labor-activist-group/"&gt;Waste watch: Illinois gives almost $1.2M to labor activist group&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 11:00:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Spending First, Taxes Later: The Structural Flaw in Tax Policy</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/spending-first-taxes-later-the-structural-flaw-in-tax-policy/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Spending First, Taxes Later: The Structural Flaw in Tax Policy" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/bridge-and-capitol.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tax debates are fundamentally imbalanced, treating government spending as virtuous while portraying taxpayers as selfish for wanting to keep more of what they earn. Spending pressures, not taxpayer capacity, drive tax increases, with policymakers and special interests too often defaulting to higher taxes rather than spending restraint. Tax reform alone is insufficient without structural limits, as shown by states like Washington; without guardrails, spending growth will eventually overwhelm tax relief, setting the stage for the need for constitutional protections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/spending-first-taxes-later-the-structural-flaw-in-tax-policy/"&gt;Spending First, Taxes Later: The Structural Flaw in Tax Policy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 13:12:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] BERGEN RECORD: NJ climate superfund is a blank check with no accountability | Opinion</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/02/bergen-record-nj-climate-superfund-is-a-blank-check-with-no-accountability-opinion/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;#160; New Jersey’s Climate Superfund Is a Blank Check With No Accountability by Rosemary Becchi New Jersey lawmakers are considering [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/02/bergen-record-nj-climate-superfund-is-a-blank-check-with-no-accountability-opinion/"&gt;BERGEN RECORD: NJ climate superfund is a blank check with no accountability | Opinion&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 13:58:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] When Complacency is Not an Option: Federal Preemption in the Face of a Growing Patchwork</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/ai-federal-preemption/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Wall Street Journal reported last week that record-breaking valuations of billions of dollars are commonplace in the age of artificial intelligence (AI). The technology has become a clear litmus test for the economic power of businesses and nations alike. A strong country will have strong AI because it powers advancements across sectors and generates...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/ai-federal-preemption/"&gt;When Complacency is Not an Option: Federal Preemption in the Face of a Growing Patchwork&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 15:07:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Week in Review: Down with DEI Mandates</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-down-with-dei-mandates/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Despite the national backlash to diversity, equity, and inclusion (DEI), many universities across the country still require their employees to..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-down-with-dei-mandates/"&gt;Week in Review: Down with DEI Mandates&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 16:18:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Governor Mills’s Supplemental Budget Abandons Fiscal Discipline, Sets Maine Up for Higher Costs</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/governor-millss-supplemental-budget-abandons-fiscal-discipline-sets-maine-up-for-higher-costs/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Governor Janet Mills’ FY 2026 supplemental budget marks a clear break from the fiscal restraint her administration often claimed to practice. Rather than using Maine’s strong revenue growth to stabilize taxpayers after years of tax increases and inflation, the proposal dramatically expands spending, broadens emergency powers, and doubles down on distortionary tax policy choices that [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/governor-millss-supplemental-budget-abandons-fiscal-discipline-sets-maine-up-for-higher-costs/"&gt;Governor Mills’s Supplemental Budget Abandons Fiscal Discipline, Sets Maine Up for Higher Costs&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 17:22:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] House GOP must promote commonsense health care reform</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/house-gop-must-promote-commonsense-health-care-reform/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Nearly half of Americans struggle to pay for health care, according to recent polling from independent health policy research organization KFF. If congressional Republicans hope to maintain their majority in the midterm elections this fall, then they need to address those concerns with credible, patient-centered reforms. They have already begun to do so, though those [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/house-gop-must-promote-commonsense-health-care-reform/"&gt;House GOP must promote commonsense health care reform&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 17:28:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] How college majors shape political ideology</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/how-college-majors-shape-political-ideology/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;What students study in college shapes not only their career prospects but also their political views, according to a new working paper from the Social Science Research Network. After examining surveys of around 300,000 students across 477 U.S. colleges, the study finds that majors matter and are a significant predictor of the political leanings students...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/how-college-majors-shape-political-ideology/"&gt;How college majors shape political ideology&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 17:36:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] A New Era of Opportunity: How Governor Landry’s LA GATOR ESA Outshines Outdated Vouchers</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/education/lagator-outshines-vouchers/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In the heart of Louisiana, where innovation and opportunity should define our future, the new LA GATOR Scholarship Program stands as a bold testament to free-market principles in education. Enacted by Governor Jeff Landry and the Louisiana Legislature 2024 and launched in 2025, this education savings account (ESA) initiative represents a seismic shift from the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/education/lagator-outshines-vouchers/"&gt;A New Era of Opportunity: How Governor Landry’s LA GATOR ESA Outshines Outdated Vouchers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 18:02:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] House Bill 579 — Justifiable homicide (+1)</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/house-bill-579-justifiable-homicide/</link><description>Bill Description:&amp;#160;House Bill 579 would clarify that justifiable homicide can include the defense of any person, not just certain relatives or employees named in code.&amp;#160; Rating: +1 Does it violate the spirit or the letter of either the United States Constitution or the Idaho Constitution? Examples include restrictions on speech, public assembly, the press, privacy, [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 18:02:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] House Bill 582 — LLC addresses (+1)</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/house-bill-582-llc-addresses/</link><description>Bill Description:&amp;#160;House Bill 582 would allow LLC filers to provide the street and mailing addresses of the company's commercial registered agent rather than their own personal address.&amp;#160; Rating: +1 Does it increase barriers to entry into the market? Examples include occupational licensure, the minimum wage, and restrictions on home businesses. Conversely, does it remove barriers [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 18:05:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] House Bill 562 — Insurance, cancel and nonrenewal (-1)</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/house-bill-562-insurance-cancel-and-nonrenewal/</link><description>Bill Description:&amp;#160;House Bill 562 would impose stricter regulations on insurance providers by requiring longer, 60-day notices of non-renewals and cancellations. Rating: -1 Does it give government any new, additional, or expanded power to prohibit, restrict, or regulate activities in the free market? Conversely, does it eliminate or reduce government intervention in the market? House Bill [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 18:12:23 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>