<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>State-Policy Think-Tank Digest</title><link>https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml</link><description>Latest posts from free-market policy institutes across the U.S.</description><atom:link href="https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 01:31:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>[Rifreedom] Center Mourns the Loss of Board Member Michael G. Riley, Civic Leader</title><link>https://rifreedom.org/2025/11/center-mourns-the-loss-of-board-member-michael-g-riley-civic-leader/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org/2025/11/center-mourns-the-loss-of-board-member-michael-g-riley-civic-leader/"&gt;Center Mourns the Loss of Board Member Michael G. Riley, Civic Leader&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org"&gt;RI Center for Freedom and Prosperity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 16:51:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Trouble on the Right – Why Conservatives Need to be Wary</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/trouble-on-the-right-why-conservatives-need-to-be-wary/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I only recently learned what a “groyper” is - you may or may not be familiar with the term?&amp;#160;From what I can tell, a groyper is a hardline white nationalist.&amp;#160; Often anti-Semitic, groypers are hostile to mainstream conservatives.&amp;#160; To the extent they have a coherent agenda, groypers seem more national socialism than free-market capitalism.&amp;#160;Having been [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/trouble-on-the-right-why-conservatives-need-to-be-wary/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Trouble on the Right – Why Conservatives Need to be Wary&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 18:29:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] On Thanksgiving, remember that gratitude makes good citizens, heals divisions</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/gratitude-makes-good-citizens-and-heals-divisions/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/gratitude-makes-good-citizens-and-heals-divisions/"&gt;On Thanksgiving, remember that gratitude makes good citizens, heals divisions&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 23:00:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] The War of Visions</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/11/28/the-war-of-visions/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Across the country, Americans are no longer divided simply by policy or party but by rival moral imaginations—two incompatible visions of truth, freedom, and even human nature itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/11/28/the-war-of-visions/"&gt;The War of Visions&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 00:23:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] YAF v SBA</title><link>https://will-law.org/yaf-v-sba/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL and the Center for Individual Rights (CIR) filed a major lawsuit against the Trump Administration today, targeting the foundation for many of the remaining federal DEI programs: the preference for so-called “socially disadvantaged individuals.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/yaf-v-sba/"&gt;YAF v SBA&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 18:10:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] A Very Grateful Immigrant’s Thanksgiving</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/a-very-grateful-immigrants-thanksgiving/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Having just celebrated Thanksgiving across the United States, I’ve been reminded of what makes this holiday truly special.&amp;#160;&amp;#160;If you’re an American who’s grown up with the holiday your whole life, it’s easy to take it for granted. Speaking as an immigrant, let me tell you: there’s something genuinely magical about a country setting aside a [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/a-very-grateful-immigrants-thanksgiving/" rel="nofollow"&gt;A Very Grateful Immigrant’s Thanksgiving&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 21:11:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] New Hampshire ranked freest state in North America for 24th time</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/12/new-hampshire-ranked-freest-state-in-north-america-for-24th-time/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New Hampshire ranks as the freest state in North America, as measured in this year’s Economic Freedom of North America report, released today by the Josiah Bartlett Center for Public Policy in conjunction with Canada’s Fraser Institute. For the 24th time, New Hampshire is the freest state among all U.S. states, having scored 8.34 out [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/12/new-hampshire-ranked-freest-state-in-north-america-for-24th-time/"&gt;New Hampshire ranked freest state in North America for 24th time&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 12:52:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] The Holiday Season Is Here — But Affordability Still Isn’t</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/the-holiday-season-is-here/</link><description>If it feels like Christmas keeps getting more expensive, that’s because it is,  and Kansans are feeling it more sharply than policymakers care to admit. The rising cost of living is no longer a blip on a chart; it’s a full-blown pocketbook problem showing up in everything from family grocery runs to holiday gift lists. [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 15:17:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG Polling: April 2025</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-polling-april-2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;April 16, 2025 NEW IRG Poll: Voters Decided Election on Abortion, Musk &amp;#38; Trump’s Agenda Despite all the emphasis on crime, voters were focused elsewhere  Delafield, Wis. –  The Institute for Reforming Government (IRG) is continuing its public polling project with Napolitan News Service and Scott Rasmussen in 2025, with the focus in this poll on Wisconsin’s [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-polling-april-2025/"&gt;IRG Polling: April 2025&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 20:28:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Book Highlights Advances in Digital Education, Policies to Unlock Its Benefits</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/book-highlights-advances-in-digital-education-policies-to-unlock-its-benefits/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;BOSTON – A new book co-edited by national digital education leader Julie Young draws on best practices and multiple studies published by Pioneer Institute to recount three decades of advances in digital education and highlights the policies necessary for students to fully...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/book-highlights-advances-in-digital-education-policies-to-unlock-its-benefits/"&gt;Book Highlights Advances in Digital Education, Policies to Unlock Its Benefits &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 12:06:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] WILL Moves to Intervene in Wisconsin Redistricting Cases on Behalf of Wisconsin Voters</title><link>https://will-law.org/will-moves-to-intervene-in-wisconsin-redistricting-cases-on-behalf-of-wisconsin-voters/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL filed motions to intervene in two lawsuits seeking to overturn Wisconsin’s Congressional Maps. Seeking again to defend those maps on behalf of a group of Wisconsin voters, WILL argues that these new lawsuits are time-barred, the three-judge panel lacks authority to overrule the Wisconsin Supreme Court, and any attempt to impose new maps in this manner would violate federal law and the U.S. Constitution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/will-moves-to-intervene-in-wisconsin-redistricting-cases-on-behalf-of-wisconsin-voters/"&gt;WILL Moves to Intervene in Wisconsin Redistricting Cases on Behalf of Wisconsin Voters&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 14:16:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] New Mexico falls to 50th among US states in latest “Index of Economic Freedom”</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/new-mexico-falls-to-50th-among-us-states-in-latest-index-of-economic-freedom/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Rio Grande Foundation has never seen &amp;#8220;eye to eye&amp;#8221; with Gov. Lujan Grisham and the leftists in Santa Fe who have failed to improve New Mexico even with the benefit of billions of dollars in oil and gas revenues. And, while these policy differences and failures may seem trivial to some, they have real [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/new-mexico-falls-to-50th-among-us-states-in-latest-index-of-economic-freedom/"&gt;New Mexico falls to 50th among US states in latest &amp;#8220;Index of Economic Freedom&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 15:40:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Nebraska Tax Reform: Why Full Expensing Is the Smart Move</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-tax-reform-why-full-expensing-is-the-smart-move/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The federal One Big Beautiful Bill (OBBB) creates the opportunity for Nebraska to adopt the most “America First” tax reform: full expensing. In an era of reshoring and friend-shoring critical supply chains, full expensing is the tax reform that properly defines “income” and incentivizes production in the U.S.A.   Full expensing is the policy of allowing...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-tax-reform-why-full-expensing-is-the-smart-move/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Nebraska Tax Reform: Why Full Expensing Is the Smart Move&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 16:55:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] Court Watch: Wisconsin Supreme Court Reverses, Consolidates Power Through New Court Management Order</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/court-watch-wisconsin-supreme-court-reverses-consolidates-power-through-new-court-management-order/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Court Watch: Wisconsin Supreme Court Reverses, Consolidates Power Through New Court Management Order Progressive majority reshapes internal court governance to cement its control of the judicial branch Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government’s Court Watch issued the following statement after the Wisconsin Supreme Court quietly issued a new court management order just days [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/court-watch-wisconsin-supreme-court-reverses-consolidates-power-through-new-court-management-order/"&gt;Court Watch: Wisconsin Supreme Court Reverses, Consolidates Power Through New Court Management Order&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 16:58:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] The Hidden Gem: Why Education Freedom is the New Economic Development</title><link>https://empowerms.org/the-hidden-gem-why-education-freedom-is-the-new-economic-development/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Forget industrial parks. The driver for economic growth in rural Mississippi is education freedom, which is the most powerful yet often overlooked tool in our economic development chest. I’ve dedicated my academic research to the topic, stemming from a comment I heard years ago at Starkville City Hall: “Education is the biggest driver of community-economic&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/the-hidden-gem-why-education-freedom-is-the-new-economic-development/"&gt;The Hidden Gem: Why Education Freedom is the New Economic Development&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 17:46:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] A4121 Is a Hatchet When New Jersey Needs a Scalpel</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/12/a4121-is-a-hatchet-when-new-jersey-needs-a-scalpel/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Today, I had the opportunity to testify before the Assembly Education Committee on A4121, a bill that would eliminate New [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/12/a4121-is-a-hatchet-when-new-jersey-needs-a-scalpel/"&gt;A4121 Is a Hatchet When New Jersey Needs a Scalpel&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 21:24:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Portland Public Schools’ Risky Real Estate Gamble</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/education/portland-public-schools-risky-real-estate-gamble/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Eric Fruits, Ph.D. On December 2, Portland Public Schools (PPS) board voted...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/education/portland-public-schools-risky-real-estate-gamble/"&gt;Portland Public Schools’ Risky Real Estate Gamble&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 01:25:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Before Spending Millions to Replace Federal Subsidies, Connecticut Should Audit Its Own Data</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/12/05/before-spending-millions-to-replace-federal-subsidies-connecticut-should-audit-its-own-data/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Access Health CT — the state’s health insurance exchange — recently warned that as many as 30 to 35 percent of its 150,000 marketplace enrollees may lose coverage in the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/12/05/before-spending-millions-to-replace-federal-subsidies-connecticut-should-audit-its-own-data/"&gt;Before Spending Millions to Replace Federal Subsidies, Connecticut Should Audit Its Own Data &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 19:18:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] A ‘Repeal Day’ glance at Liquor Commission revenues</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/12/a-repeal-day-glance-at-liquor-commission-revenues/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;December 5 is neither a federal nor state day of celebration, but it probably should be. On Dec. 5, 1933, Pennsylvania, Ohio and Utah became the final states to ratify the 21st Amendment to the U.S. Constitution.  The night before, toasting your Aunt Gertrude’s 92nd birthday with a glass of champagne was illegal. That evening, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/12/a-repeal-day-glance-at-liquor-commission-revenues/"&gt;A &amp;#8216;Repeal Day&amp;#8217; glance at Liquor Commission revenues&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 22:09:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Georgia candidates for governor should make welfare reform a top priority</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/georgia-candidates-for-governor-should-make-welfare-reform-a-top-priority/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/georgia-candidates-for-governor-should-make-welfare-reform-a-top-priority/"&gt;Georgia candidates for governor should make welfare reform a top priority&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 16:58:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] OPINION: New Mexico’s economic freedom is now dead last</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/opinion-new-mexicos-economic-freedom-is-now-dead-last/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following appeared in the Albuquerque Journal  on December 7, 2025. In a study published earlier this year, we highlighted the fact that New Mexico was the only state in the U.S. to have lost economic freedom since 1981. We now know that it is worse than we thought. People are more economically free when [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/opinion-new-mexicos-economic-freedom-is-now-dead-last/"&gt;OPINION: New Mexico&amp;#8217;s economic freedom is now dead last&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 17:53:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Wichita should reallocate spending rather than add a new (rushed?) 1% sales tax</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/sales-tax-proposal-rushed-wichita/</link><description>The Wichita City Council seems poised to rush a proposal to the ballot for a 1-cent sales tax to raise $850 million over seven years for several new projects. That at least implies that imposing a new tax is the only way to fund “public safety projects, property tax relief, and revitalizing Century II and [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 19:55:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Listen: Steve Robinson &amp; Matt Gagnon on WGAN</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/listen-steve-robinson-matt-gagnon-on-wgan/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Steve Robinson from the Maine Wire joins Matt Gagnon to discuss fraud and corruption by the Maine-based Gateway Community Services (GCS). According to reporting by the The Maine Wire, GCS has been found liable for nearly a million dollars worth of erroneous billing to MaineCare, the state’s Medicare agency, in an unsettling precursor to revelations [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/listen-steve-robinson-matt-gagnon-on-wgan/"&gt;Listen: Steve Robinson &amp;amp; Matt Gagnon on WGAN&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 20:37:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] Empty Schools, Empty Wallets: How ESSER Pandemic Aid Led to More School Referenda</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/empty-schools-empty-wallets-how-esser-pandemic-aid-led-to-more-school-referenda/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Empty Schools, Empty Wallets: How ESSER Pandemic Aid Led to More School Referenda New IRG analysis reveals hiring sprees and poor financial decisions as Wisconsin schools fall behind national leaders Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government released a new report on Tuesday, “Empty Schools, Empty Wallets: What Happened to $1.49 Billion in ESSER [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/empty-schools-empty-wallets-how-esser-pandemic-aid-led-to-more-school-referenda/"&gt;Empty Schools, Empty Wallets: How ESSER Pandemic Aid Led to More School Referenda&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 15:02:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Why CT’s Treatment of Faith-Based Nonprofits Matters for Its Civic and Fiscal Future</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/12/09/why-cts-treatment-of-faith-based-nonprofits-matters-for-its-civic-and-fiscal-future/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="1890" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/St-Joseph-scaled-e1765295362919.jpeg" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connecticut ranks among the least friendly states for faith-based nonprofit organizations, largely due to restrictive regulatory and tax policies. These rules not only limit religious expression and charitable outreach but also mirror a national trend: as civic associations shutter, governments expand — shifting more costs [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/12/09/why-cts-treatment-of-faith-based-nonprofits-matters-for-its-civic-and-fiscal-future/"&gt;Why CT&amp;#8217;s Treatment of Faith-Based Nonprofits Matters for Its Civic and Fiscal Future&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 16:12:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Massachusetts Subsidized Housing Inventory Update Shows Record Number of Communities Exceed Critical Threshold</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/massachusetts-subsidized-housing-inventory-update-shows-record-number-of-communities-exceed-critical-threshold/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This edition of The House Call explores the 2025 update to Massachusetts&amp;#8217; Subsidized Housing Inventory, showing a spike in the number of communities that have at least 10% of their housing stocks in the Inventory. It also explains the housing-related ballot questions that could...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/massachusetts-subsidized-housing-inventory-update-shows-record-number-of-communities-exceed-critical-threshold/"&gt;Massachusetts Subsidized Housing Inventory Update Shows Record Number of Communities Exceed Critical Threshold&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 20:35:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Commissioner Andy Gipson: Family, Food Security, and Mississippi’s Future</title><link>https://empowerms.org/commissioner-andy-gipson-family-food-security-and-mississippis-future/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Commissioner Andy Gipson: Family, Food Security, and Mississippi’s Future On this episode of The Empower Podcast, host Grant Callen sits down with Commissioner Andy Gipson—Mississippi’s Commissioner of Agriculture and Commerce, former state legislator, Baptist minister, cattleman, and announced candidate for governor. Gipson shares how his journey into public service began with a desire to secure&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/commissioner-andy-gipson-family-food-security-and-mississippis-future/"&gt;Commissioner Andy Gipson: Family, Food Security, and Mississippi’s Future&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:49:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Nebraska Zoning Permitting Process: Recommended Adjustments in Nebraska</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-zoning-permitting-process-recommended-adjustments-in-nebraska/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Nebraska’s zoning and permitting process for livestock operations is inconsistent, unpredictable, and varies widely from county to county. This report examines how Nebraska’s Conditional Use Permit (CUP) system works, the origins and goals of the Livestock Siting Assessment Matrix created under LB106, and why the Matrix remains underused nearly a decade later. Drawing on survey...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-zoning-permitting-process-recommended-adjustments-in-nebraska/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Nebraska Zoning Permitting Process: Recommended Adjustments in Nebraska&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 15:17:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] WILL Hires Associate Counsel to Grow Legal and Policy Capacity in Wisconsin and Beyond</title><link>https://will-law.org/will-hires-associate-counsel-to-grow-legal-and-policy-capacity-in-wisconsin-and-beyond/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL has announced Erin Gamble as our new Associate Counsel. Her hire reflects our organization’s commitment to fighting back against bureaucratic overreach in Wisconsin and across the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/will-hires-associate-counsel-to-grow-legal-and-policy-capacity-in-wisconsin-and-beyond/"&gt;WILL Hires Associate Counsel to Grow Legal and Policy Capacity in Wisconsin and Beyond&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 15:23:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Creating links that change lives: Georgia Center for Opportunity partners with Connect to Work GA</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/gco-partners-with-connect-to-work-ga/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This collaboration will help lift job seekers above the poverty line by providing opportunities for successful careers and upward mobility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/gco-partners-with-connect-to-work-ga/"&gt;Creating links that change lives: Georgia Center for Opportunity partners with Connect to Work GA&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 20:09:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] From Promises to Vetoes: Hochul’s Actions Belie Her Commitment to Transparency</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/from-promises-to-vetoes-hochuls-actions-belie-her-commitment-to-transparency/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Governor Kathy Hochul made news this fall when she used her legislative veto power in a way that looked personal.....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/from-promises-to-vetoes-hochuls-actions-belie-her-commitment-to-transparency/"&gt;From Promises to Vetoes: Hochul&amp;#8217;s Actions Belie Her Commitment to Transparency&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 20:54:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Legislature balks as Evers demands millions for more food aid bureaucrats</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/legislature-balks-as-evers-demands-millions-for-more-food-aid-bureaucrats/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Gov. Tony Evers is pressing the Legislature for $70 million to process FoodShare applications to stave off federal penalties that could cost state taxpayers as much as $225 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/legislature-balks-as-evers-demands-millions-for-more-food-aid-bureaucrats/"&gt;Legislature balks as Evers demands millions for more food aid bureaucrats&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 21:58:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Look Up: Your Bodily Autonomy and Property Rights Are Being Attacked From the Sky</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/look-up-your-bodily-autonomy-and-property-rights-are-being-attacked-from-the-sky/</link><description>Want to have some fun at your holiday family gathering this year? Ask your fellow party-goers what they think about cloud seeding. Are those lines in the sky merely contrails, or signs of weather modification, or some sort of atmospheric experimentation? You’ll soon find a variety of answers, speculation, opinion, and theory — from genuine [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 01:40:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Understanding Iowa’s School Income Surtax</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/understanding-iowas-school-income-surtax/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Understanding Iowa’s School Income Surtax" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/income-surtax.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iowa’s school income surtax, first adopted in 1971, is a district-level tax calculated as a percentage of a taxpayer’s Iowa income tax liability and used to support discretionary school programs.&lt;br /&gt;
Districts may combine the surtax with property taxes to fund the Instructional Support Levy (ISL) and the voter-approved Physical Plant and Equipment Levy (PPEL), adjusting the surtax rate annually to meet budget needs.&lt;br /&gt;
Over the past twenty years, the number of districts not using the surtax has steadily declined, making it an increasingly common but still little-understood part of Iowa’s school finance system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/understanding-iowas-school-income-surtax/"&gt;Understanding Iowa’s School Income Surtax&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 14:07:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] “Fully Funded Schools” Are a Moving Goal Post</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/education/fully-funded-schools-are-a-moving-goal-post/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Kathryn Hickok How much money does it take to “fully fund” Oregon’s...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/education/fully-funded-schools-are-a-moving-goal-post/"&gt;“Fully Funded Schools” Are a Moving Goal Post&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 17:22:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Taxpayers Asked to Fund a Hospital Takeover They’re Not Allowed to See</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/12/12/taxpayers-asked-to-fund-a-hospital-takeover-theyre-not-allowed-to-see/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Connecticut lawmakers pushed the UConn Health hospital acquisition bill through the November special session — without a public hearing — it was clear transparency was not the priority.   [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/12/12/taxpayers-asked-to-fund-a-hospital-takeover-theyre-not-allowed-to-see/"&gt;Taxpayers Asked to Fund a Hospital Takeover They’re Not Allowed to See&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 18:13:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Would you invest in Massachusetts or New Hampshire?</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/12/would-you-invest-in-massachusetts-or-new-hampshire/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;If U.S. states were companies that traded on the stock market, the only New England state with a “buy” rating would probably be New Hampshire.  Massachusetts could be called “Big Blue,” the tradition-bound leader cruising on its prior reputation, but falling behind smaller upstarts that have embraced innovation and rapid growth.  New Hampshire would be [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/12/would-you-invest-in-massachusetts-or-new-hampshire/"&gt;Would you invest in Massachusetts or New Hampshire?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 21:10:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] The Battle for Health Freedom Isn’t Over: Let’s Fight for Children</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/the-battle-for-health-freedom-isnt-over-lets-fight-for-children/</link><description>Idaho’s “Medical Freedom Act (MFA)” protects adults from employers, businesses, government agencies, or other entities imposing medical interventions on them, including vaccines. Enacted this past July, the MFA protects adults from being coerced into using medical products, devices, substances, injections, or any technology, in any form. It’s simple — bodily autonomy is a fundamental, God-given [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 02:39:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Week in Review: Medical Freedom and Informed Consent Are Fundamental</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/week-in-review-medical-freedom-and-informed-consent-are-fundamental/</link><description>Health and medical freedom, and the issues debated under this umbrella, speak directly to the overarching principles the Founders were so passionate about.&amp;#160; You have the right to access holistic healing modalities, practitioners of your choosing, and treatments to heal in the ways you choose. The state and federal governments have no place interfering in [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Arkansaspolicyfoundation] ARKANSAS GOV. SARAH HUCKABEE SANDERS &amp; STATE INCOME TAX CUTS</title><link>https://arkansaspolicyfoundation.org/arkansas-gov-sarah-huckabee-sanders-state-income-tax-cuts/</link><description>(4Q-2025) Arkansas Gov. Sarah Huckabee Sanders is the Natural State’s first female governor. Since taking office in January 2023, Sanders has also distinguished herself by advancing three separate reductions in Arkansas’ top income tax rate from 4.9 to 3.9 percent. The income tax was reduced from 7.0% to 6.9% in 2013 under Democratic Gov. Mike [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 14:33:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Empire Center Releases NYC BERS Pension Data for FY2025</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/empire-center-releases-nyc-bers-pension-data-for-fy2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Pension payments to 21,170 retirees of the New York City Board of Education Retirement System (BERS) during fiscal year 2025....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/empire-center-releases-nyc-bers-pension-data-for-fy2025/"&gt;Empire Center Releases NYC BERS Pension Data for FY2025&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 14:15:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Todd Schaible: The Importance of Career Technical Education in Tennessee Schools</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/todd-schaible-the-importance-of-career-technical-education-in-tennessee-schools/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=todd-schaible-the-importance-of-career-technical-education-in-tennessee-schools</link><description>By elevating CTE in Tennessee schools, we can increase support for employers and improve workforce readiness for students across the state.</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 15:34:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] A Small Minnesota City Offers a Big Lesson on Budget Discipline</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/a-small-minnesota-city-offers-a-big-lesson-on-budget-discipline/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="A Small Minnesota City Offers a Big Lesson on Budget Discipline" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/grand-rapids-minnesota.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facing taxpayer frustration over rising property taxes, the City of Grand Rapids pursued a zero-percent levy increase by cutting or delaying nearly $1 million in spending. Minnesota’s Truth-in-Taxation process has empowered residents to engage meaningfully in budget decisions, with strong public turnout influencing both city and county officials. The experience demonstrates that transparency, taxpayer engagement, and spending discipline can lead to alternatives to automatic tax increases while preserving local accountability. Iowa should replicate Minnesota’s Truth-in-Taxation notice. Doing so would provide clearer property tax information and help encourage taxpayer participation by showing residents how proposed budgets directly affect their tax bills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/a-small-minnesota-city-offers-a-big-lesson-on-budget-discipline/"&gt;A Small Minnesota City Offers a Big Lesson on Budget Discipline&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 15:55:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Takin’ It to the Streets: Applying New Data to Reduce Car Accidents</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/applying-new-data-to-reduce-car-accidents/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Few milestones strike more fear into the heart of parents than that of a driver license. Millions of Americans participate in this rite of passage each year—and even more are involved in car accidents. With the freedom of the road comes an element of danger, one that no amount of driver’s ed can reduce. Self-driving...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/applying-new-data-to-reduce-car-accidents/"&gt;Takin’ It to the Streets: Applying New Data to Reduce Car Accidents&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 16:42:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] Albuquerque Journal editorializes in defense of free speech, Rio Grande Foundation in “hoodie-gate”</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/albuquerque-journal-editorializes-in-defense-of-free-speech-rio-grande-foundation-in-hoodie-gate/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Rio Grande Foundation has received a great deal of publicity from all corners of Albuquerque&amp;#8217;s political scene due to our involvement in reporting on the I ♥ Tim Keller &amp;#8220;hoodies for the homeless&amp;#8221; effort. As we&amp;#8217;ve discussed at length here and in other locations the Mayor&amp;#8217;s campaign has reacted to our reporting and refusal [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/albuquerque-journal-editorializes-in-defense-of-free-speech-rio-grande-foundation-in-hoodie-gate/"&gt;Albuquerque Journal editorializes in defense of free speech, Rio Grande Foundation in &amp;#8220;hoodie-gate&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 16:53:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] The Million Petty Annoyances of California’s Regulatory State</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/the-million-petty-annoyances-of-californias-regulatory-state/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=the-million-petty-annoyances-of-californias-regulatory-state</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The litany of reasons California is broken is well documented. The highest cost of living and the highest taxes. The highest percentages of homeless people and people living in poverty. Unaffordable homes and unaffordable rent. High crime and failing schools. A hostile business climate and record migration out of state as people and businesses flee....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/the-million-petty-annoyances-of-californias-regulatory-state/"&gt;The Million Petty Annoyances of California’s Regulatory State&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 17:17:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] O’Donnell: Yes, Socialism Works . . .</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/12/odonnell-yes-socialism-works/</link><description>by James O&amp;#8217;Donnell, M.B.A.This year&amp;#160;has seen major American cities, like New York City and Seattle, elect socialist mayors. Elsewhere, positions a bit lower on the totem pole have also found successful socialist candidates, including winning city or area council seats in Atlanta, Georgia; Cambridge, Massachusetts; Detroit, Michigan; Greenbelt, Maryland; Ithaca, New York; Jersey City, New&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/12/odonnell-yes-socialism-works/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 17:42:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Portland Studies Inclusionary Zoning (Again) Despite Evidence</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/portland-studies-inclusionary-zoning-again-despite-evidence/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Portland is commissioning its own study on the “effects of inclusionary zoning,” as if the question was unsettled, novel, or open. It isn’t. Across the ideological spectrum, from UC Berkeley to NYU Law to George Mason and numerous think tanks, colleges, and studies across the country, the research record is remarkably consistent: inclusionary zoning reduces housing [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/portland-studies-inclusionary-zoning-again-despite-evidence/"&gt;Portland Studies Inclusionary Zoning (Again) Despite Evidence&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 17:47:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] Franke: Reapportionment</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/12/franke-reapportionment/</link><description>by Mark Franke The Indiana General Assembly’s special session appears to be over, having voted down a mid-decade congressional reapportionment proposal. The legislature is required to reapportion after each decennial census but not more often, although nothing prevents more frequent efforts other than their fiscal and political costs. Despite the heavy-handed involvement of Donald Trump&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/12/franke-reapportionment/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 17:48:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Mississippi's Free-Market Turnaround: A Model for America</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/mississippis-free-market-turnaround-a-model-for-america/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For decades, Mississippi has been the punchline in national discussions about economic performance - often ranked at the bottom in income, education, and opportunity. But something remarkable has happened in recent years: the Magnolia State is undergoing a genuine resurgence, driven not by federal handouts or gimmicks, but by principled free-market reforms. A major national [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/mississippis-free-market-turnaround-a-model-for-america/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi&amp;#039;s Free-Market Turnaround: A Model for America&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 21:13:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Florida Should Lead in Securing Healthcare Technology</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/florida-should-lead-in-securing-healthcare-technology/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Every day, millions of Americans are sustained, monitored, and diagnosed by medical technology they never think twice about....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/florida-should-lead-in-securing-healthcare-technology/"&gt;Florida Should Lead in Securing Healthcare Technology&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 21:54:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Goldwater: Pima County Lacks Power to Block Copper Mine Access</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/goldwater-pima-county-lacks-power-to-block-copper-mine-access/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;After objecting to a new copper mine in Southern Arizona, the Pima County Board of Supervisors is now attempting to..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/goldwater-pima-county-lacks-power-to-block-copper-mine-access/"&gt;Goldwater: Pima County Lacks Power to Block Copper Mine Access&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 23:20:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Enrollment and Employment: Is Tennessee Preparing K-12 Students for Today’s Economy?</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/enrollment-and-employment-is-tennessee-preparing-k-12-students-for-todays-economy/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=enrollment-and-employment-is-tennessee-preparing-k-12-students-for-todays-economy</link><description>Tennessee is doing well in providing Career and Technical Education (CTE) opportunities to students, but policymakers should recognize that improvements can be made.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 02:17:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Bearing False Witness</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/bearing-false-witness/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Those limits grew out of lived experience and a deep Christian faith shaped by the Protestant Reformation. The Fourth, Fifth, Sixth, Eighth, and Fourteenth Amendments reflect that inheritance. They function as a kind of secular catechism, a rule book governing our system of justice. This year, John Grisham stepped away from fiction to tell the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/bearing-false-witness/"&gt;Bearing False Witness&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 11:00:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] If Massachusetts Can Rein In Property Taxes, Any State Can</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/if-massachusetts-can-rein-in-property-taxes-any-state-can/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="If Massachusetts Can Rein In Property Taxes, Any State Can" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/massachusetts.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite ranking among the nation’s worst tax climates and having some of the highest income, sales, and property taxes, Massachusetts has successfully enforced a strong property tax cap through its Proposition 2½ for more than 40 years.&lt;br /&gt;
The cap limits annual levy growth to 2.5%, encourages disciplined budgeting, and includes a voter-approved override process, enabling communities to fund priorities without uncontrolled tax increases.&lt;br /&gt;
Massachusetts proves that even a high-spending state can maintain an effective property tax cap; Iowa can adopt similar limits without harming essential services or local government operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/if-massachusetts-can-rein-in-property-taxes-any-state-can/"&gt;If Massachusetts Can Rein In Property Taxes, Any State Can&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 13:52:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] A Cautionary Moment for Union Transparency as Former NJEA Leader Seeks a National Role</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/12/a-cautionary-moment-for-union-transparency-as-former-njea-leader-seeks-a-national-role/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The recent announcement that former New Jersey Education Association president Sean Spiller has launched a campaign for leadership within the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/12/a-cautionary-moment-for-union-transparency-as-former-njea-leader-seeks-a-national-role/"&gt;A Cautionary Moment for Union Transparency as Former NJEA Leader Seeks a National Role&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 14:20:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] New Jersey Policy Institute Welcomes Kristen Cobo to Its Board of Directors</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/12/new-jersey-policy-institute-welcomes-kristen-cobo-to-its-board-of-directors/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Leader in Children’s Mental Health and Parental Rights Advocacy Joins Expanding NJPI Board FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE Parsippany, N.J. — December [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/12/new-jersey-policy-institute-welcomes-kristen-cobo-to-its-board-of-directors/"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute Welcomes Kristen Cobo to Its Board of Directors&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 14:26:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Freedom Foundation CEO Aaron Withe Statement on House Bill Undermining President Trump’s Union Reform Executive Orders</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/national/freedom-foundation-ceo-aaron-withe-statement-on-house-bill-undermining-president-trumps-union-reform-executive-orders/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Freedom Foundation CEO Aaron Withe today released the following statement on the passage of the Protect America's Workforce Act by the U.S. House of Representatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/national/freedom-foundation-ceo-aaron-withe-statement-on-house-bill-undermining-president-trumps-union-reform-executive-orders/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation CEO Aaron Withe Statement on House Bill Undermining President Trump&amp;#8217;s Union Reform Executive Orders&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 15:35:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Florida Politics: Bedrock, We Have a Problem</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/florida-politics-bedrock-we-have-a-problem/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A funny thing happened in the Legislature last week. While the House was holding an “AI Week” to...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/florida-politics-bedrock-we-have-a-problem/"&gt;Florida Politics: Bedrock, We Have a Problem&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 16:05:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Introducing EPIC: A New Investment in Solution Development</title><link>https://empowerms.org/introducing-epic-a-new-investment-in-solution-development/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For more than a decade, Empower Mississippi has worked to advance opportunity-focused policy at the State Capitol. Many of you have been partners in that work — meeting with lawmakers, investing financially, and championing reforms that help Mississippians live free, work meaningfully, and learn effectively. From the beginning, our advocacy has been grounded in research&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/introducing-epic-a-new-investment-in-solution-development/"&gt;Introducing EPIC: A New Investment in Solution Development&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 16:08:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Kansas’s Revenue Mirage and the Case for a Responsible Budget in 2026</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/kansas-revenue-mirage-responsible-budget/</link><description>The Kansas State government may be collecting more money than expected, but that should make lawmakers nervous, not comfortable.  Individual income tax collections are surging, but at the same time retail sales are slowing and corporate income tax revenues are weakening. When workers get paid more while consumers and businesses pull back, the economy is [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 16:34:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Matthew Gagnon: Gov. Mills Allowing ICE Bill to Pass is “Cowardly”</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/matt-gagnon-gov-mills-allowing-ice-bill-to-pass-is-cowardly/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In an op-ed written to the Portland Press Herald, Governor Janet Mills announced that she will allow a controversial bill, LD 1971, to become law without her signature, limiting police cooperation with federal immigration authorities. Citing concerns about the bill’s broadness and President Trump’s actions, Mills argued that the times necessitate the law, despite not [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/matt-gagnon-gov-mills-allowing-ice-bill-to-pass-is-cowardly/"&gt;Matthew Gagnon: Gov. Mills Allowing ICE Bill to Pass is &amp;#8220;Cowardly&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 20:07:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Zoning Promised Order, But Delivered Scarcity.</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/zoning-promised-order-but-delivered-scarcity/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Texas adopted Hoover’s blueprint a century ago. Today, the bill is due in higher prices and lost liberty. Progressive-era policy rears its head in Texas housing. A century after Herbet Hoover put housing under government management, innovation has faltered, consumer choice has dwindled, and costs have exploded. Popular sentiment casts Herbert Hoover as a do-nothing,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/zoning-promised-order-but-delivered-scarcity/"&gt;Zoning Promised Order, But Delivered Scarcity.&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 20:54:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Tiffany Smiley elected to MSPC Board of Directors</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/tiffany-smiley-elected-to-mspc-board-of-directors</link><description>Mountain States Policy Center's (MSPC) Board of Directors has unanimously approved the election of Tiffany Smiley to its Board of Directors, adding a nationally recognized advocate and media contributor with deep experience in service, leadership, and public policy engagement. Smiley grew up on a small farm in rural Washington, where raising 4-H animals and working the land instilled grit, responsibility, and an entrepreneurial spirit. She became the first in her family to earn a college...</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 07:56:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Whitmer says Covid lockdowns were based on bad information</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/whitmer-says-covid-lockdowns-were-based-on-bad-information</link><description>Governor’s about-face calls for an explanation</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] How do price controls damage innovation?</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/how-do-price-controls-damage-innovation/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;What role do intellectual property laws play in encouraging innovation? They are absolutely essential. IP protections like patents reward those who succeed in creating new medicines and ushering them through the regulatory approval process. They do this by guaranteeing that the IP rights holder behind a new drug will have a period of exclusive sales. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/how-do-price-controls-damage-innovation/"&gt;How do price controls damage innovation?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 11:00:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] Franke: Farm Subsidies — A Better Way</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/12/franke-farm-subsidies-a-better-way/</link><description>by Mark Franke One of the reasons I look forward to our monthly Socratic discussion group is the opportunity to learn something new. Regardless of what knowledge I have of the designated topic going in, two hours of rigorous discussion later and I leave knowing much more. Last month the topic was agricultural subsidies and&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/12/franke-farm-subsidies-a-better-way/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 13:30:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] The Montana Constitution’s state university quagmire</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/the-montana-constitution-s-state-university-quagmire</link><description>One reason Montanans should opt for a new state constitutional convention in 2030 is that the 1972 constitution is plagued by poorly written language. The ensuing lawsuits give lawyers and judges power that belongs to the people and their elected representatives.   Illustrative are the provisions governing the Montana University System (MUS).   The document says, “The government and control of the Montana university system is vested in a board of regents . . . which shall have full power,...</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 14:52:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Research Note: Changes in AI Regulations</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/research-note-changes-in-ai-regulations/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On Thursday, December 11, President Trump signed an executive order aimed at limiting state-level regulations on artificial intelligence (AI). The order is the latest in a series of efforts by the administration to centralize AI governance at the federal level. While it takes a distinctive approach, the order also introduces several practical and legal challenges.  ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/research-note-changes-in-ai-regulations/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Research Note: Changes in AI Regulations&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 15:29:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Why is Texas Outsourcing its Government to…Canada?</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/why-is-texas-outsourcing-its-government-tocanada/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Anyone who’s met a Texan knows how proud they are of their state. Some of them even prefer the term..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/why-is-texas-outsourcing-its-government-tocanada/"&gt;Why is Texas Outsourcing its Government to…Canada?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 17:25:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Pioneer New England Legal Foundation and Sullivan &amp; Worcester Sue Boston Over Retaliatory Tax Scheme</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/pioneer-legal-foundation-sullivan-worcester-sue-boston-over-retaliatory-tax-scheme/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Class action challenges city’s unlawful penalties against commercial taxpayers who exercised their right to appeal; seeks court intervention to end this retaliatory scheme in next fiscal year BOSTON, MA — Pioneer New England Legal Foundation (the Legal Foundation) and Sullivan &amp;#38; Worcester...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/pioneer-legal-foundation-sullivan-worcester-sue-boston-over-retaliatory-tax-scheme/"&gt;Pioneer New England Legal Foundation and Sullivan &amp;amp; Worcester Sue Boston Over Retaliatory Tax Scheme&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 18:43:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Building America’s Energy Future: The Case for Federal Permitting Reform</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/energy/the-case-for-federal-permitting-reform/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;America is experiencing the largest surge in electricity demand in modern history. The rapid growth of advanced manufacturing, electrification, reshoring, and data centers are making the U.S. economy more energy-intensive by the year. Projections show electricity demand could rise as much as 50 percent by 2040.  Massive new investments in power generation, transmission, pipelines, ports,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/energy/the-case-for-federal-permitting-reform/"&gt;Building America&amp;#8217;s Energy Future: The Case for Federal Permitting Reform&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 20:46:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Illinois job growth less than half of Midwest’s in past year</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/illinois-job-growth-less-than-half-of-midwests-in-past-year/</link><description>&lt;p&gt; The information sector remains a bright spot in an otherwise challenging Illinois job market, but unemployment has pulled even with the national rate. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/illinois-job-growth-less-than-half-of-midwests-in-past-year/"&gt;Illinois job growth less than half of Midwest’s in past year&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 21:50:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Don’t Leave Kids Home Alone With AI</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/dont-leave-kids-home-alone-with-ai/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of Home Alone, Kevin McCallister is not dreaming of independence or adventure. He is frustrated, overlooked, and angry enough to wish his family would simply disappear. It is a familiar childhood impulse, played for laughs and quickly resolved by the warmth of family reunion. But in today’s Texas households, new artificial intelligence tools...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/dont-leave-kids-home-alone-with-ai/"&gt;Don’t Leave Kids Home Alone With AI&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 22:31:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] What George Bailey Understood About Housing and Families</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/what-george-bailey-understood-about-housing-and-families/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In It’s a Wonderful Life, George Bailey’s great ambition is not wealth or status. It is something far more ordinary and far more powerful: the ability for working families to afford a home, put down roots, and build a future together. Bedford Falls thrives not because of grand social programs, but because ordinary people can buy modest homes...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/what-george-bailey-understood-about-housing-and-families/"&gt;What George Bailey Understood About Housing and Families&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 22:33:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Will the Delta Pumps Operate at Capacity this Winter?</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/will-the-delta-pumps-operate-at-capacity-this-winter/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=will-the-delta-pumps-operate-at-capacity-this-winter</link><description>&lt;p&gt;With another series of drenching storms about to hit California, now is a good time to ask what has become a perennial question: why can’t we harvest more of this massive runoff and reserve it for our farms and cities? California must periodically cope with multi-year droughts, but these droughts are usually preceded by years...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/will-the-delta-pumps-operate-at-capacity-this-winter/"&gt;Will the Delta Pumps Operate at Capacity this Winter?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 22:46:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Tackling WSJ ‘fearmongering’ about gun ownership</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/tackling-wsj-fearmongering-about-gun-ownership/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;John Lott writes for Real Clear Wire about one major media outlet’s spin on recent gun-related stories. Legally armed civilians, we’re told, pose a major danger. They shoot innocent bystanders, justifiably kill others whenever they personally believe “force is reasonably necessary,” and rely on racist self-defense laws. At least these concerns are the case in...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/tackling-wsj-fearmongering-about-gun-ownership/"&gt;Tackling WSJ &amp;#8216;fearmongering&amp;#8217; about gun ownership&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 10:42:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Bond proposal results show taxpayers are skeptical</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/bond-proposal-results-show-taxpayers-are-skeptical</link><description>School districts have work to do with voters</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Gassing up in Illinois pricey during record holiday travel</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/gassing-up-in-illinois-pricey-during-record-holiday-travel/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;AAA estimates 5.7 million Illinoisans will travel this holiday season. Most will be driving, forced to pay the nation’s No. 2 gas taxes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/gassing-up-in-illinois-pricey-during-record-holiday-travel/"&gt;Gassing up in Illinois pricey during record holiday travel&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 11:00:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] One cat death is a tragedy. 43K human deaths is a statistic</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/one-cat-death-is-a-tragedy-43k-human-deaths-is-a-statistic/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For those who missed the internationally publicized brouhaha, a tabby named Kit Kat had lived in the city’s Mission, where he sauntered into bodegas and bars. Dubbed the Mayor of 16th Street, Kit Kat was by all accounts a charming character. Then on October 27, the unthinkable happened: a Waymo self-driving taxi ran him over. Kit Kat’s [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/one-cat-death-is-a-tragedy-43k-human-deaths-is-a-statistic/"&gt;One cat death is a tragedy. 43K human deaths is a statistic&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 11:00:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] IFT vows to fight funding to help public school kids</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/ift-vows-to-fight-funding-to-help-public-school-kids/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Illinois Federation of Teachers told members it will “stay vigilant” to keep privately-donated money out of students’ pockets. Illinois kids need the help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/ift-vows-to-fight-funding-to-help-public-school-kids/"&gt;IFT vows to fight funding to help public school kids&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 11:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Florida Politics: The Ghost (Students) of Public School Future?</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/florida-politics-the-ghost-students-of-public-school-future/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;U.S. Secretary of Education Linda McMahon announced last week that her department plans to step up efforts to...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/florida-politics-the-ghost-students-of-public-school-future/"&gt;Florida Politics: The Ghost (Students) of Public School Future?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 14:49:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Minnesota Man of the Day</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/minnesota-man-of-the-day-12/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Gorgonio Yanez-Magallanes is our Minnesota Man of the Day for December 18. Yanez is scheduled to appear in federal court in downtown St. Paul this afternoon to enter a guilty plea. He requires the use of a taxpayer-paid Spanish-language interpreter at all of his court appearances. He will plead guilty to one felony count of...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/minnesota-man-of-the-day-12/"&gt;Minnesota Man of the Day&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 14:58:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] A promising AI safety tool for teen accounts</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/a-promising-ai-safety-tool-for-teen-accounts</link><description>In October, Meta announced a new “teen AI safety” approach for Instagram, Facebook, and its other platforms.  The headline change is simple but important: parents will soon have a built-in “kill switch” for one-on-one chats between their teens and AI characters. Additionally, it’ll provide better insight into what their teens are doing with AI on Meta’s apps. This is exactly the type of voluntary, market-driven parental tool we highlighted in The Parental Guide to Understanding Digital Media...</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 15:14:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Only Gov. Walz can call a special session to pass new gun control laws: Why doesn’t he?</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/only-gov-walz-can-call-a-special-session-to-pass-new-gun-control-laws-why-doesnt-he/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;With the epidemic of fraud perpetrated against Minnesota’s taxpayers under Gov. Walz’ administration making national news and hammering his chances in a 2028 presidential run, he is desperate to change the conversation. The governor — and the DFL generally — hope that gun control can be in 2026 what abortion was in 2022, and distract voters from...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/only-gov-walz-can-call-a-special-session-to-pass-new-gun-control-laws-why-doesnt-he/"&gt;Only Gov. Walz can call a special session to pass new gun control laws: Why doesn&amp;#8217;t he?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 15:21:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Duke rate hikes: The lingering effects of bad policy choices</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/duke-rate-hikes-the-lingering-effects-of-bad-policy-choices/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On Nov. 20, Duke Energy announced that it had requested rate increases from the North Carolina Utilities Commission (NCUC) of 15.0 percent for Duke Energy Carolinas (DEC) customers and 15.1 percent for Duke Energy Progress (DEP) customers. If granted, the requests would raise the monthly bill of a typical residential customer by $17.22 for DEC...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/duke-rate-hikes-the-lingering-effects-of-bad-policy-choices/"&gt;Duke rate hikes: The lingering effects of bad policy choices&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 15:57:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] We’ve Got Talent: Encouraging the Innovators and Students of Our Nation Towards Excellence</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/encouraging-the-innovators-and-students-of-our-nation-towards-excellence/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The United States is home to some of the most genius innovators and groundbreaking technologies of the modern age. Headlines in high profile news outlets frequently recount the cutthroat competition between tech companies and entrepreneurs, eager to develop products that change lives and win over the market. Excellence is the result of this competitive environment,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/encouraging-the-innovators-and-students-of-our-nation-towards-excellence/"&gt;We’ve Got Talent: Encouraging the Innovators and Students of Our Nation Towards Excellence&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 15:59:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Marquette poll finds 80 percent of Americans trust government ‘only some of the time’ or ‘never’</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/marquette-poll-finds-80-percent-of-americans-trust-government-only-some-of-the-time-or-never/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Widespread, intergenerational skepticism of government is not merely the result of America’s increasingly cutthroat politics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/marquette-poll-finds-80-percent-of-americans-trust-government-only-some-of-the-time-or-never/"&gt;Marquette poll finds 80 percent of Americans trust government ‘only some of the time’ or ‘never’&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 16:58:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Freedom Foundation Forces AFSCME to Refund Dues and Honor Minnesota Worker’s Rights</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/litigation/freedom-foundation-forces-afscme-to-refund-dues-and-honor-minnesota-workers-rights/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A simple request was met with silence. In July of 2024, John Cashman, a senior press operator with the Minnesota Department of Transportation, followed his employer’s instructions and contacted AFSCME Local 221 directly to resign his union membership and revoke his dues authorization.&amp;#160;&amp;#160; He emailed a field representative affirmatively stating his intent to opt out [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/litigation/freedom-foundation-forces-afscme-to-refund-dues-and-honor-minnesota-workers-rights/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation Forces AFSCME to Refund Dues and Honor Minnesota Worker’s Rights&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 17:09:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Lawmakers Seek Bipartisan Reform for MI Economic Development Programs</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/pressroom/2025/lawmakers-seek-bipartisan-reform-for-mi-economic-development-programs</link><description>Mackinac Center applauds bills that would base programs on fairness, accountability and measurable results</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 19:48:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Has MN fraud reached $10 billion yet?</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/has-mn-fraud-reached-10-billion-yet/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;It sure looks like it. Lead federal prosecutor Joe Thompson held a 35-minute press conference today to discuss the scope of the fraud, and to announce six more indictments and a new FBI raid. You can see the entire event at this link. The program begins at the 3:00 mark. Our man Bill Walsh was...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/has-mn-fraud-reached-10-billion-yet/"&gt;Has MN fraud reached $10 billion yet?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 20:02:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Legal Challenge over Belton Housing Project Highlights Flawed Approval Process</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/regulation/legal-challenge-over-belton-housing-project-highlights-flawed-approval-process/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A legal battle has erupted over a proposed housing development in Belton, Missouri. Regardless of the lawsuit&amp;#8217;s outcome, the case [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/regulation/legal-challenge-over-belton-housing-project-highlights-flawed-approval-process/"&gt;Legal Challenge over Belton Housing Project Highlights Flawed Approval Process&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 20:27:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Accountable, Understandable, and Comparable</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/accountability/accountable-understandable-and-comparable/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;There are so many things that go well together during the Christmas season. Faith and family, sweet potatoes and those [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/accountability/accountable-understandable-and-comparable/"&gt;Accountable, Understandable, and Comparable&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 20:50:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Rights Before Power: North Carolina’s Declaration of Rights</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/rights-before-power-north-carolinas-declaration-of-rights/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When North Carolina’s Fifth Provincial Congress convened in Halifax on November 12, 1776, the delegates undertook a daunting task that would define North Carolina. In just five weeks, they debated, drafted, and ultimately adopted two foundational documents. On December 17, they ratified the North Carolina Declaration of Rights. The next day, they ratified the state’s...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/rights-before-power-north-carolinas-declaration-of-rights/"&gt;Rights Before Power: North Carolina’s Declaration of Rights&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 20:54:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Extension of property tax waiver vital for rebuilding of Lahaina</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/12/extension-of-property-tax-waiver-vital-for-rebuilding-of-lahaina/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Maui County Council on Dec. 19, 2025._____________ Dec. 19, 2025, 9 a.m.Kalana O Maui Building To: Maui County Council&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Alice Lee, Chair&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Yuki Lei Sugimura, Vice Chair From: Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Jonathan Helton, Policy Analyst Re: Bill 171 (2025) [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/12/extension-of-property-tax-waiver-vital-for-rebuilding-of-lahaina/"&gt;Extension of property tax waiver vital for rebuilding of Lahaina&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 21:04:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Santa aids Freedom Foundation outreach for another holiday season</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/santa-aids-freedom-foundation-outreach-for-another-holiday-season/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;To cut through the holiday and end-of-year chaos, we took a familiar twist. As they do every year, our outreach team members suited up as Santa Claus and his helpers to spark conversations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/santa-aids-freedom-foundation-outreach-for-another-holiday-season/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Santa aids Freedom Foundation outreach for another holiday season&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 21:05:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Allow all burned Lahaina structures to be rebuilt to pre-fire heights</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/12/allow-all-burned-lahaina-structures-to-be-rebuilt-to-pre-fire-heights/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Maui County Council on Dec. 19, 2025._____________ Dec. 19, 2025, 9 a.m.Kalana O Maui Building To: Maui County Council&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Alice Lee, Chair&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Yuki Lei Sugimura, Vice Chair From: Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Jonathan Helton, Policy Analyst RE: Bill 183 (2025) [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/12/allow-all-burned-lahaina-structures-to-be-rebuilt-to-pre-fire-heights/"&gt;Allow all burned Lahaina structures to be rebuilt to pre-fire heights&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 21:09:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Grassroot testimonies submitted in mid-December 2025</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/12/grassroot-testimonies-submitted-in-mid-december-2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Below are testimonies submitted during mid-December 2025 by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Hawai‘i and Maui county councils and the Honolulu Planning Commission. HAWAI‘I COUNTY  &amp;#62;&amp;#62;&amp;#160;Bill 103 (2025)&amp;#160;— “Limit tax hikes for senior owners as agricultural land values increase”&amp;#160; MAUI COUNTY &amp;#62;&amp;#62;&amp;#160;Bill 9 (2025)&amp;#160;— “Proposed STR phaseout is legal, economic crisis [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/12/grassroot-testimonies-submitted-in-mid-december-2025/"&gt;Grassroot testimonies submitted in mid-December 2025&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 21:27:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] One Word Could Let Missouri Students Leave Unsafe Schools</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/education/one-word-could-let-missouri-students-leave-unsafe-schools/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Under the federal Every Student Succeeds Act (ESSA), states must identify unsafe schools and notify families of students who attend [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/education/one-word-could-let-missouri-students-leave-unsafe-schools/"&gt;One Word Could Let Missouri Students Leave Unsafe Schools&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 21:30:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Albany’s School Speed Zone Camera Summer Daze</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/albanys-school-speed-zone-camera-summer-daze/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This fall, Governor Kathy Hochul signed into law bills containing the state’s permission for three cities — Mount Vernon, Schenectady....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/albanys-school-speed-zone-camera-summer-daze/"&gt;Albany’s School Speed Zone Camera Summer Daze&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 21:59:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Busting the ESA Myths with the Facts — Watch the Webinar</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/busting-the-esa-myths-with-the-facts-watch-the-webinar/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Empowerment Scholarship Accounts (ESAs) is a free government program that gives all Arizona kids the education they deserve. Today, more..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/busting-the-esa-myths-with-the-facts-watch-the-webinar/"&gt;Busting the ESA Myths with the Facts — Watch the Webinar&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 22:10:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] U.S. House defangs federal protection of gray wolves in Wisconsin</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/us-house-defangs-federal-protection-of-gray-wolves-in-wisconsin/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The U.S. House of Representatives Thursday passed a bill that would remove the state’s rapidly expanding and aggressive gray wolf population from the endangered species list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/us-house-defangs-federal-protection-of-gray-wolves-in-wisconsin/"&gt;U.S. House defangs federal protection of gray wolves in Wisconsin&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 22:32:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Ugly Math for Taxpayers</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/ugly-math-for-taxpayers/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=ugly-math-for-taxpayers</link><description>Taxpayer-funded lobbying (TFL) is nothing new in Tennessee, but it is almost universally frowned upon.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 22:52:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] The Public Purpose Program: California’s Hidden Tax Driving Up Utility Bills</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/17209-2/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=17209-2</link><description>&lt;p&gt;After several rate hikes implemented in the last few years alone, Californians are asking why their energy bills keep climbing when they use the same amount of electricity or gas. According to a 2023 report from the Transparency Foundation, residents of California pay up to 67% more for electricity and 30% more for natural gas...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/17209-2/"&gt;The Public Purpose Program: California’s Hidden Tax Driving Up Utility Bills&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 23:58:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Oregon’s “Prosperity Roadmap” Must Follow the Path of Liberty</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/economic-opportunity/oregons-prosperity-roadmap-must-follow-the-path-of-liberty/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Naomi Inman Early this December, Governor Tina Kotek’s newsroom unveiled “Oregon’s Prosperity...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/economic-opportunity/oregons-prosperity-roadmap-must-follow-the-path-of-liberty/"&gt;Oregon’s “Prosperity Roadmap” Must Follow the Path of Liberty&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 00:20:16 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>