<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>State-Policy Think-Tank Digest</title><link>https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml</link><description>Latest posts from free-market policy institutes across the U.S.</description><atom:link href="https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 19:04:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>[Rifreedom] Center Mourns the Loss of Board Member Michael G. Riley, Civic Leader</title><link>https://rifreedom.org/2025/11/center-mourns-the-loss-of-board-member-michael-g-riley-civic-leader/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org/2025/11/center-mourns-the-loss-of-board-member-michael-g-riley-civic-leader/"&gt;Center Mourns the Loss of Board Member Michael G. Riley, Civic Leader&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org"&gt;RI Center for Freedom and Prosperity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 16:51:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Trouble on the Right – Why Conservatives Need to be Wary</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/trouble-on-the-right-why-conservatives-need-to-be-wary/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I only recently learned what a “groyper” is - you may or may not be familiar with the term?&amp;#160;From what I can tell, a groyper is a hardline white nationalist.&amp;#160; Often anti-Semitic, groypers are hostile to mainstream conservatives.&amp;#160; To the extent they have a coherent agenda, groypers seem more national socialism than free-market capitalism.&amp;#160;Having been [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/trouble-on-the-right-why-conservatives-need-to-be-wary/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Trouble on the Right – Why Conservatives Need to be Wary&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 18:29:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Decoding bureaucracy: how AI could aid regulatory reform</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/decoding-bureaucracy-how-ai-could-aid-regulatory-reform/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For decades, the image of government regulation has been synonymous with dusty, overflowing binders and legal jargon. State regulatory codes tend to accumulate year after year, sometimes contradicting themselves and complicating life for those navigating the process. This accumulation of &amp;#8220;red tape&amp;#8221; creates significant burdens for small business owners trying to remain compliant, citizens trying...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/decoding-bureaucracy-how-ai-could-aid-regulatory-reform/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Decoding bureaucracy: how AI could aid regulatory reform&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 21:18:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] On Thanksgiving, remember that gratitude makes good citizens, heals divisions</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/gratitude-makes-good-citizens-and-heals-divisions/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/gratitude-makes-good-citizens-and-heals-divisions/"&gt;On Thanksgiving, remember that gratitude makes good citizens, heals divisions&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 23:00:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Oregon’s 19th Century Energy Strategy</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/economic-opportunity/oregons-19th-century-energy-strategy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By John A. Charles, Jr. Recently the Oregon Department of Energy (ODOE) published...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/economic-opportunity/oregons-19th-century-energy-strategy/"&gt;Oregon’s 19th Century Energy Strategy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 00:31:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] The War of Visions</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/11/28/the-war-of-visions/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Across the country, Americans are no longer divided simply by policy or party but by rival moral imaginations—two incompatible visions of truth, freedom, and even human nature itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/11/28/the-war-of-visions/"&gt;The War of Visions&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 00:23:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Approval of Gas Generation Plant Divides Two Big Donors Who Helped Democrats Win</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/approval-of-gas-generation-plant-divides-two-big-donors-who-helped-democrats-win/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="720" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Chesterfield-Power-Plant-1.jpg" width="1280" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The State Corporation Commission (SCC) was able to approve Dominion Energy Virginia’s application for a needed natural gas generation facility because the Virginia Clean Economy Act (VCEA) includes a safety valve. If energy reliability is threatened, the prohibitions on natural gas at the heart of that law can be waived. One of the largest donors [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/approval-of-gas-generation-plant-divides-two-big-donors-who-helped-democrats-win/"&gt;Approval of Gas Generation Plant Divides Two Big Donors Who Helped Democrats Win&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 15:15:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] YAF v SBA</title><link>https://will-law.org/yaf-v-sba/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL and the Center for Individual Rights (CIR) filed a major lawsuit against the Trump Administration today, targeting the foundation for many of the remaining federal DEI programs: the preference for so-called “socially disadvantaged individuals.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/yaf-v-sba/"&gt;YAF v SBA&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 18:10:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] A Very Grateful Immigrant’s Thanksgiving</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/a-very-grateful-immigrants-thanksgiving/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Having just celebrated Thanksgiving across the United States, I’ve been reminded of what makes this holiday truly special.&amp;#160;&amp;#160;If you’re an American who’s grown up with the holiday your whole life, it’s easy to take it for granted. Speaking as an immigrant, let me tell you: there’s something genuinely magical about a country setting aside a [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/a-very-grateful-immigrants-thanksgiving/" rel="nofollow"&gt;A Very Grateful Immigrant’s Thanksgiving&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 21:11:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] New Hampshire ranked freest state in North America for 24th time</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/12/new-hampshire-ranked-freest-state-in-north-america-for-24th-time/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New Hampshire ranks as the freest state in North America, as measured in this year’s Economic Freedom of North America report, released today by the Josiah Bartlett Center for Public Policy in conjunction with Canada’s Fraser Institute. For the 24th time, New Hampshire is the freest state among all U.S. states, having scored 8.34 out [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/12/new-hampshire-ranked-freest-state-in-north-america-for-24th-time/"&gt;New Hampshire ranked freest state in North America for 24th time&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 12:52:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] The Holiday Season Is Here — But Affordability Still Isn’t</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/the-holiday-season-is-here/</link><description>If it feels like Christmas keeps getting more expensive, that’s because it is,  and Kansans are feeling it more sharply than policymakers care to admit. The rising cost of living is no longer a blip on a chart; it’s a full-blown pocketbook problem showing up in everything from family grocery runs to holiday gift lists. [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 15:17:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG Polling: April 2025</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-polling-april-2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;April 16, 2025 NEW IRG Poll: Voters Decided Election on Abortion, Musk &amp;#38; Trump’s Agenda Despite all the emphasis on crime, voters were focused elsewhere  Delafield, Wis. –  The Institute for Reforming Government (IRG) is continuing its public polling project with Napolitan News Service and Scott Rasmussen in 2025, with the focus in this poll on Wisconsin’s [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-polling-april-2025/"&gt;IRG Polling: April 2025&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 20:28:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Pioneer New England Legal Foundation Files Lawsuit Challenging Cambridge Inclusionary Zoning Ordinance</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/pioneer-new-england-legal-foundation-files-lawsuit-challenging-cambridge-inclusionary-zoning-ordinance/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Requirement that 20 percent of a housing project remain permanently affordable places burden on developers that should be borne by the public as a whole Cambridge – Pioneer New England Legal Foundation filed a lawsuit in state Land Court against the City...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/pioneer-new-england-legal-foundation-files-lawsuit-challenging-cambridge-inclusionary-zoning-ordinance/"&gt;Pioneer New England Legal Foundation Files Lawsuit Challenging Cambridge Inclusionary Zoning Ordinance&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 11:48:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Book Highlights Advances in Digital Education, Policies to Unlock Its Benefits</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/book-highlights-advances-in-digital-education-policies-to-unlock-its-benefits/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;BOSTON – A new book co-edited by national digital education leader Julie Young draws on best practices and multiple studies published by Pioneer Institute to recount three decades of advances in digital education and highlights the policies necessary for students to fully...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/book-highlights-advances-in-digital-education-policies-to-unlock-its-benefits/"&gt;Book Highlights Advances in Digital Education, Policies to Unlock Its Benefits &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 12:06:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] WILL Moves to Intervene in Wisconsin Redistricting Cases on Behalf of Wisconsin Voters</title><link>https://will-law.org/will-moves-to-intervene-in-wisconsin-redistricting-cases-on-behalf-of-wisconsin-voters/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL filed motions to intervene in two lawsuits seeking to overturn Wisconsin’s Congressional Maps. Seeking again to defend those maps on behalf of a group of Wisconsin voters, WILL argues that these new lawsuits are time-barred, the three-judge panel lacks authority to overrule the Wisconsin Supreme Court, and any attempt to impose new maps in this manner would violate federal law and the U.S. Constitution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/will-moves-to-intervene-in-wisconsin-redistricting-cases-on-behalf-of-wisconsin-voters/"&gt;WILL Moves to Intervene in Wisconsin Redistricting Cases on Behalf of Wisconsin Voters&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 14:16:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] The SCC Decides: Dominion’s Rates and Profits Go Up, New Rules on Data Centers</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/the-scc-decides-dominions-rates-and-profits-go-up-new-rules-on-data-centers/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="630" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/dominion-energy-virginia-money.png" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The massive data centers behind a growing energy crunch in Virginia will begin to pay substantially more for electricity in Dominion Energy’s territory, but not until 2027. The State Corporation Commission’s (SCC) approval of a new rate structure for the largest users will probably only intensify debates about what their “fair share” is. On Nov. 25, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/the-scc-decides-dominions-rates-and-profits-go-up-new-rules-on-data-centers/"&gt;The SCC Decides: Dominion’s Rates and Profits Go Up, New Rules on Data Centers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 21:00:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] New Mexico falls to 50th among US states in latest “Index of Economic Freedom”</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/new-mexico-falls-to-50th-among-us-states-in-latest-index-of-economic-freedom/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Rio Grande Foundation has never seen &amp;#8220;eye to eye&amp;#8221; with Gov. Lujan Grisham and the leftists in Santa Fe who have failed to improve New Mexico even with the benefit of billions of dollars in oil and gas revenues. And, while these policy differences and failures may seem trivial to some, they have real [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/new-mexico-falls-to-50th-among-us-states-in-latest-index-of-economic-freedom/"&gt;New Mexico falls to 50th among US states in latest &amp;#8220;Index of Economic Freedom&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 15:40:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] New Revenue Forecast Shows Why Maine Should Cut Taxes, Not Grow Government</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/new-revenue-forecast-shows-why-maine-should-cut-taxes-not-grow-government/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Maine’s latest revenue forecast shows the state will bring in roughly $248 million more than expected over the next two years. However, instead of asking how to give this money back to taxpayers, state leaders are already discussing what government spending to prioritize. This framing is backwards. Maine families are the ones who generated this [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/new-revenue-forecast-shows-why-maine-should-cut-taxes-not-grow-government/"&gt;New Revenue Forecast Shows Why Maine Should Cut Taxes, Not Grow Government&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 16:03:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Nebraska Tax Reform: Why Full Expensing Is the Smart Move</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-tax-reform-why-full-expensing-is-the-smart-move/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The federal One Big Beautiful Bill (OBBB) creates the opportunity for Nebraska to adopt the most “America First” tax reform: full expensing. In an era of reshoring and friend-shoring critical supply chains, full expensing is the tax reform that properly defines “income” and incentivizes production in the U.S.A.   Full expensing is the policy of allowing...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-tax-reform-why-full-expensing-is-the-smart-move/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Nebraska Tax Reform: Why Full Expensing Is the Smart Move&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 16:55:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] Court Watch: Wisconsin Supreme Court Reverses, Consolidates Power Through New Court Management Order</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/court-watch-wisconsin-supreme-court-reverses-consolidates-power-through-new-court-management-order/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Court Watch: Wisconsin Supreme Court Reverses, Consolidates Power Through New Court Management Order Progressive majority reshapes internal court governance to cement its control of the judicial branch Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government’s Court Watch issued the following statement after the Wisconsin Supreme Court quietly issued a new court management order just days [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/court-watch-wisconsin-supreme-court-reverses-consolidates-power-through-new-court-management-order/"&gt;Court Watch: Wisconsin Supreme Court Reverses, Consolidates Power Through New Court Management Order&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 16:58:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] The Hidden Gem: Why Education Freedom is the New Economic Development</title><link>https://empowerms.org/the-hidden-gem-why-education-freedom-is-the-new-economic-development/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Forget industrial parks. The driver for economic growth in rural Mississippi is education freedom, which is the most powerful yet often overlooked tool in our economic development chest. I’ve dedicated my academic research to the topic, stemming from a comment I heard years ago at Starkville City Hall: “Education is the biggest driver of community-economic&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/the-hidden-gem-why-education-freedom-is-the-new-economic-development/"&gt;The Hidden Gem: Why Education Freedom is the New Economic Development&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 17:46:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] A4121 Is a Hatchet When New Jersey Needs a Scalpel</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/12/a4121-is-a-hatchet-when-new-jersey-needs-a-scalpel/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Today, I had the opportunity to testify before the Assembly Education Committee on A4121, a bill that would eliminate New [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/12/a4121-is-a-hatchet-when-new-jersey-needs-a-scalpel/"&gt;A4121 Is a Hatchet When New Jersey Needs a Scalpel&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 21:24:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Working folks get short shrift while city funds vanity streetcar</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/working-folks-get-short-shrift-while-city-funds-vanity-streetcar/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Money wasted on Hop while bus access for people who really need it is at risk Milwaukee County’s bus network has swerved back from the fiscal brink, one tire halfway over the void as officials shuffle money, trim back some routes’ hours and wonder what they’ll do next year. Pay attention, Wisconsin taxpayers: You’re financing [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/working-folks-get-short-shrift-while-city-funds-vanity-streetcar/"&gt;Working folks get short shrift while city funds vanity streetcar&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 22:48:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Portland Public Schools’ Risky Real Estate Gamble</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/education/portland-public-schools-risky-real-estate-gamble/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Eric Fruits, Ph.D. On December 2, Portland Public Schools (PPS) board voted...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/education/portland-public-schools-risky-real-estate-gamble/"&gt;Portland Public Schools’ Risky Real Estate Gamble&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 01:25:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Before Spending Millions to Replace Federal Subsidies, Connecticut Should Audit Its Own Data</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/12/05/before-spending-millions-to-replace-federal-subsidies-connecticut-should-audit-its-own-data/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Access Health CT — the state’s health insurance exchange — recently warned that as many as 30 to 35 percent of its 150,000 marketplace enrollees may lose coverage in the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/12/05/before-spending-millions-to-replace-federal-subsidies-connecticut-should-audit-its-own-data/"&gt;Before Spending Millions to Replace Federal Subsidies, Connecticut Should Audit Its Own Data &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 19:18:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] A ‘Repeal Day’ glance at Liquor Commission revenues</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/12/a-repeal-day-glance-at-liquor-commission-revenues/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;December 5 is neither a federal nor state day of celebration, but it probably should be. On Dec. 5, 1933, Pennsylvania, Ohio and Utah became the final states to ratify the 21st Amendment to the U.S. Constitution.  The night before, toasting your Aunt Gertrude’s 92nd birthday with a glass of champagne was illegal. That evening, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/12/a-repeal-day-glance-at-liquor-commission-revenues/"&gt;A &amp;#8216;Repeal Day&amp;#8217; glance at Liquor Commission revenues&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 22:09:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Small Cost, Big Returns: Technical Schools Building Tennessee</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/small-cost-big-returns-technical-schools-building-tennessee/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=small-cost-big-returns-technical-schools-building-tennessee</link><description>Technical schools may not be the right choice for every high school graduate. Still, for those who have graduated from such programs, data shows they have the potential to make a good living while supporting their local communities, all while avoiding years of student loan payments.</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 22:10:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Georgia candidates for governor should make welfare reform a top priority</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/georgia-candidates-for-governor-should-make-welfare-reform-a-top-priority/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/georgia-candidates-for-governor-should-make-welfare-reform-a-top-priority/"&gt;Georgia candidates for governor should make welfare reform a top priority&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 16:58:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] OPINION: New Mexico’s economic freedom is now dead last</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/opinion-new-mexicos-economic-freedom-is-now-dead-last/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following appeared in the Albuquerque Journal  on December 7, 2025. In a study published earlier this year, we highlighted the fact that New Mexico was the only state in the U.S. to have lost economic freedom since 1981. We now know that it is worse than we thought. People are more economically free when [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/opinion-new-mexicos-economic-freedom-is-now-dead-last/"&gt;OPINION: New Mexico&amp;#8217;s economic freedom is now dead last&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 17:53:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Wichita should reallocate spending rather than add a new (rushed?) 1% sales tax</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/sales-tax-proposal-rushed-wichita/</link><description>The Wichita City Council seems poised to rush a proposal to the ballot for a 1-cent sales tax to raise $850 million over seven years for several new projects. That at least implies that imposing a new tax is the only way to fund “public safety projects, property tax relief, and revitalizing Century II and [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 19:55:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Listen: Steve Robinson &amp; Matt Gagnon on WGAN</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/listen-steve-robinson-matt-gagnon-on-wgan/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Steve Robinson from the Maine Wire joins Matt Gagnon to discuss fraud and corruption by the Maine-based Gateway Community Services (GCS). According to reporting by the The Maine Wire, GCS has been found liable for nearly a million dollars worth of erroneous billing to MaineCare, the state’s Medicare agency, in an unsettling precursor to revelations [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/listen-steve-robinson-matt-gagnon-on-wgan/"&gt;Listen: Steve Robinson &amp;amp; Matt Gagnon on WGAN&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 20:37:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] The Data Center Debate Continues in Festus</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/economy/the-data-center-debate-continues-in-festus/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Amidst great debate, a city commission in Festus recently moved forward with plans for a new data center development. Festus [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/economy/the-data-center-debate-continues-in-festus/"&gt;The Data Center Debate Continues in Festus&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 21:07:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Email Confirms Early Contact Between NY Officials and CDPAP Contractor</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/email-confirms-early-contact-between-ny-officials-and-cdpap-contractor/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;State officials met with the ultimate winner of a $1 billion Medicaid contract two weeks before the Legislature authorized bidding....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/email-confirms-early-contact-between-ny-officials-and-cdpap-contractor/"&gt;Email Confirms Early Contact Between NY Officials and CDPAP Contractor&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 14:46:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] Empty Schools, Empty Wallets: How ESSER Pandemic Aid Led to More School Referenda</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/empty-schools-empty-wallets-how-esser-pandemic-aid-led-to-more-school-referenda/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Empty Schools, Empty Wallets: How ESSER Pandemic Aid Led to More School Referenda New IRG analysis reveals hiring sprees and poor financial decisions as Wisconsin schools fall behind national leaders Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government released a new report on Tuesday, “Empty Schools, Empty Wallets: What Happened to $1.49 Billion in ESSER [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/empty-schools-empty-wallets-how-esser-pandemic-aid-led-to-more-school-referenda/"&gt;Empty Schools, Empty Wallets: How ESSER Pandemic Aid Led to More School Referenda&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 15:02:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Why CT’s Treatment of Faith-Based Nonprofits Matters for Its Civic and Fiscal Future</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/12/09/why-cts-treatment-of-faith-based-nonprofits-matters-for-its-civic-and-fiscal-future/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="1890" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/St-Joseph-scaled-e1765295362919.jpeg" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connecticut ranks among the least friendly states for faith-based nonprofit organizations, largely due to restrictive regulatory and tax policies. These rules not only limit religious expression and charitable outreach but also mirror a national trend: as civic associations shutter, governments expand — shifting more costs [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/12/09/why-cts-treatment-of-faith-based-nonprofits-matters-for-its-civic-and-fiscal-future/"&gt;Why CT&amp;#8217;s Treatment of Faith-Based Nonprofits Matters for Its Civic and Fiscal Future&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 16:12:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] SEIU 503 asks members to do its political dirty work</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/oregon/seiu-503-asks-members-to-do-its-political-dirty-work/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;SEIU 503, Oregon’s largest public employee union, has launched its latest campaign — not in the legislature or at the bargaining table, but on the sidewalks asking its own dues-paying members to inform on their neighbors for engaging in the political process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/oregon/seiu-503-asks-members-to-do-its-political-dirty-work/" rel="nofollow"&gt;SEIU 503 asks members to do its political dirty work&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 20:12:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Massachusetts Subsidized Housing Inventory Update Shows Record Number of Communities Exceed Critical Threshold</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/massachusetts-subsidized-housing-inventory-update-shows-record-number-of-communities-exceed-critical-threshold/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This edition of The House Call explores the 2025 update to Massachusetts&amp;#8217; Subsidized Housing Inventory, showing a spike in the number of communities that have at least 10% of their housing stocks in the Inventory. It also explains the housing-related ballot questions that could...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/massachusetts-subsidized-housing-inventory-update-shows-record-number-of-communities-exceed-critical-threshold/"&gt;Massachusetts Subsidized Housing Inventory Update Shows Record Number of Communities Exceed Critical Threshold&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 20:35:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Commissioner Andy Gipson: Family, Food Security, and Mississippi’s Future</title><link>https://empowerms.org/commissioner-andy-gipson-family-food-security-and-mississippis-future/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Commissioner Andy Gipson: Family, Food Security, and Mississippi’s Future On this episode of The Empower Podcast, host Grant Callen sits down with Commissioner Andy Gipson—Mississippi’s Commissioner of Agriculture and Commerce, former state legislator, Baptist minister, cattleman, and announced candidate for governor. Gipson shares how his journey into public service began with a desire to secure&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/commissioner-andy-gipson-family-food-security-and-mississippis-future/"&gt;Commissioner Andy Gipson: Family, Food Security, and Mississippi’s Future&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:49:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Nebraska Zoning Permitting Process: Recommended Adjustments in Nebraska</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-zoning-permitting-process-recommended-adjustments-in-nebraska/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Nebraska’s zoning and permitting process for livestock operations is inconsistent, unpredictable, and varies widely from county to county. This report examines how Nebraska’s Conditional Use Permit (CUP) system works, the origins and goals of the Livestock Siting Assessment Matrix created under LB106, and why the Matrix remains underused nearly a decade later. Drawing on survey...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-zoning-permitting-process-recommended-adjustments-in-nebraska/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Nebraska Zoning Permitting Process: Recommended Adjustments in Nebraska&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 15:17:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] WILL Hires Associate Counsel to Grow Legal and Policy Capacity in Wisconsin and Beyond</title><link>https://will-law.org/will-hires-associate-counsel-to-grow-legal-and-policy-capacity-in-wisconsin-and-beyond/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL has announced Erin Gamble as our new Associate Counsel. Her hire reflects our organization’s commitment to fighting back against bureaucratic overreach in Wisconsin and across the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/will-hires-associate-counsel-to-grow-legal-and-policy-capacity-in-wisconsin-and-beyond/"&gt;WILL Hires Associate Counsel to Grow Legal and Policy Capacity in Wisconsin and Beyond&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 15:23:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Does Spending $62 Billion on Utility Batteries Lower Your Cost of Electricity? Of Course Not</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/does-spending-62-billion-on-utility-batteries-lower-your-cost-of-electricity-of-course-not/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="720" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/62-billion-battery.jpg" width="1280" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 2026 General Assembly is likely to amend the Virginia Clean Economy Act (VCEA) to greatly expand the construction of utility-scale batteries for our electric grid.&amp;#160;Based on the current prices for Virginia battery installations, this may saddle ratepayers with $54 billion in new capital expenses over 20 years. The Commission on Electric Utility Regulation (CEUR) [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/does-spending-62-billion-on-utility-batteries-lower-your-cost-of-electricity-of-course-not/"&gt;Does Spending $62 Billion on Utility Batteries Lower Your Cost of Electricity? Of Course Not&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 16:50:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Webster Groves Should Not Institute an Economic Development Sales Tax</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/special-taxing-districts/webster-groves-should-not-institute-an-economic-development-sales-tax/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;There is a long list of really dumb taxes in Missouri. The St. Louis and Kansas City earnings taxes are [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/special-taxing-districts/webster-groves-should-not-institute-an-economic-development-sales-tax/"&gt;Webster Groves Should Not Institute an Economic Development Sales Tax&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 20:33:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Will Advocates for More Water Supply Projects Find Unity?</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/will-advocates-for-more-water-supply-projects-find-unity/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=will-advocates-for-more-water-supply-projects-find-unity</link><description>&lt;p&gt;There’s only one way to restore reliable water allocations to farmers, avoid turning our cities into rationed “xeriscaped” heat islands, and cope with whatever the climate ultimately delivers. That’s to build more infrastructure to safely and sustainably produce millions of acre feet of new fresh water every year. There are many practical ways to accomplish...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/will-advocates-for-more-water-supply-projects-find-unity/"&gt;Will Advocates for More Water Supply Projects Find Unity?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 07:06:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] The 2025 Journal</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/the-2025-journal/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Click here to read the full version of The Journal. Table of Contents Florida&amp;#8217;s Rural Renaissance Senate Present...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/the-2025-journal/"&gt;The 2025 Journal&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Sedona’s Home-Sharing Ban Struck Down</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/sedonas-home-sharing-ban-struck-down/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Arizona’s Court of Appeals has delivered a major victory for private property rights, ruling that cities cannot bar homeowners from..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/sedonas-home-sharing-ban-struck-down/"&gt;Sedona’s Home-Sharing Ban Struck Down&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 15:10:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Creating links that change lives: Georgia Center for Opportunity partners with Connect to Work GA</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/gco-partners-with-connect-to-work-ga/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This collaboration will help lift job seekers above the poverty line by providing opportunities for successful careers and upward mobility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/gco-partners-with-connect-to-work-ga/"&gt;Creating links that change lives: Georgia Center for Opportunity partners with Connect to Work GA&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 20:09:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Two-thirds of Americans under 30 say people can’t be trusted, Marquette poll finds</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/two-thirds-of-americans-under-30-say-people-cant-be-trusted-marquette-poll-finds/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Two-thirds of Americans under the age of 30 say they believe most people cannot be trusted, according to a recent nationwide Marquette University Law School poll.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/two-thirds-of-americans-under-30-say-people-cant-be-trusted-marquette-poll-finds/"&gt;Two-thirds of Americans under 30 say people can’t be trusted, Marquette poll finds&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 20:33:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] From Promises to Vetoes: Hochul’s Actions Belie Her Commitment to Transparency</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/from-promises-to-vetoes-hochuls-actions-belie-her-commitment-to-transparency/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Governor Kathy Hochul made news this fall when she used her legislative veto power in a way that looked personal.....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/from-promises-to-vetoes-hochuls-actions-belie-her-commitment-to-transparency/"&gt;From Promises to Vetoes: Hochul&amp;#8217;s Actions Belie Her Commitment to Transparency&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 20:54:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Legislature balks as Evers demands millions for more food aid bureaucrats</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/legislature-balks-as-evers-demands-millions-for-more-food-aid-bureaucrats/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Gov. Tony Evers is pressing the Legislature for $70 million to process FoodShare applications to stave off federal penalties that could cost state taxpayers as much as $225 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/legislature-balks-as-evers-demands-millions-for-more-food-aid-bureaucrats/"&gt;Legislature balks as Evers demands millions for more food aid bureaucrats&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 21:58:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Look Up: Your Bodily Autonomy and Property Rights Are Being Attacked From the Sky</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/look-up-your-bodily-autonomy-and-property-rights-are-being-attacked-from-the-sky/</link><description>Want to have some fun at your holiday family gathering this year? Ask your fellow party-goers what they think about cloud seeding. Are those lines in the sky merely contrails, or signs of weather modification, or some sort of atmospheric experimentation? You’ll soon find a variety of answers, speculation, opinion, and theory — from genuine [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 01:40:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Understanding Iowa’s School Income Surtax</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/understanding-iowas-school-income-surtax/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Understanding Iowa’s School Income Surtax" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/income-surtax.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iowa’s school income surtax, first adopted in 1971, is a district-level tax calculated as a percentage of a taxpayer’s Iowa income tax liability and used to support discretionary school programs.&lt;br /&gt;
Districts may combine the surtax with property taxes to fund the Instructional Support Levy (ISL) and the voter-approved Physical Plant and Equipment Levy (PPEL), adjusting the surtax rate annually to meet budget needs.&lt;br /&gt;
Over the past twenty years, the number of districts not using the surtax has steadily declined, making it an increasingly common but still little-understood part of Iowa’s school finance system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/understanding-iowas-school-income-surtax/"&gt;Understanding Iowa’s School Income Surtax&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 14:07:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Why Missouri Needs Early Literacy Reform with Cory Koedel and Avery Frank</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/education/why-missouri-needs-early-literacy-reform-with-cory-koedel-and-avery-frank/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Susan Pendergrass is joined by Cory Koedel, director of education policy at the Show-Me Institute, and Avery Frank, policy analyst [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/education/why-missouri-needs-early-literacy-reform-with-cory-koedel-and-avery-frank/"&gt;Why Missouri Needs Early Literacy Reform with Cory Koedel and Avery Frank&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 15:16:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] “Fully Funded Schools” Are a Moving Goal Post</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/education/fully-funded-schools-are-a-moving-goal-post/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Kathryn Hickok How much money does it take to “fully fund” Oregon’s...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/education/fully-funded-schools-are-a-moving-goal-post/"&gt;“Fully Funded Schools” Are a Moving Goal Post&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 17:22:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Winners &amp; Losers: Watching the Data &amp; the History</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/winners-losers-watching-the-data-the-history/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Every Friday morning, I join the Cardle &amp;#38; Woolley Show on Talk 1370 Radio in Austin to announce the week’s Winners &amp;#38; Losers. Amid the joys of this holy season and the machinations of the College Football Playoff bracket, here’s the list for this week: &amp;#160; WINNER: Paying Attention to History White House Chief of...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/winners-losers-watching-the-data-the-history/"&gt;Winners &amp; Losers: Watching the Data &amp; the History&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 17:37:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Taxpayers Asked to Fund a Hospital Takeover They’re Not Allowed to See</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/12/12/taxpayers-asked-to-fund-a-hospital-takeover-theyre-not-allowed-to-see/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Connecticut lawmakers pushed the UConn Health hospital acquisition bill through the November special session — without a public hearing — it was clear transparency was not the priority.   [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/12/12/taxpayers-asked-to-fund-a-hospital-takeover-theyre-not-allowed-to-see/"&gt;Taxpayers Asked to Fund a Hospital Takeover They’re Not Allowed to See&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 18:13:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] When Past Meets Present: Russian California and the Monroe Doctrine</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/when-past-meets-present/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=when-past-meets-present</link><description>&lt;p&gt;During this week’s Radio Free California podcast, cohosts David Bahnsen and myself discussed the return of the Monroe Doctrine, now offered as the logic behind the Trump administration’s decision to blow up Venezuelan drug boats and to invite that country’s president, Nicolás Maduro, to step outside. It’s unlikely most Americans know that the doctrine, which President James Monroe...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/when-past-meets-present/"&gt;When Past Meets Present: Russian California and the Monroe Doctrine&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 19:46:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Week in Review:  Stamping Out a Trash Monopoly</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-stamping-out-a-trash-monopoly/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The government should not be in the business of protecting preferred service providers from competition—it’s a key principle of economic..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-stamping-out-a-trash-monopoly/"&gt;Week in Review:  Stamping Out a Trash Monopoly&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 20:32:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Would you invest in Massachusetts or New Hampshire?</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/12/would-you-invest-in-massachusetts-or-new-hampshire/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;If U.S. states were companies that traded on the stock market, the only New England state with a “buy” rating would probably be New Hampshire.  Massachusetts could be called “Big Blue,” the tradition-bound leader cruising on its prior reputation, but falling behind smaller upstarts that have embraced innovation and rapid growth.  New Hampshire would be [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/12/would-you-invest-in-massachusetts-or-new-hampshire/"&gt;Would you invest in Massachusetts or New Hampshire?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 21:10:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Louisiana’s Path to Economic Prosperity and Energy Dominance Runs Through Free Markets</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/energy/pathtoeconomicprosperityandenergydominance/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier this month, Entergy Louisiana broke ground on two of three new gas-fired power plants designed to serve Meta’s $10 billion AI-optimized data center in Richland Parish. That project is just one of more than 200 major industrial investments now in Louisiana’s pipeline—and nearly all have the same top concern: access to reliable, affordable electricity....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/energy/pathtoeconomicprosperityandenergydominance/"&gt;Louisiana’s Path to Economic Prosperity and Energy Dominance Runs Through Free Markets&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 00:34:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Time Is Running Out: Legislature Must Fully Fund LA GATOR to Deliver for Louisiana’s Kids</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/education/time-is-running-out-legislature-must-fully-fund-la-gator-to-deliver-for-louisianas-kids/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As Louisiana lawmakers gear up for the 2026 regular legislative session, one issue stands out as both urgent and transformative: fully funding the Louisiana Giving All True Opportunity to Rise (LA GATOR) program. Enacted in 2024 as one of the nation&amp;#8217;s most comprehensive universal education savings account (ESA) initiatives, LA GATOR promises to empower families...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/education/time-is-running-out-legislature-must-fully-fund-la-gator-to-deliver-for-louisianas-kids/"&gt;Time Is Running Out: Legislature Must Fully Fund LA GATOR to Deliver for Louisiana’s Kids&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 01:01:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] The Battle for Health Freedom Isn’t Over: Let’s Fight for Children</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/the-battle-for-health-freedom-isnt-over-lets-fight-for-children/</link><description>Idaho’s “Medical Freedom Act (MFA)” protects adults from employers, businesses, government agencies, or other entities imposing medical interventions on them, including vaccines. Enacted this past July, the MFA protects adults from being coerced into using medical products, devices, substances, injections, or any technology, in any form. It’s simple — bodily autonomy is a fundamental, God-given [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 02:39:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Week in Review: Medical Freedom and Informed Consent Are Fundamental</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/week-in-review-medical-freedom-and-informed-consent-are-fundamental/</link><description>Health and medical freedom, and the issues debated under this umbrella, speak directly to the overarching principles the Founders were so passionate about.&amp;#160; You have the right to access holistic healing modalities, practitioners of your choosing, and treatments to heal in the ways you choose. The state and federal governments have no place interfering in [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/12/the-outstater-313/</link><description>Rolling Boondoggles AS THE USUAL BOOSTERS&amp;#160;line up to cut more ribbons for the almost $400-million Indy Blue Line (bus transit) in Indianapolis, our adjunct scholar&amp;#160;Randall O’Toole&amp;#160;is finishing work on his latest report. O’Toole, a reliable and well-informed downer on public transportation issues, concludes “the more we spend, the fewer people&amp;#160;use transit.”&amp;#160; Here is his quote&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/12/the-outstater-313/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 13:09:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Arkansaspolicyfoundation] ARKANSAS GOV. SARAH HUCKABEE SANDERS &amp; STATE INCOME TAX CUTS</title><link>https://arkansaspolicyfoundation.org/arkansas-gov-sarah-huckabee-sanders-state-income-tax-cuts/</link><description>(4Q-2025) Arkansas Gov. Sarah Huckabee Sanders is the Natural State’s first female governor. Since taking office in January 2023, Sanders has also distinguished herself by advancing three separate reductions in Arkansas’ top income tax rate from 4.9 to 3.9 percent. The income tax was reduced from 7.0% to 6.9% in 2013 under Democratic Gov. Mike [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 14:33:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Performers emerge from Chicago’s projects by way of forklifts</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/performers-emerge-from-chicagos-projects-by-way-of-forklifts/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Project out of the Projects helps aspiring Chicago musicians, event producers find their way by mixing practical job skills, performance experience and advice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/performers-emerge-from-chicagos-projects-by-way-of-forklifts/"&gt;Performers emerge from Chicago’s projects by way of forklifts&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 10:58:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Cook County property taxes funding pensions more than service</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/cook-county-property-taxes-funding-pensions-more-than-service/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Cook County homeowners face rising property taxes. Three-fourths of that money is going to police and fire pensions instead of services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/cook-county-property-taxes-funding-pensions-more-than-service/"&gt;Cook County property taxes funding pensions more than service&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 11:00:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Legislators should take more care before authorizing another $1.9 billion in developer subsidies</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/legislators-should-take-more-care-before-authorizing-another-1-9-billion-in-developer-subsidies</link><description>Bill would be added to Mackinac Center business subsidy scorecard if passed into law</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Empire Center Releases NYC BERS Pension Data for FY2025</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/empire-center-releases-nyc-bers-pension-data-for-fy2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Pension payments to 21,170 retirees of the New York City Board of Education Retirement System (BERS) during fiscal year 2025....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/empire-center-releases-nyc-bers-pension-data-for-fy2025/"&gt;Empire Center Releases NYC BERS Pension Data for FY2025&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 14:15:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] 46 states have a private workers’ compensation system: Wyoming should join them</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/46-states-have-a-private-workers-compensation-system-wyoming-should-join-them</link><description>Did you know that Wyoming is only one of four states in the U.S. with a completely government-run workers’ compensation insurance system? Washington, North Dakota and Ohio are the others. North Dakota and Ohio have managed to keep their rates low. But Wyoming’s approach has led to some of the highest rates  in the nation for workers’ compensation insurance. In 2020, Wyoming’s rates were the highest  in the nation, falling to 7th highest in 2024. As background, workers’ compensation was one of...</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 15:13:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Todd Schaible: The Importance of Career Technical Education in Tennessee Schools</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/todd-schaible-the-importance-of-career-technical-education-in-tennessee-schools/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=todd-schaible-the-importance-of-career-technical-education-in-tennessee-schools</link><description>By elevating CTE in Tennessee schools, we can increase support for employers and improve workforce readiness for students across the state.</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 15:34:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Preserving the Texas Miracle</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/preserving-the-texas-miracle/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Texas did not become America’s economic engine by accident. The Texas Miracle is built on a regulatory and economic framework that expands the freedom of families and businesses. Every legislative session, state leaders work to fortify that framework and reduce the burden of government to keep Texas the best place in the nation to work,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/preserving-the-texas-miracle/"&gt;Preserving the Texas Miracle&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 15:55:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] A Small Minnesota City Offers a Big Lesson on Budget Discipline</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/a-small-minnesota-city-offers-a-big-lesson-on-budget-discipline/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="A Small Minnesota City Offers a Big Lesson on Budget Discipline" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/grand-rapids-minnesota.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facing taxpayer frustration over rising property taxes, the City of Grand Rapids pursued a zero-percent levy increase by cutting or delaying nearly $1 million in spending. Minnesota’s Truth-in-Taxation process has empowered residents to engage meaningfully in budget decisions, with strong public turnout influencing both city and county officials. The experience demonstrates that transparency, taxpayer engagement, and spending discipline can lead to alternatives to automatic tax increases while preserving local accountability. Iowa should replicate Minnesota’s Truth-in-Taxation notice. Doing so would provide clearer property tax information and help encourage taxpayer participation by showing residents how proposed budgets directly affect their tax bills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/a-small-minnesota-city-offers-a-big-lesson-on-budget-discipline/"&gt;A Small Minnesota City Offers a Big Lesson on Budget Discipline&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 15:55:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Takin’ It to the Streets: Applying New Data to Reduce Car Accidents</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/applying-new-data-to-reduce-car-accidents/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Few milestones strike more fear into the heart of parents than that of a driver license. Millions of Americans participate in this rite of passage each year—and even more are involved in car accidents. With the freedom of the road comes an element of danger, one that no amount of driver’s ed can reduce. Self-driving...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/applying-new-data-to-reduce-car-accidents/"&gt;Takin’ It to the Streets: Applying New Data to Reduce Car Accidents&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 16:42:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] Albuquerque Journal editorializes in defense of free speech, Rio Grande Foundation in “hoodie-gate”</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/albuquerque-journal-editorializes-in-defense-of-free-speech-rio-grande-foundation-in-hoodie-gate/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Rio Grande Foundation has received a great deal of publicity from all corners of Albuquerque&amp;#8217;s political scene due to our involvement in reporting on the I ♥ Tim Keller &amp;#8220;hoodies for the homeless&amp;#8221; effort. As we&amp;#8217;ve discussed at length here and in other locations the Mayor&amp;#8217;s campaign has reacted to our reporting and refusal [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/albuquerque-journal-editorializes-in-defense-of-free-speech-rio-grande-foundation-in-hoodie-gate/"&gt;Albuquerque Journal editorializes in defense of free speech, Rio Grande Foundation in &amp;#8220;hoodie-gate&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 16:53:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] The Million Petty Annoyances of California’s Regulatory State</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/the-million-petty-annoyances-of-californias-regulatory-state/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=the-million-petty-annoyances-of-californias-regulatory-state</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The litany of reasons California is broken is well documented. The highest cost of living and the highest taxes. The highest percentages of homeless people and people living in poverty. Unaffordable homes and unaffordable rent. High crime and failing schools. A hostile business climate and record migration out of state as people and businesses flee....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/the-million-petty-annoyances-of-californias-regulatory-state/"&gt;The Million Petty Annoyances of California’s Regulatory State&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 17:17:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] O’Donnell: Yes, Socialism Works . . .</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/12/odonnell-yes-socialism-works/</link><description>by James O&amp;#8217;Donnell, M.B.A.This year&amp;#160;has seen major American cities, like New York City and Seattle, elect socialist mayors. Elsewhere, positions a bit lower on the totem pole have also found successful socialist candidates, including winning city or area council seats in Atlanta, Georgia; Cambridge, Massachusetts; Detroit, Michigan; Greenbelt, Maryland; Ithaca, New York; Jersey City, New&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/12/odonnell-yes-socialism-works/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 17:42:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Portland Studies Inclusionary Zoning (Again) Despite Evidence</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/portland-studies-inclusionary-zoning-again-despite-evidence/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Portland is commissioning its own study on the “effects of inclusionary zoning,” as if the question was unsettled, novel, or open. It isn’t. Across the ideological spectrum, from UC Berkeley to NYU Law to George Mason and numerous think tanks, colleges, and studies across the country, the research record is remarkably consistent: inclusionary zoning reduces housing [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/portland-studies-inclusionary-zoning-again-despite-evidence/"&gt;Portland Studies Inclusionary Zoning (Again) Despite Evidence&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 17:47:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] Franke: Reapportionment</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/12/franke-reapportionment/</link><description>by Mark Franke The Indiana General Assembly’s special session appears to be over, having voted down a mid-decade congressional reapportionment proposal. The legislature is required to reapportion after each decennial census but not more often, although nothing prevents more frequent efforts other than their fiscal and political costs. Despite the heavy-handed involvement of Donald Trump&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/12/franke-reapportionment/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 17:48:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Minnesota’s structural budget deficit is not driven by tariffs or federal uncertainty</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/minnesotas-structural-budget-deficit-is-not-driven-by-tariffs-or-federal-uncertainty/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By all signs, the Minnesota state budget is in trouble. While the state ends the current two-year budget period —&amp;#160;2026-27 biennium — with a surplus, estimates show an imbalance in the next period (2028-29 biennium). Tackling this deficit will require some honest accounting of how Minnesota got where it is today. Certainly, tariffs and federal...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/minnesotas-structural-budget-deficit-is-not-driven-by-tariffs-or-federal-uncertainty/"&gt;Minnesota’s structural budget deficit is not driven by tariffs or federal uncertainty&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 20:13:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Mississippi's Free-Market Turnaround: A Model for America</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/mississippis-free-market-turnaround-a-model-for-america/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For decades, Mississippi has been the punchline in national discussions about economic performance - often ranked at the bottom in income, education, and opportunity. But something remarkable has happened in recent years: the Magnolia State is undergoing a genuine resurgence, driven not by federal handouts or gimmicks, but by principled free-market reforms. A major national [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/mississippis-free-market-turnaround-a-model-for-america/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi&amp;#039;s Free-Market Turnaround: A Model for America&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 21:13:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Florida Should Lead in Securing Healthcare Technology</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/florida-should-lead-in-securing-healthcare-technology/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Every day, millions of Americans are sustained, monitored, and diagnosed by medical technology they never think twice about....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/florida-should-lead-in-securing-healthcare-technology/"&gt;Florida Should Lead in Securing Healthcare Technology&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 21:54:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] A Republican healthcare package remains within reach</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/a-republican-healthcare-package-remains-within-reach/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The House is expected to vote this week on healthcare reform legislation. The upcoming action comes on the heels of two failed votes in the Senate: one a Democratic bill that would’ve extended COVID-19-era enhanced Affordable Care Act subsidies for exchange coverage and the other a Republican bill that would have helped move our healthcare [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/a-republican-healthcare-package-remains-within-reach/"&gt;A Republican healthcare package remains within reach&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 22:15:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Idaho’s Sen. Risch, Rep. Fulcher take on the NEA</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/teachers-unions/idahos-sen-risch-rep-fulcher-take-on-the-nea/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Sen. James Risch and Rep. Russ Fulcher of Idaho are standing up to the National Education Association in Congress, but the best opportunities to push back against teachers unions are at the state level. Will 2026 be the year lawmakers in Boise finally end taxpayer support teachers unions in the Gem State? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/teachers-unions/idahos-sen-risch-rep-fulcher-take-on-the-nea/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Idaho&amp;#8217;s Sen. Risch, Rep. Fulcher take on the NEA&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 22:29:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Goldwater: Pima County Lacks Power to Block Copper Mine Access</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/goldwater-pima-county-lacks-power-to-block-copper-mine-access/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;After objecting to a new copper mine in Southern Arizona, the Pima County Board of Supervisors is now attempting to..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/goldwater-pima-county-lacks-power-to-block-copper-mine-access/"&gt;Goldwater: Pima County Lacks Power to Block Copper Mine Access&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 23:20:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Require fiscal assessments for all proposed bills, Charter amendments</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/12/require-fiscal-assessments-for-all-proposed-bills-charter-amendments/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Honolulu Charter Commission on Dec. 15, 2025._____________ Dec. 15, 2025, 2:30 p.m.Honolulu Hale To: Honolulu Charter Commission       Dawn Szewczyk, Chair       Sommerset Yamamoto, Vice Chair From: Grassroot Institute of Hawaii            Ted Kefalas, Director of Strategic Campaigns RE: P066 and P156 — [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/12/require-fiscal-assessments-for-all-proposed-bills-charter-amendments/"&gt;Require fiscal assessments for all proposed bills, Charter amendments&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 01:35:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Reject empty homes tax proposal</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/12/reject-empty-homes-tax-proposal/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Honolulu Charter Commission on Dec. 15, 2025._____________ Dec. 15, 2025, 2:30 p.m.Honolulu Hale To: Honolulu Charter Commission&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Dawn Szewczyk, Chair&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Sommerset Yamamoto, Vice Chair From: Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Ted Kefalas, Director of Strategic Campaigns RE: P170 — RELATING TO [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/12/reject-empty-homes-tax-proposal/"&gt;Reject empty homes tax proposal&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 01:38:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] City ‘living wage’ not only unsound but also not allowed by state law</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/12/city-living-wage-not-only-unsound-but-also-not-allowed-by-state-law/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Honolulu Charter Commission on Dec. 15, 2025._____________ Dec. 15, 2025, 2:30 p.m.Honolulu Hale To: Honolulu Charter Commission&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Dawn Szewczyk, Chair&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Sommerset Yamamoto, Vice Chair From: Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Ted Kefalas, Director of Strategic Campaigns RE: P024 — RELATING TO [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/12/city-living-wage-not-only-unsound-but-also-not-allowed-by-state-law/"&gt;City &amp;#8216;living wage&amp;#8217; not only unsound but also not allowed by state law&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 01:42:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Enrollment and Employment: Is Tennessee Preparing K-12 Students for Today’s Economy?</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/enrollment-and-employment-is-tennessee-preparing-k-12-students-for-todays-economy/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=enrollment-and-employment-is-tennessee-preparing-k-12-students-for-todays-economy</link><description>Tennessee is doing well in providing Career and Technical Education (CTE) opportunities to students, but policymakers should recognize that improvements can be made.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 02:17:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Mark Skousen – The Greatest American</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/mark-skousen-the-greatest-american/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Nationally known investment expert, economist, Chapman University professor and author of more than 25 books Mark Skousen joins us to discuss his latest book, The Greatest American, on his distant relative, Benjamin Franklin.  We talk about Franklin&amp;#8217;s legacy in science, business, economics, politics, and diplomacy, and ponder what Franklin would think about politicians like Zohran [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/mark-skousen-the-greatest-american/"&gt;Mark Skousen &amp;#8211; The Greatest American&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 04:43:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Illinois governor signs bill supporting state-sanctioned suicide</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/illinois-governor-signs-bill-supporting-state-sanctioned-suicide/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Breccan Thies writes for the Federalist about the latest bad policy in a deep-blue Midwestern state. Gov. J.B. Pritzker, D-Ill., signed into law Friday a bill that would allow doctors in Illinois to prescribe the deaths of their own patients. Under the new law, which goes into effect in September 2026, terminally ill people above...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/illinois-governor-signs-bill-supporting-state-sanctioned-suicide/"&gt;Illinois governor signs bill supporting state-sanctioned suicide&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 10:36:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Fears of racist label helped hide Minnesota fraud scandal</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/fears-of-racist-label-helped-hide-minnesota-fraud-scandal/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Andrew Mark Miller writes for FoxNews.com about an interesting aspect of the recently exposed Minnesota fraud scandal. In the aftermath of the massive Feeding Our Future scandal and broader allegations of systemic fraud in Minnesota’s social programs, a troubling theme has emerged: accusations of racism repeatedly used to deflect scrutiny, intimidate investigators and stall accountability.&amp;#160;...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/fears-of-racist-label-helped-hide-minnesota-fraud-scandal/"&gt;Fears of racist label helped hide Minnesota fraud scandal&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 10:39:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Voters ‘barely’ trust SCOTUS to do what’s best for US</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/voters-barely-trust-scotus-to-do-whats-best-for-us/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Terry Jones of Issues and Insights dissects new polling data involving the nation’s highest court. Americans mostly trust the nation’s highest court to do what’s best, presumably by scrupulously following the laws enshrined in the 238-year-old U.S. Constitution. But that trust could be tested in coming months, as the Supreme Court decides whether President Donald...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/voters-barely-trust-scotus-to-do-whats-best-for-us/"&gt;Voters &amp;#8216;barely&amp;#8217; trust SCOTUS to do what&amp;#8217;s best for US&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 10:42:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] The inappropriate business pushback toward Sheetz coming into Michigan</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/the-inappropriate-business-pushback-toward-sheetz-coming-into-michigan</link><description>Consumers benefit when businesses compete for their business</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Bearing False Witness</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/bearing-false-witness/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Those limits grew out of lived experience and a deep Christian faith shaped by the Protestant Reformation. The Fourth, Fifth, Sixth, Eighth, and Fourteenth Amendments reflect that inheritance. They function as a kind of secular catechism, a rule book governing our system of justice. This year, John Grisham stepped away from fiction to tell the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/bearing-false-witness/"&gt;Bearing False Witness&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 11:00:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] High sales taxes suck a little joy out of Illinois holidays</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/high-sales-taxes-suck-a-little-joy-out-of-illinois-holidays/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Illinois sales taxes on holiday purchases rank No. 8 in the U.S., but Chicago charges shoppers as much as 10.25% with plans to go higher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/high-sales-taxes-suck-a-little-joy-out-of-illinois-holidays/"&gt;High sales taxes suck a little joy out of Illinois holidays&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 11:00:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] If Massachusetts Can Rein In Property Taxes, Any State Can</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/if-massachusetts-can-rein-in-property-taxes-any-state-can/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="If Massachusetts Can Rein In Property Taxes, Any State Can" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/massachusetts.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite ranking among the nation’s worst tax climates and having some of the highest income, sales, and property taxes, Massachusetts has successfully enforced a strong property tax cap through its Proposition 2½ for more than 40 years.&lt;br /&gt;
The cap limits annual levy growth to 2.5%, encourages disciplined budgeting, and includes a voter-approved override process, enabling communities to fund priorities without uncontrolled tax increases.&lt;br /&gt;
Massachusetts proves that even a high-spending state can maintain an effective property tax cap; Iowa can adopt similar limits without harming essential services or local government operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/if-massachusetts-can-rein-in-property-taxes-any-state-can/"&gt;If Massachusetts Can Rein In Property Taxes, Any State Can&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 13:52:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] A Cautionary Moment for Union Transparency as Former NJEA Leader Seeks a National Role</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/12/a-cautionary-moment-for-union-transparency-as-former-njea-leader-seeks-a-national-role/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The recent announcement that former New Jersey Education Association president Sean Spiller has launched a campaign for leadership within the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/12/a-cautionary-moment-for-union-transparency-as-former-njea-leader-seeks-a-national-role/"&gt;A Cautionary Moment for Union Transparency as Former NJEA Leader Seeks a National Role&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 14:20:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] New Jersey Policy Institute Welcomes Kristen Cobo to Its Board of Directors</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/12/new-jersey-policy-institute-welcomes-kristen-cobo-to-its-board-of-directors/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Leader in Children’s Mental Health and Parental Rights Advocacy Joins Expanding NJPI Board FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE Parsippany, N.J. — December [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/12/new-jersey-policy-institute-welcomes-kristen-cobo-to-its-board-of-directors/"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute Welcomes Kristen Cobo to Its Board of Directors&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 14:26:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Embattled DFL chair celebrates party’s failed anti-fraud measures</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/embattled-dfl-chair-celebrates-partys-failed-anti-fraud-measures/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The epidemic of fraud perpetrated against Minnesota’s taxpayers under Gov. Walz’ administration is a big issue for Minnesotans. As I noted yesterday, a KSTP poll released on Friday asked: &amp;#8220;Do you think fraud in state programs is the biggest problem in Minnesota?” KSTP reports: …79% say it’s either the biggest problem or a major problem. KSTP asked: “Has Gov....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/embattled-dfl-chair-celebrates-partys-failed-anti-fraud-measures/"&gt;Embattled DFL chair celebrates party&amp;#8217;s failed anti-fraud measures&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 15:08:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Education choice setback for Montana families requires legislative action</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/education-choice-setback-for-montana-families-requires-legislative-action</link><description>Montana families seeking flexible education options for students with special needs received disappointing news last week when a District Court Judge blocked implementation of the state’s Education Savings Account (ESA) program. While earlier court decisions allowed the program to move forward, this latest ruling has paused ESAs entirely. The Students with Special Needs Equal Opportunity Act program, created in 2023 by House Bill 393 , was designed to give families of students with special...</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 15:17:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Freedom Foundation CEO Aaron Withe Statement on House Bill Undermining President Trump’s Union Reform Executive Orders</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/national/freedom-foundation-ceo-aaron-withe-statement-on-house-bill-undermining-president-trumps-union-reform-executive-orders/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Freedom Foundation CEO Aaron Withe today released the following statement on the passage of the Protect America's Workforce Act by the U.S. House of Representatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/national/freedom-foundation-ceo-aaron-withe-statement-on-house-bill-undermining-president-trumps-union-reform-executive-orders/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation CEO Aaron Withe Statement on House Bill Undermining President Trump&amp;#8217;s Union Reform Executive Orders&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 15:35:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Florida Politics: Bedrock, We Have a Problem</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/florida-politics-bedrock-we-have-a-problem/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A funny thing happened in the Legislature last week. While the House was holding an “AI Week” to...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/florida-politics-bedrock-we-have-a-problem/"&gt;Florida Politics: Bedrock, We Have a Problem&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 16:05:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Introducing EPIC: A New Investment in Solution Development</title><link>https://empowerms.org/introducing-epic-a-new-investment-in-solution-development/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For more than a decade, Empower Mississippi has worked to advance opportunity-focused policy at the State Capitol. Many of you have been partners in that work — meeting with lawmakers, investing financially, and championing reforms that help Mississippians live free, work meaningfully, and learn effectively. From the beginning, our advocacy has been grounded in research&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/introducing-epic-a-new-investment-in-solution-development/"&gt;Introducing EPIC: A New Investment in Solution Development&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 16:08:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Kansas’s Revenue Mirage and the Case for a Responsible Budget in 2026</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/kansas-revenue-mirage-responsible-budget/</link><description>The Kansas State government may be collecting more money than expected, but that should make lawmakers nervous, not comfortable.  Individual income tax collections are surging, but at the same time retail sales are slowing and corporate income tax revenues are weakening. When workers get paid more while consumers and businesses pull back, the economy is [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 16:34:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Ada County Highway District increases impact fees by 66%</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/ada-county-highway-district-increases-impact-fees-by-66</link><description>Ada County officials have significantly increased development impact fees to pay for transportation projects, passing an ordinance to charge developers more to build starting in 2026. One silver lining, however, is that they rejected a controversial proposal to go to a two-area fee zone. Public officials say higher transportation impact fees are needed to build out the road network to mitigate the traffic impact from growth. They estimate that out of $2.3 billion in transportation needs, $1.6...</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 17:13:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Coming to a classroom near you: Politicized Ethnic Studies lesson plans</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/coming-to-a-classroom-near-you-politicized-ethnic-studies-lesson-plans/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Beginning in fall 2026, Minnesota public schools will be responsible for determining how Ethnic Studies is implemented in K-12 classrooms. Public high schools will have to offer an Ethnic Studies course, and all grade levels will be required to teach the state&amp;#8217;s revised K-12 social studies academic standards that include three Ethnic Studies concepts: Identity,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/coming-to-a-classroom-near-you-politicized-ethnic-studies-lesson-plans/"&gt;Coming to a classroom near you: Politicized Ethnic Studies lesson plans&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 17:33:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Paper Ballots Give Elections the Permanent Record They Need</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/paper-ballots-give-elections-the-permanent-record-they-need/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, President Trump applauded Dallas County, Texas for using paper ballots. That praise strikes at the heart of a fundamental truth: When our nation entrusts votes to a permanent, physical record, we safeguard election integrity. Americans have watched debates in recent years around voting machines, software patches, cyber vulnerabilities, and technological upgrades — but one thing hasn’t...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/paper-ballots-give-elections-the-permanent-record-they-need/"&gt;Paper Ballots Give Elections the Permanent Record They Need&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 17:36:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Michigan Parent Petitions U.S. Supreme Court After School Board Reports Her to DOJ</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/pressroom/2025/michigan-parent-petitions-us-supreme-court-after-school-board-reports-her-to-doj</link><description>Mackinac Center Legal Foundation defends a parent's right to speak up for her child's education</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 17:51:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>