<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>State-Policy Think-Tank Digest</title><link>https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml</link><description>Latest posts from free-market policy institutes across the U.S.</description><atom:link href="https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2025 02:45:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] Sec. Simon Should Hop Off the Ranked-Choice Voting Train</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/sec-simon-should-hop-off-the-ranked-choice-voting-train/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Ranked-Choice Voting must be rejected when it presents itself in Minnesota. Our republic deserves no less than our willingness to educate voters about this failed voting system and to resist misguided efforts like Sec. Simons who wants to expand this radical scheme to all Minnesota cities and counties. &amp;#8212; Secretary of State backs legislation to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/sec-simon-should-hop-off-the-ranked-choice-voting-train/"&gt;Sec. Simon Should Hop Off the Ranked-Choice Voting Train&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 13:13:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Average Pay at Port Authority Surges as 11 Employees Collect $400k+</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/average-pay-at-panynj-surges-as-11-employees-collect-400k/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Eleven Port Authority of New York and New Jersey (PANYNJ) employees collected more than $400,000 each in total pay last....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/average-pay-at-panynj-surges-as-11-employees-collect-400k/"&gt;Average Pay at Port Authority Surges as 11 Employees Collect $400k+&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 15:40:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] PA House Democrats Pass Unbalanced, Reckless Spending Bill</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/07/14/pa-house-democrats-pass-unbalanced-reckless-spending-bill/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Harrisburg, Pa., July 14, 2025 — Today, Pennsylvania House Democrats passed the General Appropriations Act (HB 1330), their version of a budget bill, which includes a $2.9 billion spending increase. The bill would increase general fund spending to $50.6 billion—exacerbating Pennsylvania’s structural deficit, by spending $5.3 billion more than revenue. Lawmakers would need to drain [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/07/14/pa-house-democrats-pass-unbalanced-reckless-spending-bill/"&gt;PA House Democrats Pass Unbalanced, Reckless Spending Bill&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 21:52:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] NJ ED REPORT: Is Murphy Stalling the Segregation Lawsuit? What Would His Successor Do?</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/07/nj-ed-report-is-murphy-stalling-the-segregation-lawsuit-what-would-his-successor-do/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A new NJ Education Report article covers a high-stakes lawsuit accusing the Murphy administration of stalling efforts to fix New [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/07/nj-ed-report-is-murphy-stalling-the-segregation-lawsuit-what-would-his-successor-do/"&gt;NJ ED REPORT: Is Murphy Stalling the Segregation Lawsuit? What Would His Successor Do?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 18:36:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG Announces Chief Operating Officer</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-announces-chief-operating-officer/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;THE NEWS The Institute for Reforming Government (IRG) has promoted Chris Reader to Chief Operating Officer. In this expanded role, Chris will manage the day-to-day operations of IRG, overseeing its team and project portfolio. Reader has also been named the Executive Director of IRG Action Fund, IRG’s 501(C)(4) advocacy partner.   THE QUOTE CJ Szafir, IRG, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-announces-chief-operating-officer/"&gt;IRG Announces Chief Operating Officer&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 15:54:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] A Warning for New York’s Energy Policy</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/a-warning-for-new-yorks-energy-policy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On June 24th New York’s electricity grid nearly blew a fuse. That day was extremely hot, and air conditioning was....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/a-warning-for-new-yorks-energy-policy/"&gt;A Warning for New York’s Energy Policy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 17:50:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] Parents: Ask Your District How They Will Comply</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/07/18/parents-ask-your-district-how-they-will-comply/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A momentous parental rights victory was handed down by the United States Supreme Court on Friday, June 27, 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/07/18/parents-ask-your-district-how-they-will-comply/"&gt;Parents: Ask Your District How They Will Comply&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 17:45:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Panasonic’s EV Gamble Isn’t Capitalism—It’s Corporate Welfare</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/panasonics-ev-gamble-is-corporate-welfare/</link><description>Kansas just got played. Again. Panasonic’s $4 billion EV battery plant in De Soto—touted as the state’s biggest economic development deal ever—is now delayed. Why? Because the federal government finally decided to stop propping up the electric vehicle market with taxpayer cash. President Trump’s “Big, Beautiful Bill” kills the $7,500 new EV tax credit and [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 16:56:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG Court Watch Report: Wisconsin Supreme Court Term in Review</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-court-watch-report-wisconsin-supreme-court-term-in-review/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;IRG Court Watch Report: Wisconsin Supreme Court Term in Review Court Delivers Progressive Wins in Wisconsin for the First Time in Over a Decade Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government’s (IRG) Court Watch released a report detailing the Wisconsin Supreme Court’s 2024-2025 term on Tuesday, analyzing the new path taken by the Court’s [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-court-watch-report-wisconsin-supreme-court-term-in-review/"&gt;IRG Court Watch Report: Wisconsin Supreme Court Term in Review&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 12:56:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] BBB Is Not The Tragedy Our Politicians Portray</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/bbb-is-not-the-tragedy-our-politicians-portray/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t heard already, over the 4th of July weekend, President Trump signed the so-called “Big Beautiful Bill” (BBB) into law. Setting aside the merits and demerits of the legislation, you have to hand it to President Trump and Speaker Mike Johnson for achieving the President’s goal of signing the bill by July 4. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/bbb-is-not-the-tragedy-our-politicians-portray/"&gt;BBB Is Not The Tragedy Our Politicians Portray&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 17:29:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Research Note: Use of the Nebraska Livestock Matrix</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/research-note-use-of-the-nebraska-livestock-matrix/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Introduced in 2015, the Nebraska Livestock Matrix is a tool designed to help counties evaluate proposed livestock operations seeking conditional use or special exception permits. Created to promote consistency across county lines in the permitting process, the committee tasked with developing the matrix faced two significant challenges in aligning its objectives. First, the tool needed...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/research-note-use-of-the-nebraska-livestock-matrix/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Research Note: Use of the Nebraska Livestock Matrix&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 19:58:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Former Speaker Philip Gunn: Faith, Resilience, and Leadership</title><link>https://empowerms.org/former-speaker-philip-gunn-faith-resilience-and-leadership/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;﻿ Former Speaker Philip Gunn: Faith, Resilience, and Leadership In this episode, host Grant Callen sits down with former Mississippi House Speaker Philip Gunn to trace his journey from Clinton’s small-town roots to state leadership. Gunn shares how a personal tragedy at Ole Miss Law upended his life, yet God’s faithfulness sustained him, strengthened his faith,&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/former-speaker-philip-gunn-faith-resilience-and-leadership/"&gt;Former Speaker Philip Gunn: Faith, Resilience, and Leadership&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 00:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Frontierinstitute] Written Public Comment to SFIC 7.23.25</title><link>https://frontierinstitute.org/written-public-comment-to-sfic-7-23-25/</link><description>We believe it is a constitutional and policy imperative for Montana to implement a statewide student-centered funding formula design as the primary way to fund public education.</description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 17:29:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Idaho DOGE: Misses it by That Much</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/idaho-doge-misses-it-by-that-much/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/idaho-doge-misses-it-by-that-much/" rel="nofollow" title="Idaho DOGE: Misses it by That Much"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1396" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Gemini_Generated_Image_ku2awsku2awsku2a-scaled.jpg" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="2560" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Ask any good conservative in Idaho politics, and they’ll tell you Idaho’s budgets and government growth are out of control. They’re right. Now, throw in the biggest buzzword in politics for the last six months (the start of President Trump’s return to power), “DOGE.” Of course, that’s shorthand for the Department of Government Efficiency (headed [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 22:28:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Fitzgerald, Lummis Introduce STUDENT Act to Curb Out-of-Control NEA</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/labor/fitzgerald-lummis-introduce-student-act-to-curb-out-of-control-nea/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This week, U.S. Rep. Scott Fitzgerald (R-WI) and U.S. Sen. Cynthia Lummis (R-WY) introduced legislation to overhaul the federal charter of the National Education Association (NEA), the largest teachers union in the country, to make it more accountable and less partisan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/labor/fitzgerald-lummis-introduce-student-act-to-curb-out-of-control-nea/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Fitzgerald, Lummis Introduce STUDENT Act to Curb Out-of-Control NEA&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Over 150,000 Kansas students may be functionally illiterate, yet the adults in charge won’t take action</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/150k-kansas-students-functionally-illiterate/</link><description>The 2024 state assessment indicates that more than 150,000 Kansas students suffer from what is officially described as having a “limited ability to understand and use English language arts skills and knowledge to be academically successful for postsecondary success.”  This closely aligns with what is commonly referred to as being ‘functionally illiterate’, which  Dictionary.com defines [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 14:08:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG Announces New Leadership</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-announces-new-leadership/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;IRG Announces New Leadership Alison Prange to serve as the next Chair of the Board of Directors  THE NEWS The Board of Directors for the Institute for Reforming Government has elected Alison Prange to serve as the next Chair of the Board. Alison Prange was appointed to IRG’s Board in 2022. THE QUOTES Alison Prange, IRG [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-announces-new-leadership/"&gt;IRG Announces New Leadership&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 15:54:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Maine Must Act to Lift Students Under New Federal Education Tax Credit Program</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/maine-must-act-to-lift-students-under-new-federal-education-tax-credit-program/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In 2025, Congress enacted the first-ever federal 1-to-1 tax credit for donations to K–12 education scholarships. While championed by President Trump, the program reflects a broader bipartisan vision: empowering families, driving educational innovation, and keeping funding decisions closer to home. But unless Maine lawmakers act swiftly, Maine families and students will miss out on the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/maine-must-act-to-lift-students-under-new-federal-education-tax-credit-program/"&gt;Maine Must Act to Lift Students Under New Federal Education Tax Credit Program&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 17:20:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Teacher Freedom Summit brings together educators anxious to cut ties with their union</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/teacher-conference/teacher-freedom-summit-brings-together-educators-anxious-to-cut-ties-with-their-union/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Despite the shocking news headlines from big unions like the American Federation of Teachers (AFT) and the National Education Association (NEA), 2025 has been a year of success and hope for America’s education system and educators alike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/teacher-conference/teacher-freedom-summit-brings-together-educators-anxious-to-cut-ties-with-their-union/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Teacher Freedom Summit brings together educators anxious to cut ties with their union&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 18:16:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Three issues Georgia parents are most concerned about</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/georgia-parent-top-concerns/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A new report on child well-being from Emory University reveals the issues that Georgia parents say are impacting kids—and their futures—most. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/georgia-parent-top-concerns/"&gt;Three issues Georgia parents are most concerned about&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 22:42:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Virginiainstitute] The State of Educational Opportunity in Virginia – A Survey of Virginia Parents</title><link>https://virginiainstitute.org/the-state-of-educational-opportunity-in-virginia-a-survey-of-virginia-parents/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=the-state-of-educational-opportunity-in-virginia-a-survey-of-virginia-parents</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 11:07:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Tallahassee Democrat: K-12 Scholarship Students Can Help Solve Public School Budget Woes</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/tallahassee-democrat-k-12-scholarship-students-can-help-solve-public-school-budget-woes-opinion/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;July 26, 2025 Like many public-school officials around the country, Leon County Schools Superintendent Rocky Hanna is feeling...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/tallahassee-democrat-k-12-scholarship-students-can-help-solve-public-school-budget-woes-opinion/"&gt;Tallahassee Democrat: K-12 Scholarship Students Can Help Solve Public School Budget Woes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 13:13:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Mississippi or Milei?  America’s Magnolia state is a better example of what the free market can do</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/mississippi-or-milei-americas-magnolia-state-is-a-better-example-of-what-the-free-market-can-do/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When Javier Milei burst onto the scene as a presidential candidate in Argentina in 2023, brandishing a chainsaw, many dismissed him as unhinged.&amp;#160; His radical libertarian platform was presented by the media as evidence of Argentina’s tragicomic decline. Argentina was poorer in 2023 than it had been two decades earlier. That year, the economy contracted [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/mississippi-or-milei-americas-magnolia-state-is-a-better-example-of-what-the-free-market-can-do/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi or Milei?  America’s Magnolia state is a better example of what the free market can do&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 14:52:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Is Government Truly Limited in Louisiana?</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/legal-regulatory/is-government-truly-limited-in-louisiana/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In Louisiana and across the country, there’s a growing hunger for limited government, driven by the recognition that more government doesn’t always correlate with heightened responsiveness or better outcomes. Time and again, we’ve seen how top-down policies, bloated bureaucracy, and ever-expanding regulations stand in the way of innovation, economic opportunity, and personal freedom. Louisiana’s continued...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/legal-regulatory/is-government-truly-limited-in-louisiana/"&gt;Is Government Truly Limited in Louisiana?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 12:13:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] First Principles Series: Protecting Property Rights</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/first-principle-series-protecting-property-rights/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=first-principle-series-protecting-property-rights</link><description>The Founders understood that protections for private property must exist if the nation was to remain free.</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 18:39:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Can San Francisco Be Saved From Itself?</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/can-san-francisco-be-saved-from-itself/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=can-san-francisco-be-saved-from-itself</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Daniel Lurie’s moderate promises clash with a city drowning in ideological dysfunction. Can he deliver, or will the status quo swallow him up? A City Choking on Its Own Excess San Francisco has always fancied itself a laboratory for progressive ideas. This is a place where progressive theory gets its field test, often with little...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/can-san-francisco-be-saved-from-itself/"&gt;Can San Francisco Be Saved From Itself?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 19:20:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] IFF Spending Index: Unmasking Idaho's Overgrown Government</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/iff-spending-index-unmasking-idahos-overgrown-government/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/iff-spending-index-unmasking-idahos-overgrown-government/" rel="nofollow" title="IFF Spending Index: Unmasking Idaho&amp;#039;s Overgrown Government"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Article-Headers-2025-07-28T181001.712.png" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Last week’s kickoff of the Idaho DOGE Task Force highlights the need to rein in Idaho’s spending growth. It’s a tall order. Since 2019, the Idaho Freedom Foundation’s Spending Index has been the only yardstick for measuring the impacts of individual agency appropriations bills. And necessarily, the votes on these bills by legislators provide the [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 19:50:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] The Messenger Spring 2025</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/the-messenger-spring-2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;President&amp;#8217;s Message Dear Friends, What an extraordinary year it’s been for liberty in the Sunshine State. This past...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/the-messenger-spring-2025/"&gt;The Messenger Spring 2025&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 20:45:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Ushering in America’s New Atomic Age: Three Takeaways from the House Oversight Hearing on Nuclear Energy Reform</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/energy/ushering-in-americas-new-atomic-age-three-takeaways-from-the-house-oversight-hearing-on-nuclear-energy-reform/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Last week, the U.S. House Committee on Economic Growth, Energy Policy, and Regulatory Affairs held a timely oversight hearing on the outdated and burdensome regulations holding back America’s nuclear energy future. The testimony delivered a clear message: advanced nuclear power is ready to help meet our growing energy demands—but only if policymakers act to remove...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/energy/ushering-in-americas-new-atomic-age-three-takeaways-from-the-house-oversight-hearing-on-nuclear-energy-reform/"&gt;Ushering in America’s New Atomic Age: Three Takeaways from the House Oversight Hearing on Nuclear Energy Reform&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 12:52:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Metro’s Ballooning Bond for Road Diets</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/tax-and-budget/metros-ballooning-bond-for-road-diets/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Jacob Beckwith On July 31st, the seven Metro councilors will vote to...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/tax-and-budget/metros-ballooning-bond-for-road-diets/"&gt;Metro’s Ballooning Bond for Road Diets&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 14:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Exploring transportation taxes and their impact in the Mountain States</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/exploring-transportation-taxes-and-their-impact-in-the-mountain-states</link><description>As Americans hit the road this summer, what types of transportation-related taxes will they be paying? We answer this question in our new...</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 14:25:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Virginiainstitute] Press Release – 50CAN Reveals Call for More Education Choice in Virginia</title><link>https://virginiainstitute.org/press-release-50can-reveals-call-for-more-education-choice-in-virginia/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=press-release-50can-reveals-call-for-more-education-choice-in-virginia</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Summary A recent poll conducted by the Virginia Institute for Public Policy (VIPP) in partnership with 50CAN reveals a strong demand among Virginia parents for expanded educational choices ahead of&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org/press-release-50can-reveals-call-for-more-education-choice-in-virginia/"&gt;Press Release – 50CAN Reveals Call for More Education Choice in Virginia&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org"&gt;Virginia Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 14:47:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] Press Release: New Jersey Policy Institute Appoints Unity Bank Exec George Boyan as New Board Member</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/07/press-release-new-jersey-policy-institute-appoints-unity-bank-exec-george-boyan-as-new-board-member/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 15:53:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Declining enrollment in traditional schools highlights California’s need for alternatives</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/ca-enrollment-trends/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=ca-enrollment-trends</link><description>&lt;p&gt;With many California classrooms set to reopen in August, California Policy Center took a closer look at school enrollment patterns, and what they signal for the year ahead. Looking at public school enrollment data from 2014-15 to 2024-25, broken down by county, CPC conducted an analysis of the 10-year trend in California. The data revealed...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/ca-enrollment-trends/"&gt;Declining enrollment in traditional schools highlights California’s need for alternatives&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 19:15:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Job Licensing Reviews: Health and Human Services Committee</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/job-licensing-reviews-health-and-human-services-committee/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Occupational Board Reform Act (OBRA) was passed in 2018 and became effective in 2019. It requires legislative committees of jurisdiction to review all occupational licenses in the state, roughly 20% per year, on a five-year rotation. These reviews examine whether the licensing requirements are adequate or excessive by current standards. The committees then submit...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/job-licensing-reviews-health-and-human-services-committee/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Job Licensing Reviews: Health and Human Services Committee&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 20:30:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Iowa Senator Slams Wasteful California Rail Transportation Projects</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/iowa-senator-slams-wasteful-california-rail-transportation-projects/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=iowa-senator-slams-wasteful-california-rail-transportation-projects</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Senator Joni Ernst (R-IA) has issued a report identifying wasteful federally funded construction projects, and California’s rail projects are prominently featured. In addition to High-Speed Rail, Ernst’s “Off the Rails” report correctly singles out three transit projects in Northern California. While Californians may discount criticisms from a Red State Senator, Ernst’s report might ultimately benefit...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/iowa-senator-slams-wasteful-california-rail-transportation-projects/"&gt;Iowa Senator Slams Wasteful California Rail Transportation Projects&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 18:51:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] ‘We still need to pave our roads’</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/wisconsin-land-stewardship-program-analysis/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As a Wisconsin stewardship program is up for renewal, northern counties’ budgets, economies are squeezed by how much land already is taken out of equation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/wisconsin-land-stewardship-program-analysis/"&gt;‘We still need to pave our roads’&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 21:05:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] API Announces Support of the STUDENTS Act</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/08/01/api-announces-support-of-the-students-act/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Alabama Policy Institute (API) announced its endorsement of the federal Stopping Teachers Unions from Damaging Education Needs Today (STUDENTS) Act, which seeks to reform the federal charter of the country’s largest education union, the National Education Association (NEA).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/08/01/api-announces-support-of-the-students-act/"&gt;API Announces Support of the STUDENTS Act&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 01:32:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Kansas Is Losing the Competition for People—and It’s Not Just a Kansas Problem</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/kansas-is-losing-the-competition-for-people/</link><description>Americans are voting with their feet, and states are either competing for them—or watching them leave. Data posted by the Committee to Unleash Prosperity at VoteWithYourFeet.net make it painfully clear: Kansas is hemorrhaging residents. Over the last decade, it had a net loss of nearly 100,000 people to other states. That’s not just bad optics—that’s [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 14:00:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] New York’s Medicaid Spending Rate Remains the Highest of Any State</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/new-yorks-medicaid-spending-rate-remains-the-highest-of-any-state/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New York&amp;#8217;s Medicaid program remained a spending outlier in 2024, with per-resident outlays that were 24 percent higher than those....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/new-yorks-medicaid-spending-rate-remains-the-highest-of-any-state/"&gt;New York&amp;#8217;s Medicaid Spending Rate Remains the Highest of Any State&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 14:10:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] How Often Should Schools Close?</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/accountability/how-often-should-schools-close/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been writing a lot lately about the poor performance of Missouri’s schools; for recent examples, see here and here. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/accountability/how-often-should-schools-close/"&gt;How Often Should Schools Close?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 15:15:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] Pennsylvania Enters Second Month of Budget Impasse</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/08/01/pennsylvania-enters-second-month-of-budget-impasse/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Harrisburg, Pa., August 1, 2025 — Pennsylvania is entering the second month operating without a state budget, with no end in sight. Amid the protracted impasse, many have begun to question the governor’s priorities as days pass without substantial progress. Andrew Lewis, President and CEO of the Commonwealth Foundation, issued the following statement in response: [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/08/01/pennsylvania-enters-second-month-of-budget-impasse/"&gt;Pennsylvania Enters Second Month of Budget Impasse&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 17:51:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Fight socialism: Build more housing</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/08/fight-socialism-build-more-housing/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The rise of 33-year-old “democratic” socialist Zohran Mamdami to the Democratic nomination for mayor of New York City has sensible political observers from right to left understandably concerned. How could the city that symbolizes the global dominance of American finance and capital be on the cusp of electing a mayor who advocates dismantling capitalism? Downwardly [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/08/fight-socialism-build-more-housing/"&gt;Fight socialism: Build more housing&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 19:02:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Passport to Parks? More Like Passport to Perks</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/08/01/passport-to-parks-more-like-passport-to-perks/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What began as a passport to the outdoors has turned into a backdoor subsidy for public-sector pensions.  State officials sold the Passport to Parks fee — quietly tacked onto every [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/08/01/passport-to-parks-more-like-passport-to-perks/"&gt;Passport to Parks? More Like Passport to Perks&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 20:09:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Parents</title><link>https://will-law.org/parents/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/parents/"&gt;Parents&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2025 22:10:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] WILL Releases New Model Policy &amp; Resources Following SCOTUS Parental Rights Decision</title><link>https://will-law.org/will-releases-new-model-policy-resources-following-scotus-parental-rights-decision/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Following a landmark U.S. Supreme Court decision, WILL is releasing a new model school board policy and additional tools to equip parents, teachers, and school administrators across the country to protect the fundamental right of families to raise their children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/will-releases-new-model-policy-resources-following-scotus-parental-rights-decision/"&gt;WILL Releases New Model Policy &amp;#038; Resources Following SCOTUS Parental Rights Decision&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 13:19:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] OPINION: New Mexico and the film industry recession</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/opinion-new-mexico-and-the-film-industry-recession/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Since the days of Gov. Bill Richardson’s administration, the Rio Grande Foundation has opposed New Mexico’s generous film subsidies. Back in Richardson’s day the primary subsidy was a 25% “refundable” tax credit meaning that anyone filming in New Mexico received up to 25% of what they spent to film in the Land of Enchantment (courtesy [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/opinion-new-mexico-and-the-film-industry-recession/"&gt;OPINION: New Mexico and the film industry recession&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 16:27:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Direct primary care provides medical treatment the old-fashioned way</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/direct-primary-care-provides-medical-treatment-the-old-fashioned-way</link><description>Because of the way health care has evolved in the United States over the past 80 years, it is extremely complex and now involves...</description><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 19:17:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] The AI Blueprint States Can’t Afford to Ignore</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/the-ai-blueprint-states-cant-afford-to-ignore/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;August 4, 2025 The Trump Administration’s recent AI Action Plan signals a fundamental shift in how the federal...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/the-ai-blueprint-states-cant-afford-to-ignore/"&gt;The AI Blueprint States Can&amp;#8217;t Afford to Ignore&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 20:09:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Metro Council Votes to Approve $88.5 Million Bond for Road Diets: One Intern’s Reflection</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/transportation/metro-council-votes-to-approve-88-5-million-bond-for-road-diets-one-interns-reflection/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Connor Roberts The summer of 2025 brought Cascade three talented Research Associates...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/transportation/metro-council-votes-to-approve-88-5-million-bond-for-road-diets-one-interns-reflection/"&gt;Metro Council Votes to Approve $88.5 Million Bond for Road Diets: One Intern’s Reflection  &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 22:37:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/08/the-outstater-280/</link><description>The Legislative Experiment “Decrepitude remains the path of least resistance for the institution that is supposed to be the beating heart of American self-government.”&amp;#160;— Phillip Wallach WE ALL ARE TIRED&amp;#160;of complaining about Congress so let’s abandon it as sunk cost. We may be obligated to maintain the payroll and provide a place for it to&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/08/the-outstater-280/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 11:34:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Speaker White: Game on for School Choice in Mississippi</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/speaker-white-game-on-for-school-choice-in-mississippi/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Neshoba County Fair is a Mississippi tradition, bringing together thousands of folk at the height of summer for a week of Southern celebration—music, dancing, food, cattle shows, horse racing, and, of course, politics. &amp;#160;Ever since Ronald Reagan kicked off his 1980 presidential campaign at the Fair, it’s been&amp;#160;the&amp;#160;place where public officials in our state [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/speaker-white-game-on-for-school-choice-in-mississippi/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Speaker White: Game on for School Choice in Mississippi&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 14:38:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] New Report Finds Pennsylvania Violating Law, Endangering Students in Dangerous Schools</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/08/05/new-report-finds-pennsylvania-violating-law-endangering-students-in-dangerous-schools/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Harrisburg, Pa., August 5, 2025—The Pennsylvania Department of Education (PDE) is violating state and federal law around “persistently dangerous schools,” endangering the safety of Pennsylvania’s most vulnerable students, and threatening billions in federal funding, according to a groundbreaking analysis from the Commonwealth Foundation.&amp;#160; More than 40 percent of Pennsylvania schools face dangerous incidents, but state [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/08/05/new-report-finds-pennsylvania-violating-law-endangering-students-in-dangerous-schools/"&gt;New Report Finds Pennsylvania Violating Law, Endangering Students in Dangerous Schools&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 14:42:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Fact Check: DOJ Election Oversight Has Constitutional Basis, Despite Bellows’ Claims</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/fact-check-doj-election-oversight-has-constitutional-basis-despite-bellows-claims/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When news broke that the U.S. Department of Justice (DOJ) under the Trump administration had issued a request for voter registration data from all 50 states, including Maine, Secretary of State Shenna Bellows wasted no time grabbing headlines, calling the move unprecedented and claiming “It’s an abuse of power and it contravenes what the founders [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/fact-check-doj-election-oversight-has-constitutional-basis-despite-bellows-claims/"&gt;Fact Check: DOJ Election Oversight Has Constitutional Basis, Despite Bellows&amp;#8217; Claims&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 15:31:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Frontierinstitute] Fiscally Crying Wolf</title><link>https://frontierinstitute.org/fiscally-crying-wolf/</link><description>"Trimming $350 Million from a $16 billion state budget is small potatoes, not the sky falling. If anything, our federal and state governments should be focused on eliminating even more spending to protect taxpayers."</description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 17:00:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Back to School: A New Chapter of Hope and Opportunity</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/back-to-school/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=back-to-school</link><description>As the school year begins, let’s celebrate not only a fresh start but also the "hope and opportunity" available to Tennessee families as new chapters open.</description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 17:53:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Blatant Lawlessness</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/08/05/blatant-lawlessness/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="948" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/Screenshot-2025-08-06-093200.jpg" width="1324" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new Yankee Institute report, Blatant Lawlessness: How the CT Department of Labor &amp;#38; Union Leaders Disrespect Union Workers and Ignore the Law, highlights the Connecticut Department of Labor’s (CT [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/08/05/blatant-lawlessness/"&gt;Blatant Lawlessness&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 20:35:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Speaker Jason White: Education Freedom and Mississippi’s Future</title><link>https://empowerms.org/speaker-jason-white-education-freedom-and-mississippis-future/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Speaker Jason White: Education Freedom and Mississippi&amp;#8217;s Future Fresh off his speech at the Neshoba County Fair, Mississippi&amp;#8217;s 62nd Speaker of the House, Jason White joins host Grant Callen for this episode of the Empower Podcast. We recap his fair speech and talk about the experience of walking out on that storied stage at Neshoba.&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/speaker-jason-white-education-freedom-and-mississippis-future/"&gt;Speaker Jason White: Education Freedom and Mississippi’s Future&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 21:13:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Exemption increase would help homeowners under 65 years old</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/08/exemption-increase-would-help-homeowners-under-65-years-old/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Honolulu City Council on August 6, 2025._____________ Aug. 6, 2025, 10 a.m.Honolulu Hale To: Honolulu City Council       Tommy Waters, Chair       Andria Tupola, Vice Chair From: Grassroot Institute of Hawaii            Ted Kefalas, Director of Strategic Campaigns RE: Bill 50 (2025) — [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/08/exemption-increase-would-help-homeowners-under-65-years-old/"&gt;Exemption increase would help homeowners under 65 years old&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 03:14:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Higher exemption would help seniors cope with higher property values</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/08/higher-exemption-would-help-seniors-cope-with-higher-property-values/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Honolulu City Council on August 6, 2025._____________ Aug. 6, 2025, 10 a.m.Honolulu Hale To: Honolulu City Council       Tommy Waters, Chair       Andria Tupola, Vice Chair From: Grassroot Institute of Hawaii            Ted Kefalas, Director of Strategic Campaigns RE: Bill 49 (2025) — [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/08/higher-exemption-would-help-seniors-cope-with-higher-property-values/"&gt;Higher exemption would help seniors cope with higher property values&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 03:16:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] The federal Jones Act is a case study in the power of special interests</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/08/the-federal-jones-act-is-a-case-study-in-the-power-of-special-interests/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following commentary first published by the Cato Institute on Aug. 4, 2025, under the headline &amp;#8220;How special interests keep bad laws on the books: The case of the Jones Act.&amp;#8221;_____________ Seven years ago, the Cato Institute launched its project on reforming the Jones Act — the 1920 law that restricts intra-U.S. water transport to vessels that [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/08/the-federal-jones-act-is-a-case-study-in-the-power-of-special-interests/"&gt;The federal Jones Act is a case study in the power of special interests&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 03:35:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] OP-ED by Stephanie Smith, API President/CEO and mother of seven</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/08/06/op-ed-by-stephanie-smith-api-president-ceo-and-mother-of-seven/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Fourth Circuit of the U.S. Court of Appeals recently upheld West Virginia’s near-total ban on chemical abortions — a major win for federalism, health safety, and the pro-life movement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/08/06/op-ed-by-stephanie-smith-api-president-ceo-and-mother-of-seven/"&gt;OP-ED by Stephanie Smith, API President/CEO and mother of seven&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 05:47:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] The MEDC Hall of Shame</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/the-medc-hall-of-shame</link><description>Top 10 cringe (and criminal) moments from the Michigan Economic Development Corporation</description><pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Tina Kotek’s Energy Policy: Whichever Way the Wind Blows</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/environment/tina-koteks-energy-policy-whichever-way-the-wind-blows/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Maxwell Powers Governor Tina Kotek has long expressed support for wind power....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/environment/tina-koteks-energy-policy-whichever-way-the-wind-blows/"&gt;Tina Kotek’s Energy Policy: Whichever Way the Wind Blows&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 14:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] WILL Advises DPI to Improve Transparency and Accountability in School Report Card</title><link>https://will-law.org/will-advises-dpi-to-improve-transparency-and-accountability-in-school-report-card/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL submitted recommendations to the Department of Public Instruction (DPI) today, urging an overhaul of the state’s school report card standards. WILL’s analysis highlights DPI's track record of inflating ratings that masks a decades-long stagnation in student achievement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/will-advises-dpi-to-improve-transparency-and-accountability-in-school-report-card/"&gt;WILL Advises DPI to Improve Transparency and Accountability in School Report Card&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 15:13:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] The One Big Education Opportunity with Shaka Mitchell</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/education/the-one-big-education-opportunity-with-shaka-mitchell/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Susan Pendergrass speaks with Shaka Mitchell, senior fellow at the American Federation for Children, about how a new federal scholarship [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/education/the-one-big-education-opportunity-with-shaka-mitchell/"&gt;The One Big Education Opportunity with Shaka Mitchell&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 16:01:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Opt-out record falls for the third consecutive month</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/opt-out-record-falls-for-the-third-consecutive-month/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Freedom Foundation has done it again, setting yet another record for monthly union opt-outs. That’s three months in a row. In July alone, 5,381 government employees made the decision to leave their union, bringing the total financial impact to more than $5 million in annual dues redirected away from unions that can no longer [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/opt-out-record-falls-for-the-third-consecutive-month/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Opt-out record falls for the third consecutive month&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 17:11:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Pioneer Institute Joins Coalition of Business and Taxpayers to Support Affordability, Job and Economic Growth</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/pioneer-institute-joins-coalition-of-business-and-taxpayers-to-support-affordability-job-and-economic-growth/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Boston, MA — The two 2026 ballot proposals filed today—one to lower the state income tax from 5% to 4% over three years, and another to strengthen the state’s tax revenue cap (“62F”)—represent concrete steps to return billions to taxpayers and restore Massachusetts’ economic competitiveness. According to fiscal modeling by the Mass Opportunity Alliance (MOA), of which Pioneer Institute is a founding member, the income tax reduction alone would save the average taxpayer more than $1,300 annually. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/pioneer-institute-joins-coalition-of-business-and-taxpayers-to-support-affordability-job-and-economic-growth/"&gt;Pioneer Institute Joins Coalition of Business and Taxpayers to Support Affordability, Job and Economic Growth&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 19:11:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Goldwater Urges Arizona Justices to Protect the Right to a Jury</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/goldwater-urges-arizona-justices-to-protect-the-right-to-a-jury/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In a pair of briefs filed with the Arizona Supreme Court today, the Goldwater Institute urged the justices to take..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/goldwater-urges-arizona-justices-to-protect-the-right-to-a-jury/"&gt;Goldwater Urges Arizona Justices to Protect the Right to a Jury&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 19:15:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF weighs in on fraud investigation at Office of Insurance Superintendent</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-weighs-in-on-fraud-investigation-at-office-of-insurance-superintendent/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;There is a lawsuit and investigation going on at New Mexico&amp;#8217;s Office of the Superintendent of Insurance. The state is spending nearly half a million dollars of your money investigating what they call &amp;#8220;potential irregularities&amp;#8221; in New Mexico&amp;#8217;s insurance fraud fund. But, rather than investigating companies for alleged fraud they are investigating internally. They are [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-weighs-in-on-fraud-investigation-at-office-of-insurance-superintendent/"&gt;RGF weighs in on fraud investigation at Office of Insurance Superintendent&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 19:32:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Ideas for reforming Medicaid and protecting patients</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/medicaid-reforms-for-state-lawmakers-to-consider</link><description>Medicaid is a joint federal and state-controlled health care insurance entitlement. It is not financially sustainable in its current form...</description><pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 19:52:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Frontierinstitute] Pro-Density vs. Pro-Freedom: A Look at Bozeman’s Zoning Updates</title><link>https://frontierinstitute.org/pro-density-vs-pro-freedom-a-look-at-bozemans-zoning-updates/</link><description>"The problem isn’t that government is picking the wrong types of housing – the problem is that government is trampling on property rights and making choices that should be left to Montanans."</description><pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 22:49:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] The incredible shrinking Department of Education</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/the-incredible-shrinking-department-of-education</link><description>Opportunities for Michigan as Trump moves to fulfill Reagan-era abolition promise</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Despite ‘pro-housing’ programs, California’s crisis getting worse</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/despite-pro-housing-programs-californias-crisis-getting-worse/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Cities including Spokane, Tulsa and Memphis support pre-approved designs to streamline small-scale builds, similar to what California has sought to promote with its Pro-housing Designation Program (PDP). But many question why California’s land entitlement process—getting the zoning, use and building design approval from local governments to comply with state mandates—often takes years, even in places [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/despite-pro-housing-programs-californias-crisis-getting-worse/"&gt;Despite ‘pro-housing’ programs, California’s crisis getting worse&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 10:00:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] First Statewide Poll Shows Marsha Blackburn as Clear Frontrunner Over John Rose in GOP Primary for Governor</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/blackburn-rose-beaconpoll/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=blackburn-rose-beaconpoll</link><description>In light of Senator Marsha Blackburn&amp;#8217;s recent announcement that she plans to run for governor of Tennessee, Beacon is releasing the poll results of the Republican gubernatorial primary a few days early. In the field before Senator Blackburn’s official announcement, the poll asked Tennesseans who they would support in the 2025 GOP primary for governor, Senator...</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 13:00:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Research Note: Livestock siting assessment and the Iowa case study</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/research-note-livestock-siting-assessment-and-the-iowa-case-study/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;[Note: This is the fourth in a series of Research Notes by Platte’s summer intern, focusing on county zoning and agriculture issues] Thirteen years before Nebraska developed its Livestock Siting Assessment Matrix, its neighbor, Iowa, implemented a similar tool. In 2002, the Iowa Department of Natural Resources (DNR) introduced a scoring system, known as the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/research-note-livestock-siting-assessment-and-the-iowa-case-study/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Research Note: Livestock siting assessment and the Iowa case study&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 15:10:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Maine’s Soaring Electricity Prices Highlight Need for Smarter Energy Policy</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/maines-soaring-electricity-prices-highlight-need-for-smarter-energy-policy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This year, many Mainers felt a jolt when they opened their energy bills. According to data gathered from the U.S. Energy Information Administration (EIA), Maine experienced the largest year-over-year residential electricity price increase in the country: a staggering 36.3% jump between May 2024 and May 2025. That&amp;#8217;s more than five times the national average increase [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/maines-soaring-electricity-prices-highlight-need-for-smarter-energy-policy/"&gt;Maine&amp;#8217;s Soaring Electricity Prices Highlight Need for Smarter Energy Policy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 15:22:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Not Our Cup of Tea: America Should Avoid UK Style Regulation</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/not-our-cup-of-tea-america-should-avoid-uk-style-regulation/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;After the Supreme Court’s decision in June to uphold a Texas age verification law in Free Speech Coalition v. Paxton, the fate of the internet—who can use it and how difficult it is to access—seems precarious. Age verification is an increasingly popular but short-sighted solution to the growing fears over the impact that the internet...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/not-our-cup-of-tea-america-should-avoid-uk-style-regulation/"&gt;Not Our Cup of Tea: America Should Avoid UK Style Regulation&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 15:23:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Innovation and U.S. Patents</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/blog/innovation-and-u-s-patents/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In 2023, the United States Patent Office issued 159,880 patents for American inventors, according to US DataLabs. That number was roughly half of all U.S. patents granted. One sixth of the patents granted were filed by Japanese inventors; Chinese and Korean inventors received the next most patents. Patents by State Figure 1: Number of patents filed, top five states, 2023. Data from Pioneer Institute’s US DataLabs. California (49,637), Texas (11,979), New York (11,204), Massachusetts (8,369) and Illinois (6,040) made up the top five states for most patents issued during 2023. In addition to having the largest population, California’s per capita number of patents also exceeded any other state with 127.4 per 100,000 residents. Massachusetts followed with 119.5 per 100,000 capita. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/blog/innovation-and-u-s-patents/"&gt;Innovation and U.S. Patents&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 17:47:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] The Mississippi Center for Public Policy welcomes new Chief Development Officer</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/the-mississippi-center-for-public-policy-welcomes-new-chief-development-officer/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Jackson, MS&amp;#160;— The Mississippi Center for Public Policy (MCPP) is pleased to announce the addition of Richard Wilson as its new Chief Development Officer. With a distinguished background in campaign management, government affairs, and nonprofit fundraising, Wilson brings a wealth of experience and a proven track record of results-driven leadership to MCPP. “We are thrilled [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/the-mississippi-center-for-public-policy-welcomes-new-chief-development-officer/" rel="nofollow"&gt;The Mississippi Center for Public Policy welcomes new Chief Development Officer&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 18:26:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Fact vs. Fiction: Washington Post Launches False Attack on Arizona ESAs</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/fact-vs-fiction-washington-post-launches-false-attack-on-arizona-esas/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Washington Post launched a biased and untrue attack on Arizona’s pioneering school choice program this week, profiling a Phoenix..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/fact-vs-fiction-washington-post-launches-false-attack-on-arizona-esas/"&gt;Fact vs. Fiction: Washington Post Launches False Attack on Arizona ESAs&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 18:41:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Week in Review: The Media Strikes Again</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-the-media-strikes-again/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;School choice is winning nationwide, and state after state is following the Goldwater Institute’s lead in enacting education savings accounts,..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-the-media-strikes-again/"&gt;Week in Review: The Media Strikes Again&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 19:38:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Illinois housing prices climb, production remains slow</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/illinois-housing-prices-climb-production-remains-slow/</link><description>June housing production in Illinois continues to lag the rest of the nation, leading to price problems across the state</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 19:53:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Surge in State Revenue, Growing Expenditures and Inflation</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/blog/surge-in-state-revenue-growing-expenditures-and-inflation/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;How has state government spending and revenue changed from 2017 to 2022? Changes in revenue and spending can be a key indicator of state priorities for the size and scope of government, as well as a state’s overall health and economic output. Oftentimes revenue and expense growth tracks with the rate of inflation, as well as increases in wages and property values. However, state and local governments have generally grown larger overtime, having tripled inflation-adjusted spending from 1997 to 2021. State revenue and expenditures can also be impacted by variations in geography, demographics, history, and other external factors. Growth of expenses State’s expenses fluctuate over time. Changes to public services, growth in aid programs or entitlement benefits, and state emergencies [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/blog/surge-in-state-revenue-growing-expenditures-and-inflation/"&gt;Surge in State Revenue, Growing Expenditures and Inflation&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 20:16:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Port Washington data center on track to by far be state’s largest electricity user</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/port-washington-data-center-on-track-to-by-far-be-states-largest-electricity-user/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Vantage Data Center in Port Washington is on its way to becoming the largest single energy user in state history — an indication of the immense power needs of the five data centers in the works in Wisconsin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/port-washington-data-center-on-track-to-by-far-be-states-largest-electricity-user/"&gt;Port Washington data center on track to by far be state’s largest electricity user&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 20:37:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] A win for Wisconsin families: Childcare in the 2025-2027 biennial state budget</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/a-win-for-wisconsin-families-childcare-in-the-2025-2027-biennial-state-budget/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Wisconsin’s 2025-2027 biennial budget includes several provisions aimed at improving the affordability of childcare in the Badger state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/a-win-for-wisconsin-families-childcare-in-the-2025-2027-biennial-state-budget/"&gt;A win for Wisconsin families: Childcare in the 2025-2027 biennial state budget&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 20:39:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] EFA enrollment for this fall in line with Josiah Bartlett Center estimates</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/08/efa-enrollment-for-this-fall-in-line-with-josiah-bartlett-center-estimates/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New Hampshire’s Education Freedom Account program hit its enrollment cap of 10,000 students for the upcoming school year, the Children’s Scholarship Fund-NH confirmed this week. As talk of the program growing beyond expectations spread through social media, readers of this website shouldn’t have been surprised by the numbers.  They’re almost exactly what we predicted five [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/08/efa-enrollment-for-this-fall-in-line-with-josiah-bartlett-center-estimates/"&gt;EFA enrollment for this fall in line with Josiah Bartlett Center estimates&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 21:14:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Pritzker further undermines Chicago police, fire pensions</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/pritzker-further-undermines-chicago-police-fire-pensions/</link><description>Gov. J.B. Pritzker had a chance to stop a bill putting taxpayers on the hook for $11.1 billion in inflated pension benefits for Chicago police and firefighters. He blew it. Taxpayers will be paying the price for decades.</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 21:39:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Municipalities Should Not Be Commercial Landlords (I’m Looking at You, Chesterfield)</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/municipal-policy/municipalities-should-not-be-commercial-landlords-im-looking-at-you-chesterfield/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Chesterfield, which is poised to be the largest city in St. Louis County, is attempting to get into the commercial [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/municipal-policy/municipalities-should-not-be-commercial-landlords-im-looking-at-you-chesterfield/"&gt;Municipalities Should Not Be Commercial Landlords (I’m Looking at You, Chesterfield)&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 22:20:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Minnesota Dad dreams of Honduran gold</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/minnesota-dad-dreams-of-honduran-gold/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Fredy Kirrington-Mendoza, age 35, wins Minnesota Dad of the Week honors. A name matching Mr. Kirrington&amp;#8217;s appears in court records in St. Cloud, Sherburne County, as a convicted felon for a January 2025 domestic incident. Police came to his St. Cloud home to discover that he had assaulted his wife and threatened her with a...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/minnesota-dad-dreams-of-honduran-gold/"&gt;Minnesota Dad dreams of Honduran gold&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 23:27:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/08/the-outstater-281/</link><description>Excerpts from Paul Fussell’s 1981 article in the New Republic commemorating the dropping of an atomic bomb on Hiroshima 80 years ago this week: Arthur T. Hadley said recently that those for whom the use of the A-bomb was “wrong” seem to be implying “that it would have been better to allow thousands on thousands of American&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/08/the-outstater-281/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 00:03:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Nampa’s Ford Idaho Center: A Multi-Million Dollar Giveaway?</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/nampas-ford-idaho-center-a-multi-million-dollar-giveaway/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/nampas-ford-idaho-center-a-multi-million-dollar-giveaway/" rel="nofollow" title="Nampa’s Ford Idaho Center: A Multi-Million Dollar Giveaway? "&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/Article-Headers-2025-08-07T185321.585.png" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;In what may well be the most extraordinary act of unsolicited civic generosity on this side of the Treasure Valley, Nampa Mayor Debbie Kling and the Nampa City Council are contemplating the “conveyance” of the Ford Idaho Center (FIC) to the College of Western Idaho (CWI) — no appraisal, no payment, and an utter lack [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 02:20:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Meet Our New Director of Research</title><link>https://empowerms.org/meet-our-new-director-of-research/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;We’re excited to welcome Dr. Kristin Vance Richards as the new Director of Research at Empower Mississippi. In this role, she will lead our research efforts and help shape data-driven strategies that advance our work in education, work, and criminal justice. Kristin brings deep expertise and a strong commitment to using research to drive meaningful&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/meet-our-new-director-of-research/"&gt;Meet Our New Director of Research&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 06:00:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Cities should forget sport-subsidy hype and focus on basics</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/cities-should-forget-sport-subsidy-hype-and-focus-on-basics/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Cities should forget sport-subsidy hype and focus on basics By D. Dowd Muska   &amp;#124;  August 8, 2025 Three years to go. The opening ceremony for the Games of the XXXIV Olympiad is scheduled for July 14, 2028. And the men and women of the organizing committee are working feverishly to ensure that the event [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/cities-should-forget-sport-subsidy-hype-and-focus-on-basics/"&gt;Cities should forget sport-subsidy hype and focus on basics&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 09:06:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Health, fitness cause partisan split</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/health-fitness-cause-partisan-split/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Ingrid Jacques writes for USA Today about a disturbing trend that has emerged in recent months. The reality is that more than 70% of Americans are overweight or obese, and the trend has been moving rapidly in the wrong direction, leading to a plethora of preventable health problems and costs associated with them.  It’s concerning,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/health-fitness-cause-partisan-split/"&gt;Health, fitness cause partisan split&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 09:39:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Even Colbert sees crazy Illinois gerrymander</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/even-colbert-sees-crazy-illinois-gerrymander/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Josh Christenson writes for the New York Post about an interesting exchange on late-night television. Lame-duck CBS late-night host Stephen Colbert showed Democratic Illinois Gov. JB Pritzker just how gerrymandered the Land of Lincoln is after dozens of Texas Dem legislators stalled redistricting in their own state by decamping to Pritzker’s domain. The face of...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/even-colbert-sees-crazy-illinois-gerrymander/"&gt;Even Colbert sees crazy Illinois gerrymander&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 09:42:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] ‘When there’s a threat of failure, people innovate’</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/podcasts/the-overton-window/richard-vedder-discusses-his-book-on-creative-destruction-in-higher-education</link><description>Richard Vedder discusses his book on creative destruction in higher education</description><pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] A lesson from Iowa on government reform: It’s not just the taxes — it’s the spending</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/a-lesson-from-iowa-on-government-reform-its-not-just-the-taxes-its-the-spending/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Former President Herbert Hoover argued that governments have the instincts of a vegetable — that is, “they keep spreading and growing.” Iowa Gov. Kim Reynolds (R) echoed Hoover when she stated that “like any large organization, government is marked by bureaucracy’s natural tendency to grow. If that growth isn’t constantly checked and rechanneled toward its core function, it quickly takes on a life of its own.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/a-lesson-from-iowa-on-government-reform-its-not-just-the-taxes-its-the-spending/"&gt;A lesson from Iowa on government reform: It’s not just the taxes — it’s the spending&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 12:57:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] The Taxman Cometh: City of Jersey Village</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/the-taxman-cometh-city-of-jersey-village/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Most cities, counties, and school districts are right now in the process of adopting budgets and determining tax rates for the next fiscal year. In some cases, these local decisions will increase the cost of government and put upward pressure on property tax bills. Given the very real prospect of tax increases, now is the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/the-taxman-cometh-city-of-jersey-village/"&gt;The Taxman Cometh: City of Jersey Village&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 15:24:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Florida’s DOGE Teams Target Local Government Spending</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/floridas-doge-teams-target-local-government-spending/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Iowa isn’t the only state deploying a DOGE initiative to reform local government. In Florida, Governor Ron DeSantis has dispatched DOGE teams to investigate spending practices in specific cities and counties, with a sharp focus on transparency, accountability, and responsible fiscal management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Florida is the model for fiscal responsibility at the state level, and we will utilize our authority to ensure local governments follow suit,” said Governor DeSantis. He emphasized that “Florida’s DOGE efforts are owed to the taxpayer and represent yet another way our state is pursuing fiscal responsibility.” The DOGE teams are tasked with reviewing local government spending practices and procedures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/floridas-doge-teams-target-local-government-spending/"&gt;Florida’s DOGE Teams Target Local Government Spending&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 15:25:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Bill Analysis: SB 9</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/bill-analysis-sb-9/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Despite having passed tax relief at the state level during the 89th Legislative Session (SB 4, 2025), Texans are still burdened with some of the highest property taxes in the nation. This is largely due to relief being eroded at the local level. Local government taxes and spending need to be scrutinized by voters more...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/bill-analysis-sb-9/"&gt;Bill Analysis: SB 9&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 15:48:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Competition in education is an opportunity, not a crisis</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/08/competition-in-education-is-an-opportunity-not-a-crisis/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;There’s been a bit of a media freakout this week about the growing popularity of school choice programs nationwide.  The Children’s Scholarship Fund-NH confirmed this week that the Education Freedom Account program hit its 2025-26 enrollment cap of 10,000 students in early August.   “Record number of students matched with their preferred form of education,” [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/08/competition-in-education-is-an-opportunity-not-a-crisis/"&gt;Competition in education is an opportunity, not a crisis&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 16:56:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] </title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/08/14082/</link><description>Andre Carson, Part II&amp;#160; I don&amp;#8217;t have any reasonsI&amp;#8217;ve left them all behindI&amp;#8217;m in a New York state of mind — Billy Joel NEW YORK CITY is poised to elect an Islamist mayor and at least the prospect of Sharia Law, “no go” zones, globalization of the infidel, anti-semitism and so forth, not to mention a historically ignorant race-Marxism.&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/08/14082/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 17:14:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Feeding Our Future: 73rd defendant</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/feeding-our-future-73rd-defendant/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;From the U.S. Attorney&amp;#8217;s press release, Hussein Mohamed Farah, the executive director of New Vision Foundation, a non-profit located in St. Paul, Minnesota, was charged by information with one count of wire fraud for his role in the $300 million Feeding Our Future fraud scheme. Farah becomes the 73rd defendant, overall, in the sprawling free-food...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/feeding-our-future-73rd-defendant/"&gt;Feeding Our Future: 73rd defendant&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 18:59:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Connecticut’s New Law Lets Unions and the State Peek into School Budgets</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/08/08/connecticuts-new-law-lets-unions-and-the-state-peek-into-school-budgets/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senate Bill 1 was promoted as a $300 million investment in early childhood education and special education services. But buried in the bill is a provision with little to do [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/08/08/connecticuts-new-law-lets-unions-and-the-state-peek-into-school-budgets/"&gt;Connecticut’s New Law Lets Unions and the State Peek into School Budgets&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 20:06:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Gov. Stein’s defense of his veto of HB 87: far from convincing</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/gov-steins-defense-of-his-veto-of-hb-87-far-from-convincing/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;School choice is good for students and parents, and I have long supported magnet and accountable charter schools because public schools open doors of opportunity for kids in every county of the state. Congress and the Administration should strengthen our public schools, not hollow them out. Cutting public education funding by billions of dollars while...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/gov-steins-defense-of-his-veto-of-hb-87-far-from-convincing/"&gt;Gov. Stein’s defense of his veto of HB 87: far from convincing&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 20:39:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Chicago mayor want to keep taxing groceries despite hit to families</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/chicago-mayor-want-to-keep-taxing-groceries-despite-hit-to-families/</link><description>As food costs soar, Mayor Brandon Johnson wants to keep hurting Chicago’s working families with a grocery tax. He faces a $1.12 billion deficit that a $73 million grocery tax won’t budge.</description><pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 21:19:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Winners &amp; Losers: Quorum Breaking Democrats Don’t Really Represent Texans</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/winners-losers-quorum-breaking-democrats-dont-really-represent-texans-2/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Every Friday morning, I join the Cardle &amp;#38; Woolley Show on 1370 Talk Radio in Austin to announce the week’s Winners &amp;#38; Losers. President Donald Trump completed his 200th day in office yesterday and now that we are in August, we can officially begin the countdown to college football season—Week Zero is on Aug. 23...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/winners-losers-quorum-breaking-democrats-dont-really-represent-texans-2/"&gt;Winners &amp; Losers: Quorum Breaking Democrats Don’t Really Represent Texans&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 22:13:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] MinnesotaCare eligibility guide for illegal aliens is a license to steal</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/minnesotacare-eligibility-guide-for-illegal-aliens-is-a-license-to-steal/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When the Walz administration allowed illegal aliens into the Minnesota taxpayer-supported healthcare system, a bulletin was provided by the Minnesota Department of Human Services that basically provided a roadmap for how to commit fraud against the state. Illegal immigrants were not only coached to provide unverifiable eligibility data (that could not be used to prosecute...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/minnesotacare-eligibility-guide-for-illegal-aliens-is-a-license-to-steal/"&gt;MinnesotaCare eligibility guide for illegal aliens is a license to steal&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 00:36:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] County fairs are great opportunities to go meat shopping</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/county-fairs-are-great-opportunities-to-go-meat-shopping/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Many of California’s county fairs host livestock exhibits giving youth exhibitors an opportunity to sell their livestock during a live auction. Money from the sale of livestock is often saved in college funds, spent on first-car purchases, or funneled into the following years’ project – teaching youth real world money management. Meanwhile, people who buy [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/county-fairs-are-great-opportunities-to-go-meat-shopping/"&gt;County fairs are great opportunities to go meat shopping&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 10:00:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] DOGE Wants Merit Pay, Accountability, &amp; Transparency in Schools</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/doge-wants-merit-pay-accountability-transparency-in-schools/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The DOGE Taskforce recognizes that school districts are not only the primary driver of property tax bills, but that Iowa’s educational outcomes are falling short despite significant taxpayer investment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the taskforce’s key recommendations for improving outcomes is the implementation of merit pay for teachers. Under a merit-based system, teacher compensation would be directly linked to student achievement. “Our current system rewards teachers and administrators based on seniority or the duties they take on, with no connection to student success. This system does not reward excellence in education,” noted committee member Jeff Lutz.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/doge-wants-merit-pay-accountability-transparency-in-schools/"&gt;DOGE Wants Merit Pay, Accountability, &amp;amp; Transparency in Schools&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 14:12:47 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>