<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>State-Policy Think-Tank Digest</title><link>https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml</link><description>Latest posts from free-market policy institutes across the U.S.</description><atom:link href="https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 11:03:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] Microschooling Spreads In Choice-Friendly States</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/06/11/microschooling-spreads-in-choice-friendly-states/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Since 2020, microschools have spread rapidly all across the U.S., but they are particularly popular in states with expansive school-choice programs. These choice-friendly states have passed legislation that enables families to use a portion of state-allocated education funding toward their preferred learning environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/06/11/microschooling-spreads-in-choice-friendly-states/"&gt;Microschooling Spreads In Choice-Friendly States&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 02:16:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alaskapolicyforum] PRESS RELEASE: Alaska Policy Forum Elects Ray Kreig Board President</title><link>https://alaskapolicyforum.org/2025/06/press-release-alaska-policy-forum-elects-ray-kreig-board-president/#utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=press-release-alaska-policy-forum-elects-ray-kreig-board-president</link><description>&lt;div style="margin: 5px 5% 10px 5%;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" height="630" src="https://alaskapolicyforum.org/wp-content/uploads/APF-Press-Release.png" title="Press Release" width="1280" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anchorage, Alaska (June 9, 2025) – Alaska Policy Forum (APF) has elected Ray Kreig as the President of the Board of Directors. Kreig was a co-founder of Alaska Policy Forum in 2009. ARead More&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alaskapolicyforum.org/2025/06/press-release-alaska-policy-forum-elects-ray-kreig-board-president/"&gt;PRESS RELEASE: Alaska Policy Forum Elects Ray Kreig Board President&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://alaskapolicyforum.org"&gt;Alaska Policy Forum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 21:36:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alaskapolicyforum] Want better schools? Healthy competition is the difference</title><link>https://alaskapolicyforum.org/2025/06/want-better-schools-healthy-competition-is-the-difference/#utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=want-better-schools-healthy-competition-is-the-difference</link><description>&lt;div style="margin: 5px 5% 10px 5%;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" height="1440" src="https://alaskapolicyforum.org/wp-content/uploads/school-6900381_1920.jpg" title="" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite significant disparities in funding and adequacy, Florida dramatically outperforms Alaska in the quality of high school graduates. This is despite having a higher poverty rate than Alaska and twice the rate ofRead More&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alaskapolicyforum.org/2025/06/want-better-schools-healthy-competition-is-the-difference/"&gt;Want better schools? Healthy competition is the difference&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://alaskapolicyforum.org"&gt;Alaska Policy Forum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 00:54:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Rep. Lee Yancey: Kratom, Underground Markets, and the Demon Chipmunk</title><link>https://empowerms.org/rep-lee-yancey-kratom-underground-markets-and-the-demon-chipmunk/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;﻿ Rep. Lee Yancey: Kratom, Underground Markets, and the Demon Chipmunk In this episode, host, Grant Callen sits down with State Representative Lee Yancey, a seasoned lawmaker with 11 years of service in the Mississippi Legislature. A one-time Senator, Rep. Yancey now chairs the House Business and Commerce Committee and serves on eight other committees&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/rep-lee-yancey-kratom-underground-markets-and-the-demon-chipmunk/"&gt;Rep. Lee Yancey: Kratom, Underground Markets, and the Demon Chipmunk&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 01:00:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Frontierinstitute] Let’s Start at the Beginning: Vouchers, Tax Credit Scholarships and ESAs</title><link>https://frontierinstitute.org/lets-start-at-the-beginning-vouchers-tax-credit-scholarships-and-esas/</link><description>"Education choice represents a fundamental shift toward recognizing student diversity and parental agency while maintaining our collective commitment to ensuring every child receives a quality education."</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 08:00:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Arkansaspolicyfoundation] RIGHT TO TRY 2.0</title><link>https://arkansaspolicyfoundation.org/right-to-try-2-0/</link><description>RIGHT TO TRY 2.0   (2025-2Q) The idea behind Right-To-Try is that &amp;#8220;terminally ill patients who have exhausted their government-approved options&amp;#8221; should have the freedom to access treatments that may help them.(1)  The idea originated with the Goldwater Institute of Arizona, a member of the State Policy Network (SPN), a market-based group that includes the [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 06:11:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Virginiainstitute] How to navigate and improve Virginia’s education options</title><link>https://virginiainstitute.org/how-to-navigate-and-improve-virginias-education-options/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=how-to-navigate-and-improve-virginias-education-options</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 14:25:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Virginiainstitute] Elections in Virginia: Your Guide to Navigating the Law</title><link>https://virginiainstitute.org/elections-in-virginia-your-guide-to-navigating-the-law/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=elections-in-virginia-your-guide-to-navigating-the-law</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Lindsey Zea Senior Fellow Dr. Clara Belle Wheeler Senior Fellow&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org/elections-in-virginia-your-guide-to-navigating-the-law/"&gt;Elections in Virginia: Your Guide to Navigating the Law&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org"&gt;Virginia Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 14:49:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Rifreedom] Center CEO Mike Stenhouse To Be Inducted Into College Baseball Hall Of Fame</title><link>https://rifreedom.org/2025/06/center-ceo-mike-stenhouse-to-be-inducted-into-college-baseball-hall-of-fame/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;?The Rhode Island Center for Freedom &amp;#38; Prosperity Congratulates CEO Mike Stenhouse on Induction into College Baseball Hall of Fame Providence, RI &amp;#8211; The Rhode Island Center for Freedom &amp;#38; [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org/2025/06/center-ceo-mike-stenhouse-to-be-inducted-into-college-baseball-hall-of-fame/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Center CEO Mike Stenhouse To Be Inducted Into College Baseball Hall Of Fame&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;RI Center for Freedom and Prosperity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 18:23:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Research Note: LB106 and the Nebraska livestock siting assessment matrix</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/research-note-lb106-and-the-nebraska-livestock-siting-assessment-matrix/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Note: This is the first in a series of Research Notes authored by this year&amp;#8217;s Platte Institute Summer Intern, Jakob Myers. Jakob is researching information related to zoning issues involving livestock facilities. The continued growth of Nebraska’s agricultural sector depends significantly on the development and expansion of livestock operations across the state. These projects typically...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/research-note-lb106-and-the-nebraska-livestock-siting-assessment-matrix/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Research Note: LB106 and the Nebraska livestock siting assessment matrix&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 20:32:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF opinion piece:  Arizona policy runs circles around NM</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-opinion-piece-arizona-policy-runs-circles-around-nm/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following appeared in Albuquerque Journal on June 22nd, 2025. Similar versions appeared in numerous other media outlets. Recently, a group of Albuquerque business and economic leaders traveled to Phoenix to get some ideas on why the Phoenix economy is so much stronger than New Mexico’s. Ideas were exchanged and I’m sure a good time [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-opinion-piece-arizona-policy-runs-circles-around-nm/"&gt;RGF opinion piece:  Arizona policy runs circles around NM&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 23:26:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alaskapolicyforum] Alaska’s schools are rolling in cash, so why aren’t the results better?</title><link>https://alaskapolicyforum.org/2025/06/alaskas-schools-are-rolling-in-cash-so-why-arent-the-results-better/#utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=alaskas-schools-are-rolling-in-cash-so-why-arent-the-results-better</link><description>&lt;div style="margin: 5px 5% 10px 5%;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" height="1707" src="https://alaskapolicyforum.org/wp-content/uploads/Money-scaled.jpg" title="" width="2560" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alaska was ranked the second most adequately funded school system in the US by a 2024 study from Rutgers University. The rest of the story — the study actually understates how well neighborhood schoolsRead More&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alaskapolicyforum.org/2025/06/alaskas-schools-are-rolling-in-cash-so-why-arent-the-results-better/"&gt;Alaska’s schools are rolling in cash, so why aren’t the results better?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://alaskapolicyforum.org"&gt;Alaska Policy Forum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 02:25:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Thank Goodness for Mississippi!</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/thank-goodness-for-mississippi/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When I first moved to Mississippi, one or two of my friends back in England raised their eyebrows.&amp;#160;“Mississippi!” the expression of their faces seemed to say. Like many people who’ve never had the good fortune to live in this state, when they hear the word “Mississippi”, they think of the river, or a riverboat or [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/thank-goodness-for-mississippi/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Thank Goodness for Mississippi!&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 18:19:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] New Hampshire Is First in New England to Enact Universal School Choice</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/education/new-hampshire-is-first-in-new-england-to-enact-universal-school-choice/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Kathryn Hickok New Hampshire has removed the income cap for families applying...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/education/new-hampshire-is-first-in-new-england-to-enact-universal-school-choice/"&gt;New Hampshire Is First in New England to Enact Universal School Choice&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 14:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Virginiainstitute] Press Release – VIPP Champions AI Moratorium, Invokes Commerce Clause</title><link>https://virginiainstitute.org/5850-2/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=5850-2</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Virginia Institute for Public Policy’s statement for memorandum highlights the urgent need for a coordinated federal approach to AI regulation, leveraging constitutional authority to avoid a fragmented and counterproductive patchwork of state laws. The proposed moratorium offers a pragmatic pathway to safeguard innovation, support small businesses, and ensure U.S. leadership in the rapidly evolving global AI landscape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org/5850-2/"&gt;Press Release – VIPP Champions AI Moratorium, Invokes Commerce Clause&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org"&gt;Virginia Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 14:10:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Understanding the 2025 state budget pension fight</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/06/understanding-the-2025-state-budget-pension-fight/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Republican leaders in Concord have entered the final week of the fiscal year in a dramatic showdown with each other—not over cutting spending, but increasing it. Gov. Kelly Ayotte wants legislators to honor her campaign promise to police officers and firefighters to undo retirement benefit reforms passed in the 2011-2012 budget.  Those changes improved the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/06/understanding-the-2025-state-budget-pension-fight/"&gt;Understanding the 2025 state budget pension fight&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 18:12:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Kathy Hochul’s ambition cancels out claims of coming ‘climate disaster’</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/kathy-hochuls-ambition-cancels-out-claims-of-coming-climate-disaster/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New York politicians are extremely worried about the threat of global climate change. Their only bigger worry is that the....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/kathy-hochuls-ambition-cancels-out-claims-of-coming-climate-disaster/"&gt;Kathy Hochul’s ambition cancels out claims of coming ‘climate disaster’&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 18:51:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] WILL Statement on Wisconsin Supreme Court Rejecting Partisan Efforts to Redraw Congressional Maps</title><link>https://will-law.org/will-statement-on-wisconsin-supreme-court-rejecting-partisan-efforts-to-redraw-congressional-maps/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The News: The Wisconsin Supreme Court today declined to hear challenges seeking to redraw the state’s current congressional district maps, effectively ensuring the maps will remain in place for the 2026 midterm elections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/will-statement-on-wisconsin-supreme-court-rejecting-partisan-efforts-to-redraw-congressional-maps/"&gt;WILL Statement on Wisconsin Supreme Court Rejecting Partisan Efforts to Redraw Congressional Maps&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 23:25:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cardinalinstitute] Colleges Must Educate for Freedom</title><link>https://cardinalinstitute.com/colleges-must-educate-for-freedom/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Colleges Must Educate for Freedom A great American college or university will prepare students for self-governance as both a wise human being and a prudent, productive citizen. Rightly understood, the liberal arts are the intellectual potentials shared by the leaders of a free people. That is, education policy should consider, first of all, how to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com/colleges-must-educate-for-freedom/"&gt;Colleges Must Educate for Freedom&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com"&gt;Cardinal Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 16:31:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Education Freedom: A Lifeline for Tennessee Families</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/education-freedom-a-lifeline-for-tennessee-families/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=education-freedom-a-lifeline-for-tennessee-families</link><description>Education Freedom Scholarships won’t just change where kids go to school. They’ll change who they become.</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 18:15:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Group II pension compromise allows, but limits, pension spiking</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/06/group-ii-pension-compromise-allows-but-limits-pension-spiking/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Legislative leaders and Gov. Kelly Ayotte worked out a compromise on Group II pension benefits on Wednesday, the day before the House and Senate were scheduled to vote on the budget the governor had threatened to veto over those benefits. The late deal settles six main points of disagreement, including one of the big disputes [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/06/group-ii-pension-compromise-allows-but-limits-pension-spiking/"&gt;Group II pension compromise allows, but limits, pension spiking&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 19:15:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Taxpayers getting jobbed</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/taxpayers-getting-jobbed-northern-wisconsin-job-corps/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A federal judge’s injunction is blocking the closing down Job Corps centers — including two in Wisconsin — that have an expensive and dismal record ostensibly training the young and disadvantaged for work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/taxpayers-getting-jobbed-northern-wisconsin-job-corps/"&gt;Taxpayers getting jobbed&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 20:21:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] The Slippery Slope of Market Intervention: Why Louisiana Must Choose Economic Freedom</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/legal-regulatory/the-slippery-slope-of-market-intervention-why-louisiana-must-choose-economic-freedom/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Louisiana Legislature just wrapped up its regular session, and while lawmakers accomplished much good work, a troubling pattern emerged that should concern anyone who believes in economic opportunity and free markets. Louisiana faces a choice: Will we transform into a state where families and entrepreneurs can flourish, or will we remain the big-government populist...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/legal-regulatory/the-slippery-slope-of-market-intervention-why-louisiana-must-choose-economic-freedom/"&gt;The Slippery Slope of Market Intervention: Why Louisiana Must Choose Economic Freedom&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 20:23:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Arkansaspolicyfoundation] MEDICAL CARE IDEAS ADVANCE</title><link>https://arkansaspolicyfoundation.org/medical-care-ideas-advance/</link><description>(2025-2Q) The Arkansas Policy Foundation was founded by business leaders to serve the community and advance ideas to create more prosperity for Arkansans. The Policy Foundation was founded 30 years ago as a 501(c)(3) nonprofit, nonpartisan think tank that publishes credible research, hosts forums to encourage citizenship and is cited in national and state news [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 06:09:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Mapping the Public Workforce: State Government Employment Trends in 2024</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/blog/usdatalabs/mapping-the-public-workforce-state-government-employment-trends-in-2024/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;During the COVID-19 pandemic, state and federal policy sought to stabilize the economy and job market. Today we still see the effects on public employment, where some states have experienced recovery at differing rates.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/blog/usdatalabs/mapping-the-public-workforce-state-government-employment-trends-in-2024/"&gt;Mapping the Public Workforce: State Government Employment Trends in 2024&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 14:09:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] Paul sits down with Vance Ginn for “Let People Prosper” podcast</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/paul-sits-down-with-vance-ginn-for-let-people-prosper-podcast/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Why does New Mexico, rich in resources and culture, remain poor in economic freedom? That’s the question I explore in this week’s Let People Prosper Show with Paul Gessing, president of the Rio Grande Foundation. Paul brings nearly two decades of insight into New Mexico’s political and economic trends, offering a sobering look at why the state is falling behind and [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/paul-sits-down-with-vance-ginn-for-let-people-prosper-podcast/"&gt;Paul sits down with Vance Ginn for &amp;#8220;Let People Prosper&amp;#8221; podcast&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 17:59:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Frontierinstitute] Recent Permitting Reforms Are Protecting Property Rights</title><link>https://frontierinstitute.org/recent-permitting-reforms-are-protecting-property-rights/</link><description>"What property rights are unequivocally not, however, is a license to control what others do with their own property."</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 18:27:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] WILL Reacts to SCOTUS Parental Rights Ruling</title><link>https://will-law.org/will-reacts-to-scotus-parental-rights-ruling/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL released a statement praising the U.S. Supreme Court’s (SCOTUS) 6–3 ruling in Mahmoud v. Taylor—a landmark parental rights case that confirms parents’ ability to challenge school curricula and potentially other school policies and practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/will-reacts-to-scotus-parental-rights-ruling/"&gt;WILL Reacts to SCOTUS Parental Rights Ruling&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 21:56:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Job Licensing Reviews: Business and Labor Committee and General Affairs Committee</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/job-licensing-reviews-business-general-affairs-and-labor-committee-and-general-affairs-committee/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;[Note: This is the second in a group of articles reviewing occupational licensing reviews for the first five-plus years of the Occupational Board Reform Act. For more context, see this post.] The Business and Labor Committee has reviewed a number of licenses from 2019 to 2024. Their areas of review included: Boiler Safety/Pressure Vessel Inspectors...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/job-licensing-reviews-business-general-affairs-and-labor-committee-and-general-affairs-committee/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Job Licensing Reviews: Business and Labor Committee and General Affairs Committee&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 13:19:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Candidate Policy Briefing – Wichita | K-12 Finance</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/cpb-2025-wichita-k12-finance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 14:38:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG’s Work Bridging the Political Divide and Digging into the Impact of the Immigration Crisis in Wisconsin Named as Finalists for National Awards</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irgs-work-bridging-the-political-divide-and-digging-into-the-impact-of-the-immigration-crisis-in-wisconsin-named-as-finalists-for-national-awards/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;IRG’s Work Bridging the Political Divide and Digging into the Impact of the Immigration Crisis in Wisconsin Named as Finalists for National Awards  State Policy Network Recognizes IRG as a finalist for the Bob Williams Award for Most Influential Research and Innovation in Marketing Delafield, Wis. – The State Policy Network (SPN) nominated the Institute [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irgs-work-bridging-the-political-divide-and-digging-into-the-impact-of-the-immigration-crisis-in-wisconsin-named-as-finalists-for-national-awards/"&gt;IRG’s Work Bridging the Political Divide and Digging into the Impact of the Immigration Crisis in Wisconsin Named as Finalists for National Awards&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 17:41:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/06/the-outstater-276/</link><description>Meet the New IEDC Board (Yawn) A FRIEND, a former submarine commander now a troubleshooter for a regional manufacturer, shared a management technique: Cancel the company picnic. Please, stick with me; this will explain why Gov. Mike Braun missed a golden eco-devo opportunity. My friend’s experience told him that nobody coming&amp;#160;to his office to complain would be&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/06/the-outstater-276/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 18:22:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] Shapiro, House Democrats Miss the Budget Deadline Again, With No Deal in Sight</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/06/30/shapiro-house-democrats-miss-the-budget-deadline-again-with-no-deal-in-sight/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Harrisburg, Pa., June 30, 2025 —Today marks the end of Pennsylvania’s fiscal year and the deadline for lawmakers to pass the FY 2025–26 state budget, with no apparent deal in sight. Pennsylvania stares down yet another budget impasse under Gov. Josh Shapiro, his third in as many years. In this year’s proposed budget, Democratic leaders [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/06/30/shapiro-house-democrats-miss-the-budget-deadline-again-with-no-deal-in-sight/"&gt;Shapiro, House Democrats Miss the Budget Deadline Again, With No Deal in Sight&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 20:15:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] A better way to get welfare recipients back into the labor force</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/better-way-to-get-welfare-recipients-back-into-labor-force/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;If the One Big Beautiful Bill becomes law, states will quickly discover that their administrative systems are ill-equipped to move recipients from welfare to work. To succeed, states should adopt a more integrated approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/better-way-to-get-welfare-recipients-back-into-labor-force/"&gt;A better way to get welfare recipients back into the labor force&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 07:20:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] 2025 City Freedom Index: How Free is Your City?</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/2025-city-freedom-index/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=2025-city-freedom-index</link><description>In 2020, Beacon released its first-ever City Freedom Index to shed light on the ways taxpayers are impacted by local government policies. Five years and many changed local policies later, the time has come for an update.</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 11:30:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Sutherlandinstitute] Does government spend too much money on higher ed? | Josh Bandoch</title><link>https://sutherlandinstitute.org/does-government-spend-too-much-money-on-higher-ed-josh-bandoch/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Is college still the best path to a good job? We explore how career-first education and apprenticeships can better meet today’s workforce needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://sutherlandinstitute.org/does-government-spend-too-much-money-on-higher-ed-josh-bandoch/"&gt;Does government spend too much money on higher ed? | Josh Bandoch&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://sutherlandinstitute.org"&gt;Sutherland Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 13:17:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] WATCH: Megan Martin on PCN Discussing State Budget, Mass Transit Bail-out, and More</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/07/01/watch-megan-martin-on-pcn-discussing-state-budget-mass-transit-bail-out-and-more/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Megan Martin, Commonwealth Foundation&amp;#8217;s Chief Operating Officer and General Counsel, joins PCN&amp;#8217;s Capitol Preview to talk all things state budget. From public transit to Lifeline Scholarships, Martin outlines what good looks like in this year&amp;#8217;s budget, and which proposals will damage Pennsylvania&amp;#8217;s economic future. Watch below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/07/01/watch-megan-martin-on-pcn-discussing-state-budget-mass-transit-bail-out-and-more/"&gt;WATCH: Megan Martin on PCN Discussing State Budget, Mass Transit Bail-out, and More&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 13:27:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] PRESS RELEASE: ONNJ DEBUTS NEW PUBLIC AFFAIRS SERIES: “ENERGY MATTERS”</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/07/press-release-onnj-debuts-new-public-affairs-series-energy-matters/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 17:49:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] BINJE: Energy Matters with Jeanette Hoffman launches today on ONNJ</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/07/binje-energy-matters-with-jeanette-hoffman-launches-today-on-onnj/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 17:56:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] How both sides lost the ConVal school funding case</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/07/how-both-sides-lost-the-conval-school-funding-case/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday morning, the New Hampshire Supreme Court for the first time ordered the state to spend a minimum amount of money—$7.356.01 per pupil—to educate public school students.  The state therefore lost this landmark school funding case, Contoocook Valley School District v. State, as it had tried to avoid such a decree. But a closer [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/07/how-both-sides-lost-the-conval-school-funding-case/"&gt;How both sides lost the ConVal school funding case&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 17:57:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Cascade Quarterly Spring 2025</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/newsletters/cascade-quarterly-spring-2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Download the full PDF here&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/newsletters/cascade-quarterly-spring-2025/"&gt;Cascade Quarterly Spring 2025&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:59:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Sutherlandinstitute] We need a “PostBS” civics – starting in elementary and middle school</title><link>https://sutherlandinstitute.org/we-need-a-postbs-civics/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;To build lasting democratic habits, we must begin teaching civics in elementary school – through age-appropriate lessons, daily modeling, and real-life engagement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://sutherlandinstitute.org/we-need-a-postbs-civics/"&gt;We need a “PostBS” civics – starting in elementary and middle school&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://sutherlandinstitute.org"&gt;Sutherland Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 12:48:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Education officials top the 2024 KPERS ‘millionaires’ list</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/2024-kpers-millionaires/</link><description>Data provided by the Kansas Public Employees Retirement System shows that Kansas has 4,758 KPERS ‘millionaires’—state and local government retirees who will collect at least $1 million in pension benefits over their first 20 years of retirement. That is an increase of 380 over last year. The complete list of KPERS ‘millionaires’ can be found at KansasOpenGov.org. [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 13:25:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] AI Regulation’s State-by-State Chaos Shows the Need for Federal Leadership</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/ai-regulations-state-by-state-chaos-shows-the-need-for-federal-leadership/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Dr. Edward Longe and Taylor Barkley The fierce opposition to federal artificial intelligence preemption tells us everything we...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/ai-regulations-state-by-state-chaos-shows-the-need-for-federal-leadership/"&gt;AI Regulation’s State-by-State Chaos Shows the Need for Federal Leadership&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 13:36:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Truth on Trial: Relativism in the Classroom</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/blog/truth-on-trial-relativism-in-the-classroom/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As Steven Wilson argues in his new book, The Lost Decade: Returning to the Fight for Better Schools in America, “central to a liberal education is the pursuit of truth, however elusive.” Indeed, the quest for truth, and knowledge of it, is enshrined in the slogans of most universities, including my own—the University of Chicago—as a reminder of our purpose. It seems absurd to suggest otherwise, to propose educating students in anything but rationality, logic, and ultimately, truth; but absurdity has taken hold in education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/blog/truth-on-trial-relativism-in-the-classroom/"&gt;Truth on Trial: Relativism in the Classroom&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 13:45:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Tallahassee Democrat: Restoring the Citizens’ Voice in Florida’s Citizen’s Initiative Process</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/restoring-the-citizens-voice-in-floridas-citizens-initiative-process/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As a lifelong Floridian who cares deeply about the future of our state, I was pleased to see...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/restoring-the-citizens-voice-in-floridas-citizens-initiative-process/"&gt;Tallahassee Democrat: Restoring the Citizens’ Voice in Florida’s Citizen’s Initiative Process&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 13:47:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Voters Aren’t Interested in New Transportation Taxes</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/transportation/voters-arent-interested-in-new-transportation-taxes/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By John A. Charles, Jr. The Oregon legislature ended on June 27 without...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/transportation/voters-arent-interested-in-new-transportation-taxes/"&gt;Voters Aren’t Interested in New Transportation Taxes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 14:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Press Release: Mississippi Center for Public Policy Named Finalist for National Bob Williams Award</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/press-release-mississippi-center-for-public-policy-named-finalist-for-national-bob-williams-award/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE (Jackson, MS) Mississippi Center for Public Policy Named Finalist for National Bob Williams Award The Mississippi Center for Public Policy (MCPP) has been selected as a finalist for the prestigious Bob Williams Award for Outstanding Policy Achievement in the “Biggest Home State Win” category. This national recognition, awarded by the State Policy [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/press-release-mississippi-center-for-public-policy-named-finalist-for-national-bob-williams-award/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Press Release: Mississippi Center for Public Policy Named Finalist for National Bob Williams Award&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 15:02:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Stanford’s Pulitzer Winner Jack Rakove on American Independence</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/stanfords-pulitzer-winner-jack-rakove-on-american-independence/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In this week’s episode of The Learning Curve, co-hosts Alisha Searcy and Massachusetts civics teacher Kelley Brown interview Pulitzer Prize-winning historian Jack Rakove, Coe Professor Emeritus at Stanford University. Prof. Rakove explores the origins of the American Revolution and U.S. Constitution through the lives of the nation’s Founding Era figures. Reflecting on young John Adams’ vivid depiction of his schoolhouse in colonial Massachusetts, Rakove offers context for the political and social landscape of the 18th-century America.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/stanfords-pulitzer-winner-jack-rakove-on-american-independence/"&gt;Stanford&amp;#8217;s Pulitzer Winner Jack Rakove on American Independence&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 15:25:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Listen: RCV Expansion Recalled from Gov. Mills’ Desk</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/listen-rcv-expansion-recalled-from-gov-mills-desk/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Policy analyst, Harris Van Pate, joined the George Hale Ric Tyler Show on WVOM to discuss the Legislature&amp;#8217;s decision to recall LD 1666 from Gov. Mills&amp;#8217; desk. Maine Policy immediately called on Mills to veto the bill after its passage due to its unconstitutionality, and according to press reports, the bill was pulled off her [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/listen-rcv-expansion-recalled-from-gov-mills-desk/"&gt;Listen: RCV Expansion Recalled from Gov. Mills&amp;#8217; Desk&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 16:09:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Closing the Gap: How Wisconsin’s Budget Continues to Close the Funding Gap Between Public &amp; Parental Choice Options</title><link>https://will-law.org/closing-the-gap-how-wisconsins-budget-continues-to-close-the-funding-gap-between-public-parental-choice-options/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Like any budget that is a result of compromise in divided government, there are positive and negative aspects.  But one definite positive to come from this year's budget agreement is the continued closing of the spending gap between private, charter, and traditional public schools.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/closing-the-gap-how-wisconsins-budget-continues-to-close-the-funding-gap-between-public-parental-choice-options/"&gt;Closing the Gap: How Wisconsin’s Budget Continues to Close the Funding Gap Between Public &amp;#038; Parental Choice Options&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 18:57:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Highlights From the 2025 Florida Tech and Innovation Summit</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/highlights-from-the-2025-florida-tech-and-innovation-summit/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On Thursday, June 26, 2025, thought leaders from across the country joined The James Madison Institute in Coral...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/highlights-from-the-2025-florida-tech-and-innovation-summit/"&gt;Highlights From the 2025 Florida Tech and Innovation Summit&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 19:15:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] Trenton Just Made It Harder to Do Business in New Jersey</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/07/trenton-just-made-it-harder-to-do-business-in-new-jersey/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Andy Mulvihill, NJPI Board Chairman  New Jersey isn’t known for being an easy place to build or invest—but somehow, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/07/trenton-just-made-it-harder-to-do-business-in-new-jersey/"&gt;Trenton Just Made It Harder to Do Business in New Jersey&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 19:16:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] This Independence Day, Let’s Reject European-Style Regulation</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/this-independence-day-lets-reject-european-style-regulation/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;249 years ago, when the Declaration of Independence was signed, our founding fathers committed to writing the singular virtues of the new nation. Unlike Europe, the United States rejected the premise that a dictate from above could supplant the will of the people. This Independence Day is an opportunity to remember the freedoms that make...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/this-independence-day-lets-reject-european-style-regulation/"&gt;This Independence Day, Let’s Reject European-Style Regulation&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 13:26:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] DOJ sues Minnesota over college tuition for illegals. Will Minnesota Follow Texas?</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/doj-sues-minnesota-over-college-tuition-for-illegals-will-minnesota-follow-texas/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Within hours of a federal lawsuit targeting Texas’ policy of letting its nearly 20,000 undocumented students qualify for lower public tuition rates, the 24-year-old law was no more. Now, the DoJ is suing Minnesota over college tuition for illegal immigrants. Will Minnesota follows Texas? We won&amp;#8217;t hold our breath. &amp;#8212; Department of Justice sues Minnesota [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/doj-sues-minnesota-over-college-tuition-for-illegals-will-minnesota-follow-texas/"&gt;DOJ sues Minnesota over college tuition for illegals. Will Minnesota Follow Texas?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 13:55:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] Court Watch: Karofsky Court Leans Into Partisan Rhetoric In Abortion Decision</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/court-watch-karofsky-court-leans-into-partisan-rhetoric-in-abortion-decision/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Court Watch: Karofsky Court Leans Into Partisan Rhetoric In Abortion Decision Court uses rarely used doctrine to achieve preferred policy outcome Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government (IRG) released the following statement following the Wisconsin Supreme Court’s ruling in Josh Kaul v. Joel Urmanski. The majority’s decision utilized implied repeal to strike down [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/court-watch-karofsky-court-leans-into-partisan-rhetoric-in-abortion-decision/"&gt;Court Watch: Karofsky Court Leans Into Partisan Rhetoric In Abortion Decision&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 15:53:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Celebrating Leadership: Peggy Nguyen earns Woman of Distinction Award</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/california/celebrating-leadership-peggy-nguyen-earns-woman-of-distinction-award/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This year, we’re proud to share that our very own freedom fighter, Peggy Nguyen (no relation), was among the recipients of this award.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/california/celebrating-leadership-peggy-nguyen-earns-woman-of-distinction-award/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Celebrating Leadership: Peggy Nguyen earns Woman of Distinction Award&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 16:32:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Nation’s most liberal, union-beholden congressman wants out</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/pennsylvania/nations-most-liberal-union-beholden-congressman-wants-out/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;After representing Philadelphia, our nation's birthplace, in Congress for the past decade, Congressman Dwight Evans announced that he will not seek re-election. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/pennsylvania/nations-most-liberal-union-beholden-congressman-wants-out/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Nation’s most liberal, union-beholden congressman wants out&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 17:40:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Wisconsin’s retirement income exclusion will shift tax burdens to working families over time</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/wisconsins-retirement-income-exclusion-will-shift-tax-burdens-to-working-families-over-time/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Wisconsin’s expanded retirement income exclusion will undermine the tax code’s neutrality and shift burdens onto working families over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/wisconsins-retirement-income-exclusion-will-shift-tax-burdens-to-working-families-over-time/"&gt;Wisconsin’s retirement income exclusion will shift tax burdens to working families over time&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 18:46:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Welfare stands in the way of the American dream</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/welfare-stands-in-the-way-of-the-american-dream/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Meaningful relationships and a strong sense of community are as much a part of the American dream as any economic measure. What’s rarely discussed is how systemic obstacles are undermining these important aspects of a flourishing life. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/welfare-stands-in-the-way-of-the-american-dream/"&gt;Welfare stands in the way of the American dream&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 18:55:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] The truth about MPS, who makes it to graduation and who doesn’t</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/the-truth-about-mps-who-makes-it-to-graduation-and-who-doesnt/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The big picture: For every kid who enters MPS as a freshman each fall and goes on post-secondary education, there are at least two who do not, at least not in the year after high school ended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/the-truth-about-mps-who-makes-it-to-graduation-and-who-doesnt/"&gt;The truth about MPS, who makes it to graduation and who doesn’t &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 19:04:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] OBBB Delivers Historic Expansion of Educational Choice, Sweeping Reforms</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/07/03/obbb-delivers-historic-expansion-of-educational-choice-sweeping-reforms/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Harrisburg, Pa., July 3, 2025 —&amp;#160;After much anticipation and debate, the One Big, Beautiful Bill (OBBB) is now passed and set to be enacted—delivering policy accomplishments that Pennsylvanians can celebrate: Protecting Taxpayers: Preventing an average $2,500 tax hike per Pennsylvania taxpayer. Nearly every Pennsylvanian has benefited from the 2017 Tax Cuts and Job Act, which [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/07/03/obbb-delivers-historic-expansion-of-educational-choice-sweeping-reforms/"&gt;OBBB Delivers Historic Expansion of Educational Choice, Sweeping Reforms&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 19:17:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Are we witnessing a Baltimore Miracle in the fight against crime?</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/baltimore-miracle-in-fight-against-crime/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Baltimore has struggled with crime, especially drugs and violent crime, in both reality and in the imaginations of the American people for decades. That is, until recently. What changed and what can other high-crime cities learn from Baltimore's approach? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/baltimore-miracle-in-fight-against-crime/"&gt;Are we witnessing a Baltimore Miracle in the fight against crime?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 19:33:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] Tipping Point NM episode 722 Daniel Chavez – Candidate for Mayor of Albuquerque</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/tipping-point-nm-episode-722-daniel-chavez-candidate-for-mayor-of-albuquerque/</link><description>&lt;p&gt; Albuquerque Mayoral candidate Daniel Chavez has completed the Rio Grande Foundation&amp;#8217;s candidate survey.  You can find that completed survey here and below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/tipping-point-nm-episode-722-daniel-chavez-candidate-for-mayor-of-albuquerque/"&gt;Tipping Point NM episode 722 Daniel Chavez – Candidate for Mayor of Albuquerque&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 19:38:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Winners &amp; Losers: Spain’s Winning Bet on America—Trump Still Up, Democrats Down</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/winners-losers-spains-winning-bet-on-america-trump-still-up-democrats-down/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This Fourth of July weekend we will celebrate the 249th anniversary of the signing of the Declaration of Independence with fireworks and all the usual fanfare. As Texans, we should also take a moment to celebrate Spain’s big win in 1776, picking the American side in the war with England. Everyone knows France played a...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/winners-losers-spains-winning-bet-on-america-trump-still-up-democrats-down/"&gt;Winners &amp; Losers: Spain’s Winning Bet on America—Trump Still Up, Democrats Down&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 20:19:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/07/the-outstater-277/</link><description>We&amp;#8217;re All Greta Thunberg Now SOME OF US&amp;#160;no longer&amp;#160;pay&amp;#160;attention to opinion surveys. We assume, politics and media being what they are, that the public is too ill-informed to have anything useful to say. One recent poll, though, begs analysis. It&amp;#160;finds that a good majority of&amp;#160;young Americans&amp;#160;are not proud to be Americans. Now, it is wise&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/07/the-outstater-277/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 21:53:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] How Washington’s Budget Bill Will Affect Health Care in New York</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/how-washingtons-budget-bill-will-affect/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: The final version of the federal budget bill omitted a handful of provisions that had been included in earlier....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/how-washingtons-budget-bill-will-affect/"&gt;How Washington&amp;#8217;s Budget Bill Will Affect Health Care in New York&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 23:24:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] The Promise Of The Fourth of July</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/the-promise-of-the-fourth-of-july/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Every year on the Fourth of July, we gather under the banner of celebration—barbecues, parades, fireworks, and the familiar ritual..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/the-promise-of-the-fourth-of-july/"&gt;The Promise Of The Fourth of July&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 00:16:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] July Fourth reminder: Freedom should include your choice of doctor</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/07/july-fourth-reminder-freedom-should-include-your-choice-of-doctor/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Fourth of July is just around the corner, and for many of us, it’s an occasion to reflect on the many freedoms that we have — or don’t have, as the case may be. When it comes to healthcare in Hawaii, it is clear there is room for more freedom. Imagine, for example, that [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/07/july-fourth-reminder-freedom-should-include-your-choice-of-doctor/"&gt;July Fourth reminder: Freedom should include your choice of doctor&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 01:02:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Budget Challenges are the Symptom—The Real Problem Is Mission Creep</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/budget-challenges-are-the-symptom-the-real-problem-is-mission-creep/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Local government is not the heart of a community—it’s the tool that protects the space for community to thrive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Municipal finance expert Mark Moses argued that local governments face ongoing budget stress because their missions are too vague and expansive, leading to unchecked growth in programs and spending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cities and counties should return to a limited, clearly defined role focused on core functions like public safety, infrastructure, and legal order—not economic development schemes or nonessential amenities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elected officials must reframe local policy debates by asking what government should do, not just how it operates, and prioritize protecting individual liberty over expanding government reach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/budget-challenges-are-the-symptom-the-real-problem-is-mission-creep/"&gt;Budget Challenges are the Symptom—The Real Problem Is Mission Creep&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] What Is the Independence Day, and Why Do We Celebrate It?</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/what-is-the-independence-day-and-why-do-we-celebrate-it/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As we gather for picnics, parades, and fireworks, here’s a refreshing primer on what our Independence Day in America is all about. What Is Independence Day, and Why Do We Celebrate It? By Kelly Kuehn Reader&amp;#8217;s Digest What is the 4th of July? Here&amp;#8217;s your complete guide to the 4th of July and why we [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/what-is-the-independence-day-and-why-do-we-celebrate-it/"&gt;What Is the Independence Day, and Why Do We Celebrate It?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 13:15:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] The "Big Beautiful Bill": What It Means for Idaho</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/the-big-beautiful-bill-what-it-means-for-idaho/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/the-big-beautiful-bill-what-it-means-for-idaho/" rel="nofollow" title="The &amp;quot;Big Beautiful Bill&amp;quot;: What It Means for Idaho"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Article-Headers-2025-07-04T121803.006.png" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Normally, we at the Idaho Freedom Foundation (IFF) don’t weigh in on federal legislation that does not directly impact Idaho. However, any massive Congressional omnibus bill with tax and spending provisions is bound to impact Idahoans. We would like to bring to the attention of our readers a few key points for consideration. And perhaps [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 19:04:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Norman Rockwell</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/norman-rockwell/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/norman-rockwell/" rel="nofollow" title="Norman Rockwell"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="580" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Prop-1-Exposed-2-27.png" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;In celebration of our national heritage, we continue our Pride in America series by honoring Norman Rockwell, an artist whose work didn't just illustrate America, but helped define its soul. For decades, his captivating images on the covers of the Saturday Evening Post chronicled the idealized spirit of American life, capturing moments of everyday joy, [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 22:01:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Week in Review: The Fourth of July Promise</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-the-fourth-of-july-promise/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Every year on the Fourth of July, we gather under the banner of celebration—barbecues, parades, fireworks, and the familiar ritual..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-the-fourth-of-july-promise/"&gt;Week in Review: The Fourth of July Promise&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2025 00:04:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Andrew Jackson</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/andrew-jackson/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/andrew-jackson/" rel="nofollow" title="Andrew Jackson"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="580" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Prop-1-Exposed-2-28.png" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;In celebration of our national heritage, we finish our Pride in America series by honoring a duelist, frontiersman, populist, war hero, statesman, and patriot: Andrew Jackson.  Well before Jackson ascended to the Presidency, he earned renown as one of the nation’s first military heroes. During the War of 1812, Jackson rallied a force of several [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2025 00:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Can you hear the cell phone taxes now?</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/can-you-hear-the-cell-phone-taxes-now-1</link><description>Add outrageous cell phone taxes to the major financial difference between living in states like Idaho and Montana, versus Washington state.</description><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2025 22:03:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] Grace-Marie Turner, RIP</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/grace-marie-turner-rip/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Please join us in mourning the loss of a great American leader. Our free-market movement lost a great one recently and a friend, Michael F. Cannon of the CATO Institute, published a terrific tribute to this gracious and talented scholar: Grace-Marie Turner. We join many, many others who mourn her passing five weeks ago from [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/grace-marie-turner-rip/"&gt;Grace-Marie Turner, RIP&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2025 13:30:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] Franke: Population Worries</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/07/franke-population-worries/</link><description>by Mark Franke During the 50 plus years of my adult lifetime, world population has been an issue but with a change in perspective. In the 1960s the concern was uncontrolled and unsupportable growth especially in the poorer parts of the globe. The doomsayers predicted mass starvation and other unpleasant outcomes unless the rate of&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/07/franke-population-worries/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2025 22:06:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Why I think the governor and Legislature deserve praise</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/07/why-i-think-the-governor-and-legislature-deserve-praise/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;If you’re wondering why I’ve tended to praise Gov. Josh Green and Hawaii legislators in recent years, it’s because I’ve had no choice. They keep passing bills aimed at alleviating Hawaii’s housing shortage, allowing more healthcare freedom and limiting government overreach. Just this week, Gov. Green&amp;#160;signed: &amp;#62;&amp;#62;&amp;#160;SB66, which allows building permits to be approved automatically [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/07/why-i-think-the-governor-and-legislature-deserve-praise/"&gt;Why I think the governor and Legislature deserve praise&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 08:20:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Michigan underperforms on new worker mobility ranking</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/michigan-underperforms-on-new-worker-mobility-ranking</link><description>Without freedom to work, there is no pursuit of happiness</description><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] We have filed the case that could overturn Wickard and limit Commerce Clause powers</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/we-have-filed-the-case-that-could-overturn-wickard-and-limit-commerce-clause-powers/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Roscoe Filburn owned a wheat farm in rural Montgomery County, Ohio. When he used his own farm to feed his own family, he fell under the hammer of the federal government. It was 1938, and America was in the throes of the Great Depression and the Dust Bowl. Agricultural commodity prices—and specifically, wheat prices—fluctuated wildly,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/we-have-filed-the-case-that-could-overturn-wickard-and-limit-commerce-clause-powers/"&gt;We have filed the case that could overturn Wickard and limit Commerce Clause powers&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 11:08:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] America is Worth Seeing and Celebrating; Route 66 is a Great Place to Start</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/america-is-worth-seeing-and-celebrating-route-66-is-a-great-place-to-start/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;People don’t visit Route 66 to change America; they come to be changed by it. Janice Mollet doesn’t know how many people come through the restored Valentine Diner at the National Route 66 Museum in Elk City, Oklahoma. But her friend and fellow museum volunteer Sharon Brown pointed to a box of hundreds of push pins sitting...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/america-is-worth-seeing-and-celebrating-route-66-is-a-great-place-to-start/"&gt;America is Worth Seeing and Celebrating; Route 66 is a Great Place to Start&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 11:18:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Schools After the Storm with Noah Devine</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/education/schools-after-the-storm-with-noah-devine/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Susan Pendergrass speaks with Noah Devine, executive director of the Missouri Charter Public Schools Association, about how charter schools in [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/education/schools-after-the-storm-with-noah-devine/"&gt;Schools After the Storm with Noah Devine&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 11:55:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] New school finance formula should focus on accountability</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/new-school-finance-accountability/</link><description>Funding for public K-12 education is complex—let alone increasing every year. The formula for determining how much money each district receives– available here – requires an Excel workbook with 12 individual spreadsheets. The main spreadsheet, Legalmax, is essentially a roll-up of the other 11. It takes 85 columns of data to determine the Legalmax and [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 14:00:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Massive tobacco tax hike will hurt poorest Mainers, fuel black markets</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/massive-tobacco-tax-hike-will-hurt-poorest-mainers-fuel-black-markets/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Democrats on the Appropriations and Financial Affairs Committee voted to raise the tobacco tax by $1.50 this session, surpassing Gov. Janet Mills’ proposed $1.00 increase. This boosts the tax of cigarettes and other nicotine products from $2.00 to $3.50. This change was adopted as part of Democrats’ “Part 2” budget, which was approved along party [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/massive-tobacco-tax-hike-will-hurt-poorest-mainers-fuel-black-markets/"&gt;Massive tobacco tax hike will hurt poorest Mainers, fuel black markets&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 14:39:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Louisiana public schools showing some gains; do families still need choice?</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/education/louisianas-public-schools-showing-some-gains-do-families-still-need-choice/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For the past several months, state K-12 education officials have touted Louisiana’s climb to 32nd in the nation, as measured by the National Assessment of Educational Progress (NAEP). And rightly so—let’s give credit where credit is due. For the past decade, the Louisiana Department of Education (LDOE) and the State Board of Elementary and Secondary...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/education/louisianas-public-schools-showing-some-gains-do-families-still-need-choice/"&gt;Louisiana public schools showing some gains; do families still need choice?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 16:59:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] A Game-Changer for School Choice in Our State!</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/a-game-changer-for-school-choice-in-our-state/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Some groundbreaking news for Mississippi!&amp;#160; With the passage of the&amp;#160;One Big Beautiful Bill, a federal tax credit is due to transform the school choice landscape in our state. &amp;#160;This new tax credit enables individual donors to fund scholarships for local Mississippi families, who will now be able to select the schools that best suit their [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/a-game-changer-for-school-choice-in-our-state/" rel="nofollow"&gt;A Game-Changer for School Choice in Our State!&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 17:57:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Let’s get real about the Medicaid reform in the “Big Beautiful Bill”</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/let-s-get-real-about-the-medicaid-reform-in-the-big-beautiful-bill</link><description>President Trump recently signed H.R.1, aka the " One Big Beautiful Bill Act ," into law. The basis of the bill is an extension of the...</description><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 20:44:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] The Lonely Prophet No More: Samuel Francis and American Conservatism</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/the-lonely-prophet-no-more-samuel-francis-and-american-conservatism/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On January 20, 2016, Rush Limbaugh quoted  from an essay, “From Household to Nation” published in Chronicles magazine in 1996. “[S]ooner or later, as the globalist elites seek to drag the country into conflicts and global commitments, preside over the economic pastoralization of the United States, manage the delegitimization of our own culture, and the dispossession of our people, and disregard or diminish our national interests and national sovereignty, a nationalist reaction is almost inevitable and will probably assume populist form when it arrives.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/the-lonely-prophet-no-more-samuel-francis-and-american-conservatism/"&gt;The Lonely Prophet No More: Samuel Francis and American Conservatism&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 21:40:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Maui Council doing right thing to support ‘by right’ ‘food truck bill</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/07/maui-council-doing-right-thing-to-support-by-right-food-truck-bill/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following commentary by Ahryanna McGuirk was first published on July 3, 2025, by The Maui News under the headline “Food truck bill would right a wrong for Maui farmers.”_____________ It has been part of Maui’s Countywide Policy Plan for years that local lawmakers “support opportunities for local merchants, farmers and small businesses to sell [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/07/maui-council-doing-right-thing-to-support-by-right-food-truck-bill/"&gt;Maui Council doing right thing to support &amp;#8216;by right&amp;#8217; &amp;#8216;food truck bill&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 22:03:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Dr. Ed Amos – A First Hand Acccount of the Southern California Wildfires and Recovery</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/dr-ed-amos-a-first-hand-acccount-of-the-southern-california-wildfires-and-recovery/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This week, we talk with Dr. Ed Amos, noted physician and neurologist who tragically lost his home in the Pacific Palisades wildfires. He shares his first hand experience on the day of, and the immediate aftermath, of the wildfires, and offers a close-up view of just how effective government at all levels has done in [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/dr-ed-amos-a-first-hand-acccount-of-the-southern-california-wildfires-and-recovery/"&gt;Dr. Ed Amos &amp;#8211; A First Hand Acccount of the Southern California Wildfires and Recovery&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 01:16:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] The Gordon Chang Report–In China’s ‘Intriguing Period,’ Xi Jinping Could Be Deposed</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/the-gordon-chang-report-in-chinas-intriguing-period-xi-jinping-could-be-deposed/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;READ THE PDF In China’s ‘Intriguing Period,’ Xi Jinping Could Be Deposed Xi Jinping, often called China’s “all-powerful” leader, has recently lost substantial influence over the Chinese regime. Some analysts even believe that in the next few months Xi will be formally removed from his three positions: Communist Party general secretary, chairman of the Party’s [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/the-gordon-chang-report-in-chinas-intriguing-period-xi-jinping-could-be-deposed/"&gt;The Gordon Chang Report–In China’s ‘Intriguing Period,’ Xi Jinping Could Be Deposed&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 09:23:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Claims about Medicaid work requirements ignore facts, fuel fear</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/claims-about-medicaid-work-requirements-ignore-facts-fuel-fear</link><description>Here’s the truth about Medicaid numbers from Wayne County</description><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 09:59:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Maine, like New Hampshire, Should Kick Vehicle Inspections to the Curb</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/maine-like-new-hampshire-should-kick-vehicle-inspections-to-the-curb/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New Hampshire lawmakers recently voted to eliminate mandatory vehicle inspections starting in January 2026. The provision served as a major bargaining chip in the state’s latest budget, which was signed into law by Gov. Kelly Ayotte in late June. Since 1930, Mainers have been forced to have annual safety inspections performed on their cars as [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/maine-like-new-hampshire-should-kick-vehicle-inspections-to-the-curb/"&gt;Maine, like New Hampshire, Should Kick Vehicle Inspections to the Curb&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] 97 NYSLRS Retirees Eligible for Pensions Over $200K in FY2025</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/97-nyslrs-retirees-eligible-for-pensions-over-200k-in-fy2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A total of 97 retirees from the New York State and Local Retirement System (NYSLRS) were eligible for pensions of....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/97-nyslrs-retirees-eligible-for-pensions-over-200k-in-fy2025/"&gt;97 NYSLRS Retirees Eligible for Pensions Over $200K in FY2025&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 13:50:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Sutherlandinstitute] Are men turning away from college? | Mike Kofoed and Melinda Brock</title><link>https://s35049.pcdn.co/are-men-turning-away-from-college/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;College has long been seen as a gateway to opportunity and upward mobility. But today, fewer young men are pursuing higher education, accounting for just two out of every five degrees in the U.S. – a reversal of trends seen a generation ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://sutherlandinstitute.org/are-men-turning-away-from-college/"&gt;Are men turning away from college? | Mike Kofoed and Melinda Brock&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://sutherlandinstitute.org"&gt;Sutherland Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 13:57:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] Court Watch: Wisconsin Supreme Court Concentrates Even More Power in the Evers Administration</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/court-watch-wisconsin-supreme-court-concentrates-even-more-power-in-the-evers-administration/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Court Watch: Wisconsin Supreme Court Concentrates Even More Power in the Evers Administration Ruling in Evers v. Marklein takes away ability of legislature’s JCRAR Committee to suspend administrative rules Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government (IRG) released the following statement following the Wisconsin Supreme Court’s ruling in Evers v. Marklein. The majority’s decision [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/court-watch-wisconsin-supreme-court-concentrates-even-more-power-in-the-evers-administration/"&gt;Court Watch: Wisconsin Supreme Court Concentrates Even More Power in the Evers Administration&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 15:03:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Important details released for Idaho's new education choice tax credit</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/details-on-how-to-apply-for-idaho-s-school-choice-parental-choice-tax-credit</link><description>Parents, you won't want to miss these details from the Idaho State Tax Commission. The full implementation of HB 93 (school choice tax...</description><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 15:36:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] California’s First Fourth of July</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/californias-first-fourth-of-july/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=californias-first-fourth-of-july</link><description>&lt;p&gt;California’s first Fourth of July was celebrated in the rugged hills of present-day San Bernardino, when the region was still under Mexican rule. On that day in 1842, Daniel Sexton, a Louisiana-born carpenter and early American settler, raised an American flag and celebrated Independence Day with an unlikely group: Native Americans of the local Cahuilla...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/californias-first-fourth-of-july/"&gt;California’s First Fourth of July&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 16:04:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] SCOTUS Delivers Big Wins for Freedom</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/scotus-delivers-big-wins/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=scotus-delivers-big-wins</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This Independence Day, parents across America are celebrating freedom — thanks to three big wins out of the U.S. Supreme Court. Last week, the Court’s ruling in Mahmoud v. Taylor was a decisive victory for parental rights. The High Court made it clear: parents cannot be sidelined in their child’s education. In a 6–3 decision, the Court upheld the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/scotus-delivers-big-wins/"&gt;SCOTUS Delivers Big Wins for Freedom&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 16:22:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Saving America’s Family Farms: A Rural Revival</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/saving-americas-family-farms-a-rural-revival/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;States like Nebraska – and my native Wisconsin – face one of the biggest challenges, and public policy opportunities, you are likely to find in America.  Our family farms in rural areas across the country have been disappearing at the staggering rate of 45,000 per year on average for the past century. The incredible thing...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/saving-americas-family-farms-a-rural-revival/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Saving America’s Family Farms: A Rural Revival&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 16:54:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Frontierinstitute] Montana Leading with Free Market Healthcare</title><link>https://frontierinstitute.org/montana-leading-with-free-market-healthcare/</link><description>By eliminating the middlemen and bureaucracy involved in billing third parties, DPC providers are able to save patients money and focus on their health while also being radically transparent with their prices – a breath of fresh air in today’s modern healthcare world.</description><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 18:26:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Walz Wants Four More?!</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/walz-wants-four-more/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome back to the American Experiment Podcast! In our 83rd episode, Kathryn and Grace are joined by American Experiment President John Hinderaker. The three address rumors that Governor Tim Walz is planning to run for a third term—and he seems… pretty confident. Next, a University of Minnesota professor “hopes you seek to dismantle the United...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/walz-wants-four-more/"&gt;Walz Wants Four More?!&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 19:42:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Big Beautiful Break for wind and solar? Not quite, says Trump EO</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/big-beautiful-break-for-wind-and-solar-not-quite-says-trump-eo/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The One Big Beautiful Bill Act passed into law on July 4, 2025. With it came sharp rollbacks of some Inflation Reduction Act tax credits but not others. There have been a number of myths circulating about the law, including that it will harm reliability and raise electricity prices, including in Minnesota. Paige Lambermont, Research...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/big-beautiful-break-for-wind-and-solar-not-quite-says-trump-eo/"&gt;Big Beautiful Break for wind and solar? Not quite, says Trump EO&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 20:21:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Understanding the One Big Beautiful Bill with Elias Tsapelas</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/economy/understanding-the-one-big-beautiful-bill-with-elias-tsapelas/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Susan Pendergrass is joined by Elias Tsapelas, director of state budget and fiscal policy at the Show-Me Institute, to break [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/economy/understanding-the-one-big-beautiful-bill-with-elias-tsapelas/"&gt;Understanding the One Big Beautiful Bill with Elias Tsapelas&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 20:57:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Back to Mexico</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/back-to-mexico/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Abymahel Torres-Arriaga, age 36, appears to be on his way back to his native Veracruz, Mexico, after pleading guilty this afternoon in federal court in downtown Minneapolis. Your correspondent was there. Mr. Torres pled guilty to one count of re-entry of a removed alien, a felony. To restate: Mr. Torres was convicted today on a...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/back-to-mexico/"&gt;Back to Mexico&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 21:26:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] WASHINGTON: Second opt-out window another opportunity for union treachery</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/washington-second-opt-out-window-another-opportunity-for-union-treachery/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This spring, Washington’s Outreach team launched a brand-new opt-out campaign intended to inform government union members about a second opt-out window that only opens when a labor contract expires.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/washington-second-opt-out-window-another-opportunity-for-union-treachery/" rel="nofollow"&gt;WASHINGTON: Second opt-out window another opportunity for union treachery&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 21:38:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Orange County’s $649 million Trolley to Nowhere</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/orange-countys-649-million-trolley-to-nowhere/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=orange-countys-649-million-trolley-to-nowhere</link><description>&lt;p&gt;California’s bullet-train may be the state’s most high-profile transportation money-sink, consuming a projected $135 billion with no clear path to the finish line. However, taxpayers shouldn’t overlook the other transit boondoggles torching public funds. Chief among them is Orange County’s 4.15-mile OC Streetcar: proof that you can pour high-speed-rail-style money into a monument to tunnel...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/orange-countys-649-million-trolley-to-nowhere/"&gt;Orange County’s $649 million Trolley to Nowhere&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 21:58:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Why Third Grade Reading Matters More Than You Think</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/why-third-grade-reading-matters-more-than-you-think/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;1 out of every 3 Iowa third graders cannot read at grade level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learning to read is one of the most important milestones in a child’s education. But if a child hasn’t learned to read by the end of third grade, they’re likely to struggle throughout the rest of their school years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s because starting in fourth grade, the focus of education shifts. Instead of learning how to read, students are expected to read in order to learn. Textbooks, assignments, and tests all assume that students can understand written information. Without strong reading skills by this stage, students begin to fall behind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/why-third-grade-reading-matters-more-than-you-think/"&gt;Why Third Grade Reading Matters More Than You Think&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 22:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Vallas: It was a bad weekend, but Chicago’s violent crime rate falling</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/vallas-it-was-a-bad-weekend-but-chicagos-violent-crime-rate-falling/</link><description>A violent Independence Day weekend has Chicagoans worried about violent crime, but it was a spike and not a trend. Crime is falling, thanks to new law enforcement efforts.</description><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 22:11:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] 16 missed chances for state lawmakers to help out Illinoisans</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/16-missed-chances-for-state-lawmakers-to-help-out-illinoisans/</link><description>Out of almost 7,000 bills filed, the Illinois General Assembly passed a little over 400. Some were good. Some were bad. Here are 16 bills that would have improved life in the state had they passed.</description><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 22:16:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] 37 states wouldn’t let Pritzker run for 3rd term in 2026</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/37-states-wouldnt-let-pritzker-run-for-3rd-term-in-2026/</link><description>Illinois Gov. J.B. Pritzker is running for a third term in 2026. In two-thirds of the states, term-limit laws would prevent him from running.</description><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 22:22:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Congress, Not the President, Sets Taxes—Including Tariffs</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/congress-not-the-president-sets-taxes-including-tariffs/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Goldwater Institute along with the Dallas Market Center—a private business in Texas—filed a friend of the court brief today..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/congress-not-the-president-sets-taxes-including-tariffs/"&gt;Congress, Not the President, Sets Taxes—Including Tariffs&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 23:21:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] What’s in a NAEP Score?</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/performance/whats-in-a-naep-score/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The National Assessment of Educational Progress (NAEP), often called the Nation’s Report Card, is the gold standard for measuring academic [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/performance/whats-in-a-naep-score/"&gt;What’s in a NAEP Score?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 00:46:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Dr. Keri Ingraham: Industry-Specific High Schools</title><link>https://empowerms.org/dr-keri-ingraham-industry-specific-high-schools/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;﻿ Dr. Keri Ingraham: Industry-Specific High Schools Join us on the Empower Podcast as we dive into the transformative world of industry-specific high schools with Dr. Keri Ingraham, whose recent policy brief at the American Enterprise Institute, “The Case for Industry-Specific High Schools,” is sparking conversation. In this episode, Dr. Ingraham explains why these specialized&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/dr-keri-ingraham-industry-specific-high-schools/"&gt;Dr. Keri Ingraham: Industry-Specific High Schools&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 01:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Border czar claps back at socialist NYC mayoral candidate</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/border-czar-claps-back-at-socialist-nyc-mayoral-candidate/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Meghan Blonder writes for the Washington Free Beacon about the federal border czar’s response to recent comments from New York City’s leading mayoral candidate. Border czar Tom Homan offered a four-word response to New York City mayoral frontrunner Zohran Mamdani’s vow to undermine ICE&amp;#8217;s operations: &amp;#8220;Good luck on that.&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;We’re going to be in New...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/border-czar-claps-back-at-socialist-nyc-mayoral-candidate/"&gt;Border czar claps back at socialist NYC mayoral candidate&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 09:36:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Democrats turn Texas floods into campaign prop</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/democrats-turn-texas-floods-into-campaign-prop/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;M.D. Kittle uses a Federalist column to label certain Democrats “despicable.” The worst of times has often brought out the best in Americans. But not always.  As the death toll in the Independence Day Weekend’s Texas Hill Country floods topped 100 people on Monday, Democrats played politics with devastation. The flailing party, which seems to...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/democrats-turn-texas-floods-into-campaign-prop/"&gt;Democrats turn Texas floods into campaign prop&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 09:39:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Nobody is above the law … unless she helps leftists</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/nobody-is-above-the-law-unless-she-helps-leftists/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;David Manney writes for PJMedia.com about a clear example of leftist hypocrisy. Like neon lights in the fog, five words we&amp;#8217;ve seen and heard everywhere, along with the self-righteous posts: &amp;#8220;Nobody is above the law!&amp;#8221; We heard those five words more than we heard &amp;#8220;Good morning&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;Have a nice day.&amp;#8221;  They echoed from tote...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/nobody-is-above-the-law-unless-she-helps-leftists/"&gt;Nobody is above the law … unless she helps leftists&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 09:42:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Mackinac ferry regulatory expansion is bad policy</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/mackinac-ferry-regulatory-expansion-is-bad-policy</link><description>Proposed bill repeats past transportation regulation mistakes</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] How’s That ‘Accelerated’ Fire Rebuild Going?</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/hows-that-accelerated-fire-rebuild-going/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The toll from the wildfires is staggering: More than 18,000 structures were burned, 53 square miles were incinerated, 30, maybe more, people were killed, a couple of hundred thousand were evacuated. For the latter, there are pieces to pick up. Some estimates say more than 11,000 homes were destroyed. Politicians, from Sacramento to the neighborhood [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/hows-that-accelerated-fire-rebuild-going/"&gt;How’s That ‘Accelerated’ Fire Rebuild Going?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 10:00:20 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>