<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>State-Policy Think-Tank Digest</title><link>https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml</link><description>Latest posts from free-market policy institutes across the U.S.</description><atom:link href="https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 23:07:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>[Cardinalinstitute] Healthcare in West Virginia</title><link>https://cardinalinstitute.com/healthcare-in-west-virginia/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Healthcare in West Virginia Healthcare policy is complicated. These resources make it understandable. If you are trying to make sense of West Virginia’s latest healthcare debates, you are not alone. PBM regulation, PEIA’s recurring funding crises, and Certificate of Need laws all affect what care costs, where it is available, and who has choices. We [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com/healthcare-in-west-virginia/"&gt;Healthcare in West Virginia&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com"&gt;Cardinal Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 15:44:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] If You Want Parent Power, Only HB2 Will Do</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/if-you-want-parent-power-only-hb2-will-do/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past few years, Mississippi lawmakers have passed some critical conservative reforms.&amp;#160;Last year, Mississippi became the first state in America to legislate to eliminate the income tax in 40 years.&amp;#160; In 2022, we implemented flat tax reform.&amp;#160; A few years before that, we passed important labor market reforms.&amp;#160; In 2024, we reformed school funding [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/if-you-want-parent-power-only-hb2-will-do/" rel="nofollow"&gt;If You Want Parent Power, Only HB2 Will Do&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 16:09:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Rifreedom] MEDIA RELEASE: Center Launches Petition Calling for Affordable Energy Policies</title><link>https://rifreedom.org/2026/01/media-release-center-launches-petition-calling-for-affordable-energy-policies/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Rhode Island Center for Freedom &amp;#038; Prosperity today announced that it has launched an online petition drive calling for policymakers to support a fundamental pivot away from our state's current energy strategy, which will lead to staggeringly high electricity prices and potentially dangerous blackouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org/2026/01/media-release-center-launches-petition-calling-for-affordable-energy-policies/"&gt;MEDIA RELEASE: Center Launches Petition Calling for Affordable Energy Policies&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org"&gt;RI Center for Freedom and Prosperity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 14:19:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] Day One, Energy First: Governor Mikie Sherrill’s Opening Strategy on Affordability</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/01/day-one-energy-first-governor-mikie-sherrills-opening-strategy-on-affordability/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Sean Barry, NJPI Jr. Fellow When Governor Mikie Sherrill was sworn in as New Jersey’s 57th governor, she did [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/01/day-one-energy-first-governor-mikie-sherrills-opening-strategy-on-affordability/"&gt;Day One, Energy First: Governor Mikie Sherrill’s Opening Strategy on Affordability&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 19:08:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] A New Governor Takes Office. Will She Deliver on Education?</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/01/a-new-governor-takes-office-will-she-deliver-on-education/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;by Aiden DeMarsey, NJPI Jr. Fellow &amp;#160; Governor Mikie Sherrill, sworn into office last week, enters her term with a [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/01/a-new-governor-takes-office-will-she-deliver-on-education/"&gt;A New Governor Takes Office. Will She Deliver on Education?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 19:10:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] New housing permits are highest since 2006, but single-family homes lag</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2026/01/new-housing-permits-are-highest-since-2006-but-single-family-homes-lag/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New Hampshire towns and cities are permitting more residential housing units than they have in years, which is great news. But the new units are skewed heavily toward rentals, suggesting that local restrictions on small, single-family homes remain a significant barrier. Local governments issued permits for 5,822 new housing units in 2024, the highest number [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2026/01/new-housing-permits-are-highest-since-2006-but-single-family-homes-lag/"&gt;New housing permits are highest since 2006, but single-family homes lag&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:16:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] The Denial of Distinctions</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/the-denial-of-distinctions/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Denial of Distinctions By Abe Greenwald Yesterday, I wrote about the return of American disorder in the form of mobs that obstruct ICE raids. Part of what makes anti-ICE/open-border activism so strange is that it attacks the most fundamental aspect of what it means to be a country: its physical boundaries. When leftists repeat, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/the-denial-of-distinctions/"&gt;The Denial of Distinctions&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:37:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Crime is down, and it should end ‘root cause’ excuse-making for good</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/crime-is-down-and-it-should-end-root-cause-excuse-making-for-good/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/crime-is-down-and-it-should-end-root-cause-excuse-making-for-good/"&gt;Crime is down, and it should end ‘root cause’ excuse-making for good&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 22:13:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Introducing TennSight, Tennessee’s only hub for voter insights</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/introducing-tennsight-tennessees-only-hub-for-voter-insights/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=introducing-tennsight-tennessees-only-hub-for-voter-insights</link><description>We hope that TennSight will become the go-to source for you to learn what matters most to your fellow Tennesseans, why it matters, and what can be done about it.</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 13:08:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Idaho schools paying $1.2 million per year for IEA/NEA dues</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/labor/idaho-schools-paying-1-2-million-per-year-for-iea-nea-dues/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;According to a new Freedom Foundation analysis, the Boise and Twin Falls School Districts are spending more than $1.2 million per year on programs to cover the cost of teachers union dues to the Idaho Education Association. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/labor/idaho-schools-paying-1-2-million-per-year-for-iea-nea-dues/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Idaho schools paying $1.2 million per year for IEA/NEA dues&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 17:33:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Beacon Poll: January 2026 Results</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/beacon-poll-january-2026-results/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=beacon-poll-january-2026-results</link><description>Today, we released the latest installment of the Beacon Poll, a statewide survey of 1,200 Tennessee voters featuring questions about voters’ views on property taxes, the federal school choice tax credit included in the One Big Beautiful Bill Act, and political approval ratings at the state and federal level, and more. Tennesseans continue to prioritize key...</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 19:35:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cardinalinstitute] Op-Ed: Hospitals Collect Tax Breaks. West Virginians Collect Medical Debt.</title><link>https://cardinalinstitute.com/op-ed-hospitals-collect-tax-breaks-west-virginians-collect-medical-debt/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;To many West Virginians, healthcare continues to be a burden more than a lifeline as roughly 180,000 residents, or 13.3% of adults, now facing some sort of  medical debt. This is well above the national average of 8.6% and, even worse, nearly one in four of these residents in rural Appalachia have medical debt in [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com/op-ed-hospitals-collect-tax-breaks-west-virginians-collect-medical-debt/"&gt;Op-Ed: Hospitals Collect Tax Breaks. West Virginians Collect Medical Debt.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com"&gt;Cardinal Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 15:16:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Why Portland’s Suggested Statewide Eviction Moratorium Would Hurt Maine’s Housing Market</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/why-portlands-suggested-statewide-eviction-moratorium-would-hurt-maines-housing-market/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Portland city officials are urging Gov. Janet Mills to impose a 60-day statewide eviction moratorium in response to “fear and instability” that they are linking to federal immigration enforcement. While the resolution is framed as an emergency measure that they are claiming is only meant to protect “vulnerable residents,” such a moratorium risks repeating a [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/why-portlands-suggested-statewide-eviction-moratorium-would-hurt-maines-housing-market/"&gt;Why Portland&amp;#8217;s Suggested Statewide Eviction Moratorium Would Hurt Maine’s Housing Market&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 16:38:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] Tim Pawlenty: The Crisis Will Subside in Minnesota, but Trust Will Need to be Rebuilt</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/tim-pawlenty-the-crisis-will-subside-in-minnesota-but-trust-will-need-to-be-rebuilt/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;We’ll all be part of that task. Here’s where efforts could be focused. By Tim Pawlenty For the Star Tribune It’s been said that trust is the glue that holds relationships together. That may well explain why recent events in Minnesota have stretched our relationship with government to the breaking point. Fraudsters stole a ton [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/tim-pawlenty-the-crisis-will-subside-in-minnesota-but-trust-will-need-to-be-rebuilt/"&gt;Tim Pawlenty: The Crisis Will Subside in Minnesota, but Trust Will Need to be Rebuilt&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 19:57:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] The Numbers Don’t Lie: The CHOOSE Act is Empowering Alabama’s Families</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2026/02/04/the-numbers-dont-lie-the-choose-act-is-empowering-alabamas-families/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For decades, the Alabama Policy Institute has championed a simple, powerful idea: every child in Alabama deserves a high-quality education, regardless of their zip code or their size of their parents’ bank account. With the passage and implementation of the CHOOSE Act, that vision is finally becoming a reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2026/02/04/the-numbers-dont-lie-the-choose-act-is-empowering-alabamas-families/"&gt;The Numbers Don’t Lie: The CHOOSE Act is Empowering Alabama’s Families&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 22:48:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] 312 Out of More than 3 Million Votes</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/312-out-of-more-than-3-million-votes/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Federal prosecutors are closing in on prosecuting more than 100 Minnesotans for rampant fraud in several social service programs designed to serve children and low-income residents. By the time the US Attorney’s office is done investigating, charging, convicting, and sentencing these felons, this unchecked fraud will significantly increase Minnesota’s prison population. But there’s one other [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/312-out-of-more-than-3-million-votes/"&gt;312 Out of More than 3 Million Votes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 13:58:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Record-breaking start to 2026: 6,000 employees opt out</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/record-breaking-start-to-2026-6000-employees-opt-out/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Freedom Foundation set an all-time record in January with 6,000 public employees opting out—topping our previous record by nearly 3,000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/record-breaking-start-to-2026-6000-employees-opt-out/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Record-breaking start to 2026: 6,000 employees opt out&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 18:57:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] A Badger Institute policy report: Character education and teacher retention</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/a-badger-institute-policy-report-character-education-and-teacher-retention/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Wisconsinites should be concerned the state's growing crisis of disappearing educators — a phenomenon the Badger Institute has been taking a closer look at. Multiple studies confirm that retaining good teachers is essential to school effectiveness and student achievement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/a-badger-institute-policy-report-character-education-and-teacher-retention/"&gt;A Badger Institute policy report: Character education and teacher retention&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 20:25:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Rifreedom] TESTIMONY: Senate Commission to Study the Successful Implementation of the Act on Climate</title><link>https://rifreedom.org/2026/02/senate-commission-act-on-climate/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In this powerful testimony, Mike Stenhouse, CEO of the RI Center for Freedom &amp;#038; Prosperity, explains why energy policy—not taxes, not housing, not government services—is the single most important determinant of Rhode Island’s future prosperity or poverty. Whether one believes in climate change or not, the economic consequences of the Act on Climate are unavoidable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org/2026/02/senate-commission-act-on-climate/"&gt;TESTIMONY: Senate Commission to Study the Successful Implementation of the Act on Climate&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org"&gt;RI Center for Freedom and Prosperity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 21:12:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] BERGEN RECORD: NJ climate superfund is a blank check with no accountability | Opinion</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/02/bergen-record-nj-climate-superfund-is-a-blank-check-with-no-accountability-opinion/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;#160; New Jersey’s Climate Superfund Is a Blank Check With No Accountability by Rosemary Becchi New Jersey lawmakers are considering [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2026/02/bergen-record-nj-climate-superfund-is-a-blank-check-with-no-accountability-opinion/"&gt;BERGEN RECORD: NJ climate superfund is a blank check with no accountability | Opinion&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 13:58:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Governor Mills’ Supplemental Budget Abandons Fiscal Discipline, Sets Maine Up for Higher Costs</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/governor-millss-supplemental-budget-abandons-fiscal-discipline-sets-maine-up-for-higher-costs/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Governor Janet Mills’ FY 2026 supplemental budget marks a clear break from the fiscal restraint her administration often claimed to practice. Rather than using Maine’s strong revenue growth to stabilize taxpayers after years of tax increases and inflation, the proposal dramatically expands spending, broadens emergency powers, and doubles down on distortionary tax policy choices that [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/governor-millss-supplemental-budget-abandons-fiscal-discipline-sets-maine-up-for-higher-costs/"&gt;Governor Mills’ Supplemental Budget Abandons Fiscal Discipline, Sets Maine Up for Higher Costs&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 17:22:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Affordability tops the list of state priorities for 2026</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/affordability-tops-the-list-of-state-priorities-for-2026/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/affordability-tops-the-list-of-state-priorities-for-2026/"&gt;Affordability tops the list of state priorities for 2026&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 21:36:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] 2026 Capitol Chat: Week 5</title><link>https://empowerms.org/2026-capitol-chat-week-5/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Capitol Chat: Week 5 Week 5 at the Capitol featured some of the most consequential policy and political moves yet. In this episode, we walk through some of the biggest developments, including shifts in the education debate, major House action, an update on the ballot initiative, and another big deadline on the horizon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/2026-capitol-chat-week-5/"&gt;2026 Capitol Chat: Week 5&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 22:11:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Ayotte: Maximize economic freedom, and New Hampshire will thrive</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2026/02/ayotte-maximize-economic-freedom-and-new-hampshire-will-thrive/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Gov. Kelly Ayotte’s 2026 State of the State address can be summed up in seven words: New Hampshire wins by competing on freedom. Leading with a list of eight No. 1 national rankings for the state—including economic freedom, economic opportunity and taxpayer return on investment—Ayotte noted that, overall, “U.S. News ranks us the #2 state [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2026/02/ayotte-maximize-economic-freedom-and-new-hampshire-will-thrive/"&gt;Ayotte: Maximize economic freedom, and New Hampshire will thrive&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 14:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] Alabama Senate unanimously passes App Store Accountability Act</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2026/02/09/alabama-senate-unanimously-passes-app-store-accountability-act/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The App Store Accountability Act passed the Alabama Senate with a unanimous vote on Feb. 5. The bill is focused on online safety for children and teens by requiring parental approval for kids to download apps from the App Store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2026/02/09/alabama-senate-unanimously-passes-app-store-accountability-act/"&gt;Alabama Senate unanimously passes App Store Accountability Act&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 23:47:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] Alabama Senate passes App Store age verification requirement</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2026/02/10/alabama-senate-passes-app-store-age-verification-requirement/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Lawmakers spoke before the Senate in favor of shielding minors from inappropriate content, requiring parental permission for account creation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2026/02/10/alabama-senate-passes-app-store-age-verification-requirement/"&gt;Alabama Senate passes App Store age verification requirement&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 02:12:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Hammond Calls for Restraint on Medicaid Spending</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/hammond-calls-for-restraint-on-medicaid-spending/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Albany, N.Y. — The state and its taxpayers cannot afford to allow Medicaid spending to keep growing at five times the....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/hammond-calls-for-restraint-on-medicaid-spending/"&gt;Hammond Calls for Restraint on Medicaid Spending&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 13:36:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Freedom Foundation Attorneys Secure Compensation from SEIU 099 for a Public-School Employee</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/litigation/freedom-foundation-attorneys-secure-compensation-from-seiu-099-for-a-public-school-employee/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Freedom Foundation attorneys have successfully freed California public school employee Keshawna Adams from SEIU 099’ unconstitutional dues deductions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/litigation/freedom-foundation-attorneys-secure-compensation-from-seiu-099-for-a-public-school-employee/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation Attorneys Secure Compensation from SEIU 099 for a Public-School Employee&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 17:52:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Strengthening families for generational change: GCO welcomes Travis Thorne to the team</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/welcoming-travis-thorne/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/welcoming-travis-thorne/"&gt;Strengthening families for generational change: GCO welcomes Travis Thorne to the team&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 14:26:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF talks to KOAT TV about roads</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-talks-to-koat-tv-about-roads/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;SB 2 has passed which means that the road issue has been &amp;#8220;put to bed&amp;#8221; for the time being. The bill which has been signed by the Gov. includes: $1.5 billion in new road spending via a bond (debt) package. This also includes: A 35% increase in the weight-distance tax on trucks A 25% increase [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-talks-to-koat-tv-about-roads/"&gt;RGF talks to KOAT TV about roads&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 16:09:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] California Forever Stagnating</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/california-forever-stagnating/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=california-forever-stagnating</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When Permission Replaces Property Rights, the California Dream Becomes a Dream Deferred For over a century, California stood as a frontier of first resort for the ambitious, attracting those eager to escape old-world constraints in exchange for a promise of radical autonomy. This California Dream was not a byproduct of luck; it was forged by...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/california-forever-stagnating/"&gt;California Forever Stagnating&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 01:05:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Domestic Outmigration is Hollowing Out Massachusetts’ Workforce and Economy</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/domestic-outmigration-is-hollowing-out-massachusetts-workforce-and-economy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;From April 2020 through July 2025, Massachusetts experienced a net loss of approximately 182,000 residents to domestic outmigration — the equivalent of losing one-and-a-half Cambridges. While a recent surge in international immigration temporarily boosted labor force numbers, new research from Pioneer Institute shows that underlying demographic, workforce, and economic challenges continue to threaten the Commonwealth’s long-term competitiveness. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/domestic-outmigration-is-hollowing-out-massachusetts-workforce-and-economy/"&gt;Domestic Outmigration is Hollowing Out Massachusetts’ Workforce and Economy &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 14:37:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Florida Politics: Florida’s A+ Plan To Help ‘Plan B’ Families</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/floridas-a-plan-to-help-plan-b-families/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;February 11, 2026 Lawmakers seek to expand private school classroom access It was a curious finding that seemed...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/floridas-a-plan-to-help-plan-b-families/"&gt;Florida Politics: Florida’s A+ Plan To Help ‘Plan B’ Families&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 14:47:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] The Wisconsin Higher-Ed Reform Model</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/the-wisconsin-higher-ed-reform-model/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Republican lawmakers managed to pass a conservative-coded policy in a purple state with a Democratic governor. It’s all well and good to point to Florida or Texas and wish that every state could do likewise. Unfortunately, not every state capitol boasts a conservative governor ready to pick controversial fights backed up by a large Republican majority. Wisconsin demonstrates that even purple states can win meaningful, albeit limited, conservative victories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/the-wisconsin-higher-ed-reform-model/"&gt;The Wisconsin Higher-Ed Reform Model&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 15:34:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Bipartisan electoral politics stand in the way of property tax relief</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/electoral-politics-property-tax-relief/</link><description>Kansas homeowners aren’t just facing higher property taxes — they’re facing unaffordable assessed valuation increases that make it impossible to budget for life essentials or stay in their homes. Property tax is the #1 affordability issue facing many Kansans, but nothing may be done about it – again – because electoral politics is the #1 [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 15:59:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] An Open Letter to Maine’s Legislature: Stop Advancing a Bill You Know is Unconstitutional</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/an-open-letter-to-maines-legislature-stop-advancing-a-bill-you-know-is-unconstitutional/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Last June, Maine Policy Institute urged Governor Janet Mills to veto LD 1666, a bill expanding ranked-choice voting (RCV) to elections for governor, state senator, and state representative. That request was grounded in clear constitutional text, the Maine Supreme Judicial Court’s 2017 advisory opinion, and Governor Mills’ own legal analysis as Attorney General. Since then, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/an-open-letter-to-maines-legislature-stop-advancing-a-bill-you-know-is-unconstitutional/"&gt;An Open Letter to Maine’s Legislature: Stop Advancing a Bill You Know is Unconstitutional&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 16:39:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Medicaid mission-creeps its way into the housing business</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/medicaid-mission-creeps-its-way-into-providing-homes-for-wisconsinites/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Very few people know it, but Wisconsin’s Medicaid program is in the housing business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not construction or real estate, but assistance in finding a home for any Medicaid recipient with a qualifying health or mental health issue and a qualifying risk of homelessness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/medicaid-mission-creeps-its-way-into-providing-homes-for-wisconsinites/"&gt;Medicaid mission-creeps its way into the housing business&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 17:31:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2026/02/the-outstater-327/</link><description>The Media: Prescience Matters &amp;#8220;A journalist needs a disciplined reverence for the facts, because the temptations of story-telling are strong and seductive.&amp;#8221; — Lance Morrow in &amp;#8220;The Noise of Typewriters&amp;#8221; A SCHOLAR OF OUR FOUNDATION&amp;#160;is an expert at framing questions, instructions and context for Artificial Intelligence (AI). He&amp;#160;and others are training a new profession, Prompt&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2026/02/the-outstater-327/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 18:20:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Louisiana’s Grid Gambit: Is It Time to Let Private Power Play?</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/energy/private-power-play/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Last month, the New Orleans City Council voted unanimously to impose a one-year moratorium on data center development across the city. The debate was heated and familiar: overwhelming concerns about the strain these facilities could place on an already vulnerable grid, the risk of compromised reliability during our next storm season, and the potential for higher electricity...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/energy/private-power-play/"&gt;Louisiana’s Grid Gambit: Is It Time to Let Private Power Play?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 18:45:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Texas Parents Break Records for School Choice Applications</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/education/texas-parents-break-records-for-school-choice-applications/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Kathryn Hickok At last count, more than one and a half million...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/education/texas-parents-break-records-for-school-choice-applications/"&gt;Texas Parents Break Records for School Choice Applications&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 19:45:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Metro’s Plan for Making Housing More Expensive</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/reports/metros-plan-for-making-housing-more-expensive/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Randal O’Toole High housing prices in the Portland area led to a&amp;#160;legislative...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/reports/metros-plan-for-making-housing-more-expensive/"&gt;Metro’s Plan for Making Housing More Expensive&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 20:18:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] Jake Curtis Joins the Benjamin Yount Show</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/jake-curtis-joins-the-benjamin-yount-show/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Listen to the interview here. https://youtu.be/sxbsni1kot4?si=EU3oINN-O1XkTNTN&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/jake-curtis-joins-the-benjamin-yount-show/"&gt;Jake Curtis Joins the Benjamin Yount Show&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 21:03:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG urges Wisconsin lawmakers to question DPI secrecy</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-urges-wisconsin-lawmakers-to-question-dpi-secrecy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;IRG urges Wisconsin lawmakers to question DPI secrecy (The Center Square) – It’s not just the nearly $400,000 expense that has one watchdog group wanting more from Wisconsin’s public school managers. The Institute for Reforming Government on Thursday said lawmakers in Madison need to question the secrecy around the Department of Public Instruction&amp;#8217;s 2024 meeting to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-urges-wisconsin-lawmakers-to-question-dpi-secrecy/"&gt;IRG urges Wisconsin lawmakers to question DPI secrecy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 21:08:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] California’s healthcare industrial complex is booming. Guess who’s paying?</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/californias-healthcare-industrial-complex-is-booming-guess-whos-paying/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=californias-healthcare-industrial-complex-is-booming-guess-whos-paying</link><description>&lt;p&gt;California’s hospitals recorded $11.3 billion in total net income in 2024 — 10% above pre-pandemic levels. The average hospital CEO in the state earns roughly $920,000 a year. And the largest union representing healthcare workers collected $114.5 million in dues in 2024 alone, according to its federal LM-2 filing — spending just 16 cents of...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/californias-healthcare-industrial-complex-is-booming-guess-whos-paying/"&gt;California’s healthcare industrial complex is booming. Guess who’s paying?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 03:28:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Shedding Light on Louisiana’s Boards and Commissions: Opportunities for Transparency, Accountability, and Reform</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/legal-regulatory/shedding-light-louisiana/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Louisiana’s occupational licensing boards get a lot of attention, and rightfully so. The state requires a permission slip from the government to work in 77 of 102 lower income occupations, making it the sixth worst state for occupational licensing burden in the U.S., according to the Institute for Justice. However, there are hundreds of boards...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/legal-regulatory/shedding-light-louisiana/"&gt;Shedding Light on Louisiana’s Boards and Commissions: Opportunities for Transparency, Accountability, and Reform&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 14:22:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Nebraska Shouldn’t Tax Social Media Accounts</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-shouldnt-tax-social-media-accounts/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Under LB 1025, Nebraska would implement a first-in-the-nation tax on social media accounts, at rates of up to $6 per account per year. Other states have considered similar taxes, but no state has adopted a social media tax to date, and with good reason. The proposed tax could deprive Nebraskans of free access to online...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-shouldnt-tax-social-media-accounts/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Nebraska Shouldn’t Tax Social Media Accounts&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 15:38:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] New York’s Electricity Prices Among the Highest in the Country</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/new-yorks-electricity-prices-among-the-highest-in-the-country/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Albany, NY — New York households continue to pay some of the highest electricity prices in the nation, according to data from....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/new-yorks-electricity-prices-among-the-highest-in-the-country/"&gt;New York’s Electricity Prices Among the Highest in the Country&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 16:54:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] 2026 Capitol Chat: Week 6</title><link>https://empowerms.org/2026-capitol-chat-week-6/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Capitol Chat: Week 6 From floor votes to a few “spirited” House measures, Week 6 had a little bit of everything. We break down the education bills still moving, the buzz around a recent voice vote, and what’s brewing as lawmakers eye the next big deadline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/2026-capitol-chat-week-6/"&gt;2026 Capitol Chat: Week 6&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 17:22:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Newsmax: CMS Should Be Embracing Fla.’s Medicaid Success Story</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/newsmax-cms-should-be-embracing-fla-s-medicaid-success-story/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A decade ago, as speaker of the Florida House of Representatives, I&amp;#160;led&amp;#160;the fight against Medicaid expansion under Obamacare....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/newsmax-cms-should-be-embracing-fla-s-medicaid-success-story/"&gt;Newsmax: CMS Should Be Embracing Fla.&amp;#8217;s Medicaid Success Story&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 17:33:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Portland’s “Affordable” Housing Averages $800 per Square Foot</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/land-use/portlands-affordable-housing-averages-800-per-square-foot/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Randal O’Toole Note: This post is a sequel to Metro’s Plan for...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/land-use/portlands-affordable-housing-averages-800-per-square-foot/"&gt;Portland’s “Affordable” Housing Averages $800 per Square Foot&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 17:46:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] School Budget Questions We Should Be Asking</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/school-budget-questions-we-should-be-asking/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="School Budget Questions We Should Be Asking" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/school-board.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;School boards control spending and every budget involves choices. While administrators draft proposals, boards hold the legal responsibility to set priorities. Claims that “we have no choice” should be questioned, because budgeting always involves tradeoffs in programs, staffing, compensation, benefits, and district structure. Spending decisions should be evaluated through a per-pupil and outcomes lens. Enrollment trends drive funding, making per-pupil spending a critical metric. Programs and projects—whether new buildings or tutoring initiatives—should be evaluated based on cost per student and measurable results. Long-term sustainability requires aligning staffing, compensation, facilities, and reserves with enrollment realities. Declining enrollment and rising benefit costs create financial pressure, making it essential to right-size operations, strategically reward effective educators, responsibly manage benefits, and use reserves for stability, not to delay difficult decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/school-budget-questions-we-should-be-asking/"&gt;School Budget Questions We Should Be Asking&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 17:47:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Redefine ‘farm dwelling’ to include employee housing structures</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/02/redefine-farm-dwelling-to-include-employee-housing-structures/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii on Feb. 12, 2026, for consideration by the Senate Committees on Agriculture and Environment and Housing._____________ Feb. 12, 2026, 1:05 p.m.Hawaii State CapitolConference Room 225 and Videoconference To: Senate Committee on Agriculture and Environment&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Sen. Mike Gabbard, Chair&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Sen. Herbert M. &amp;#8220;Tim&amp;#8221; Richards, III, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/02/redefine-farm-dwelling-to-include-employee-housing-structures/"&gt;Redefine &amp;#8216;farm dwelling&amp;#8217; to include employee housing structures&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 18:08:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Massive ‘carbon tax’ would reduce state’s total economic output</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/02/massive-carbon-tax-would-reduce-states-total-economic-output/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii on Feb. 12, 2026, for consideration by the House Committees on Energy &amp;#38; Environmental Protection and Agriculture &amp;#38; Food Systems._____________ Feb. 12, 2026, 10:20 a.m. &amp;#160;Hawaii State CapitolConference Room 325 and Videoconference To: House Committee on Energy &amp;#38; Environmental Protection&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Rep. Nicole E. Lowen, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/02/massive-carbon-tax-would-reduce-states-total-economic-output/"&gt;Massive &amp;#8216;carbon tax&amp;#8217; would reduce state&amp;#8217;s total economic output&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 18:12:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] Franke: Daylight Saving Folly</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2026/02/franke-daylight-saving-folly/</link><description>by Mark Frank “Time is the only scarce commodity.”&amp;#160;I heard this on a Viking commercial from company chairman Torstein Hagen. His point, I assume, is don’t put off things you have always wanted to do. Since Viking’s clientele is largely aging retirees, his advice is certainly well given. The problem with time is that it&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2026/02/franke-daylight-saving-folly/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 13:41:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Presidents’ Day: Two and a Half Centuries of Leadership—and the Limits That Sustain It</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/principles-of-liberty/presidents-day/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This year, Louisianans observe two holidays on the same day—celebrating Lundi Gras with their communities and Presidents’ Day with the rest of the nation. While the traditions and festivities of Carnival season should be enjoyed, the history and significance of Presidents’ Day should not be overlooked. Presidents’ Day was first established to honor the birthday...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/principles-of-liberty/presidents-day/"&gt;Presidents’ Day: Two and a Half Centuries of Leadership—and the Limits That Sustain It&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 14:12:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Statement of Jim Stergios, Executive Director of Pioneer Institute on Governor Healey’s Opposition to Lowering State Income Tax</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/statement-of-jim-stergios-executive-director-of-pioneer-institute-on-governor-healeys-opposition-to-lowering-state-income-tax/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On Friday, Governor Healey opposed a proposed cut in the personal income tax that would put an average of $1,300 back into people’s pockets. Her claim that it would devastate the budget and gut education is a wild distortion—and it ignores more...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/statement-of-jim-stergios-executive-director-of-pioneer-institute-on-governor-healeys-opposition-to-lowering-state-income-tax/"&gt;Statement of Jim Stergios, Executive Director of Pioneer Institute on Governor Healey’s Opposition to Lowering State Income Tax&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 14:12:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Rifreedom] Center Launches K-12 Student Video Contest to Celebrate America’s 250th Birthday #America250RI</title><link>https://rifreedom.org/2026/02/center-launches-k-12-student-video-contest-to-celebrate-americas-250th-birthday-america250ri/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In recognition of President's Day and George Washington's upcoming birthday, the  RI Center for Freedom &amp;#038; Prosperity today launched a video contest encouraging K-12 students to create a video about why they are proud to celebrate America's semiquincentennial, commemorating the 250th Anniversary of the US Declaration of Independence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org/2026/02/center-launches-k-12-student-video-contest-to-celebrate-americas-250th-birthday-america250ri/"&gt;Center Launches K-12 Student Video Contest to Celebrate America&amp;#8217;s 250th Birthday #America250RI&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org"&gt;RI Center for Freedom and Prosperity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 14:18:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Research Note: Updates in Regulatory Restraint</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/research-note-updates-in-regulatory-restraint/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In recent years, states across the country have taken renewed interest in reviewing longstanding and often outdated regulatory frameworks. Many legislatures are reassessing rules that may constrain economic growth, aiming to reduce regulatory accumulation and increase legislative oversight of unelected agencies. Although each state varies in its approach, a common goal has emerged: limiting high-cost...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/research-note-updates-in-regulatory-restraint/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Research Note: Updates in Regulatory Restraint&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 14:18:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] The Cost of an Unforgiving Compliance System</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/the-cost-of-an-unforgiving-compliance-system/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="The Cost of an Unforgiving Compliance System" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/bank.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is often labeled “de-banking” is largely the result of an outdated and rigid federal regulatory framework rooted in the 1970s Bank Secrecy Act that incentivizes banks to over-comply to avoid severe penalties. Political signaling by regulators, combined with strict confidentiality rules around Suspicious Activity Reports, leaves banks cautious and opaque, fueling public frustration and perceptions of ideological targeting. Meaningful reform must occur at the federal level by modernizing compliance standards and disclosure rules; state-by-state approaches risk creating confusion without fixing the underlying problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/the-cost-of-an-unforgiving-compliance-system/"&gt;The Cost of an Unforgiving Compliance System&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 15:08:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Economic Updates Suggest Kansas Can Lead</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/economic-updates-suggest-kansas-can-lead/</link><description>If you only look at Kansas’s unemployment rate, you might think everything is fine. That’s the political trap: point to a low number, declare victory, and move on.  But the latest state labor and economic output data show a more complicated truth. Kansas has real strengths, but it’s also leaving growth on the table because [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 19:15:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Virginiainstitute] Repealing Certificate of Need Laws: A Path to Affordable, Accessible Healthcare in Virginia</title><link>https://virginiainstitute.org/repealing-con/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=repealing-con</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The United States healthcare system faces a crisis of escalating costs, limited access, and stifled innovation. At the heart of these challenges lie outdated Certificate of Need (CON) laws—regulations rooted&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org/repealing-con/"&gt;Repealing Certificate of Need Laws: A Path to Affordable, Accessible Healthcare in Virginia&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org"&gt;Virginia Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 19:20:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Teachers’ Unions Get Desperate</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/article/education/teachers-unions-get-desperate/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;🎧 Listen to this article A recent editorial in the Wall Street Journal lays out what has been on the minds of many (or at least mine) for some time. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/article/education/teachers-unions-get-desperate/"&gt;Teachers’ Unions Get Desperate&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 22:42:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Lawmakers should reject sales tax holidays</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2026/lawmakers-should-reject-sales-tax-holidays</link><description>Exemptions for No. 2 pencils will not solve state’s economic crisis</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] A Roadmap for States to Build High-Quality Online Education</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/a-roadmap-for-states-to-build-high-quality-online-education/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;BOSTON – State policy is pivotal to the development and availability of online and virtual learning options, and Pioneer Institute’s new Virtual Schools Toolkit provides tactical guidance for developing such policies in the current educational landscape.   “Virtual learning began by serving students...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/a-roadmap-for-states-to-build-high-quality-online-education/"&gt;A Roadmap for States to Build High-Quality Online Education&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 13:32:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Lawmakers Across the Country Push Firm Limits on Property Taxes</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/lawmakers-across-the-country-push-firm-limits-on-property-taxes/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Lawmakers Across the Country Push Firm Limits on Property Taxes" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/us-spending-cap-states.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rising spending is driving rising property taxes. Lawmakers across the country are increasingly acknowledging that escalating local government spending — whether in schools, cities, or counties — is the root cause of higher property tax burdens. “Buying down” property taxes with state dollars has failed. Efforts in states like Vermont, Iowa, and Nebraska to offset property taxes with general fund revenue have often encouraged more local spending rather than delivering lasting tax relief. States are turning to spending caps. From Vermont and Kansas to Tennessee, Texas, and Iowa, policymakers are proposing spending and property tax caps, as structural reforms designed to impose discipline and provide sustainable relief.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/lawmakers-across-the-country-push-firm-limits-on-property-taxes/"&gt;Lawmakers Across the Country Push Firm Limits on Property Taxes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 13:58:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Y It Matters: Why Process Protects People</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/02/17/y-it-matters-why-process-protects-people/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="1024" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Connecticut-state-flag-in-the-breeze.png" width="1536" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Connecticut’s legislative session is underway, Yankee Institute will be deeply engaged at the Capitol — explaining which policies we support, which we oppose, and why. Throughout the year, our work focuses on one key objective: ensuring Connecticut is affordable, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/02/17/y-it-matters-why-process-protects-people/"&gt;Y It Matters: Why Process Protects People&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 14:54:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Florida Politics: Anastasios Kamoutsas Curbs Double Counting in K-12 Scholarships</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/florida-politics-anastasios-kamoutsas-curbs-double-counting-in-k-12-scholarships/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;February 16, 2026 Administrative fix delivers zero net cost to state Anastasios Kamoutsas&amp;#160;has been in his new job...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/florida-politics-anastasios-kamoutsas-curbs-double-counting-in-k-12-scholarships/"&gt;Florida Politics: Anastasios Kamoutsas Curbs Double Counting in K-12 Scholarships&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 15:26:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] WILL Supports Teacher Bill of Rights</title><link>https://will-law.org/will-supports-teacher-bill-of-rights/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;#038; Liberty (WILL) supports the Teacher Bill of Rights, AB 614 / SB 611, introduced by Representative Goeben and Senator Cabral-Guevara. The legislation clarifies and strengthens teachers’ authority to maintain order in the classroom, protects teachers from retaliation when they enforce classroom rules or respond to disruptive or violent behavior, and ensures transparency and accountability when serious behavior incidents occur at school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/will-supports-teacher-bill-of-rights/"&gt;WILL Supports Teacher Bill of Rights&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 15:48:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Legislators look at local zoning rules blocking education, child care &amp; home businesses</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2026/02/legislators-look-at-local-zoning-rules-blocking-education-child-care-home-businesses/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Local land use regulations do more than severely restrict the size, shape, design and placement of homes, creating scarcity and driving up prices. They also heavily regulate the activities that occur inside those homes. These regulations derive from legitimate local police powers. Local governments exist primarily for the purpose of keeping the peace, and Americans [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2026/02/legislators-look-at-local-zoning-rules-blocking-education-child-care-home-businesses/"&gt;Legislators look at local zoning rules blocking education, child care &amp;#038; home businesses&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 16:01:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cardinalinstitute] West Virginia’s hospital debate is missing a key piece of the financial picture</title><link>https://cardinalinstitute.com/west-virginias-hospital-debate-is-missing-a-key-piece-of-the-financial-picture/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;West Virginia’s hospital debate is missing a key piece of the financial picture Debates over hospital policy in West Virginia usually follow a familiar pattern. Hospital systems warn that their finances are weak. Industry groups say they have too many patients with government insurance. Certificate of Need (CON) rules are defended as needed to keep [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com/west-virginias-hospital-debate-is-missing-a-key-piece-of-the-financial-picture/"&gt;West Virginia’s hospital debate is missing a key piece of the financial picture&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com"&gt;Cardinal Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 16:10:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] The Lesson from Kansas—and the Question for Missouri</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/article/taxes/the-lesson-from-kansas-and-the-question-for-missouri/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;🎧 Listen to this article Dave Helling recently responded to my Show-Me Institute colleagues’ piece on what Missouri should learn from Kansas’s tax changes a decade ago. He questions whether [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/article/taxes/the-lesson-from-kansas-and-the-question-for-missouri/"&gt;The Lesson from Kansas—and the Question for Missouri&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 16:40:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Testimony in Opposition to SB 151</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/02/17/testimony-in-opposition-to-sb-151/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="630" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Testimonies-2026.jpg" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Chairs Senator Marx and Representative Felipe, Ranking Members Senator Sampson, and Representative Scott, and distinguished members of the Housing Committee.   Thank you for the opportunity to provide testimony on SB 151, An Act Prohibiting Certain Land [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/02/17/testimony-in-opposition-to-sb-151/"&gt;Testimony in Opposition to SB 151&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 16:43:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Amazon Fresh cuts 1,545 Illinois jobs in January</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/amazon-fresh-cuts-1545-illinois-jobs-in-january/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon laid off 1,545 Illinois employees. That was most of 2,000 total layoffs across the state in January.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/amazon-fresh-cuts-1545-illinois-jobs-in-january/"&gt;Amazon Fresh cuts 1,545 Illinois jobs in January&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 16:48:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] $50 Million Owed to Pinal Taxpayers: Will the Arizona Legislature Ensure Justice is Served?</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/pinal-taxes/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been four years since The Arizona Supreme Court sided with the Goldwater Institute and found that Pinal County illegally..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/pinal-taxes/"&gt;$50 Million Owed to Pinal Taxpayers: Will the Arizona Legislature Ensure Justice is Served?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 17:18:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Kansas City Reverses Costly Energy Code Legislation</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/article/economy/kansas-city-reverses-costly-energy-code-legislation/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Listen to this article It’s not often that there is good regulatory news out of Kansas City, but today there is. Recently, the city council passed Ordinance No. 260144, repealing [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/article/economy/kansas-city-reverses-costly-energy-code-legislation/"&gt;Kansas City Reverses Costly Energy Code Legislation&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 18:02:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] We Can’t Afford to Trim Your Trees, but We Can Hire Lobbyists</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/we-cant-afford-to-trim-your-trees-but-we-can-hire-lobbyists/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=we-cant-afford-to-trim-your-trees-but-we-can-hire-lobbyists</link><description>We’ve long called for reform to the practice of taxpayer-funded lobbying. But this NES response is probably the most glaring example of the need for reform.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 18:22:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] States should think twice before embracing single-payer</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/states-should-think-twice-before-embracing-single-payer/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Progressives are dreaming once again of a government takeover of the healthcare system. Locked out of power in Washington, they’re taking their fight for single-payer to blue states. This week, four New Yorkers took to the pages of the journal Health Affairs to make their case for how the Empire State can deliver universal coverage [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/states-should-think-twice-before-embracing-single-payer/"&gt;States should think twice before embracing single-payer&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 18:24:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Aaron Rice: Defending the Constitution in Uniform and in Court</title><link>https://empowerms.org/aaron-rice-defending-the-constitution-in-uniform-and-in-court/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Aaron Rice: Defending the Constitution in Uniform and in Court What does it look like to defend the Constitution with your life, and then keep defending it with your career? In this episode, Grant sits down with Aaron Rice, a Mississippi Marine and Purple Heart recipient who was wounded in Iraq and later became a&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/aaron-rice-defending-the-constitution-in-uniform-and-in-court/"&gt;Aaron Rice: Defending the Constitution in Uniform and in Court&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 19:52:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Michigan Lawmakers Introduce Housing Reform Bills</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/pressroom/2026/michigan-lawmakers-introduce-housing-reform-bills</link><description>Mackinac Center supports legislation aimed at easing regulations</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 20:03:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Dueling habeas and 57 lbs. of meth</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/dueling-habeas-and-57-lbs-of-meth/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Junior de Jesus Herrera Berrios, aged just 18, is a popular man. We have not one but two separate habeas corpus petitions seeking his release from ICE custody. First, some backstory. In 2022, Herrera, then-aged 15 and from Guatemala, crossed the U.S. border, apparently without any authorization. Fast forward to 2026, on January 5, Herrera...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/dueling-habeas-and-57-lbs-of-meth/"&gt;Dueling habeas and 57 lbs. of meth&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 20:52:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Mamdani Gets an Important Tax Fact Wrong</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/mamdani-gets-an-important-tax-fact-wrong/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;At a hearing in Albany last week, New York City Mayor Zohran Mamdani lobbied state lawmakers to help him balance....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/mamdani-gets-an-important-tax-fact-wrong/"&gt;Mamdani Gets an Important Tax Fact Wrong&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 20:58:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Reducing Red Tape: Advancing Economic Liberty and Accountability In Nebraska</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/reducing-red-tape-advancing-economic-liberty-and-accountability-in-nebraska/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The growing volume and complexity of government regulation at the state and local levels threaten economic freedom, entrepreneurial innovation, and democratic accountability. State regulations, often issued by unelected officials in executive agencies, accumulate over time, creating significant &amp;#8220;hidden taxes&amp;#8221; on small businesses and families within the state. This policy brief outlines a set of proven,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/reducing-red-tape-advancing-economic-liberty-and-accountability-in-nebraska/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Reducing Red Tape: Advancing Economic Liberty and Accountability In Nebraska&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 21:01:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Drop ‘Bigger Subsidies’ Narrative for Better Insurance Options</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/drop-bigger-subsidies-narrative-for-better-insurance-options/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The federal government is covering a smaller share of Obamacare enrollees&amp;#8217; premiums this year. That has Democrats warning of a surge in the number of uninsured, as people struggle to shoulder more of the cost themselves. But recent reporting on some of those losing their enhanced premium subsidies reveals that the federal dollars have merely [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/drop-bigger-subsidies-narrative-for-better-insurance-options/"&gt;Drop &amp;#8216;Bigger Subsidies&amp;#8217; Narrative for Better Insurance Options&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 22:07:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] 2025 data is in: Four straight years of unaffordable assessed valuation hikes. Where’s the relief?</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/four-straight-years-assessed-valuation-hikes/</link><description>Assessed valuation changes for 2025, released this morning, reiterate the need for a constitutional amendment to limit the increases. The average increase for existing residential property (not counting new construction) of 5.9% is more than double the inflation rate, and that’s not the worst of the story. Homeowners in a dozen counties had double-digit increases [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 22:51:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] More local food starts with housing</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/02/more-local-food-starts-with-housing/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When it comes to supporting agricultural production in Hawaii, there seems to be a big difference between rhetoric and reality. State and county officials frequently identify farming as the key to diversifying our economy and making our islands self-sufficient in food production. But what policies have they implemented that would make it easier for farmers [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2026/02/more-local-food-starts-with-housing/"&gt;More local food starts with housing&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 02:28:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Senate Bill 1301 — Licensed brewers, sales (+1)</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/senate-bill-1301-licensed-brewers-sales/</link><description>Bill Description:&amp;#160;Senate Bill 1301 would allow small breweries to have up to two remote retail locations rather than just one.&amp;#160; Rating: +1 Does it give government any new, additional, or expanded power to prohibit, restrict, or regulate activities in the free market? Conversely, does it eliminate or reduce government intervention in the market? Idaho law [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 04:43:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Senate Bill 1302 — Single countywide highway districts (+1)</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/senate-bill-1302-single-countywide-highway-districts/</link><description>Bill Description:&amp;#160;Senate Bill 1302 would require the Ada County Highway District to hold partisan primary elections starting in 2028. Rating: +1 NOTE: Senate Bill 1302 is similar to Senate Bill 1229 (2026) and House Bill 471 (2025); however, Senate Bill 1302 would delay the implementation of partisan primary elections until 2028. Does it in any way restrict public [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 04:48:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Newsom admits overseas that Trump is no existential threat</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/newsom-admits-overseas-that-trump-is-no-existential-threat/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Editors at Issues and Insights discuss interesting recent comments from California’s governor. No one has ever accused California Gov. Gavin Newsom of being consistent, or of having any actual principles, or of being much of an intellect, for that matter. Still, the fact that – while trying to bash a sitting president while in Munich...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/newsom-admits-overseas-that-trump-is-no-existential-threat/"&gt;Newsom admits overseas that Trump is no existential threat&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 10:42:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Setting the record straight on schools of choice</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2026/setting-the-record-straight-on-schools-of-choice</link><description>Residents’ concerns should not prevent expansion of highly successful program</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Price controls won’t save credit card borrowers</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/price-controls-wont-save-credit-card-borrowers/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Americans are drowning in credit card debt, but President Donald Trump’s suggestion to cap interest rates at 10% for one year is not a particularly good solution. On its face, it sounds great. Americans largely hate banks and Trump’s suggestion gives the Robinhoodish illusion of robbing the rich to give to the poor. Lowering a borrower’s interest [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/price-controls-wont-save-credit-card-borrowers/"&gt;Price controls won’t save credit card borrowers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 11:00:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Trump Administration Sides with WILL, Federal Scholarships Now Open to All Students in Need Regardless of Race</title><link>https://will-law.org/trump-administration-sides-with-will-federal-scholarships-now-open-to-all-needy-students-regardless-of-race/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/trump-administration-sides-with-will-federal-scholarships-now-open-to-all-needy-students-regardless-of-race/"&gt;Trump Administration Sides with WILL, Federal Scholarships Now Open to All Students in Need Regardless of Race&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 13:29:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Ready to celebrate America 250? Sign up for "We the Students" Civics Bowl</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/post/ready-to-celebrate-america-250-sign-up-for-we-the-students-civics-bowl</link><description>Civic education doesn’t belong to one type of school or region. It belongs to everyone. Our hope is that teams will come from across Idaho, Montana, Wyoming, and Eastern Washington, so students can meet peers from different communities, compete respectfully, and go home with a deeper appreciation for how our system works.</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 14:56:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2026/02/the-outstater-328/</link><description>History Matters, Ms. Ocasio-Cortez IT IS EASY to make fun of Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez (AOC) and her flubs. It is clear she doesn&amp;#8217;t  understand the dynamics that created America or her own heritage. But she is not alone. It would be surprising if there are 20 Indiana legislators who would fare better. Surveys of how little this generation understands of Western Civilization are so discouraging that&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2026/02/the-outstater-328/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 15:34:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] 79th Feeding Our Future defendant charged</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/79th-feeding-our-future-defendant-charged/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Fahima Egeh Mahamud became the 79th defendant charged in the sprawling Feeding Our Future fraud case, and the first to be charged in 2026. She is currently being held in the federal lockup at the Sherburne County jail. According to court filings in the case, Mahamud operated a food distribution site under the name Future...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/79th-feeding-our-future-defendant-charged/"&gt;79th Feeding Our Future defendant charged&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 15:46:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Goldwater Launches $300K Landmark American Civics Initiative</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/goldwater-launches-300k-landmark-american-civics-initiative/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;After nearly 40 years of fighting for freedom in courtrooms and capitols across the country, the Goldwater Institute is launching..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/goldwater-launches-300k-landmark-american-civics-initiative/"&gt;Goldwater Launches $300K Landmark American Civics Initiative&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 16:24:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] DFLers open legislative session with proposal to make Minnesota a sanctuary state</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/dflers-open-legislative-session-with-proposal-to-make-minnesota-a-sanctuary-state/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In my session preview on Monday, I wrote that &amp;#8220;the Republicans are leading with fraud&amp;#8221; while &amp;#8220;the DFL is prioritizing immigration.&amp;#8221; This was quickly born out. Yesterday, MinneapoliMedia reported on the launch of: &amp;#8230;the North Star Act (HF1100 / SF1181), a proposal backed by members of the Minnesota Democratic-Farmer-Labor Party that would prohibit state and local...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/dflers-open-legislative-session-with-proposal-to-make-minnesota-a-sanctuary-state/"&gt;DFLers open legislative session with proposal to make Minnesota a sanctuary state&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 16:39:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Fear Porn About AI Dominance Follows The Covid Tyrants’ Playbook</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/fear-porn-about-ai-dominance-follows-the-covid-tyrants-playbook/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I don’t know what the future of AI holds. But neither do any of the people using panic rhetoric to induce population-wide fear and dread. Reading Matt Shumer’s viral essay about artificial intelligence was like stepping back in time to roughly six years ago, when the world started going insane over Covid-19. It hits all the same...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/fear-porn-about-ai-dominance-follows-the-covid-tyrants-playbook/"&gt;Fear Porn About AI Dominance Follows The Covid Tyrants’ Playbook&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 16:58:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] More on birthright citizenship</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/more-on-the-birthright-citizenship-debate/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;About a year ago, in &amp;#8220;A guide to the birthright citizenship debate,&amp;#8221; I provided links to some of the best academic arguments on both sides. The current issue of the Harvard Journal of Law and Public Policy includes several more well-researched and well-reasoned arguments. I was particularly impressed by Gerard N. Magliocca&amp;#8217;s discussion of Blackstone&amp;#8217;s influence....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/more-on-the-birthright-citizenship-debate/"&gt;More on birthright citizenship&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 17:25:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] Government in the Shadows: Gov. Evers, AG Kaul, DPI and Other Officials Failing to Comply with Public Records Law</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/government-in-the-shadows-gov-evers-ag-kaul-dpi-and-other-officials-failing-to-comply-with-public-records-law/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Government in the Shadows: Gov. Evers, AG Kaul, DPI and Other Officials Failing to Comply with Public Records Law IRG has several outstanding requests that have been pending for months  Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government (IRG) has waited over eight months for records on DOJ immigration enforcement and the Evers Administration’s Office [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/government-in-the-shadows-gov-evers-ag-kaul-dpi-and-other-officials-failing-to-comply-with-public-records-law/"&gt;Government in the Shadows: Gov. Evers, AG Kaul, DPI and Other Officials Failing to Comply with Public Records Law&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 17:45:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Public sector workers’ rights would be strengthened under new Wyoming bill</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/post/public-sector-workers-rights-would-be-strengthened-under-new-wyoming-bill</link><description>While workers in Wyoming have the ability to opt out of union membership, requiring them to proactively send dues instead of having them automatically deducted from paychecks ensures that they want to belong without doubt.</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 18:54:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] New Certificate of Need Law – A Small Free Market Win</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/new-certificate-of-need-law-a-small-free-market-win/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A small win for freedom in Mississippi!&amp;#160; Governor Tate Reeves recently signed HB3, a law that reforms the state’s Certificate of Need (CON) rules.&amp;#160; CON is basically a government approval process healthcare providers (like hospitals) must go through before they can add certain services, build new facilities, buy expensive equipment, or make big expansions. HB3 [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/new-certificate-of-need-law-a-small-free-market-win/" rel="nofollow"&gt;New Certificate of Need Law – A Small Free Market Win&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 19:24:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] What Will California Gas Prices Do in 2026?</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/what-will-california-gas-prices-do-in-2026/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=what-will-california-gas-prices-do-in-2026</link><description>&lt;p&gt;About the time it became inevitable that California was going to lose two major refineries, in May of last year, an alarming study was released by Michael Mische, an economist and business professor at USC. In his analysis, “Ensuring California’s Gasoline Security for the 21st Century,” Mische made a prediction that was widely quoted: “Based on current...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/what-will-california-gas-prices-do-in-2026/"&gt;What Will California Gas Prices Do in 2026?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 19:43:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Goldwater Institute Defends Homes-Sharing in Arkansas Federal Court</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/goldwater-institute-defends-homes-sharing-in-arkansas-federal-court/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Goldwater Institute has filed a friend of the court brief in support of property owners who have gone to..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/goldwater-institute-defends-homes-sharing-in-arkansas-federal-court/"&gt;Goldwater Institute Defends Homes-Sharing in Arkansas Federal Court&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 19:55:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Connecticut’s Proposed Climate Superfund Would Centralize Authority — and Raise Cost Questions</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/02/18/connecticuts-proposed-climate-superfund-would-centralize-authority-and-raise-cost-questions/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="1024" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/ChatGPT-Image-Feb-18-2026-at-03_03_58-PM.png" width="1536" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Environment Committee will hold a public hearing on Feb. 20 regarding H.B. 5156, a proposal to create a new “climate superfund” requiring certain fossil-fuel companies to pay for climate-related [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2026/02/18/connecticuts-proposed-climate-superfund-would-centralize-authority-and-raise-cost-questions/"&gt;Connecticut’s Proposed Climate Superfund Would Centralize Authority — and Raise Cost Questions &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 20:06:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Illinois at near record-low union membership in 2025</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/illinois-at-near-record-low-union-membership-in-2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Just 13.1% of workers in Illinois were union members in 2025. Thousands of government workers have rejected union membership. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/illinois-at-near-record-low-union-membership-in-2025/"&gt;Illinois at near record-low union membership in 2025&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 20:13:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] The Grasping Hand of the Welfare State: Medicaid and Rural Health Transformation</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/the-grasping-hand-of-the-welfare-state-medicaid-and-rural-health-transformation/</link><description>The Idaho House recently passed House Concurrent Resolution 25, calling for an Article V Convention to propose a federal Balanced Budget Amendment (BBA). Legislators who supported the BBA bemoaned the lack of fiscal discipline in D.C. Yet, less than a week later, the Senate Health and Welfare Committee passed Senate Bill 1264, calling for about [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 20:20:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Legislature Grants Initial Approval for WILL-Backed Constitutional Amendment to Protect Legislative Oversight</title><link>https://will-law.org/legislature-grants-initial-approval-for-will-backed-constitutional-amendment-to-protect-legislative-oversight/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Wisconsin State Senate approved Assembly Joint Resolution 133 (AJR 133) on first consideration, a WILL-supported proposed amendment to the Wisconsin Constitution designed to restore legislative oversight of administrative rulemaking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/legislature-grants-initial-approval-for-will-backed-constitutional-amendment-to-protect-legislative-oversight/"&gt;Legislature Grants Initial Approval for WILL-Backed Constitutional Amendment to Protect Legislative Oversight&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 20:32:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Illinois’ increased revenue because of federal economy, not state lawmakers</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/illinois-increased-revenue-because-of-federal-economy-not-state-lawmakers/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Higher tax revenue paints a better picture for Illinois’ budget, but increases have been driven by strong national economy, rather than local policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/illinois-increased-revenue-because-of-federal-economy-not-state-lawmakers/"&gt;Illinois’ increased revenue because of federal economy, not state lawmakers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 21:28:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Assessing Tax Trends in the City of Dallas</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/assessing-tax-trends-in-the-city-of-dallas/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Does history suggest that property taxes are too high in the city of Dallas? And, if so, have local decision-makers actively helped or hurt the situation?   To help answer these questions, let’s review the city’s 2024 Annual Comprehensive Financial Report (ACFR) and gather four types of data—i.e., tax levies, local population, total tax rates, and taxable values—over a 10-year time horizon. Using these audited estimates, we can gauge the growth of government (i.e., tax levy trends), assess its reasonability...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/assessing-tax-trends-in-the-city-of-dallas/"&gt;Assessing Tax Trends in the City of Dallas&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 21:36:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] NC schools that beat the odds: it’s time to get noticed</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/nc-schools-that-beat-the-odds-its-time-to-get-noticed/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Students from schools with a low percentage of children in poverty generally do better than students from schools that a have a high percentage of children in poverty. That’s a statement that’s generally true — but not always. Chad Aldeman, who contributes to the Bright Spots column at education web site, The 74 Million, recently highlighted...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/nc-schools-that-beat-the-odds-its-time-to-get-noticed/"&gt;NC schools that beat the odds: it&amp;#8217;s time to get noticed&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 21:55:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Nearly 11,000 Idaho students are now signed up for state's parental choice tax credit</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/post/nearly-11-000-idaho-students-are-now-signed-up-for-state-s-parental-choice-tax-credit</link><description>To put that in perspective: if the students currently represented in applications formed a single public school district, it would rank as the 6th largest district in Idaho. And the application window doesn’t close until March 15.</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 21:58:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] SBOE Workgroups Announced: The Final Fight for Texas History</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/sboe-workgroups-announced-the-final-fight-for-texas-history/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The workgroup numbers for the Texas State Board of Education are finally out, and they reveal a historic milestone for our state’s education system. As the SBOE moves toward the completion of this monumental process, it is clear that they have assembled a team with more history experts and more frontline Texas teachers than ever before. Our amazing Texas teachers, those who...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/sboe-workgroups-announced-the-final-fight-for-texas-history/"&gt;SBOE Workgroups Announced: The Final Fight for Texas History&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 22:00:16 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>