<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>State-Policy Think-Tank Digest</title><link>https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml</link><description>Latest posts from free-market policy institutes across the U.S.</description><atom:link href="https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 00:12:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] Tim Walz Leaves Minnesotans on the Hook for a $430,000 Legal Bill</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/tim-walz-leaves-minnesotans-on-the-hook-for-a-430000-legal-bill/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Minnesota Gov. Tim Walz already has taxpayer-funded legal counsel. Additionally, he has access to the Attorney General&amp;#8217;s office. Yet, Minnesota taxpayers are now left to foot a $430,000 legal bill from outside lawyers that Walz racked up trying to prepare for a congressional hearing where he provided testimony on his Sanctuary City illegal immigration policies. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/tim-walz-leaves-minnesotans-on-the-hook-for-a-430000-legal-bill/"&gt;Tim Walz Leaves Minnesotans on the Hook for a $430,000 Legal Bill&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 19:22:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] What the “One Big Beautiful Bill Act” Means for School Choice in Mississippi</title><link>https://empowerms.org/what-the-one-big-beautiful-bill-act-means-for-school-choice-in-mississippi/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;There are two aspects to the school choice provisions in the OBBB: a tax credit for contributions to organizations that provide scholarships to students in public or private schools, and rules those organizations have to follow in granting scholarships (including eligibility of scholarship students).  Tax Credit for Contributions  Starting in 2027, an individual taxpayer (not&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/what-the-one-big-beautiful-bill-act-means-for-school-choice-in-mississippi/"&gt;What the “One Big Beautiful Bill Act” Means for School Choice in Mississippi&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 21:47:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] NORTHJERSEY.COM: Appeals court to hear arguments in NJ school segregation lawsuit</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/07/northjersey-com-appeals-court-to-hear-arguments-in-nj-school-segregation-lawsuit/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In this NorthJersey.com article, the New Jersey appellate court prepares to hear arguments in the high‑profile school segregation lawsuit filed [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/07/northjersey-com-appeals-court-to-hear-arguments-in-nj-school-segregation-lawsuit/"&gt;NORTHJERSEY.COM: Appeals court to hear arguments in NJ school segregation lawsuit&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 16:00:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] Congressional Republicans Call Out Walz’s ‘Wasted Taxpayer Money’</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/congressional-republicans-call-out-walzs-wasted-taxpayer-money/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Minnesota Republicans criticized the use of taxpayer funds for the legal counsel, with U.S. House Majority Whip Tom Emmer calling the governor a “scam artist” and Rep. Pete Stauber saying, “more wasted taxpayer money by the ‘knucklehead.’” It&amp;#8217;s extremely disappointing that the governor felt the need to burn nearly half a million dollars of taxpayer [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/congressional-republicans-call-out-walzs-wasted-taxpayer-money/"&gt;Congressional Republicans Call Out Walz&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8216;Wasted Taxpayer Money&amp;#8217;&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 18:39:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] Sec. Simon Should Hop Off the Ranked-Choice Voting Train</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/sec-simon-should-hop-off-the-ranked-choice-voting-train/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Ranked-Choice Voting must be rejected when it presents itself in Minnesota. Our republic deserves no less than our willingness to educate voters about this failed voting system and to resist misguided efforts like Sec. Simons who wants to expand this radical scheme to all Minnesota cities and counties. &amp;#8212; Secretary of State backs legislation to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/sec-simon-should-hop-off-the-ranked-choice-voting-train/"&gt;Sec. Simon Should Hop Off the Ranked-Choice Voting Train&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 13:13:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Average Pay at Port Authority Surges as 11 Employees Collect $400k+</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/average-pay-at-panynj-surges-as-11-employees-collect-400k/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Eleven Port Authority of New York and New Jersey (PANYNJ) employees collected more than $400,000 each in total pay last....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/average-pay-at-panynj-surges-as-11-employees-collect-400k/"&gt;Average Pay at Port Authority Surges as 11 Employees Collect $400k+&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 15:40:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Frontierinstitute] Mike Mansfield and the Japanese</title><link>https://frontierinstitute.org/mike-mansfield-and-the-japanese/</link><description>"In 1988, on behalf of America and with Mike Mansfield’s support, President Ronald Reagan formally apologized for the internments and publicly admitted they were not justified."</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 17:43:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] PA House Democrats Pass Unbalanced, Reckless Spending Bill</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/07/14/pa-house-democrats-pass-unbalanced-reckless-spending-bill/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Harrisburg, Pa., July 14, 2025 — Today, Pennsylvania House Democrats passed the General Appropriations Act (HB 1330), their version of a budget bill, which includes a $2.9 billion spending increase. The bill would increase general fund spending to $50.6 billion—exacerbating Pennsylvania’s structural deficit, by spending $5.3 billion more than revenue. Lawmakers would need to drain [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/07/14/pa-house-democrats-pass-unbalanced-reckless-spending-bill/"&gt;PA House Democrats Pass Unbalanced, Reckless Spending Bill&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 21:52:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] NJ ED REPORT: Is Murphy Stalling the Segregation Lawsuit? What Would His Successor Do?</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/07/nj-ed-report-is-murphy-stalling-the-segregation-lawsuit-what-would-his-successor-do/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A new NJ Education Report article covers a high-stakes lawsuit accusing the Murphy administration of stalling efforts to fix New [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/07/nj-ed-report-is-murphy-stalling-the-segregation-lawsuit-what-would-his-successor-do/"&gt;NJ ED REPORT: Is Murphy Stalling the Segregation Lawsuit? What Would His Successor Do?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 18:36:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG Announces Chief Operating Officer</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-announces-chief-operating-officer/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;THE NEWS The Institute for Reforming Government (IRG) has promoted Chris Reader to Chief Operating Officer. In this expanded role, Chris will manage the day-to-day operations of IRG, overseeing its team and project portfolio. Reader has also been named the Executive Director of IRG Action Fund, IRG’s 501(C)(4) advocacy partner.   THE QUOTE CJ Szafir, IRG, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-announces-chief-operating-officer/"&gt;IRG Announces Chief Operating Officer&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 15:54:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] Albuquerque Mayoral Candidate Darren White completes RGF Mayoral candidate survey</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/albuquerque-mayoral-candidate-darren-white-completes-rgf-mayoral-candidate-survey/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce that Albuquerque mayoral candidate (former Bernalillo County Sheriff and former Secretary of the New Mexico Department of Public Safety) Darren White, has completed and submitted the Rio Grande Foundation&amp;#8217;s mayoral candidate survey. You can find that survey embedded below and linked to here.  You can also find White&amp;#8217;s campaign website here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/albuquerque-mayoral-candidate-darren-white-completes-rgf-mayoral-candidate-survey/"&gt;Albuquerque Mayoral Candidate Darren White completes RGF Mayoral candidate survey&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 16:16:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] A Warning for New York’s Energy Policy</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/a-warning-for-new-yorks-energy-policy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On June 24th New York’s electricity grid nearly blew a fuse. That day was extremely hot, and air conditioning was....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/a-warning-for-new-yorks-energy-policy/"&gt;A Warning for New York’s Energy Policy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 17:50:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Job Licensing Reviews: Education Committee</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/job-licensing-reviews-education-committee/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Occupational Board Reform Act (OBRA) was passed in 2018 and became effective in 2019. It requires legislative committees of jurisdiction to review all occupational licenses in the state, roughly 20% per year, on a five-year rotation. These reviews examine whether the licensing requirements are adequate or excessive by current standards. The committees then submit...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/job-licensing-reviews-education-committee/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Job Licensing Reviews: Education Committee&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 16:59:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] Parents: Ask Your District How They Will Comply</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/07/18/parents-ask-your-district-how-they-will-comply/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A momentous parental rights victory was handed down by the United States Supreme Court on Friday, June 27, 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/07/18/parents-ask-your-district-how-they-will-comply/"&gt;Parents: Ask Your District How They Will Comply&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 17:45:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Boise’s FY26 Budget: A Betrayal of Taxpayer Trust</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/boises-fy26-budget-a-betrayal-of-taxpayer-trust/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/boises-fy26-budget-a-betrayal-of-taxpayer-trust/" rel="nofollow" title="Boise’s FY26 Budget: A Betrayal of Taxpayer Trust"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Cream-Neutral-Minimalist-New-Business-Pitch-Deck-Presentation-1.jpg" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;On July 15, 2025, the Boise City Council approved the FY26 budget, which included a 7.6% property tax increase — ignoring the financial strain on residents. As one of the few voices opposing this budget, I’m dismayed by the council’s disregard for taxpayers and the chorus of speakers who showered praise on the council, mayor, [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 19:19:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Panasonic’s EV Gamble Isn’t Capitalism—It’s Corporate Welfare</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/panasonics-ev-gamble-is-corporate-welfare/</link><description>Kansas just got played. Again. Panasonic’s $4 billion EV battery plant in De Soto—touted as the state’s biggest economic development deal ever—is now delayed. Why? Because the federal government finally decided to stop propping up the electric vehicle market with taxpayer cash. President Trump’s “Big, Beautiful Bill” kills the $7,500 new EV tax credit and [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 16:56:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] 10 Best Things About Mississippi</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/10-best-things-about-mississippi/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Speaking to my friends at Smith County Republicans the other day, someone asked me what I most loved about moving to Mississippi from London. There are so many things I love about the Magnolia state, the more I thought about it, the longer my answer grew.&amp;#160;&amp;#160;I thought I’d list a few of my favorite things [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/10-best-things-about-mississippi/" rel="nofollow"&gt;10 Best Things About Mississippi&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 17:38:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG Court Watch Report: Wisconsin Supreme Court Term in Review</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-court-watch-report-wisconsin-supreme-court-term-in-review/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;IRG Court Watch Report: Wisconsin Supreme Court Term in Review Court Delivers Progressive Wins in Wisconsin for the First Time in Over a Decade Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government’s (IRG) Court Watch released a report detailing the Wisconsin Supreme Court’s 2024-2025 term on Tuesday, analyzing the new path taken by the Court’s [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-court-watch-report-wisconsin-supreme-court-term-in-review/"&gt;IRG Court Watch Report: Wisconsin Supreme Court Term in Review&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 12:56:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] BBB Is Not The Tragedy Our Politicians Portray</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/bbb-is-not-the-tragedy-our-politicians-portray/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following appeared in Eastern New Mexico News and other outlets throughout July of 2025. If you haven’t heard already, over the 4th of July weekend, President Trump signed the so-called “Big Beautiful Bill” (BBB) into law. Setting aside the merits and demerits of the legislation, you have to hand it to President Trump and Speaker Mike [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/bbb-is-not-the-tragedy-our-politicians-portray/"&gt;BBB Is Not The Tragedy Our Politicians Portray&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 17:29:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Lawsuit Against United Teachers of Los Angeles Dismissed, Freedom Foundation to Appeal to Ninth Circuit</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/press-release/lawsuit-against-united-teachers-of-los-angeles-dismissed-freedom-foundation-to-appeal-to-ninth-circuit/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Today, the U.S. District Court for the Central District of California ruled against the lawsuit filed by seven Jewish teachers against United Teachers of Los Angeles (UTLA). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/press-release/lawsuit-against-united-teachers-of-los-angeles-dismissed-freedom-foundation-to-appeal-to-ninth-circuit/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Lawsuit Against United Teachers of Los Angeles Dismissed, Freedom Foundation to Appeal to Ninth Circuit&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 17:58:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Research Note: Use of the Nebraska Livestock Matrix</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/research-note-use-of-the-nebraska-livestock-matrix/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Introduced in 2015, the Nebraska Livestock Matrix is a tool designed to help counties evaluate proposed livestock operations seeking conditional use or special exception permits. Created to promote consistency across county lines in the permitting process, the committee tasked with developing the matrix faced two significant challenges in aligning its objectives. First, the tool needed...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/research-note-use-of-the-nebraska-livestock-matrix/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Research Note: Use of the Nebraska Livestock Matrix&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 19:58:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Former Speaker Philip Gunn: Faith, Resilience, and Leadership</title><link>https://empowerms.org/former-speaker-philip-gunn-faith-resilience-and-leadership/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;﻿ Former Speaker Philip Gunn: Faith, Resilience, and Leadership In this episode, host Grant Callen sits down with former Mississippi House Speaker Philip Gunn to trace his journey from Clinton’s small-town roots to state leadership. Gunn shares how a personal tragedy at Ole Miss Law upended his life, yet God’s faithfulness sustained him, strengthened his faith,&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/former-speaker-philip-gunn-faith-resilience-and-leadership/"&gt;Former Speaker Philip Gunn: Faith, Resilience, and Leadership&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 00:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Frontierinstitute] Written Public Comment to SFIC 7.23.25</title><link>https://frontierinstitute.org/written-public-comment-to-sfic-7-23-25/</link><description>We believe it is a constitutional and policy imperative for Montana to implement a statewide student-centered funding formula design as the primary way to fund public education.</description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 17:29:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Federal Courts Strike Down Maine’s Unconstitutional Campaign Finance Laws</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/federal-courts-strike-down-maines-unconstitutional-campaign-finance-laws/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Two rulings were handed down against different Maine ballot initiatives in recent weeks, with federal courts finding that they both violated the First Amendment by restricting political speech. The rulings are a win for freedom of speech in Maine, as they each reaffirmed that political contributions to political action committees (PACs) cannot be hindered. Notably, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/federal-courts-strike-down-maines-unconstitutional-campaign-finance-laws/"&gt;Federal Courts Strike Down Maine’s Unconstitutional Campaign Finance Laws&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 18:11:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Layoffs at Bloated Federal Agencies Versus the Impact of Private Sector Layoffs Caused by the Federal Government</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/layoffs-at-bloated-federal-agencies-versus-the-impact-of-private-sector-layoffs-caused-by-the-federal-government/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Layoffs.jpg" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Secretary of State Marco Rubio recently laid off 1,350 employees as part of a broader restructuring effort, the media response was swift and emotional. Stories of tearful farewells, union outrage, and dramatic claims of “fascism” filled the airwaves. One would think these federal employees had lifetime appointments and that accountability or right-sizing government were foreign [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/layoffs-at-bloated-federal-agencies-versus-the-impact-of-private-sector-layoffs-caused-by-the-federal-government/"&gt;Layoffs at Bloated Federal Agencies Versus the Impact of Private Sector Layoffs Caused by the Federal Government&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 21:03:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Idaho DOGE: Misses it by That Much</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/idaho-doge-misses-it-by-that-much/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/idaho-doge-misses-it-by-that-much/" rel="nofollow" title="Idaho DOGE: Misses it by That Much"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1396" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Gemini_Generated_Image_ku2awsku2awsku2a-scaled.jpg" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="2560" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Ask any good conservative in Idaho politics, and they’ll tell you Idaho’s budgets and government growth are out of control. They’re right. Now, throw in the biggest buzzword in politics for the last six months (the start of President Trump’s return to power), “DOGE.” Of course, that’s shorthand for the Department of Government Efficiency (headed [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 22:28:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Fitzgerald, Lummis Introduce STUDENT Act to Curb Out-of-Control NEA</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/labor/fitzgerald-lummis-introduce-student-act-to-curb-out-of-control-nea/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This week, U.S. Rep. Scott Fitzgerald (R-WI) and U.S. Sen. Cynthia Lummis (R-WY) introduced legislation to overhaul the federal charter of the National Education Association (NEA), the largest teachers union in the country, to make it more accountable and less partisan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/labor/fitzgerald-lummis-introduce-student-act-to-curb-out-of-control-nea/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Fitzgerald, Lummis Introduce STUDENT Act to Curb Out-of-Control NEA&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Over 150,000 Kansas students may be functionally illiterate, yet the adults in charge won’t take action</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/150k-kansas-students-functionally-illiterate/</link><description>The 2024 state assessment indicates that more than 150,000 Kansas students suffer from what is officially described as having a “limited ability to understand and use English language arts skills and knowledge to be academically successful for postsecondary success.”  This closely aligns with what is commonly referred to as being ‘functionally illiterate’, which  Dictionary.com defines [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 14:08:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG Announces New Leadership</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-announces-new-leadership/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;IRG Announces New Leadership Alison Prange to serve as the next Chair of the Board of Directors  THE NEWS The Board of Directors for the Institute for Reforming Government has elected Alison Prange to serve as the next Chair of the Board. Alison Prange was appointed to IRG’s Board in 2022. THE QUOTES Alison Prange, IRG [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-announces-new-leadership/"&gt;IRG Announces New Leadership&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 15:54:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Maine Must Act to Lift Students Under New Federal Education Tax Credit Program</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/maine-must-act-to-lift-students-under-new-federal-education-tax-credit-program/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In 2025, Congress enacted the first-ever federal 1-to-1 tax credit for donations to K–12 education scholarships. While championed by President Trump, the program reflects a broader bipartisan vision: empowering families, driving educational innovation, and keeping funding decisions closer to home. But unless Maine lawmakers act swiftly, Maine families and students will miss out on the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/maine-must-act-to-lift-students-under-new-federal-education-tax-credit-program/"&gt;Maine Must Act to Lift Students Under New Federal Education Tax Credit Program&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 17:20:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Teacher Freedom Summit brings together educators anxious to cut ties with their union</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/teacher-conference/teacher-freedom-summit-brings-together-educators-anxious-to-cut-ties-with-their-union/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Despite the shocking news headlines from big unions like the American Federation of Teachers (AFT) and the National Education Association (NEA), 2025 has been a year of success and hope for America’s education system and educators alike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/teacher-conference/teacher-freedom-summit-brings-together-educators-anxious-to-cut-ties-with-their-union/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Teacher Freedom Summit brings together educators anxious to cut ties with their union&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 18:16:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] “What Does It Cost?” Film by Discovery Institute Exposes the West Coast Climate Agenda</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/economic-opportunity/what-does-it-cost-film-by-discovery-institute-exposes-the-west-coast-climate-agenda/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This summer, Cascade’s summer Research Associates reviewed a film produced by the Discovery...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/economic-opportunity/what-does-it-cost-film-by-discovery-institute-exposes-the-west-coast-climate-agenda/"&gt;“What Does It Cost?” Film by Discovery Institute Exposes the West Coast Climate Agenda&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 21:57:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] How the pandemic is now used to make politicians look wonderful</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/how-the-pandemic-is-now-used-to-make-politicians-look-wonderful/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Wisconsin’s tourism resurgence has been built, at least in part, by more than $160 million in federal bailout money and a record doubling of the tourism department’s budget.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/how-the-pandemic-is-now-used-to-make-politicians-look-wonderful/"&gt;How the pandemic is now used to make politicians look wonderful&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 22:16:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Three issues Georgia parents are most concerned about</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/georgia-parent-top-concerns/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A new report on child well-being from Emory University reveals the issues that Georgia parents say are impacting kids—and their futures—most. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/georgia-parent-top-concerns/"&gt;Three issues Georgia parents are most concerned about&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 22:42:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Virginiainstitute] The State of Educational Opportunity in Virginia – A Survey of Virginia Parents</title><link>https://virginiainstitute.org/the-state-of-educational-opportunity-in-virginia-a-survey-of-virginia-parents/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=the-state-of-educational-opportunity-in-virginia-a-survey-of-virginia-parents</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 11:07:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Manchester mayoral race creates test for media</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/07/manchester-mayoral-race-creates-test-for-media/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Manchester Mayor Jay Ruais was about to become the city’s first incumbent mayor to run for reelection unopposed in 150 years when Board of School Committee member Jessica Spillers announced her candidacy on Thursday.  Spillers’ entry creates a campaign custom-made to test the credibility of New Hampshire’s media.  In her announcement, Spillers said she decided [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/07/manchester-mayoral-race-creates-test-for-media/"&gt;Manchester mayoral race creates test for media&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 11:33:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] As Goes AI, So Goes the Nation</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/as-goes-ai-so-goes-the-nation/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The artificial intelligence (AI) of a country, including its capabilities, growth, and the culture surrounding it, is a powerful indicator of a nation’s global standing. The technology is interwoven into all industries, from medicine to education and defense, and is a major economic driver with billions of dollars pouring into the global AI marketplace. Despite...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/as-goes-ai-so-goes-the-nation/"&gt;As Goes AI, So Goes the Nation&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 17:48:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] How strict zoning can delay development even in housing-friendly towns</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/07/how-strict-zoning-can-delay-development-even-in-housing-friendly-towns/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For a great example of the delays local land use regulations can cause for housing construction in New Hampshire, you don’t have to look to the towns where building is made the most difficult. Even in housing-friendly towns, strict regulations delay and often prevent projects. Merrimack is one of the more housing-friendly communities in the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/07/how-strict-zoning-can-delay-development-even-in-housing-friendly-towns/"&gt;How strict zoning can delay development even in housing-friendly towns&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 18:34:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Tallahassee Democrat: K-12 Scholarship Students Can Help Solve Public School Budget Woes | Opinion</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/tallahassee-democrat-k-12-scholarship-students-can-help-solve-public-school-budget-woes-opinion/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;July 26, 2025 Like many public-school officials around the country, Leon County Schools Superintendent Rocky Hanna is feeling...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/tallahassee-democrat-k-12-scholarship-students-can-help-solve-public-school-budget-woes-opinion/"&gt;Tallahassee Democrat: K-12 Scholarship Students Can Help Solve Public School Budget Woes | Opinion&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 13:13:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Wyoming parents shouldn’t lose hope about paused education choice funds</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/wyoming-parents-shouldn-t-lose-hope-about-paused-education-choice-funds</link><description>While funds may be temporarily paused for the nearly 4,000 families approved to receive education savings account funding in Wyoming...</description><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 14:15:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Mississippi or Milei?  America’s Magnolia state is a better example of what the free market can do</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/mississippi-or-milei-americas-magnolia-state-is-a-better-example-of-what-the-free-market-can-do/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When Javier Milei burst onto the scene as a presidential candidate in Argentina in 2023, brandishing a chainsaw, many dismissed him as unhinged.&amp;#160; His radical libertarian platform was presented by the media as evidence of Argentina’s tragicomic decline. Argentina was poorer in 2023 than it had been two decades earlier. That year, the economy contracted [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/mississippi-or-milei-americas-magnolia-state-is-a-better-example-of-what-the-free-market-can-do/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi or Milei?  America’s Magnolia state is a better example of what the free market can do&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 14:52:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] First Principles: When the Government Takes Your Land</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/first-principles-when-the-government-takes-your-land/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=first-principles-when-the-government-takes-your-land</link><description>"They didn’t ask. They just took." Travis Lewis details the emotional toll of eminent domain and reminds us why property rights still matter.</description><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 19:32:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Is Government Truly Limited in Louisiana?</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/legal-regulatory/is-government-truly-limited-in-louisiana/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In Louisiana and across the country, there’s a growing hunger for limited government, driven by the recognition that more government doesn’t always correlate with heightened responsiveness or better outcomes. Time and again, we’ve seen how top-down policies, bloated bureaucracy, and ever-expanding regulations stand in the way of innovation, economic opportunity, and personal freedom. Louisiana’s continued...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/legal-regulatory/is-government-truly-limited-in-louisiana/"&gt;Is Government Truly Limited in Louisiana?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 12:13:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Coalition of WI Parents Encourage Court of Appeals to Protect Young Girls at School</title><link>https://will-law.org/coalition-of-wi-parents-encourage-court-of-appeals-to-protect-young-girls-at-school/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The News: WILL filed an amicus brief in the Seventh Circuit Court of Appeals, urging it to overrule two prior cases that require schools to allow biological males who identify as transgender to access girls’ restrooms and locker rooms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/coalition-of-wi-parents-encourage-court-of-appeals-to-protect-young-girls-at-school/"&gt;Coalition of WI Parents Encourage Court of Appeals to Protect Young Girls at School&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 14:25:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] First Principles Series: Protecting Property Rights</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/first-principle-series-protecting-property-rights/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=first-principle-series-protecting-property-rights</link><description>The Founders understood that protections for private property must exist if the nation was to remain free.</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 18:39:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Can San Francisco Be Saved From Itself?</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/can-san-francisco-be-saved-from-itself/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=can-san-francisco-be-saved-from-itself</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Daniel Lurie’s moderate promises clash with a city drowning in ideological dysfunction. Can he deliver, or will the status quo swallow him up? A City Choking on Its Own Excess San Francisco has always fancied itself a laboratory for progressive ideas. This is a place where progressive theory gets its field test, often with little...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/can-san-francisco-be-saved-from-itself/"&gt;Can San Francisco Be Saved From Itself?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 19:20:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] IFF Spending Index: Unmasking Idaho's Overgrown Government</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/iff-spending-index-unmasking-idahos-overgrown-government/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/iff-spending-index-unmasking-idahos-overgrown-government/" rel="nofollow" title="IFF Spending Index: Unmasking Idaho&amp;#039;s Overgrown Government"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Article-Headers-2025-07-28T181001.712.png" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Last week’s kickoff of the Idaho DOGE Task Force highlights the need to rein in Idaho’s spending growth. It’s a tall order. Since 2019, the Idaho Freedom Foundation’s Spending Index has been the only yardstick for measuring the impacts of individual agency appropriations bills. And necessarily, the votes on these bills by legislators provide the [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 19:50:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] The Messenger Spring 2025</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/the-messenger-spring-2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;President&amp;#8217;s Message Dear Friends, What an extraordinary year it’s been for liberty in the Sunshine State. This past...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/the-messenger-spring-2025/"&gt;The Messenger Spring 2025&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 20:45:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Vision for Virginia 2025: Education Policy – Six Education Policy Positions for the Next Governor</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/vision-for-virginia-2025-education-policy-six-education-policy-positions-for-the-next-governor/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="630" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/vision-for-virginia-2025.webp" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Education is a top concern for voters in Virginia.&amp;#160;As President Trump closes the Federal Department of Education, shifting funding and control to the states, the issues surrounding education policy are more important now than ever.&amp;#160; Below is a look at the state of education in Virginia, the Thomas Jefferson Institute’s vision for education reform, and [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/vision-for-virginia-2025-education-policy-six-education-policy-positions-for-the-next-governor/"&gt;Vision for Virginia 2025: Education Policy &amp;#8211; Six Education Policy Positions for the Next Governor&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 02:22:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Ushering in America’s New Atomic Age: Three Takeaways from the House Oversight Hearing on Nuclear Energy Reform</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/energy/ushering-in-americas-new-atomic-age-three-takeaways-from-the-house-oversight-hearing-on-nuclear-energy-reform/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Last week, the U.S. House Committee on Economic Growth, Energy Policy, and Regulatory Affairs held a timely oversight hearing on the outdated and burdensome regulations holding back America’s nuclear energy future. The testimony delivered a clear message: advanced nuclear power is ready to help meet our growing energy demands—but only if policymakers act to remove...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/energy/ushering-in-americas-new-atomic-age-three-takeaways-from-the-house-oversight-hearing-on-nuclear-energy-reform/"&gt;Ushering in America’s New Atomic Age: Three Takeaways from the House Oversight Hearing on Nuclear Energy Reform&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 12:52:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Metro’s Ballooning Bond for Road Diets</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/tax-and-budget/metros-ballooning-bond-for-road-diets/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Jacob Beckwith On July 31st, the seven Metro councilors will vote to...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/tax-and-budget/metros-ballooning-bond-for-road-diets/"&gt;Metro’s Ballooning Bond for Road Diets&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 14:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Exploring transportation taxes and their impact in the Mountain States</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/exploring-transportation-taxes-and-their-impact-in-the-mountain-states</link><description>As Americans hit the road this summer, what types of transportation-related taxes will they be paying? We answer this question in our new...</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 14:25:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Virginiainstitute] Press Release – 50CAN Reveals Call for More Education Choice in Virginia</title><link>https://virginiainstitute.org/press-release-50can-reveals-call-for-more-education-choice-in-virginia/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=press-release-50can-reveals-call-for-more-education-choice-in-virginia</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Summary A recent poll conducted by the Virginia Institute for Public Policy (VIPP) in partnership with 50CAN reveals a strong demand among Virginia parents for expanded educational choices ahead of&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org/press-release-50can-reveals-call-for-more-education-choice-in-virginia/"&gt;Press Release – 50CAN Reveals Call for More Education Choice in Virginia&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org"&gt;Virginia Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 14:47:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] Press Release: New Jersey Policy Institute Appoints Unity Bank Exec George Boyan as New Board Member</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/07/press-release-new-jersey-policy-institute-appoints-unity-bank-exec-george-boyan-as-new-board-member/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 15:53:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Declining enrollment in traditional schools highlights California’s need for alternatives</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/ca-enrollment-trends/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=ca-enrollment-trends</link><description>&lt;p&gt;With many California classrooms set to reopen in August, California Policy Center took a closer look at school enrollment patterns, and what they signal for the year ahead. Looking at public school enrollment data from 2014-15 to 2024-25, broken down by county, CPC conducted an analysis of the 10-year trend in California. The data revealed...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/ca-enrollment-trends/"&gt;Declining enrollment in traditional schools highlights California’s need for alternatives&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 19:15:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Waiting for Perception on Crime to Change Is Not a Winning Strategy for St. Louis</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/criminal-justice/waiting-for-perception-on-crime-to-change-is-not-a-winning-strategy-for-st-louis/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve highlighted the progress St. Louis has made in reducing crime in recent blog posts. The improving data are positive [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/criminal-justice/waiting-for-perception-on-crime-to-change-is-not-a-winning-strategy-for-st-louis/"&gt;Waiting for Perception on Crime to Change Is Not a Winning Strategy for St. Louis&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 19:29:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Job Licensing Reviews: Health and Human Services Committee</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/job-licensing-reviews-health-and-human-services-committee/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Occupational Board Reform Act (OBRA) was passed in 2018 and became effective in 2019. It requires legislative committees of jurisdiction to review all occupational licenses in the state, roughly 20% per year, on a five-year rotation. These reviews examine whether the licensing requirements are adequate or excessive by current standards. The committees then submit...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/job-licensing-reviews-health-and-human-services-committee/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Job Licensing Reviews: Health and Human Services Committee&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 20:30:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Understanding the Decline in Student Test Scores with Jim Wyckoff</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/education/understanding-the-decline-in-student-test-scores-with-jim-wyckoff/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Susan Pendergrass speaks with Dr. Jim Wyckoff about how national test scores, especially for the lowest-performing students, began falling well before the pandemic and what states can do to reverse the trend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/education/understanding-the-decline-in-student-test-scores-with-jim-wyckoff/"&gt;Understanding the Decline in Student Test Scores with Jim Wyckoff&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 21:12:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Boston’s 2026 Budget: Prioritizing Stability in Uncertain Times</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/blog/usdatalabs/bostons-2026-budget-prioritizing-stability-in-uncertain-times/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;With Boston projected to lose about $1.4 billion in commercial property tax revenue over the next five years, the city's new budget is less about growth and more about long-term stability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/blog/usdatalabs/bostons-2026-budget-prioritizing-stability-in-uncertain-times/"&gt;Boston’s 2026 Budget: Prioritizing Stability in Uncertain Times&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 15:14:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Iowa Senator Slams Wasteful California Rail Transportation Projects</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/iowa-senator-slams-wasteful-california-rail-transportation-projects/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=iowa-senator-slams-wasteful-california-rail-transportation-projects</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Senator Joni Ernst (R-IA) has issued a report identifying wasteful federally funded construction projects, and California’s rail projects are prominently featured. In addition to High-Speed Rail, Ernst’s “Off the Rails” report correctly singles out three transit projects in Northern California. While Californians may discount criticisms from a Red State Senator, Ernst’s report might ultimately benefit...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/iowa-senator-slams-wasteful-california-rail-transportation-projects/"&gt;Iowa Senator Slams Wasteful California Rail Transportation Projects&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 18:51:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Affordable Housing Crisis in Massachusetts: Could Manufactured Homes be a Solution?</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/blog/usdatalabs/affordable-housing-crisis-in-massachusetts-could-manufactured-homes-be-a-solution/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Massachusetts is in an affordable housing crisis. The median home price across the state was $629,500 in December 2024, up 9.15 percent from $576,700 in December 2023. The median home price across the U.S. was $427,728 in December 2024.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/blog/usdatalabs/affordable-housing-crisis-in-massachusetts-could-manufactured-homes-be-a-solution/"&gt;Affordable Housing Crisis in Massachusetts: Could Manufactured Homes be a Solution?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 20:10:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Where the precipitous drop in birthrates is a very, very good thing</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/where-the-precipitous-drop-in-birthrates-is-a-very-very-good-thing/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Teen birthrates are a small fraction of what they used to be As some of America’s most prominent conservative voices push the pronatalist movement, there’s been a dramatic decrease in pregnancies and births among one particular subset of Wisconsin females that should get more attention — and praise. Births to teenage girls in the Badger [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/where-the-precipitous-drop-in-birthrates-is-a-very-very-good-thing/"&gt;Where the precipitous drop in birthrates is a very, very good thing&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 21:04:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] ‘We still need to pave our roads’</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/wisconsin-land-stewardship-program-analysis/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As a Wisconsin stewardship program is up for renewal, northern counties’ budgets, economies are squeezed by how much land already is taken out of equation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/wisconsin-land-stewardship-program-analysis/"&gt;‘We still need to pave our roads’&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 21:05:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Grassroot testimonies — July 2025</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/07/grassroot-testimonies-july-2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Below are testimonies submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii during July, 2025, for consideration by the Honolulu City Council. HONOLULU CITY COUNCIL &amp;#62;&amp;#62; Bill 48 (2024) — “Reduce rates for rentals in Residential A tax class” &amp;#62;&amp;#62; Bill 49 (2025) — “Increase exemptions, spare kupuna from ‘tax shock’” &amp;#62;&amp;#62; Bill 49 (2025) — “Increase [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/07/grassroot-testimonies-july-2025/"&gt;Grassroot testimonies — July 2025&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 21:16:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Victory! NC Legislature Overrides Veto to Enact REINS Act</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/victory-nc-legislature-overrides-veto-to-enact-reins-act/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In a major win for separation of powers and limited government, the North Carolina legislature overrode Governor Josh Stein’s veto..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/victory-nc-legislature-overrides-veto-to-enact-reins-act/"&gt;Victory! NC Legislature Overrides Veto to Enact REINS Act&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:21:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] API Announces Support of the STUDENTS Act</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/08/01/api-announces-support-of-the-students-act/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Alabama Policy Institute (API) announced its endorsement of the federal Stopping Teachers Unions from Damaging Education Needs Today (STUDENTS) Act, which seeks to reform the federal charter of the country’s largest education union, the National Education Association (NEA).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/08/01/api-announces-support-of-the-students-act/"&gt;API Announces Support of the STUDENTS Act&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 01:32:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Conforming to Trump’s Tax Bill Would Save Virginians $1.4 Billion More</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/conforming-to-trumps-tax-bill-would-save-virginians-1-4-billion-more/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="630" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Virginia-and-Trump.jpg" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Should the 2026 Virginia General Assembly choose to conform state tax laws to the full set of new tax rules at the federal level, Virginia families and businesses might save as much at $1.4 billion annually. That is a fresh estimate from the Tax Foundation, which looked at the impact of full conformity in all 50 [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/conforming-to-trumps-tax-bill-would-save-virginians-1-4-billion-more/"&gt;Conforming to Trump&amp;#8217;s Tax Bill Would Save Virginians $1.4 Billion More&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 12:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Connecticut: Where Americans and French Planned the End of War</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/08/01/connecticut-where-americans-and-french-planned-the-end-of-war/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="542" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/service-pnp-pga-01600-01668v-e1754055254996.jpg" width="785" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By September 1780, the American Revolution trudged into its fifth grueling year. Though the Continental Army had scored major triumphs against the British since the “shot heard ‘round the world” [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/08/01/connecticut-where-americans-and-french-planned-the-end-of-war/"&gt;Connecticut: Where Americans and French Planned the End of War&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 13:35:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Kansas Is Losing the Competition for People—and It’s Not Just a Kansas Problem</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/kansas-is-losing-the-competition-for-people/</link><description>Americans are voting with their feet, and states are either competing for them—or watching them leave. Data posted by the Committee to Unleash Prosperity at VoteWithYourFeet.net make it painfully clear: Kansas is hemorrhaging residents. Over the last decade, it had a net loss of nearly 100,000 people to other states. That’s not just bad optics—that’s [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 14:00:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] New York’s Medicaid Spending Rate Remains the Highest of Any State</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/new-yorks-medicaid-spending-rate-remains-the-highest-of-any-state/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New York&amp;#8217;s Medicaid program remained a spending outlier in 2024, with per-resident outlays that were 24 percent higher than those....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/new-yorks-medicaid-spending-rate-remains-the-highest-of-any-state/"&gt;New York&amp;#8217;s Medicaid Spending Rate Remains the Highest of Any State&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 14:10:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] How Often Should Schools Close?</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/accountability/how-often-should-schools-close/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been writing a lot lately about the poor performance of Missouri’s schools; for recent examples, see here and here. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/accountability/how-often-should-schools-close/"&gt;How Often Should Schools Close?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 15:15:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] Pennsylvania Enters Second Month of Budget Impasse</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/08/01/pennsylvania-enters-second-month-of-budget-impasse/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Harrisburg, Pa., August 1, 2025 — Pennsylvania is entering the second month operating without a state budget, with no end in sight. Amid the protracted impasse, many have begun to question the governor’s priorities as days pass without substantial progress. Andrew Lewis, President and CEO of the Commonwealth Foundation, issued the following statement in response: [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/08/01/pennsylvania-enters-second-month-of-budget-impasse/"&gt;Pennsylvania Enters Second Month of Budget Impasse&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 17:51:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Fight socialism: Build more housing</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/08/fight-socialism-build-more-housing/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The rise of 33-year-old “democratic” socialist Zohran Mamdami to the Democratic nomination for mayor of New York City has sensible political observers from right to left understandably concerned. How could the city that symbolizes the global dominance of American finance and capital be on the cusp of electing a mayor who advocates dismantling capitalism? Downwardly [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/08/fight-socialism-build-more-housing/"&gt;Fight socialism: Build more housing&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 19:02:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Week in Review: Free Speech vs. Administrative State</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-free-speech-vs-administrative-state/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Can the government silence you simply by hinting at punishment? That’s the troubling reality for a group of employers who..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-free-speech-vs-administrative-state/"&gt;Week in Review: Free Speech vs. Administrative State&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 19:44:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Passport to Parks? More Like Passport to Perks</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/08/01/passport-to-parks-more-like-passport-to-perks/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What began as a passport to the outdoors has turned into a backdoor subsidy for public-sector pensions.  State officials sold the Passport to Parks fee — quietly tacked onto every [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/08/01/passport-to-parks-more-like-passport-to-perks/"&gt;Passport to Parks? More Like Passport to Perks&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 20:09:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Friends And Enemies of Free Speech: Looking at the Amicus Briefs in the Prop 211 Case</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/friends-and-enemies-of-free-speech-looking-at-the-amicus-briefs-in-the-prop-211-case/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Goldwater Institute lawyers will argue in the Arizona Supreme Court next month against the constitutionality of Prop. 211, a state..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/friends-and-enemies-of-free-speech-looking-at-the-amicus-briefs-in-the-prop-211-case/"&gt;Friends And Enemies of Free Speech: Looking at the Amicus Briefs in the Prop 211 Case&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 20:48:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Winners &amp; Losers: All Over the Map</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/winners-losers-all-over-the-map/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Every Friday morning, I join the Cardle &amp;#38; Woolley Show on 1370 Talk Radio in Austin to announce the week’s Winners &amp;#38; Losers. As we enter the month of August and finish up the second week of the first called legislative session in Texas, some things are turning out to be more special than others....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/winners-losers-all-over-the-map/"&gt;Winners &amp; Losers: All Over the Map&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 21:42:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Minnesota’s Economic News — W/E 8/1/25</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/minnesotas-economic-news-w-e-8-1-25/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Labor market KROC: Rochester Jobless Rate Rises Despite Record Employment KRWC: Wright County Unemployment Takes a Jump in June State and local taxes and spending KROC: Minnesota Ends Fiscal Year $850M Over Revenue Forecast&amp;#160; Southernminn.com: Minnesota Middle-Class Families Pay the 12th Most in Taxes St. Cloud Times: Stearns County debates hefty property tax increase Rochester...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/minnesotas-economic-news-w-e-8-1-25/"&gt;Minnesota’s Economic News — W/E 8/1/25&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2025 05:01:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Texas Holds the Keys to Higher Ed Reform</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/texas-holds-the-keys-to-higher-ed-reform/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A number of respected higher education reform leaders, led by the Manhattan Institute, recently issued a statement detailing everything that is wrong with colleges and universities today. Recounting the results of a couple of decades of institutional blight, the comprehensive list names identity politics, DEI, divisive racial quotas, and demonizing the values of Western civilization as the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/texas-holds-the-keys-to-higher-ed-reform/"&gt;Texas Holds the Keys to Higher Ed Reform&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2025 10:37:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] Watts: ‘Tucker: A Man and His Dream’</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/08/watts-tucker-a-man-and-his-dream/</link><description>by Tyler Watts, Ph.D. The history of American capitalism is littered with the dashed hopes and shattered dreams of failed entrepreneurs. Seldom does a business failure story make for compelling Hollywood drama, but the 1989 film Tucker: the Man and His Dream does just that. The movie tells a heroic, riveting story of a revolutionary business that&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/08/watts-tucker-a-man-and-his-dream/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2025 20:20:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Parents</title><link>https://will-law.org/parents/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/parents/"&gt;Parents&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2025 22:10:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Conservative lawmakers should resist unaccountable hospital slush fund</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/conservative-lawmakers-should-resist-unaccountable-hospital-slush-fund</link><description>Michigan should reform the federal 340B program</description><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Governor Newsom Protests Too Much – the Minimum Wage Increase Did Destroy Jobs</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/governor-newsom-protests-too-much-the-minimum-wage-increase-did-destroy-jobs/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As the New York Post reported, Newsom’s deputy director of communications Tara Gallegos disputed the findings of the piece, pointing out to Fox News Digital that the research paper was linked to the Hoover Institution, a public policy think tank she claimed has published “false or misleading information” about California’s minimum wage hike “that later [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/governor-newsom-protests-too-much-the-minimum-wage-increase-did-destroy-jobs/"&gt;Governor Newsom Protests Too Much – the Minimum Wage Increase Did Destroy Jobs&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 10:00:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Chicago homicides lowest in decade, but so is arrest rate</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/chicago-homicides-lowest-in-decade-but-so-is-arrest-rate/</link><description>Chicago homicides were at a decade low for the 12 months through June, but also down was the arrest rate from 42% to 27%.</description><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 10:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] ‘Death Star Bill’ Is Fully Operational — For Freedom</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/death-star-bill-is-fully-operational-for-freedom/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In its first century in existence, the city of Dallas—from 1856 until 1961—passed an estimated 2,000 city ordinances, in total. Since then, it has passed approximately 33,000. That doesn’t count regulations issued by various city agencies. Texans—like all Americans—are overwhelmed with countless federal and state laws and regulations. Harvard Professor Harvey Silverglate estimates in his...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/death-star-bill-is-fully-operational-for-freedom/"&gt;‘Death Star Bill’ Is Fully Operational — For Freedom&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 10:35:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] Franke: The Dog Days of Baseball</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/08/franke-the-dog-days-of-baseball/</link><description>by Mark Franke It is August now and for baseball that means the July 31 trading deadline has passed. For major league teams it is the best opportunity to upgrade rosters for those with playoff potential, or to unload high salaries and impending free agents for those with no hope for October baseball. For minor&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/08/franke-the-dog-days-of-baseball/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 12:57:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] WILL Releases New Model Policy &amp; Resources Following SCOTUS Parental Rights Decision</title><link>https://will-law.org/will-releases-new-model-policy-resources-following-scotus-parental-rights-decision/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Following a landmark U.S. Supreme Court decision, WILL is releasing a new model school board policy and additional tools to equip parents, teachers, and school administrators across the country to protect the fundamental right of families to raise their children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/will-releases-new-model-policy-resources-following-scotus-parental-rights-decision/"&gt;WILL Releases New Model Policy &amp;#038; Resources Following SCOTUS Parental Rights Decision&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 13:19:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Massachusetts Youth Population in Decline</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/news/massachusetts-youth-population-in-decline/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Massachusetts has a large share of young adults in its population. However, although Massachusetts’ labor force participation is among the highest in the country, its youth population is dwindling. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/news/massachusetts-youth-population-in-decline/"&gt;Massachusetts Youth Population in Decline&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 14:00:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] OPINION: New Mexico and the film industry recession</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/opinion-new-mexico-and-the-film-industry-recession/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following appeared in the Albuquerque Journal on August 3, 2025. Since the days of Gov. Bill Richardson’s administration, the Rio Grande Foundation has opposed New Mexico’s generous film subsidies. Back in Richardson’s day the primary subsidy was a 25% “refundable” tax credit meaning that anyone filming in New Mexico received up to 25% of [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/opinion-new-mexico-and-the-film-industry-recession/"&gt;OPINION: New Mexico and the film industry recession&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 16:27:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] National award recognizes Center for Poverty Solutions’ job co-op</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/national-award-recognizes-center-for-poverty-solutions-job-co-op/</link><description>The Illinois Policy Institute’s Center for Poverty Solutions received national backing for a job co-op that will target Chicago’s most beleaguered neighborhoods. The effort will help communities liberate themselves from government dependence.</description><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 17:12:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Direct primary care provides medical treatment the old-fashioned way</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/direct-primary-care-provides-medical-treatment-the-old-fashioned-way</link><description>Because of the way health care has evolved in the United States over the past 80 years, it is extremely complex and now involves...</description><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 19:17:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] The AI Blueprint States Can’t Afford to Ignore</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/the-ai-blueprint-states-cant-afford-to-ignore/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;August 4, 2025 The Trump Administration’s recent AI Action Plan signals a fundamental shift in how the federal...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/the-ai-blueprint-states-cant-afford-to-ignore/"&gt;The AI Blueprint States Can&amp;#8217;t Afford to Ignore&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 20:09:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Kenneth Schrupp – Reporting on Lessons Learned from Southern California Wildfires</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/kenneth-schrupp-reporting-on-lessons-learned-from-southern-california-wildfires/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Center Square California reporter and Free Cities Center contributor Kenneth Schrupp joins us to discuss his recent reporting on policy mistakes that made preventing and fighting the recent Southern California wildfires worse. He also discusses what he&amp;#8217;s learned about controversial legislation to &amp;#8220;reimagine&amp;#8221; the Palisades as it is rebuilt. He also shares insights in his [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/kenneth-schrupp-reporting-on-lessons-learned-from-southern-california-wildfires/"&gt;Kenneth Schrupp &amp;#8211; Reporting on Lessons Learned from Southern California Wildfires&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 21:06:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Grassroot views on housing reform going mainstream</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/08/grassroot-views-on-housing-reform-going-mainstream/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A new home goes up in Kaimuki. Photo by Mark Coleman A U.S. senator recently made the following statement about the housing shortages across America. Can you guess who it was? “Ask anyone who has tried to build anything — a shed, a patio, or an accessory dwelling unit for their in-laws. They will tell [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/08/grassroot-views-on-housing-reform-going-mainstream/"&gt;Grassroot views on housing reform going mainstream&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 21:44:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Metro Council Votes to Approve $88.5 Million Bond for Road Diets: One Intern’s Reflection</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/transportation/metro-council-votes-to-approve-88-5-million-bond-for-road-diets-one-interns-reflection/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Connor Roberts The summer of 2025 brought Cascade three talented Research Associates...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/transportation/metro-council-votes-to-approve-88-5-million-bond-for-road-diets-one-interns-reflection/"&gt;Metro Council Votes to Approve $88.5 Million Bond for Road Diets: One Intern’s Reflection  &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 22:37:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Public is following ‘Russiagate’ developments</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/public-is-following-russiagate-developments/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Miranda Devine writes for the New York Post about public interest in recent political revelations. Despite the best efforts of Russiagate-complicit media to dismiss as “Russian disinformation” the latest revelations in this escalating scandal implicating President Barack Obama and Hillary Clinton in the treasonous “years-long coup” against President Trump, the public is paying attention and...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/public-is-following-russiagate-developments/"&gt;Public is following ‘Russiagate’ developments&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 09:42:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Public tools make state government more transparent</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/public-tools-make-state-government-more-transparent</link><description>You don’t need a press pass to keep an eye on state agencies</description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] California Goes Groucho On Gasoline</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/california-goes-groucho-on-gasoline/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;What did California officials think was going to happen when they decided it was a dazzlingly brilliant idea to hound the oil industry out of the state? That magic would take over and there would be no consequences for their rash decisions? Apparently, they weren’t thinking at all, because, according to reports, the California Energy Commission (CEC) is looking for [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/california-goes-groucho-on-gasoline/"&gt;California Goes Groucho On Gasoline&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 10:00:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/08/the-outstater-280/</link><description>The Legislative Experiment “Decrepitude remains the path of least resistance for the institution that is supposed to be the beating heart of American self-government.”&amp;#160;— Phillip Wallach WE ALL ARE TIRED&amp;#160;of complaining about Congress so let’s abandon it as sunk cost. We may be obligated to maintain the payroll and provide a place for it to&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/08/the-outstater-280/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 11:34:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Grassroot marks Lahaina anniversary with more ways to speed up recovery</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/08/grassroot-marks-lahaina-anniversary-with-more-ways-to-speed-up-recovery/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been two years since wildfires devastated the West Maui town, yet few structures have been rebuilt and many residents remain in limbo HONOLULU, Aug. 5, 2025 &amp;#62;&amp;#62; As the second anniversary approaches of the wildfires that destroyed much of Maui’s beloved Lahaina town, the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii has released a policy brief detailing [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/08/grassroot-marks-lahaina-anniversary-with-more-ways-to-speed-up-recovery/"&gt;Grassroot marks Lahaina anniversary with more ways to speed up recovery&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 13:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Minnesota’s persistent budget deficits, not the big beautiful bill, are the real threat to Medicaid</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/minnesotas-persistent-budget-deficits-not-the-big-beautiful-bill-are-the-real-threat-to-medicaid/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As horror stories continue to circulate about the thousands who could lose Medicaid coverage due to the &amp;#8220;work requirements&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;eligibility checks&amp;#8221; in the One Big Beautiful Bill (OBBB), two points are worth emphasizing. First, Minnesotans support these Medicaid provisions. A Thinking Minnesota survey conducted in May found, for instance, that over half of all...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/minnesotas-persistent-budget-deficits-not-the-big-beautiful-bill-are-the-real-threat-to-medicaid/"&gt;Minnesota&amp;#8217;s persistent budget deficits, not the big beautiful bill, are the real threat to Medicaid&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Speaker White: Game on for School Choice in Mississippi</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/speaker-white-game-on-for-school-choice-in-mississippi/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Neshoba County Fair is a Mississippi tradition, bringing together thousands of folk at the height of summer for a week of Southern celebration—music, dancing, food, cattle shows, horse racing, and, of course, politics. &amp;#160;Ever since Ronald Reagan kicked off his 1980 presidential campaign at the Fair, it’s been&amp;#160;the&amp;#160;place where public officials in our state [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/speaker-white-game-on-for-school-choice-in-mississippi/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Speaker White: Game on for School Choice in Mississippi&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 14:38:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] New Report Finds Pennsylvania Violating Law, Endangering Students in Dangerous Schools</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/08/05/new-report-finds-pennsylvania-violating-law-endangering-students-in-dangerous-schools/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;CORRECTION: A previous version of this release did not include a link to the new report. The link has been added below.&amp;#160; Harrisburg, Pa., August 5, 2025—The Pennsylvania Department of Education (PDE) is violating state and federal law around “persistently dangerous schools,” endangering the safety of Pennsylvania’s most vulnerable students, and threatening billions in federal [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/08/05/new-report-finds-pennsylvania-violating-law-endangering-students-in-dangerous-schools/"&gt;New Report Finds Pennsylvania Violating Law, Endangering Students in Dangerous Schools&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 14:42:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Fact Check: DOJ Election Oversight Has Constitutional Basis, Despite Bellows’ Claims</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/fact-check-doj-election-oversight-has-constitutional-basis-despite-bellows-claims/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When news broke that the U.S. Department of Justice (DOJ) under the Trump administration had issued a request for voter registration data from all 50 states, including Maine, Secretary of State Shenna Bellows wasted no time grabbing headlines, calling the move unprecedented and claiming “It’s an abuse of power and it contravenes what the founders [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/fact-check-doj-election-oversight-has-constitutional-basis-despite-bellows-claims/"&gt;Fact Check: DOJ Election Oversight Has Constitutional Basis, Despite Bellows&amp;#8217; Claims&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 15:31:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Chicago mayor recycles failed tax idea to fix $1.12B deficit</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/chicago-mayor-recycles-failed-tax-idea-to-fix-1-12b-deficit/</link><description>As Chicago faces a major deficit for fiscal year 2026, Mayor Brandon Johnson is considering resurrecting a failed idea that punishes job creation: the corporate head tax.</description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 16:57:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Market prices are essential to a free, flourishing society</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/market-prices-are-essential-to-a-free-flourishing-society/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;All economic goods must, by definition, be allocated by some mechanism. Because the world’s resources are insufficient to satisfy all human wants, some process must be used to determine to what end these resources are to be utilized. How a society confronts this reality of scarcity determines its level of prosperity. It can ultimately make...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/market-prices-are-essential-to-a-free-flourishing-society/"&gt;Market prices are essential to a free, flourishing society&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Frontierinstitute] Fiscally Crying Wolf</title><link>https://frontierinstitute.org/fiscally-crying-wolf/</link><description>"Trimming $350 Million from a $16 billion state budget is small potatoes, not the sky falling. If anything, our federal and state governments should be focused on eliminating even more spending to protect taxpayers."</description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 17:00:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Dollars Over Optics: Rethinking Local Government Spending</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/dollars-over-optics-rethinking-local-government-spending/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Despite falling property tax rates, cities like Jefferson, Iowa are quietly expanding spending and government roles, creating the illusion of fiscal restraint while drifting from core responsibilities due to vague missions and unnecessary projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Across Iowa, local leaders often point proudly to declining property tax rates as evidence of fiscal responsibility. But what those numbers hide is the quiet rise in actual government spending — and a fundamental shift in how cities define their role. The City of Jefferson offers a clear example of this disconnect between perception and reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/dollars-over-optics-rethinking-local-government-spending/"&gt;Dollars Over Optics: Rethinking Local Government Spending&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 17:14:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] New Report: Michigan’s Green Energy Plan Means Higher Bills, More Blackouts</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/pressroom/2025/new-report-michigans-green-energy-plan-means-higher-bills-more-blackouts</link><description>Experts urge pause on plant closures, push for grid reliability standards</description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Back to School: A New Chapter of Hope and Opportunity</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/back-to-school/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=back-to-school</link><description>As the school year begins, let’s celebrate not only a fresh start but also the "hope and opportunity" available to Tennessee families as new chapters open.</description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 17:53:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Herbert Hoover’s American Exceptionalism</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/herbert-hoovers-american-exceptionalism/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The idea of American exceptionalism is a strong cord in our history, especially within the philosophy of American conservatism. Conservatives from the Puritans to Alexander Hamilton to President Ronald Reagan have championed the principle that the United States was divinely created as a “shining city upon a hill” and beacon of liberty. As Herbert Hoover wrote, “the Founding Fathers consecrated a new republic ‘under the protection of Divine Providence.’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/herbert-hoovers-american-exceptionalism/"&gt;Herbert Hoover&amp;#8217;s American Exceptionalism&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 18:16:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Red Lines, Blue Tears: The Texas Map MELTDOWN</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/red-lines-blue-tears-the-texas-map-meltdown/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome back to the American Experiment Podcast! Today, Grace, Kathryn, and Bill dive deep into the politics of gerrymandering. First, Bill takes us behind the scenes of the congressional mapmaking process, sharing stories and insights from his time at the Capitol. Then, the trio analyzes the congressional maps of Minnesota, Texas, and Illinois—yes, the state...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/red-lines-blue-tears-the-texas-map-meltdown/"&gt;Red Lines, Blue Tears: The Texas Map MELTDOWN&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 19:04:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Blatant Lawlessness</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/08/05/blatant-lawlessness/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="702" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/Fat-Cat.jpg" width="936" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new Yankee Institute report, Blatant Lawlessness: How the CT Department of Labor &amp;#38; Union Leaders Disrespect Union Workers and Ignore the Law, exposes the Connecticut Department of Labor’s (CT [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/08/05/blatant-lawlessness/"&gt;Blatant Lawlessness&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 20:35:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Herbert Hoover and the American founding</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/herbert-hoover-and-the-american-founding/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/herbert-hoover-and-the-american-founding/"&gt;Herbert Hoover and the American founding&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 20:43:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Speaker Jason White: Education Freedom and Mississippi’s Future</title><link>https://empowerms.org/speaker-jason-white-education-freedom-and-mississippis-future/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Speaker Jason White: Education Freedom and Mississippi&amp;#8217;s Future Fresh off his speech at the Neshoba County Fair, Mississippi&amp;#8217;s 62nd Speaker of the House, Jason White joins host Grant Callen for this episode of the Empower Podcast. We recap his fair speech and talk about the experience of walking out on that storied stage at Neshoba.&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/speaker-jason-white-education-freedom-and-mississippis-future/"&gt;Speaker Jason White: Education Freedom and Mississippi’s Future&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 21:13:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] NC at risk: Assessing academic achievement in the Carolinas</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/nc-at-risk-assessing-academic-achievement-in-the-carolinas/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A new report shows that students across the Carolinas face many of the same problems identified by the Reagan administration in its landmark report A Nation at Risk more than 40 years ago. The report, a collaboration between the John Locke Foundation, the South Carolina Policy Council, Palmetto Promise Institute, and the Carolinas Academic Leadership...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/nc-at-risk-assessing-academic-achievement-in-the-carolinas/"&gt;NC at risk: Assessing academic achievement in the Carolinas&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 22:03:08 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>