<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>State-Policy Think-Tank Digest</title><link>https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml</link><description>Latest posts from free-market policy institutes across the U.S.</description><atom:link href="https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2025 05:05:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>[Arkansaspolicyfoundation] RIGHT TO TRY 2.0</title><link>https://arkansaspolicyfoundation.org/right-to-try-2-0/</link><description>RIGHT TO TRY 2.0   (2025-2Q) The idea behind Right-To-Try is that &amp;#8220;terminally ill patients who have exhausted their government-approved options&amp;#8221; should have the freedom to access treatments that may help them.(1)  The idea originated with the Goldwater Institute of Arizona, a member of the State Policy Network (SPN), a market-based group that includes the [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 06:11:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Virginiainstitute] How to navigate and improve Virginia’s education options</title><link>https://virginiainstitute.org/how-to-navigate-and-improve-virginias-education-options/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=how-to-navigate-and-improve-virginias-education-options</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 14:25:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Virginiainstitute] Elections in Virginia: Your Guide to Navigating the Law</title><link>https://virginiainstitute.org/elections-in-virginia-your-guide-to-navigating-the-law/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=elections-in-virginia-your-guide-to-navigating-the-law</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Lindsey Zea Senior Fellow Dr. Clara Belle Wheeler Senior Fellow&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org/elections-in-virginia-your-guide-to-navigating-the-law/"&gt;Elections in Virginia: Your Guide to Navigating the Law&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org"&gt;Virginia Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 14:49:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Rifreedom] Center CEO Mike Stenhouse To Be Inducted Into College Baseball Hall Of Fame</title><link>https://rifreedom.org/2025/06/center-ceo-mike-stenhouse-to-be-inducted-into-college-baseball-hall-of-fame/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;?The Rhode Island Center for Freedom &amp;#38; Prosperity Congratulates CEO Mike Stenhouse on Induction into College Baseball Hall of Fame Providence, RI &amp;#8211; The Rhode Island Center for Freedom &amp;#38; [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org/2025/06/center-ceo-mike-stenhouse-to-be-inducted-into-college-baseball-hall-of-fame/"&gt;Center CEO Mike Stenhouse To Be Inducted Into College Baseball Hall Of Fame&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org"&gt;RI Center for Freedom and Prosperity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 18:23:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alaskapolicyforum] Alaska’s schools are rolling in cash, so why aren’t the results better?</title><link>https://alaskapolicyforum.org/2025/06/alaskas-schools-are-rolling-in-cash-so-why-arent-the-results-better/#utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=alaskas-schools-are-rolling-in-cash-so-why-arent-the-results-better</link><description>&lt;div style="margin: 5px 5% 10px 5%;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" height="1707" src="https://alaskapolicyforum.org/wp-content/uploads/Money-scaled.jpg" title="" width="2560" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alaska was ranked the second most adequately funded school system in the US by a 2024 study from Rutgers University. The rest of the story — the study actually understates how well neighborhood schoolsRead More&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alaskapolicyforum.org/2025/06/alaskas-schools-are-rolling-in-cash-so-why-arent-the-results-better/"&gt;Alaska’s schools are rolling in cash, so why aren’t the results better?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://alaskapolicyforum.org"&gt;Alaska Policy Forum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 02:25:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Virginiainstitute] Press Release – VIPP Champions AI Moratorium, Invokes Commerce Clause</title><link>https://virginiainstitute.org/5850-2/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=5850-2</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Virginia Institute for Public Policy’s statement for memorandum highlights the urgent need for a coordinated federal approach to AI regulation, leveraging constitutional authority to avoid a fragmented and counterproductive patchwork of state laws. The proposed moratorium offers a pragmatic pathway to safeguard innovation, support small businesses, and ensure U.S. leadership in the rapidly evolving global AI landscape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org/5850-2/"&gt;Press Release – VIPP Champions AI Moratorium, Invokes Commerce Clause&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org"&gt;Virginia Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 14:10:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cardinalinstitute] Colleges Must Educate for Freedom</title><link>https://cardinalinstitute.com/colleges-must-educate-for-freedom/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Colleges Must Educate for Freedom A great American college or university will prepare students for self-governance as both a wise human being and a prudent, productive citizen. Rightly understood, the liberal arts are the intellectual potentials shared by the leaders of a free people. That is, education policy should consider, first of all, how to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com/colleges-must-educate-for-freedom/"&gt;Colleges Must Educate for Freedom&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com"&gt;Cardinal Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 16:31:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Education Freedom: A Lifeline for Tennessee Families</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/education-freedom-a-lifeline-for-tennessee-families/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=education-freedom-a-lifeline-for-tennessee-families</link><description>Education Freedom Scholarships won’t just change where kids go to school. They’ll change who they become.</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 18:15:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Arkansaspolicyfoundation] MEDICAL CARE IDEAS ADVANCE</title><link>https://arkansaspolicyfoundation.org/medical-care-ideas-advance/</link><description>(2025-2Q) The Arkansas Policy Foundation was founded by business leaders to serve the community and advance ideas to create more prosperity for Arkansans. The Policy Foundation was founded 30 years ago as a 501(c)(3) nonprofit, nonpartisan think tank that publishes credible research, hosts forums to encourage citizenship and is cited in national and state news [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 06:09:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Frontierinstitute] Recent Permitting Reforms Are Protecting Property Rights</title><link>https://frontierinstitute.org/recent-permitting-reforms-are-protecting-property-rights/</link><description>"What property rights are unequivocally not, however, is a license to control what others do with their own property."</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 18:27:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] A better way to get welfare recipients back into the labor force</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/better-way-to-get-welfare-recipients-back-into-labor-force/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;If the One Big Beautiful Bill becomes law, states will quickly discover that their administrative systems are ill-equipped to move recipients from welfare to work. To succeed, states should adopt a more integrated approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/better-way-to-get-welfare-recipients-back-into-labor-force/"&gt;A better way to get welfare recipients back into the labor force&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 07:20:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] 2025 City Freedom Index: How Free is Your City?</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/2025-city-freedom-index/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=2025-city-freedom-index</link><description>In 2020, Beacon released its first-ever City Freedom Index to shed light on the ways taxpayers are impacted by local government policies. Five years and many changed local policies later, the time has come for an update.</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 11:30:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] WATCH: Megan Martin on PCN Discussing State Budget, Mass Transit Bail-out, and More</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/07/01/watch-megan-martin-on-pcn-discussing-state-budget-mass-transit-bail-out-and-more/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Megan Martin, Commonwealth Foundation&amp;#8217;s Chief Operating Officer and General Counsel, joins PCN&amp;#8217;s Capitol Preview to talk all things state budget. From public transit to Lifeline Scholarships, Martin outlines what good looks like in this year&amp;#8217;s budget, and which proposals will damage Pennsylvania&amp;#8217;s economic future. Watch below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/07/01/watch-megan-martin-on-pcn-discussing-state-budget-mass-transit-bail-out-and-more/"&gt;WATCH: Megan Martin on PCN Discussing State Budget, Mass Transit Bail-out, and More&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 13:27:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] How both sides lost the ConVal school funding case</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/07/how-both-sides-lost-the-conval-school-funding-case/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday morning, the New Hampshire Supreme Court for the first time ordered the state to spend a minimum amount of money—$7,356.01 per pupil—to educate public school students.  The state therefore lost this landmark school funding case, Contoocook Valley School District v. State, as it had tried to avoid such a decree. But a closer [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/07/how-both-sides-lost-the-conval-school-funding-case/"&gt;How both sides lost the ConVal school funding case&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 17:57:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Voters Aren’t Interested in New Transportation Taxes</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/transportation/voters-arent-interested-in-new-transportation-taxes/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By John A. Charles, Jr. The Oregon legislature ended on June 27 without...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/transportation/voters-arent-interested-in-new-transportation-taxes/"&gt;Voters Aren’t Interested in New Transportation Taxes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 14:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Press Release: Mississippi Center for Public Policy Named Finalist for National Bob Williams Award</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/press-release-mississippi-center-for-public-policy-named-finalist-for-national-bob-williams-award/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE (Jackson, MS) Mississippi Center for Public Policy Named Finalist for National Bob Williams Award The Mississippi Center for Public Policy (MCPP) has been selected as a finalist for the prestigious Bob Williams Award for Outstanding Policy Achievement in the “Biggest Home State Win” category. This national recognition, awarded by the State Policy [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/press-release-mississippi-center-for-public-policy-named-finalist-for-national-bob-williams-award/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Press Release: Mississippi Center for Public Policy Named Finalist for National Bob Williams Award&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 15:02:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Closing the Gap: How Wisconsin’s Budget Continues to Close the Funding Gap Between Public &amp; Parental Choice Options</title><link>https://will-law.org/closing-the-gap-how-wisconsins-budget-continues-to-close-the-funding-gap-between-public-parental-choice-options/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Like any budget that is a result of compromise in divided government, there are positive and negative aspects.  But one definite positive to come from this year's budget agreement is the continued closing of the spending gap between private, charter, and traditional public schools.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/closing-the-gap-how-wisconsins-budget-continues-to-close-the-funding-gap-between-public-parental-choice-options/"&gt;Closing the Gap: How Wisconsin’s Budget Continues to Close the Funding Gap Between Public &amp;#038; Parental Choice Options&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 18:57:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Welfare stands in the way of the American dream</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/welfare-stands-in-the-way-of-the-american-dream/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Meaningful relationships and a strong sense of community are as much a part of the American dream as any economic measure. What’s rarely discussed is how systemic obstacles are undermining these important aspects of a flourishing life. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/welfare-stands-in-the-way-of-the-american-dream/"&gt;Welfare stands in the way of the American dream&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 18:55:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] OBBB Delivers Historic Expansion of Educational Choice, Sweeping Reforms</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/07/03/obbb-delivers-historic-expansion-of-educational-choice-sweeping-reforms/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Harrisburg, Pa., July 3, 2025 —&amp;#160;After much anticipation and debate, the One Big, Beautiful Bill (OBBB) is now passed and set to be enacted—delivering policy accomplishments that Pennsylvanians can celebrate: Protecting Taxpayers: Preventing an average $2,500 tax hike per Pennsylvania taxpayer. Nearly every Pennsylvanian has benefited from the 2017 Tax Cuts and Job Act, which [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/07/03/obbb-delivers-historic-expansion-of-educational-choice-sweeping-reforms/"&gt;OBBB Delivers Historic Expansion of Educational Choice, Sweeping Reforms&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 19:17:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Are we witnessing a Baltimore Miracle in the fight against crime?</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/baltimore-miracle-in-fight-against-crime/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Baltimore has struggled with crime, especially drugs and violent crime, in both reality and in the imaginations of the American people for decades. That is, until recently. What changed and what can other high-crime cities learn from Baltimore's approach? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/baltimore-miracle-in-fight-against-crime/"&gt;Are we witnessing a Baltimore Miracle in the fight against crime?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 19:33:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Fiscal Restraint Worked. So Obviously, It Has to Go</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/07/03/fiscal-restraint-worked-so-obviously-it-has-to-go/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The General Assembly adjourned less than a month ago, but progressive activists are already calling for more taxes, more spending, and another round of fiscal recklessness — wasting no time [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/07/03/fiscal-restraint-worked-so-obviously-it-has-to-go/"&gt;Fiscal Restraint Worked. So Obviously, It Has to Go &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 19:35:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] Tipping Point NM episode 722 Daniel Chavez – Candidate for Mayor of Albuquerque</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/tipping-point-nm-episode-722-daniel-chavez-candidate-for-mayor-of-albuquerque/</link><description>&lt;p&gt; Albuquerque Mayoral candidate Daniel Chavez has completed the Rio Grande Foundation&amp;#8217;s candidate survey.  You can find that completed survey here and below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/tipping-point-nm-episode-722-daniel-chavez-candidate-for-mayor-of-albuquerque/"&gt;Tipping Point NM episode 722 Daniel Chavez – Candidate for Mayor of Albuquerque&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 19:38:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] Franke: Population Worries</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/07/franke-population-worries/</link><description>by Mark Franke During the 50 plus years of my adult lifetime, world population has been an issue but with a change in perspective. In the 1960s the concern was uncontrolled and unsupportable growth especially in the poorer parts of the globe. The doomsayers predicted mass starvation and other unpleasant outcomes unless the rate of&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/07/franke-population-worries/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2025 22:06:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] New school finance formula should focus on accountability</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/new-school-finance-accountability/</link><description>Funding for public K-12 education is complex—let alone increasing every year. The formula for determining how much money each district receives– available here – requires an Excel workbook with 12 individual spreadsheets. The main spreadsheet, Legalmax, is essentially a roll-up of the other 11. It takes 85 columns of data to determine the Legalmax and [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 14:00:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] A Game-Changer for School Choice in Our State!</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/a-game-changer-for-school-choice-in-our-state/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Some groundbreaking news for Mississippi!&amp;#160; With the passage of the&amp;#160;One Big Beautiful Bill, a federal tax credit is due to transform the school choice landscape in our state. &amp;#160;This new tax credit enables individual donors to fund scholarships for local Mississippi families, who will now be able to select the schools that best suit their [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/a-game-changer-for-school-choice-in-our-state/" rel="nofollow"&gt;A Game-Changer for School Choice in Our State!&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 17:57:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] 97 NYSLRS Retirees Eligible for Pensions Over $200K in FY2025</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/97-nyslrs-retirees-eligible-for-pensions-over-200k-in-fy2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A total of 97 retirees from the New York State and Local Retirement System (NYSLRS) were eligible for pensions of....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/97-nyslrs-retirees-eligible-for-pensions-over-200k-in-fy2025/"&gt;97 NYSLRS Retirees Eligible for Pensions Over $200K in FY2025&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 13:50:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] Court Watch: Wisconsin Supreme Court Concentrates Even More Power in the Evers Administration</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/court-watch-wisconsin-supreme-court-concentrates-even-more-power-in-the-evers-administration/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Court Watch: Wisconsin Supreme Court Concentrates Even More Power in the Evers Administration Ruling in Evers v. Marklein takes away ability of legislature’s JCRAR Committee to suspend administrative rules Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government (IRG) released the following statement following the Wisconsin Supreme Court’s ruling in Evers v. Marklein. The majority’s decision [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/court-watch-wisconsin-supreme-court-concentrates-even-more-power-in-the-evers-administration/"&gt;Court Watch: Wisconsin Supreme Court Concentrates Even More Power in the Evers Administration&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 15:03:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Frontierinstitute] Montana Leading with Free Market Healthcare</title><link>https://frontierinstitute.org/montana-leading-with-free-market-healthcare/</link><description>By eliminating the middlemen and bureaucracy involved in billing third parties, DPC providers are able to save patients money and focus on their health while also being radically transparent with their prices – a breath of fresh air in today’s modern healthcare world.</description><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 18:26:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Dr. Keri Ingraham: Industry-Specific High Schools</title><link>https://empowerms.org/dr-keri-ingraham-industry-specific-high-schools/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Dr. Keri Ingraham: Industry-Specific High Schools Join us on the Empower Podcast as we dive into the transformative world of industry-specific high schools with Dr. Keri Ingraham, whose recent policy brief at the American Enterprise Institute, “The Case for Industry-Specific High Schools,” is sparking conversation. In this episode, Dr. Ingraham explains why these specialized schools&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/dr-keri-ingraham-industry-specific-high-schools/"&gt;Dr. Keri Ingraham: Industry-Specific High Schools&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 01:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] KSDE denies lowering standards despite implausible proficiency gains</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/ksde-denies-lowering-standards/</link><description>Kansas Department of Education (KSDE) staff put on a master class of political spin and deception at yesterday’s meeting of the State Board of Education. Board members were given the 2025 state assessment results based on a new test and cut scores to determine achievement levels, and were told to ignore conflicting historical results and [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 13:08:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] HB 2089 Brings Oregon into Compliance with the Supreme Court’s Tyler Ruling on Property Rights and Home Equity</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/tax-and-budget/hb-2089-brings-oregon-into-compliance-with-the-supreme-courts-tyler-ruling-on-property-rights-and-home-equity/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Kathryn Hickok With the passage of House Bill 2089 in late June,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/tax-and-budget/hb-2089-brings-oregon-into-compliance-with-the-supreme-courts-tyler-ruling-on-property-rights-and-home-equity/"&gt;HB 2089 Brings Oregon into Compliance with the Supreme Court’s Tyler Ruling on Property Rights and Home Equity&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 14:06:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] Tim Walz Leaves Minnesotans on the Hook for a $430,000 Legal Bill</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/tim-walz-leaves-minnesotans-on-the-hook-for-a-430000-legal-bill/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Minnesota Gov. Tim Walz already has taxpayer-funded legal counsel. Additionally, he has access to the Attorney General&amp;#8217;s office. Yet, Minnesota taxpayers are now left to foot a $430,000 legal bill from outside lawyers that Walz racked up trying to prepare for a congressional hearing where he provided testimony on his Sanctuary City illegal immigration policies. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/tim-walz-leaves-minnesotans-on-the-hook-for-a-430000-legal-bill/"&gt;Tim Walz Leaves Minnesotans on the Hook for a $430,000 Legal Bill&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 19:22:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG Poll: Wisconsin Has a New State Budget; Voters Want Specific Solutions Next</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-poll-wisconsin-has-a-new-state-budget-voters-want-specific-solutions-next/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;IRG Poll: Wisconsin Has a New State Budget; Voters Want Specific Solutions Next   High approval ratings may give politicians comfort, but won’t pay the bills  Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government (IRG) is continuing its public polling project with Napolitan News Service and Scott Rasmussen in 2025, with the focus in this poll [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-poll-wisconsin-has-a-new-state-budget-voters-want-specific-solutions-next/"&gt;IRG Poll: Wisconsin Has a New State Budget; Voters Want Specific Solutions Next&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 20:44:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] What the “One Big Beautiful Bill Act” Means for School Choice in Mississippi</title><link>https://empowerms.org/what-the-one-big-beautiful-bill-act-means-for-school-choice-in-mississippi/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;There are two aspects to the school choice provisions in the OBBB: a tax credit for contributions to organizations that provide scholarships to students in public or private schools, and rules those organizations have to follow in granting scholarships (including eligibility of scholarship students).  Tax Credit for Contributions  Starting in 2027, an individual taxpayer (not&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/what-the-one-big-beautiful-bill-act-means-for-school-choice-in-mississippi/"&gt;What the “One Big Beautiful Bill Act” Means for School Choice in Mississippi&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 21:47:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Silver Linings, Not Silver Bullets</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/silver-linings-not-silver-bullets/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;At the end of June, the Supreme Court of the United States reached its decision in Free Speech Coalition v. Paxton, ruling in favor of a Texas law that requires age verification for access to websites that host explicit content. The decision is a break from precedent and presents a heightened risk to user privacy,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/silver-linings-not-silver-bullets/"&gt;Silver Linings, Not Silver Bullets&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 13:13:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] NJ SPOTLIGHT: Marathon school segregation case goes to appeals court</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/07/nj-spotlight-marathon-school-segregation-case-goes-to-appeals-court/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In this NJ Spotlight News piece, the long-running New Jersey school segregation case moves to the Appellate Division. As the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/07/nj-spotlight-marathon-school-segregation-case-goes-to-appeals-court/"&gt;NJ SPOTLIGHT: Marathon school segregation case goes to appeals court&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 15:56:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] NORTHJERSEY.COM: Appeals court to hear arguments in NJ school segregation lawsuit</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/07/northjersey-com-appeals-court-to-hear-arguments-in-nj-school-segregation-lawsuit/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In this NorthJersey.com article, the New Jersey appellate court prepares to hear arguments in the high‑profile school segregation lawsuit filed [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/07/northjersey-com-appeals-court-to-hear-arguments-in-nj-school-segregation-lawsuit/"&gt;NORTHJERSEY.COM: Appeals court to hear arguments in NJ school segregation lawsuit&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 16:00:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Increase property tax exemption for homeowners age 65 and older</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/07/increase-property-tax-exemption-for-homeowners-age-65-and-older/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Honolulu City Council on July 9, 2025._____________ July 9, 2025, 10 a.m.Honolulu Hale To: Honolulu City Council       Tommy Waters, Chair       Andria Tupola, Vice Chair From: Grassroot Institute of Hawaii            Ted Kefalas, Director of Strategic Campaigns RE: Bill 49 (2025) — [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/07/increase-property-tax-exemption-for-homeowners-age-65-and-older/"&gt;Increase property tax exemption for homeowners age 65 and older&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 16:30:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] Congressional Republicans Call Out Walz’s ‘Wasted Taxpayer Money’</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/congressional-republicans-call-out-walzs-wasted-taxpayer-money/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Minnesota Republicans criticized the use of taxpayer funds for the legal counsel, with U.S. House Majority Whip Tom Emmer calling the governor a “scam artist” and Rep. Pete Stauber saying, “more wasted taxpayer money by the ‘knucklehead.’” It&amp;#8217;s extremely disappointing that the governor felt the need to burn nearly half a million dollars of taxpayer [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/congressional-republicans-call-out-walzs-wasted-taxpayer-money/"&gt;Congressional Republicans Call Out Walz&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8216;Wasted Taxpayer Money&amp;#8217;&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 18:39:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Antiquated Wisconsin law doesn’t allow driverless vehicles</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/antiquated-wisconsin-law-doesnt-allow-driverless-vehicles/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As self-driving taxis roll out across much of America, Wisconsinites won’t be seeing them without some changes to existing law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/antiquated-wisconsin-law-doesnt-allow-driverless-vehicles/"&gt;Antiquated Wisconsin law doesn’t allow driverless vehicles&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 21:37:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] Albuquerque Mayoral Candidate Eddie Varela completes RGF candidate survey</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/albuquerque-mayoral-candidate-eddie-varela-completes-rgf-candidate-survey/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In its ongoing efforts to ensure that voters are fully informed about the views and plans of the various candidates for Albuquerque Mayor. The latest candidate to respond is Eddie Varela. His survey can be found here. Varela&amp;#8217;s campaign website can be accessed here. You can also see images of Varela&amp;#8217;s survey answers below: &amp;#160; [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/albuquerque-mayoral-candidate-eddie-varela-completes-rgf-candidate-survey/"&gt;Albuquerque Mayoral Candidate Eddie Varela completes RGF candidate survey&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 22:32:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] Sec. Simon Should Hop Off the Ranked-Choice Voting Train</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/sec-simon-should-hop-off-the-ranked-choice-voting-train/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Ranked-Choice Voting must be rejected when it presents itself in Minnesota. Our republic deserves no less than our willingness to educate voters about this failed voting system and to resist misguided efforts like Sec. Simons who wants to expand this radical scheme to all Minnesota cities and counties. &amp;#8212; Secretary of State backs legislation to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/sec-simon-should-hop-off-the-ranked-choice-voting-train/"&gt;Sec. Simon Should Hop Off the Ranked-Choice Voting Train&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 13:13:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] A Tale of Two Budgets: How Maine and New Hampshire’s Latest Spending Plans Compare</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/a-tale-of-two-budgets-how-maine-and-new-hampshires-latest-spending-plans-compare/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Maine and New Hampshire share a border, but when it comes to fiscal policy, taxation, and education, they live in two totally different worlds. While Maine raises taxes and grows government to chase underwhelming outcomes, New Hampshire delivers superior services—especially in education—while maintaining no state sales or individual income taxes. That contrast has never been [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/a-tale-of-two-budgets-how-maine-and-new-hampshires-latest-spending-plans-compare/"&gt;A Tale of Two Budgets: How Maine and New Hampshire&amp;#8217;s Latest Spending Plans Compare&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 13:44:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] In Special Session, West Hartford Democrats Set Sights on Fiscal Guardrails — Again</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/07/11/in-special-session-west-hartford-democrats-set-sights-on-fiscal-guardrails-again/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you thought Connecticut’s fiscal guardrails were safe, think again.   At a post-session town hall in West Hartford on July 8, local Democratic legislators made it abundantly clear that [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/07/11/in-special-session-west-hartford-democrats-set-sights-on-fiscal-guardrails-again/"&gt;In Special Session, West Hartford Democrats Set Sights on Fiscal Guardrails — Again &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 15:25:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Average Pay at Port Authority Surges as 11 Employees Collect $400k+</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/average-pay-at-panynj-surges-as-11-employees-collect-400k/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Eleven Port Authority of New York and New Jersey (PANYNJ) employees collected more than $400,000 each in total pay last....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/average-pay-at-panynj-surges-as-11-employees-collect-400k/"&gt;Average Pay at Port Authority Surges as 11 Employees Collect $400k+&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 15:40:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] A quiet victory: Trump rule protecting federal workers survives Biden’s presidency</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/labor/a-quiet-victory-trump-rule-protecting-federal-workers-survives-bidens-presidency/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;It took two years to find out, but it turns out the Freedom Foundation helped ensure the quiet defeat of a Biden proposal to trap federal workers in unions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/labor/a-quiet-victory-trump-rule-protecting-federal-workers-survives-bidens-presidency/" rel="nofollow"&gt;A quiet victory: Trump rule protecting federal workers survives Biden’s presidency&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 17:30:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/07/14041/</link><description>Urban Life: Shoplifting HOW ARE THINGS GOING?&amp;#160;Well, few venture out after dusk&amp;#160;on&amp;#160;our multi-million-dollar trail system;&amp;#160;there are stabbings at&amp;#160;Promenade&amp;#160;Park, if that tells you anything;&amp;#160;shootings threaten to become&amp;#160;routine&amp;#160;on the streets below our&amp;#160;majestic new downtown constructions; and there is shoplifting and theft throughout. At some point we are going to have to face a sad fact, that is,&amp;#160;there&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/07/14041/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 18:12:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Legislature passes 15 housing reform bills in 2025</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/07/legislature-passes-15-housing-reform-bills-in-2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Five years ago, there was little action in the Legislature to address the decades-long rising cost of housing in New Hampshire. St. Anselm College polling found in 2020 that voters hadn&amp;#8217;t yet connected surging prices to local land use regulations. Only 28.7% of voters said local governments should relax planning and zoning rules to allow [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/07/legislature-passes-15-housing-reform-bills-in-2025/"&gt;Legislature passes 15 housing reform bills in 2025&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 18:34:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] California: Three straight record-shattering months and counting</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/california/california-three-straight-record-shattering-months-and-counting/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Freedom Foundation’s California outreach team in June broke another record for opt-outs, with over 2,700 opt outs, making it three consecutive months of incredible growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/california/california-three-straight-record-shattering-months-and-counting/" rel="nofollow"&gt;California: Three straight record-shattering months and counting&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 21:08:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] The Answer is “Cowardice”</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/the-answer-is-cowardice/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/the-answer-is-cowardice/" rel="nofollow" title="The Answer is “Cowardice”"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Article-Headers-2025-07-10T140332.879.png" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Want to know what happens in an Idaho Freedom Foundation team meeting? Here’s a glimpse.&amp;#160; The question was asked, “If Argentina can cut its government and spending by 28% in one year, why can’t Idaho do that or more?” Without missing a beat, “The answer is ‘cowardice,’” rang out from one (unnamed) freedom fighter. And [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 21:45:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] JMI 2025 Legislative Wrap-Up</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/jmi-2025-legislative-wrap-up/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Center for Technology and Innovation Marshall Center for Education Freedom Gibbs Center for Economic Prosperity Find the full...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/jmi-2025-legislative-wrap-up/"&gt;JMI 2025 Legislative Wrap-Up&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 04:01:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] New transparency law a major win for Maine taxpayers</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/new-transparency-law-a-major-win-for-maine-taxpayers/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;At the end of the most recent legislative session, the Maine Legislature passed LD 857, “An Act to Increase Government Transparency in the Procurement of Goods and Services.” Gov. Janet Mills chose to allow the bill to become law without her signature.  LD 857 is a win for Maine because it increases government transparency in [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/new-transparency-law-a-major-win-for-maine-taxpayers/"&gt;New transparency law a major win for Maine taxpayers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 17:15:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Frontierinstitute] Mike Mansfield and the Japanese</title><link>https://frontierinstitute.org/mike-mansfield-and-the-japanese/</link><description>"In 1988, on behalf of America and with Mike Mansfield’s support, President Ronald Reagan formally apologized for the internments and publicly admitted they were not justified."</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 17:43:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Mississippi’s Moment: Bold Reforms to Drive Growth</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/mississippis-moment-bold-reforms-to-drive-growth/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Mississippi is shedding its image as an economic laggard. Over the past five years, the state’s economic output has grown more than it did over the previous fifteen years combined. According to the U.S. Bureau of Economic Analysis, Mississippi posted the second-fastest per capita GDP growth and fifth-fastest personal income growth among all states in [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/mississippis-moment-bold-reforms-to-drive-growth/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi’s Moment: Bold Reforms to Drive Growth&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 17:49:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Is “Big” Really Bad? What Critics Miss About Big Oil, Big Tech, and Big Pharma</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/tax-budget/is-big-really-bad-what-critics-miss-about-big-oil-big-tech-and-big-pharma/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Every few months, headlines warn us about the dangers of “Big” something—Big Oil, Big Tech, Big Pharma. The narrative is familiar: powerful corporations exploit consumers, stifle innovation, and corrupt our politics. But is being big really bad? Not necessarily. In fact, in a truly free-market system, size often reflects success—earned by serving consumers well, innovating,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/tax-budget/is-big-really-bad-what-critics-miss-about-big-oil-big-tech-and-big-pharma/"&gt;Is “Big” Really Bad? What Critics Miss About Big Oil, Big Tech, and Big Pharma&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 19:41:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Permitting progress prevails</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/07/permitting-progress-prevails/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;After years of complaints and horror stories, policymakers can finally say they’ve taken decisive action to address Hawaii’s notorious permitting delays. SB66, now Act 295, might not be as attention-grabbing as big tax cuts, but it could wind up being one of the most important bills passed by the Legislature in 2025. I’m talking about [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/07/permitting-progress-prevails/"&gt;Permitting progress prevails&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 21:22:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] PA House Democrats Pass Unbalanced, Reckless Spending Bill</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/07/14/pa-house-democrats-pass-unbalanced-reckless-spending-bill/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Harrisburg, Pa., July 14, 2025 — Today, Pennsylvania House Democrats passed the General Appropriations Act (HB 1330), their version of a budget bill, which includes a $2.9 billion spending increase. The bill would increase general fund spending to $50.6 billion—exacerbating Pennsylvania’s structural deficit, by spending $5.3 billion more than revenue. Lawmakers would need to drain [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/07/14/pa-house-democrats-pass-unbalanced-reckless-spending-bill/"&gt;PA House Democrats Pass Unbalanced, Reckless Spending Bill&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 21:52:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Digital Foundations: The Essential Guide to Data Centers and Their Growth</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/digital-foundations-the-essential-guide-to-data-centers-and-their-growth/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Turner Loesel — Policy Analyst, Center for Technology and Innovation, The James Madison Institute Josh Smith — Energy...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/digital-foundations-the-essential-guide-to-data-centers-and-their-growth/"&gt;Digital Foundations: The Essential Guide to Data Centers and Their Growth&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] The James Madison Institute Releases New Policy Brief on Data Centers</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/the-james-madison-releases-new-policy-brief-on-data-centers/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE July 15, 2025 CONTACT Emma Rose Graddy 850-386-3131 The James Madison Institute Releases New Policy...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/the-james-madison-releases-new-policy-brief-on-data-centers/"&gt;The James Madison Institute Releases New Policy Brief on Data Centers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 13:12:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Kansas Taxpayers Still Waiting: Budget Bloat Blocks Relief Despite Strong Revenues</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/kansas-budget-bloat-despite-strong-revenues/</link><description>Kansas recently reported better-than-expected tax receipts—$248 million above projections—for the fiscal year ending June 30, 2025. Yet despite this encouraging news, Kansans won’t be seeing tax cuts anytime soon. Why? Because government spending continues to outpace sustainable levels, and the state’s new automatic tax reduction law has built-in roadblocks that delay relief even when taxpayers [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 14:00:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/07/the-outstater-278/</link><description>Islamists, Welcome? &amp;#8220;Islamism is a totalitarian ideology that seeks to impose a rigid, theocratic order, incompatible with the pluralistic values of Western civilization.” — Ayaan Hirsi Ali, Somali-born author and activist for women’s rights.&amp;#160; THE DEGRADING&amp;#160;EFFECTS&amp;#160;are&amp;#160;inarguable in&amp;#160;a half dozen U.S. cities, not to mention in the great cultural centers&amp;#160;of&amp;#160;Great Britain and Europe. So why are&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/07/the-outstater-278/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 17:10:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] NJ ED REPORT: Is Murphy Stalling the Segregation Lawsuit? What Would His Successor Do?</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/07/nj-ed-report-is-murphy-stalling-the-segregation-lawsuit-what-would-his-successor-do/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A new NJ Education Report article covers a high-stakes lawsuit accusing the Murphy administration of stalling efforts to fix New [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/07/nj-ed-report-is-murphy-stalling-the-segregation-lawsuit-what-would-his-successor-do/"&gt;NJ ED REPORT: Is Murphy Stalling the Segregation Lawsuit? What Would His Successor Do?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 18:36:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] New Hampshire Lawmakers Send Right to Try Expansion to Governor Kelly Ayotte</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/new-hampshire-lawmakers-send-right-to-try-expansion-to-governor-kelly-ayotte/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Rare disease patients are one step closer to accessing cutting-edge bespoke medical treatments after New Hampshire lawmakers overwhelmingly advanced Goldwater-backed..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/new-hampshire-lawmakers-send-right-to-try-expansion-to-governor-kelly-ayotte/"&gt;New Hampshire Lawmakers Send Right to Try Expansion to Governor Kelly Ayotte&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 21:50:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] The left loves its kings (and queens)</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/the-left-loves-its-kings-(and-queens)</link><description>Everything everywhere is always an emergency in leveraged America</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Research note: Conditional Use and Special Exception Permits</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/research-note-conditional-use-and-special-exception-permits/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;[Note: This is the second in a series of Research Notes by Platte&amp;#8217;s summer intern, focusing on county zoning and agriculture issues] In Nebraska, conditional use and special exception permits are regulatory tools used by county commissions or boards to allow specific land uses that are not typically permitted under existing zoning rules but may...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/research-note-conditional-use-and-special-exception-permits/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Research note: Conditional Use and Special Exception Permits&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 13:10:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] One Big Beautiful Bill and Nebraska’s Fiscal Response</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/one-big-beautiful-bill-and-nebraskas-fiscal-response/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The One Big Beautiful Bill introduces sweeping changes to federal fiscal policy that will have tangible impacts on the state of Nebraska. Policymakers must choose which provisions to adopt of the federal law and which to defer. These decisions will have significant budgetary and growth implications for Nebraska.   On the tax side, the OBBB makes...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/one-big-beautiful-bill-and-nebraskas-fiscal-response/" rel="nofollow"&gt;One Big Beautiful Bill and Nebraska’s Fiscal Response&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 13:58:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] TriMet’s Plan for 82nd Avenue “Road Diet” Looms in Metro Decision</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/transportation/trimets-plan-for-82nd-avenue-road-diet-looms-in-metro-decision/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Maxwell Powers TriMet has a new “road diet” planned for Portland, this...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/transportation/trimets-plan-for-82nd-avenue-road-diet-looms-in-metro-decision/"&gt;TriMet’s Plan for 82nd Avenue “Road Diet” Looms in Metro Decision&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 14:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Good and bad news on the Washington ferries deal</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/good-news-and-bad-news-on-washington-s-ferry-deal</link><description>Taxpayers across Washington state have had a rough go as of late. New gas taxes, increased capital gains income taxes, and higher B&amp;#38;O...</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 14:17:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Freedom Foundation applauds Blackburn, Harris bill to repeal NEA charter</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/labor/freedom-foundation-applauds-blackburn-harris-bill-to-repeal-nea-charter/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Statement by Freedom Foundation CEO Aaron Withe regarding legislation introduced by U.S. Sen. Marsha Blackburn (R-TN) and Rep. Mark Harris (R-NC) to repeal the National Education Association’s federal charter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/labor/freedom-foundation-applauds-blackburn-harris-bill-to-repeal-nea-charter/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation applauds Blackburn, Harris bill to repeal NEA charter&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 15:14:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG Announces Chief Operating Officer</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-announces-chief-operating-officer/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;THE NEWS The Institute for Reforming Government (IRG) has promoted Chris Reader to Chief Operating Officer. In this expanded role, Chris will manage the day-to-day operations of IRG, overseeing its team and project portfolio. Reader has also been named the Executive Director of IRG Action Fund, IRG’s 501(C)(4) advocacy partner.   THE QUOTE CJ Szafir, IRG, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-announces-chief-operating-officer/"&gt;IRG Announces Chief Operating Officer&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 15:54:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] The Grand Bargain of Desalination</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/the-grand-bargain-of-desalination/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=the-grand-bargain-of-desalination</link><description>&lt;p&gt;We are told that water scarcity in the arid American West is inevitable and that the great water projects of the past century were the product of misguided hubris. Environmentalists call for Westerners to shrink their agricultural sector and ration their urban water use and, increasingly, demolish the dams and reservoirs that enabled a civilization...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/the-grand-bargain-of-desalination/"&gt;The Grand Bargain of Desalination&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 16:51:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Goldwater Sues Feds to Demand Transparency in $15 Million Case</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/goldwater-sues-feds-to-demand-transparency-in-15-million-case/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Why has the federal government spent nearly a decade targeting a successful moving company for “age discrimination,” when lifting heavy..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/goldwater-sues-feds-to-demand-transparency-in-15-million-case/"&gt;Goldwater Sues Feds to Demand Transparency in $15 Million Case&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 18:34:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] On Literacy, Time to Learn From Louisiana &amp; Mississippi</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/news/education-literacy-louisianna-mississippi/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Twenty years ago, saying that Louisiana and Mississippi had something to teach Massachusetts about education would have given rise to laughter. Well, it’s no longer a laughing matter. After years during which Massachusetts was celebrated as a national leader in education, we have come into hard times. Our performance on the National Assessment of Educational Progress (NAEP) was nation-leading until 2013, at which point the impacts of the adoption of Common Core, the watering down of our state tests and the dissolution of the state’s school audit office began to register. We have been in full retreat since, experiencing significant declines in reading and math—to the point where Massachusetts’ performance on NAEP is not materially different from 2003. We gave [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/news/education-literacy-louisianna-mississippi/"&gt;On Literacy, Time to Learn From Louisiana &amp;#038; Mississippi&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 19:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Massachusetts and the Energy Equation: Balancing Imports with Innovation</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/blog/usdatalabs/massachusetts-and-the-energy-equation-balancing-imports-with-innovation/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The gap between the energy Massachusetts produces and the amount it consumes results in a reliance on out-of-state energy sources, making the Commonwealth vulnerable to price volatility and supply disruptions. While consumer prices continue to rise, clean energy production provides an avenue for the state to be more energy self-sufficient. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/blog/usdatalabs/massachusetts-and-the-energy-equation-balancing-imports-with-innovation/"&gt;Massachusetts and the Energy Equation: Balancing Imports with Innovation&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 19:20:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] The Good, Bad &amp; Ugly of Maine’s 2025 Legislative Session</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/the-good-bad-ugly-of-maines-2025-legislative-session/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As the dust settles on Maine’s 2025 legislative session, it’s clear that the state’s policy landscape was defined less by dramatic headlines about legislative censures, transgender student athletics or the state’s spat with the federal government over Title IX. Instead, it was more defined by the quiet passage of consequential bills.&amp;#160; This roundup focuses exclusively [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/the-good-bad-ugly-of-maines-2025-legislative-session/"&gt;The Good, Bad &amp;amp; Ugly of Maine&amp;#8217;s 2025 Legislative Session&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 19:42:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Sophistry</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/sophistry/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/sophistry/" rel="nofollow" title="Sophistry"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Cream-Neutral-Minimalist-New-Business-Pitch-Deck-Presentation-Copy.jpg" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;NOTE: This op-ed has been edited by the author to ensure it adheres to the guidelines of our 501(c)(3) organizational status. Sophistry is the use of fallacious arguments with the intent to deceive. Critics will use sophistry to make an argument when the facts do not support their position. We see this all too often [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 21:55:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Improve teacher quality to fix education system</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/improve-teacher-quality-to-fix-education-system</link><description>Teachers prefer smaller class sizes, but they don’t improve student outcomes</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Newsom wisely uses political capital to secure CEQA reform</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/newsom-wisely-uses-political-capital-to-secure-ceqa-reform/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Gov. Gavin Newsom isn’t afraid to step into the political fray when it comes to standing up to President Donald Trump over national issues that impact California. He’s not always wrong when he sues the administration or speaks out against, say, ICE raids in Los Angeles. But most of those high-profile actions seem designed to burnish his [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/newsom-wisely-uses-political-capital-to-secure-ceqa-reform/"&gt;Newsom wisely uses political capital to secure CEQA reform&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 10:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Willing and Label: The Free Market Is Willing to Help Families—Will a Warning Label Stand in the Way?</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/willing-and-label-the-free-market-is-willing-to-help-families-will-a-warning-label-stand-in-the-way/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Labels can be profoundly helpful in many instances. Nutrition information, brands, and medicine dosages, to name just a few, are all communicated to customers through the assistance of easily digestible labels. However, some things involve far more nuance than a simple label can communicate. Social media, an unavoidable feature of modernity, is one such case....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/willing-and-label-the-free-market-is-willing-to-help-families-will-a-warning-label-stand-in-the-way/"&gt;Willing and Label: The Free Market Is Willing to Help Families—Will a Warning Label Stand in the Way?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 13:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] NEW: “School Dashboard” Provides Comprehensive District Data to Wisconsin Families</title><link>https://will-law.org/new-school-dashboard-provides-comprehensive-district-data-to-wisconsin-families/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL released its 2025 School Scorecard Dashboard with new features and data sets to better equip parents, education stakeholders, and taxpayers with insight on how school districts across the state are performing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/new-school-dashboard-provides-comprehensive-district-data-to-wisconsin-families/"&gt;NEW: “School Dashboard” Provides Comprehensive District Data to Wisconsin Families&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 14:28:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Does Iowa Really Have a Truth-in-Taxation Law?</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/does-iowa-really-have-a-truth-in-taxation-law/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Truth-in-Taxation policies aim to increase transparency and accountability in local government budgeting, especially around property taxes. Utah’s model, enacted in 1985, is considered the national gold standard because it controls property tax growth by focusing on limiting revenue, not rates. Iowa’s current system lacks key components, relying instead on partial transparency measures that do not effectively restrain local government spending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/does-iowa-really-have-a-truth-in-taxation-law/"&gt;Does Iowa Really Have a Truth-in-Taxation Law?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 14:36:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Missouri Families Need the “Unsafe School Choice Option”</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/school-choice/missouri-families-need-the-unsafe-school-choice-option/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A version of the following commentary appeared in the St. Louis Post-Dispatch. When asked why they want school choice, families often [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/school-choice/missouri-families-need-the-unsafe-school-choice-option/"&gt;Missouri Families Need the &amp;#8220;Unsafe School Choice Option&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 15:07:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Trump Administration, Congress Offer Vastly Different Visions for the Future of the Housing Choice Voucher Program</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/trump-administration-congress-offer-vastly-different-visions-for-the-future-of-the-housing-choice-voucher-program/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This edition of The House Call explores a federal proposal to cut Housing and Urban Development funding by 44 percent, and how it contrasts with a more recent congressional appropriations bill. The newsletter also provides an update on compliance with Massachusetts' multifamily zoning mandate around MBTA stations after the latest deadline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/trump-administration-congress-offer-vastly-different-visions-for-the-future-of-the-housing-choice-voucher-program/"&gt;Trump Administration, Congress Offer Vastly Different Visions for the Future of the Housing Choice Voucher Program&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 15:09:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] Albuquerque Mayoral Candidate Darren White completes RGF Mayoral candidate survey</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/albuquerque-mayoral-candidate-darren-white-completes-rgf-mayoral-candidate-survey/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce that Albuquerque mayoral candidate (former Bernalillo County Sheriff and former Secretary of the New Mexico Department of Public Safety) Darren White, has completed and submitted the Rio Grande Foundation&amp;#8217;s mayoral candidate survey. You can find that survey embedded below and linked to here.  You can also find White&amp;#8217;s campaign website here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/albuquerque-mayoral-candidate-darren-white-completes-rgf-mayoral-candidate-survey/"&gt;Albuquerque Mayoral Candidate Darren White completes RGF Mayoral candidate survey&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 16:16:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Wisconsin Bar Association Eliminates Race-Based DEI in Settlement with WILL</title><link>https://will-law.org/wisconsin-bar-association-eliminates-race-based-dei-in-settlement-with-will/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The State Bar of Wisconsin has agreed to settle a federal lawsuit and remove harmful and discriminatory “diversity, equity, and inclusion,” or DEI, from its program. The Bar also agreed to change its definition of diversity and will no longer consider race, religion, sex, or other characteristics when determining eligibility for its programs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/wisconsin-bar-association-eliminates-race-based-dei-in-settlement-with-will/"&gt;Wisconsin Bar Association Eliminates Race-Based DEI in Settlement with WILL&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 16:55:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] A Warning for New York’s Energy Policy</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/a-warning-for-new-yorks-energy-policy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On June 24th New York’s electricity grid nearly blew a fuse. That day was extremely hot, and air conditioning was....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/a-warning-for-new-yorks-energy-policy/"&gt;A Warning for New York’s Energy Policy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 17:50:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] St. Louis’s Improving Crime Data</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/criminal-justice/st-louiss-improving-crime-data/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;If you were to guess that St. Louis was the most dangerous city in Missouri, you would be correct. You [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/criminal-justice/st-louiss-improving-crime-data/"&gt;St. Louis’s Improving Crime Data&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 18:39:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Students and teachers deserve better: Congress should reform the NEA federal charter</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/students-and-teachers-deserve-better-congress-should-reform-the-nea-federal-charter</link><description>Most Americans are unaware that the National Education Association (NEA) — the nation’s largest teachers’ union — enjoys a rare privilege: a federal charter granted by Congress in 1906. That puts the NEA in the same elite company as storied civic institutions like the American Red Cross, the Boy Scouts of America, and the U.S. Olympic Committee.</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 18:51:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Spending, Not Revenue, Is the Real Threat to Iowa’s Fiscal Health</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/spending-not-revenue-is-the-real-threat-to-iowas-fiscal-health/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Iowa’s fiscal health remains strong, with billions in reserves, projected surpluses, and a fully funded Taxpayer Relief Fund, even amid tax reform transitions.&lt;br /&gt;
Government spending—especially in education and Medicaid—is the key risk to long-term stability, not reduced tax revenues.&lt;br /&gt;
Conservative budgeting must remain the priority; surpluses and reserve funds are tools for stability, not invitations to grow government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/spending-not-revenue-is-the-real-threat-to-iowas-fiscal-health/"&gt;Spending, Not Revenue, Is the Real Threat to Iowa’s Fiscal Health&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 18:58:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] One Way to Avoid Gasoline Lines in 2026</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/one-way-to-avoid-gasoline-lines-in-2026/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=one-way-to-avoid-gasoline-lines-in-2026</link><description>&lt;p&gt;It’s well known by now that California’s refinery capacity is stretched to the limit. The state’s total crude oil consumption last year was 1.40 million barrels per day, with daily refinery capacity at 1.62 million barrels per day. When accounting for downtime for maintenance and accidents such as the fire in the PBF refinery in Martinez, that’s a thin...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/one-way-to-avoid-gasoline-lines-in-2026/"&gt;One Way to Avoid Gasoline Lines in 2026&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 20:20:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Robocars vs. overpriced groceries</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/robocars-vs-overpriced-groceries/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;And the real reason Wisconsin won’t join the modern world and let cars operate without drivers With automated, driverless robotaxis carrying paying passengers in at least half a dozen cities, but none of them in Wisconsin because our state law will not permit it, you may wonder why we don’t just change our law. Why [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/robocars-vs-overpriced-groceries/"&gt;Robocars vs. overpriced groceries&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 21:37:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Supreme Court gives governor’s bureaucrats free rein</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/supreme-court-gives-governors-bureaucrats-free-rein/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A state Supreme Court decision wresting rulemaking authority from elected state representatives has opened the door to a barrage of new regulations and fees in Wisconsin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/supreme-court-gives-governors-bureaucrats-free-rein/"&gt;Supreme Court gives governor’s bureaucrats free rein&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 21:38:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] California May Never Get High-Speed Rail as Brightline Also Struggles</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/california-may-never-get-high-speed-rail-as-brightline-also-struggles/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=california-may-never-get-high-speed-rail-as-brightline-also-struggles</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Although Governor Newsom and Rail Authority management are in denial, President Trump’s decision to claw back $4 billion in California high-speed rail funding is likely the coup de grace for the state project. But the state’s other high-speed rail project, Brightline West’s effort to connect Rancho Cucamonga with Las Vegas, also faces headwinds and may...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/california-may-never-get-high-speed-rail-as-brightline-also-struggles/"&gt;California May Never Get High-Speed Rail as Brightline Also Struggles&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 22:36:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Grassroot testimonies — early June to mid July 2025</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/07/grassroot-testimonies-early-june-to-mid-july-2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Below are the testimonies submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii between early June and mid July for consideration by the Honolulu and Maui county councils and the Maui Planning Commission. HONOLULU COUNTY COUNCIL &amp;#62;&amp;#62;&amp;#160;Bill 49 (2025)&amp;#160;— “Increase property tax exemption for homeowners age 65 and older” &amp;#62;&amp;#62;&amp;#160;Bill 50 (2025)&amp;#160;— “Increase property tax exemption for [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/07/grassroot-testimonies-early-june-to-mid-july-2025/"&gt;Grassroot testimonies — early June to mid July 2025&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 23:32:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Legislative whiffs—and a few wins—on state housing reform</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/legislative-whiffs-and-a-few-wins-on-state-housing-reform/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Legislative whiffs—and a few wins—on state housing reform In a recent piece for RealClearInvestigations, urban experts Joel Kotkin and Wendell Cox lamented that “housing affordability stands at the lowest level ever recorded, while one in three Americans now spend over 30% of their income on mortgage or rent.” Try telling that to state lawmakers. With [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/legislative-whiffs-and-a-few-wins-on-state-housing-reform/"&gt;Legislative whiffs—and a few wins—on state housing reform&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 09:00:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Trump team kills $4B for California’s ‘train to nowhere’</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/trump-team-kills-4b-for-californias-train-to-nowhere/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Stepheny Price writes for Fox Business about a sound Trump administration transportation decision. California&amp;#8217;s embattled high-speed rail project suffered a major setback after Transportation Secretary Sean Duffy announced the termination of $4 billion in unspent federal funding by the Federal Railroad Administration (FRA). Citing 16 years of failure, no completed high-speed track, and escalating costs,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/trump-team-kills-4b-for-californias-train-to-nowhere/"&gt;Trump team kills $4B for California’s ‘train to nowhere’&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 09:39:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Trump’s big bill included real government rollbacks</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/trumps-big-bill-included-real-government-rollbacks/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Veronique de Rugy writes for Townhall.com about a significant accomplishment tied to the “one big beautiful bill.” The &amp;#8220;Big Beautiful Bill&amp;#8221; accomplished many things, not all of them positive. One positive step was to repeal many of the Inflation Reduction Act&amp;#8217;s green energy subsidies. It&amp;#8217;s somewhat disappointing that Congress didn&amp;#8217;t repeal all of them, as...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/trumps-big-bill-included-real-government-rollbacks/"&gt;Trump’s big bill included real government rollbacks&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 09:42:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Tax hike proposal is bad business</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/tax-hike-proposal-is-bad-business</link><description>‘Fair Share Surcharge’ would crush economic activity without helping schools</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 09:59:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Think Chicago Teachers Union stays in Chicago? Not according to its VP</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/think-chicago-teachers-union-stays-in-chicago-not-according-to-its-vp/</link><description>Chicago Teachers Union Vice President Jackson Potter said CTU needs to be more involved in other school districts. That means 52 school districts negotiating teachers contracts this year are targets for CTU tactics and militancy.</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 10:00:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Iowans Just Avoided a Huge Tax Increase, But New Warning Flags Lie Ahead</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/iowans-just-avoided-a-huge-tax-increase-but-new-warning-flags-lie-ahead/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;With the passage of the “Big, Beautiful Bill,” Iowans avoided a catastrophic tax increase. But even with many positives in the measure, there are still reasons to keep a sharp eye on what lies ahead. Washington’s spending—and the national debt—will continue to grow in the near term, but that trajectory cannot continue indefinitely.  Iowa policymakers must begin to prepare for contingencies to protect the state’s hard-won fiscal responsibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/iowans-just-avoided-a-huge-tax-increase-but-new-warning-flags-lie-ahead/"&gt;Iowans Just Avoided a Huge Tax Increase, But New Warning Flags Lie Ahead&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 13:13:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Wyoming Supreme Court ruling strengthens property rights</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/wyoming-supreme-court-ruling-strengthens-property-rights</link><description>Government officials who damage private property must pay for what they ruin ruled the Wyoming Supreme Court unanimously last week in...</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 14:24:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] A Freeze in July?</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/education-finance/a-freeze-in-july/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As a former tutor at a Tennessee Boys &amp;#38; Girls Club, a recent headline caught my eye: the Boys &amp;#38; [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/education-finance/a-freeze-in-july/"&gt;A Freeze in July?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 15:32:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Now what, California?</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/now-what-california/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;President Donald Trump’s Big Beautiful Bill is a grotesque monster to the renewable energy partisans. It phases out subsidies for wind and solar power, which have been around for decades and were extended by the previous administration’s Inflation Reduction Act. Industry sources have told the media that without taxpayer help, the renewables sector is in [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/now-what-california/"&gt;Now what, California?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 16:31:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Texas v. DHS</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/texas-v-dhs/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Date Filed: October 24, 2023 Original Court: U.S. District Court for the Western District of Texas Appeals: U.S. Court of Appeals for the Fifth Circuit Case Status: Victory In 2023, the State of Texas installed razor wire fencing along the border with Mexico. The federal government cut this wire fencing, and by doing so facilitated...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/texas-v-dhs/"&gt;Texas v. DHS&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 16:46:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Job Licensing Reviews: Education Committee</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/job-licensing-reviews-education-committee/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Occupational Board Reform Act (OBRA) was passed in 2018 and became effective in 2019. It requires legislative committees of jurisdiction to review all occupational licenses in the state, roughly 20% per year, on a five-year rotation. These reviews examine whether the licensing requirements are adequate or excessive by current standards. The committees then submit...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/job-licensing-reviews-education-committee/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Job Licensing Reviews: Education Committee&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 16:59:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] Parents: Ask Your District How They Will Comply</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/07/18/parents-ask-your-district-how-they-will-comply/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A momentous parental rights victory was handed down by the United States Supreme Court on Friday, June 27, 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/07/18/parents-ask-your-district-how-they-will-comply/"&gt;Parents: Ask Your District How They Will Comply&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 17:45:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Elections board finally collecting missing voter ID numbers</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/elections-board-finally-collecting-missing-voter-id-numbers/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The North Carolina State Board of Elections (SBE) will work to collect missing data from hundreds of thousands of voter registrations this year. That will fix a problem the board should have fixed in 2023 and correct a decades-long mistake. SBE Executive Director Sam Hayes announced the launch of the program to the media on...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/elections-board-finally-collecting-missing-voter-id-numbers/"&gt;Elections board finally collecting missing voter ID numbers&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 18:05:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Week in Review: Transparency is the Law</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-transparency-is-the-law/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;What happens when a federal agency targets a successful business, demands millions in fines, and then refuses to explain why?..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-transparency-is-the-law/"&gt;Week in Review: Transparency is the Law&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 18:15:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Busting Two Common Myths About Property Taxes</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/busting-two-common-myths-about-property-taxes/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On Thursday, the FOX television affiliate in El Paso, KFOX14, published an article related to local property taxes that is raising eyebrows for promoting 2 very misleading arguments. Let’s briefly review each one and see if we can spot the fallacy. The first troubled argument can be found in the opening paragraph, which advances the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/busting-two-common-myths-about-property-taxes/"&gt;Busting Two Common Myths About Property Taxes&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 19:05:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Boise’s FY26 Budget: A Betrayal of Taxpayer Trust</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/boises-fy26-budget-a-betrayal-of-taxpayer-trust/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/boises-fy26-budget-a-betrayal-of-taxpayer-trust/" rel="nofollow" title="Boise’s FY26 Budget: A Betrayal of Taxpayer Trust"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Cream-Neutral-Minimalist-New-Business-Pitch-Deck-Presentation-1.jpg" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;On July 15, 2025, the Boise City Council approved the FY26 budget, which included a 4% property tax increase — 3% allowed by law, plus a 1% foregone hike — ignoring the financial strain on residents. As one of the few voices opposing this budget, I’m dismayed by the council’s disregard for taxpayers and the [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 19:19:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] SEIU Wants Unemployment for Strikers — While Blowing Cash on Billboards</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/07/18/seiu-wants-unemployment-for-strikers-while-blowing-cash-on-billboards/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When 1,700 unionized healthcare workers went on strike in the spring of 2023, SEIU 1199 New England had millions in reserve — including a strike fund. But instead of using [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/07/18/seiu-wants-unemployment-for-strikers-while-blowing-cash-on-billboards/"&gt;SEIU Wants Unemployment for Strikers — While Blowing Cash on Billboards&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 19:33:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Do advocates for total government dependency have any limiting principles?</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/07/do-advocates-for-total-government-dependency-have-any-limiting-principles/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;“I find more and more that dependency from [upon] the will of others is always some diminution of human happiness, principally to a man accustom’d to follow his own will uncontrolled.”  &amp;#8211; Jan Ingenhousz to Ben Franklin, 1777 &amp;#160; During the two weeks since Americans celebrated the 249th anniversary of the Declaration of Independence, political [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/07/do-advocates-for-total-government-dependency-have-any-limiting-principles/"&gt;Do advocates for total government dependency have any limiting principles?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 19:45:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Chicago aldermanic control issue again stalls granny flats</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/chicago-aldermanic-control-issue-again-stalls-granny-flats/</link><description>Residential permits across Chicago remained low in 2024, and efforts to increase housing on existing lots have been put off. Some of Chicago’s aldermen want to maintain power over their wards, including thwarting a popular housing solution.</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 20:12:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Feeding Our Future: date certain</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/feeding-our-future-date-certain/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Federal District Judge Nancy Brasel is adamant that the next Feeding Our Future trial will begin on August 18. This trial has already been postponed twice, from April to August 11, then for another week to the 18th. This afternoon, Judge Brasel presided over a status conference for one of the August defendants, Hamdi Hussein...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/feeding-our-future-date-certain/"&gt;Feeding Our Future: date certain&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 20:57:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Nearly 2M Illinoisans still need federal food benefits, most in Chicago</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/nearly-2m-illinoisans-still-need-federal-food-benefits-most-in-chicago/</link><description>Although enrollment in the Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program declined marginally in April, nearly 2 million Illinoisans still depend on the federal food aid. Illinois’ food insecurity has yet to recover from the pandemic.</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 21:08:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Winners &amp; Losers: Bad Week for NPR, Teachers Are Screaming &amp; Biden Team Still Taking the Fifth</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/winners-losers-bad-week-for-npr-teachers-are-screaming-biden-team-still-taking-the-fifth/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Every Friday morning, I join the Cardle &amp;#38; Woolley Show on 1370 Talk Radio in Austin to announce the week’s Winners &amp;#38; Losers. As we enter the “dead of summer” with what must now be officially referred to as “the first called Special Session,” scheduled to start Monday in the Texas Capitol, here’s who made...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/winners-losers-bad-week-for-npr-teachers-are-screaming-biden-team-still-taking-the-fifth/"&gt;Winners &amp; Losers: Bad Week for NPR, Teachers Are Screaming &amp; Biden Team Still Taking the Fifth&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 21:17:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Guilty, guilty</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/guilty-guilty/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Next, state Sen. Nicole Mitchell must resign, immediately. From MPR News, Sen. Nicole Mitchell guilty of two counts of burglary after multi-day trial. The two counts arose from an Apri 2024 incident, The first-term DFLer from Woodbury broke into the Detroit Lakes home of her stepmother in the early morning hours of April 22, 2024,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/guilty-guilty/"&gt;Guilty, guilty&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 21:43:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Where’s Francisco?</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/wheres-francisco/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;He&amp;#8217;s in the federal lockup at the Sherburne County jail awaiting trial on a federal felony charge. From the Minnesota Star Tribune, Restaurant owner in Lake Street raid spent weeks in ICE detention. You will recall that raid from last month involving the seizure of 900 pounds of meth from a storage unit in Burnsville....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/wheres-francisco/"&gt;Where&amp;#8217;s Francisco?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2025 02:31:34 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>