<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>State-Policy Think-Tank Digest</title><link>https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml</link><description>Latest posts from free-market policy institutes across the U.S.</description><atom:link href="https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 08:04:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>[Foropportunity] New Report: Corrections spending rises in Georgia even as prison population declines</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/new-report-corrections-spending-rises-in-georgia/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A new report by Joshua Crawford, Public Safety Fellow at the Georgia Center for Opportunity, shows that the decreasing number of inmates hasn’t translated to meaningful savings or improvements in public safety for Georgians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/new-report-corrections-spending-rises-in-georgia/"&gt;New Report: Corrections spending rises in Georgia even as prison population declines&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 23:02:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF provides comments in support of unlocking new water supplies for New Mexicans</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-provides-comments-in-support-of-unlocking-new-water-supplies-for-new-mexicans/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;They say &amp;#8220;agua es vida&amp;#8221; in New Mexico (water is life). In the desert southwest water is critical to human flourishing and the broader economy of the state and region. So, when we were presented with an opportunity to put water that is produced alongside oil and gas, we had only one question: &amp;#8220;Is it [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-provides-comments-in-support-of-unlocking-new-water-supplies-for-new-mexicans/"&gt;RGF provides comments in support of unlocking new water supplies for New Mexicans&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 16:38:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Accountability and Action: The Path to Safer Communities</title><link>https://empowerms.org/accountability-and-action-the-path-to-safer-communities/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This past weekend, our state was rocked by a wave of violent crime. Over the course of twenty-four hours, five shootings claimed the lives of at least nine Mississippians. While these horrific acts do not appear to be connected, they are alarming nevertheless. Words like horrific, tragic, and avoidable all come to mind. First and&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/accountability-and-action-the-path-to-safer-communities/"&gt;Accountability and Action: The Path to Safer Communities&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 14:16:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] New Statewide Ad Calls Out Governor Shapiro For Budget Impasse</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/10/19/new-statewide-ad-end-the-impasse-governor-shapiro/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Harrisburg, Pa., October 19, 2025 —&amp;#160;The Commonwealth Foundation has launched a new statewide ad calling on Gov. Josh Shapiro to end the state budget impasse by getting to work negotiating a bipartisan, fiscally responsible compromise that protects Pennsylvania taxpayers. Pennsylvania remains the only state in the nation without a state budget. The new ad calls [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/10/19/new-statewide-ad-end-the-impasse-governor-shapiro/"&gt;New Statewide Ad Calls Out Governor Shapiro For Budget Impasse&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 23:35:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] The Federal Shutdown Explained: What it Means for Maine</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/the-federal-shutdown-explained-what-it-means-for-maine/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Congress isn’t known as the place for bipartisan cooperation, but since October 1, inter-party arguing has led to a shutdown of the federal government. This has caused the closing of offices, the suspension of services, and the placing of hundreds of thousands of workers on furlough. The reason, as usual, is infuriating but straightforward: Congress [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/the-federal-shutdown-explained-what-it-means-for-maine/"&gt;The Federal Shutdown Explained: What it Means for Maine&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 19:26:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] Pennsylvania Senate Passes Budget Plan, RGGI Abrogation, Regulatory Reform</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/10/22/pennsylvania-senate-passes-budget-plan/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Harrisburg, Pa., October 22, 2025&amp;#160;— This week, the Pennsylvania Senate advanced legislation, including a spending bill (Senate Bill 160), that protects taxpayers and fosters economic growth. The commonwealth remains the only state in the country without an operating budget or stop gap plan. Now weeks into a federal government shutdown, Pennsylvania’s four-month-long impasse holds the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/10/22/pennsylvania-senate-passes-budget-plan/"&gt;Pennsylvania Senate Passes Budget Plan, RGGI Abrogation, Regulatory Reform&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 18:11:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG CIO Submits Request to DPI Seeking Teacher Licensing and Misconduct Scandal Public Records</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-cio-submits-request-to-dpi-seeking-teacher-licensing-and-misconduct-scandal-public-records/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government’s (IRG) Center for Investigative Oversight (CIO) submitted a public records request to the Wisconsin Department of Public Instruction (DPI), seeking to uncover details surrounding the Department’s handling of teacher licenses for educators accused of misconduct and grooming. Recent reporting by The Capital Times revealed serious concerns surrounding [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-cio-submits-request-to-dpi-seeking-teacher-licensing-and-misconduct-scandal-public-records/"&gt;IRG CIO Submits Request to DPI Seeking Teacher Licensing and Misconduct Scandal Public Records&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 19:07:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] New Jersey’s Bag Ban Backfired. Repeal It—and Cut Waste the Smart Way.</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/10/new-jerseys-bag-ban-backfired-repeal-it-and-cut-waste-the-smart-way/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Wells Winegar, Executive Director, New Jersey Policy Institute (NJPI) &amp;#160; Walk into any New Jersey kitchen and open the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/10/new-jerseys-bag-ban-backfired-repeal-it-and-cut-waste-the-smart-way/"&gt;New Jersey’s Bag Ban Backfired. Repeal It—and Cut Waste the Smart Way.&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 19:51:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] If Lawmakers Are Trying to Defund Public Education, They Aren’t Very Good at It</title><link>https://empowerms.org/if-lawmakers-are-trying-to-defund-public-education-they-arent-very-good-at-it/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;You’ve probably heard the claim that Mississippi’s Republican leaders are “defunding” public education, and that school choice is just another way to siphon dollars away from public schools. But if that’s true, they’re doing a remarkably bad job of it.  Over the past decade, Mississippi has dramatically increased its investment in public education. According to&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/if-lawmakers-are-trying-to-defund-public-education-they-arent-very-good-at-it/"&gt;If Lawmakers Are Trying to Defund Public Education, They Aren’t Very Good at It&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 02:00:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Destroying Democracy: Will Dems Trample on Voters’ Will?</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/destroying-democracy-will-dems-trample-on-voters-will/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="720" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/IMG_4669.jpeg" width="1280" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have to be pretty confident – no, read that “arrogant” – to tell 2.7 million Virginia voters that you’re willing to stick it to them. But that’s exactly what Virginia House and Senate Democratic leaders appear ready to do at 4:00 pm on Monday, all in the cause of enhancing political power and rejecting the voters’ [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/destroying-democracy-will-dems-trample-on-voters-will/"&gt;Destroying Democracy: Will Dems Trample on Voters’ Will?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 16:43:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Nebraska’s Tax Treatment of Non-Profits</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/nebraskas-tax-treatment-of-non-profits/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The origins of favorable tax treatment for nonprofit and not-for-profit organizations in the United States were based on the admirable ideals promoting community service and public good.    However, today the United States’ federally tax-exempt economy makes up 15% of gross domestic output (GDP) and spans 1.8 million organizations. A total of $3.3 trillion dollars of...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/nebraskas-tax-treatment-of-non-profits/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Nebraska&amp;#8217;s Tax Treatment of Non-Profits&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 19:37:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Tennessee’s Time for Energy Abundance</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/tennessees-time-for-energy-abundance/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=tennessees-time-for-energy-abundance</link><description>By embracing Tennessee's nuclear roots, small modular reactor and micro modular reactor technologies will have a chance to thrive in a new era of energy independence.</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 19:39:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] The Good, Bad, and Ugly of 2nd Session Bill Requests</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/the-good-bad-and-ugly-of-2nd-session-bill-requests/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Legislative Council has released the list of bill titles under consideration for the Maine Legislature’s 2026 legislative session, and on October 23, the Council met for an initial bill screening. The full list of results is available here.&amp;#160; The Legislative Council is made up of 10 members of legislative leadership. For a bill request [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/the-good-bad-and-ugly-of-2nd-session-bill-requests/"&gt;The Good, Bad, and Ugly of 2nd Session Bill Requests&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 19:40:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] Court ratifies City of Albuquerque donation to Planned Parenthood</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/court-ratifies-city-of-albuquerque-donation-to-planned-parenthood/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In what can only be described as a ruling based on twisted logic a New Mexico District Judge (Denise Barela Shepherd) has decided that it is somehow NOT a violation of New Mexico&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8220;anti-donation clause&amp;#8221; for the City of Albuquerque to explicitly donation $250,000 of our tax dollars to Planned Parenthood.  Our friends at the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/court-ratifies-city-of-albuquerque-donation-to-planned-parenthood/"&gt;Court ratifies City of Albuquerque donation to Planned Parenthood&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 22:24:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] New Video Exposes How Unions Trap Public Employees in Membership</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/press-release/new-video-exposes-how-unions-trap-public-employees-in-membership/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Freedom Foundation today released a new video exposing the deliberate obstacles unions place in front of public employees trying to exercise their constitutional right to leave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/press-release/new-video-exposes-how-unions-trap-public-employees-in-membership/" rel="nofollow"&gt;New Video Exposes How Unions Trap Public Employees in Membership&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 15:22:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Frightfully pricey treats: Why Halloween fun is costing Georgia families more</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/georgia-halloween-candy-prices/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As Halloween approaches, Georgia families look forward to making great memories involving adorable costumes and fun candy hauls. But candy prices have become nothing short of scary for families trying to make ends meet. Here's why prices are on the rise for Georgia's favorite Halloween treats. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/georgia-halloween-candy-prices/"&gt;Frightfully pricey treats: Why Halloween fun is costing Georgia families more&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 16:01:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] PRESS RELEASE: Governor Reeves and Rich Lowry Highlight Mississippi's Success</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/press-release-governor-reeves-and-rich-lowry-highlight-mississippis-success/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASEOctober 28, 2025 Mississippi Center for Public Policy Celebrates Statewide Success with Governor Tate Reeves and National Review Editor Rich Lowry Jackson, Miss. — October 28, 2025 — The Mississippi Center for Public Policy hosted its Celebration of Mississippi Success Gala on Thursday, October 23, at the Country Club of Jackson, honoring the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/press-release-governor-reeves-and-rich-lowry-highlight-mississippis-success/" rel="nofollow"&gt;PRESS RELEASE: Governor Reeves and Rich Lowry Highlight Mississippi&amp;#039;s Success&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 19:43:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Mayor John Horhn: Jackson Rising</title><link>https://empowerms.org/mayor-john-horhn-jackson-rising/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Mayor John Horhn: Jackson Rising What does it take to turn around a city? In this special episode recorded at Jackson City Hall, host Grant Callen talks with Mayor John Horhn about his love for Jackson, the lessons from his childhood and career in public service, and his mission to restore trust, safety, and opportunity&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/mayor-john-horhn-jackson-rising/"&gt;Mayor John Horhn: Jackson Rising&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 01:00:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG Court Watch: Options for Structural Reforms for our Courts</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-court-watch-options-for-structural-reforms-for-our-courts/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;IRG Court Watch: Options for Structural Reforms for our Courts Voters Open to Reform after Multi-Million Dollar, Partisan Judicial Elections Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government’s (IRG)‘s Court Watch initiative released a report, Structural Reform of Judicial Selection in Wisconsin, detailing potential structural reforms to strengthen judicial integrity and public trust in Wisconsin [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-court-watch-options-for-structural-reforms-for-our-courts/"&gt;IRG Court Watch: Options for Structural Reforms for our Courts&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 13:38:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Dear PPS Bond Committee: Please Tell the Taxpayers</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/testimony/testimony-before-the-pps-bond-accountability-committee/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By John A. Charles, Jr. Cascade’s president, John Charles, testified online at the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/testimony/testimony-before-the-pps-bond-accountability-committee/"&gt;Dear PPS Bond Committee: Please Tell the Taxpayers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 23:13:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Nichols v. DOT</title><link>https://will-law.org/nichols-v-dot/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL is challenging a state law that unlawfully restricts Wisconsin drivers’ First Amendment rights. The state uses subjective and arbitrary decisions to decide what drivers can print on their personalized license plates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/nichols-v-dot/"&gt;Nichols v. DOT&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 13:52:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Debunking 2 more property tax myths: setting mill rates and blaming legislators for unfunded mandates</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/2-property-tax-myths-mill-rates-unfunded-mandates/</link><description>Last month, we debunked several property tax myths that some local officials are using to shift the blame for their unaffordable tax increases, and now there are two more excuses to address. For years, many local officials tried to blame County Clerks for setting mill rates, saying something along the lines of ‘we just set [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 15:31:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Killing the I&amp;D Tax leaps N.H. to No. 3 on national tax competitiveness index</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/10/killing-the-id-tax-leaps-n-h-to-no-3-on-national-tax-competitiveness-index/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Killing New Hampshire’s Interest &amp;#38; Dividends Tax has breathed new life into the New Hampshire Advantage. That’s the conclusion from reading the Tax Foundation’s 2026 State Tax Competitiveness Index, released on Oct. 30.  Last year, New Hampshire slipped past Texas to claim the No. 6 spot on the index. Passing the famously conservative and economically [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/10/killing-the-id-tax-leaps-n-h-to-no-3-on-national-tax-competitiveness-index/"&gt;Killing the I&amp;#038;D Tax leaps N.H. to No. 3 on national tax competitiveness index&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 17:51:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Large Scale Desalination Could Transform California</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/large-scale-desalination-could-transform-california/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=large-scale-desalination-could-transform-california</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Why is it axiomatic among California’s water agencies and policymakers that large scale desalination is inconceivable in California? That certainly isn’t the case in other arid locales. In 2024, an estimated 30 million acre feet of fresh water was produced by desalination plants worldwide. On the coast of the Red Sea, about 60 miles south of the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/large-scale-desalination-could-transform-california/"&gt;Large Scale Desalination Could Transform California&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 17:53:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Parsing the Impact of Mamdani’s Tax Hike Plans</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/parsing-the-impact-of-mamdanis-tax-hike-plans/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The front-running candidate for New York City mayor, Zohran Mamdani, has said he can finance his costly campaign promises –....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/parsing-the-impact-of-mamdanis-tax-hike-plans/"&gt;Parsing the Impact of Mamdani&amp;#8217;s Tax Hike Plans&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 20:28:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Maine’s 2025 Ballot Questions: What Voters Should Know</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/maines-2025-ballot-questions-what-voters-should-know/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As Maine heads into the 2025 election, voters will face two ballot questions that cut to the heart of the state’s debates over election integrity and gun rights. Both questions resurrect legislative fights that failed in Augusta and are now placed directly before the people. Ballot Question 1: Election Integrity Ballot Summary:“Do you want to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/maines-2025-ballot-questions-what-voters-should-know/"&gt;Maine’s 2025 Ballot Questions: What Voters Should Know&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 21:09:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] As hunger looms, Democrats in ‘non-winnable’ situation</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/as-hunger-looms-democrats-in-non-winnable-situation/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;“Democrats put themselves in the situation we’re in, and it’s non-winnable,” says Rachidi, a researcher who has written extensively about FoodShare and SNAP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/as-hunger-looms-democrats-in-non-winnable-situation/"&gt;As hunger looms, Democrats in ‘non-winnable’ situation&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 21:22:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Beacon Wins Final Approval in $1.4 Million Stormwater Settlement, Bringing Justice to Nashville Homeowners</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/beacon-wins-final-approval-in-1-4-million-stormwater-settlement-bringing-justice-to-nashville-homeowners/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=beacon-wins-final-approval-in-1-4-million-stormwater-settlement-bringing-justice-to-nashville-homeowners</link><description>This ruling is a landmark win for property owners and sends a clear message that government overreach will not go unchecked.</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 21:26:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] WI Speaks Polling Results</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/wi-speaks-survey-results/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WI 1023 Toplines (1) WI 1023 Summary of Key Findings (2) WI 1023 Summary of Key Findings (2)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/wi-speaks-survey-results/"&gt;WI Speaks Polling Results&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 00:18:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Virginiainstitute] Examining HJ6007 and Its Implications for Virginia’s Redistricting Process</title><link>https://virginiainstitute.org/examining-hj6007/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=examining-hj6007</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As lawmakers consider HJ6007, Virginians are asking how the proposal aligns with the 2020 constitutional amendment supporting fair maps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org/examining-hj6007/"&gt;Examining HJ6007 and Its Implications for Virginia’s Redistricting Process&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org"&gt;Virginia Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 01:53:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] NYC Employees Receive $300k+ in Overtime</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/nyc-employees-receive-300k-in-overtime/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Two New York City employees received more than $300,000 in overtime payouts, according to fiscal year 2025 payroll data posted....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/nyc-employees-receive-300k-in-overtime/"&gt;NYC Employees Receive $300k+ in Overtime&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 13:20:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Florida Politics: No, Georgia, It’s Not a Trick; Florida Just Wants To Share a Kid-Friendly Treat</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/florida-politics-no-georgia-its-not-a-trick-florida-just-wants-to-share-a-kid-friendly-treat/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As Saturday’s&amp;#160;Georgia-Florida game&amp;#160;approaches, much attention is being paid to the fact that the Gators just fired their head...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/florida-politics-no-georgia-its-not-a-trick-florida-just-wants-to-share-a-kid-friendly-treat/"&gt;Florida Politics: No, Georgia, It’s Not a Trick; Florida Just Wants To Share a Kid-Friendly Treat&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 14:08:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] PRESS RELEASE: MISSISSIPPI CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY HONORS LEGISLATIVE HEROES AT ANNUAL GALA CELEBRATING STATE SUCCESS</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/press-release-mississippi-center-for-public-policy-honors-legislative-heroes-at-annual-gala-celebrating-state-success/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASEOctober 30, 2025 MISSISSIPPI CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY HONORS LEGISLATIVE HEROES AT ANNUAL GALA CELEBRATING STATE SUCCESS JACKSON, MS – October 30, 2025 –Six of Mississippi’s leading lawmakers were presented with award to honor them for championing principled conservative policy. Rich Lowry, editor of the National Review, presented each of the winners. HealthcareRep. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/press-release-mississippi-center-for-public-policy-honors-legislative-heroes-at-annual-gala-celebrating-state-success/" rel="nofollow"&gt;PRESS RELEASE: MISSISSIPPI CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY HONORS LEGISLATIVE HEROES AT ANNUAL GALA CELEBRATING STATE SUCCESS&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 19:21:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Income: You Earned It, You Should Keep It</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/income-you-earned-it-you-should-keep-it/</link><description>Income Taxes: We have options Are you getting the idea that the Idaho Freedom Foundation (IFF) thinks government takes too much in taxes? Good, let’s keep going. By applying our 2026 Freedom and Family Agenda’s strong position on tax cuts, we have proposed eliminating the sales tax on groceries and have offered a plan to [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 23:08:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Virginiainstitute] Press Release – HJ 6007: “one of the worst ideas” passed by the General Assembly</title><link>https://virginiainstitute.org/press-release-hj6007/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=press-release-hj6007</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Virginia Institute for Public Policy has expressed concern over HJ6007, a proposed amendment to Virginia’s Constitution that would alter the state’s current redistricting process. The Institute emphasized that Virginia voters approved a bipartisan approach in 2020 to ensure fair and transparent elections for all citizens. Citing constitutional and procedural issues surrounding HJ6007, the Institute encourages lawmakers to uphold established safeguards that protect the integrity and balance of Virginia’s electoral system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org/press-release-hj6007/"&gt;Press Release – HJ 6007: “one of the worst ideas” passed by the General Assembly&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org"&gt;Virginia Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 00:15:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Tallahassee Democrat: Florida’s Established Approach to Kids’ Online Safety Doesn’t Need Tweaking</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/floridas-established-approach-to-kids-online-safety-doesnt-need-tweaking-opinion/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In the ongoing debate about how to best protect children online, a new proposal gaining traction would force...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/floridas-established-approach-to-kids-online-safety-doesnt-need-tweaking-opinion/"&gt;Tallahassee Democrat: Florida’s Established Approach to Kids’ Online Safety Doesn’t Need Tweaking&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 14:55:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] Average Twin Cities Commuter = 73 Hours Stuck in Traffic</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/average-twin-cities-commuter-73-hours-stuck-in-traffic/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Every year, the Texas A&amp;#38;M Transportation Institute issues a report documenting the price of road congestion on American roads. This 2025 report is notable for Minnesota commuters because it documented that the “average Twin Cities car commuter now spends a record 73 hours a year stuck in traffic.” This is an increase after a COVID-pandemic [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/average-twin-cities-commuter-73-hours-stuck-in-traffic/"&gt;Average Twin Cities Commuter = 73 Hours Stuck in Traffic&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 18:14:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Week in Review: Everything Should Be Smaller in Taxes</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/week-in-review-everything-should-be-smaller-in-taxes/</link><description>That’s right, the title says “Taxes,” not “Texas.” Even in Idaho, taxes are out of control. Please enjoy — if that’s the right word — this mini-series on Idaho taxes. But, before you read, one word of reminder: high taxes are merely the symptom of the true disease: out-of-control government spending. This symptom inflicts real [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 20:04:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] New Pioneer Institute Analysis Finds Proposed Massachusetts Income-Tax Cut Unlikely to Cause Major State Revenue Decline</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/news/2026-tax-cut/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Lessons from the 2000 Massachusetts Income-Tax Rollback: A Reality-Check for the 2025 Ballot Debate is an empirical analysis of Massachusetts revenue data from FY1998–FY2021. The study concludes that a one-point rate reduction is unlikely to produce large, persistent revenue shortfalls, and that long-term fiscal stability depends far more on economic performance than on marginal rate differences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/news/2026-tax-cut/"&gt;New Pioneer Institute Analysis Finds Proposed Massachusetts Income-Tax Cut Unlikely to Cause Major State Revenue Decline&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 15:06:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Why CT’s Special Session Must Be Narrow and Focused</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/11/03/why-cts-special-session-must-be-narrow-and-focused/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="1707" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/shutterstock_2628868481-scaled.jpg" width="2560" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a special session expected in mid-November, progressives are using an emerging funding crisis to revisit Connecticut’s fiscal guardrails and advance other priorities such as health care and affordable housing.   [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/11/03/why-cts-special-session-must-be-narrow-and-focused/"&gt;Why CT&amp;#8217;s Special Session Must Be Narrow and Focused&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 15:15:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] New Report Calls for More Freedom and Consumer Choice in Energy Policy to Lower Costs</title><link>https://will-law.org/new-report-calls-for-more-freedom-and-consumer-choice-in-energy-policy-to-lower-costs/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A new report from WILL, titled “Energy Choice for Wisconsin: A Free-Market Case for Community Solar,” outlines how privately financed community solar projects can expand consumer choice, strengthen the electric grid, preserve farmland, and inject market competition into Wisconsin’s monopoly utility system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/new-report-calls-for-more-freedom-and-consumer-choice-in-energy-policy-to-lower-costs/"&gt;New Report Calls for More Freedom and Consumer Choice in Energy Policy to Lower Costs&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 17:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF in National Review: New Mexico’s ‘Free’ Child Care an Attempt to Cover for Past Failures</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-in-national-review-new-mexicos-free-child-care-an-attempt-to-cover-for-past-failures/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following appeared at National Review on November 11, 2025. Child care isn’t cheap, especially once the government gets involved. Recently, New Mexico’s Democratic Governor Michelle Lujan Grisham announced a new plan for taxpayers to fund “free” child care for all New Mexicans, regardless of their income levels. The announcement generated favorable news coverage in [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-in-national-review-new-mexicos-free-child-care-an-attempt-to-cover-for-past-failures/"&gt;RGF in National Review: New Mexico’s ‘Free’ Child Care an Attempt to Cover for Past Failures&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 21:15:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] AEA Has Shown Alabamians Who They Are: Believe Them</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/11/04/aea-has-shown-alabamians-who-they-are-believe-them/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;AEA has worked for decades to stop school choice legislation. AEA actively worked against the passage of the AAA Scholarship program, the PRICE Act, and the CHOOSE Act. AEA used political influence and political contributions to people and parties to weaken parental rights in the CHOOSE Act and then tried to kill the CHOOSE Act unless they could “control the spending” with a cap. Further, AEA worked last legislative session to minimize funding for special needs kids, military kids, and kids whose families are living in poverty; they are currently working against future CHOOSE Act schoolchildren. AEA is trying to render void the promises legislators made to Alabama parents when they passed the law in 2024. They are attempting to undercut the work and the word of Governor Kay Ivey, Lt. Governor Will Ainsworth, Speaker Nathaniel Ledbetter, Chairman Danny Garrett, Chairman Arthur Orr, and each of the ninety-two legislators who voted on behalf of the people they represent for universal school choice for Alabama’s children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/11/04/aea-has-shown-alabamians-who-they-are-believe-them/"&gt;AEA Has Shown Alabamians Who They Are: Believe Them&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 05:04:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] No Energy Crisis Debate? A Last Minute Redistricting Amendment? Virginians Deserved Better Before Today’s Vote</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/no-energy-crisis-debate-a-last-minute-redistricting-amendment-virginians-deserved-better-before-todays-vote/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="720" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/Virginia-Election.jpg" width="1280" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With election day now upon us, Virginia voters were short-changed this election cycle while Democracy is literally being threatened!  Virginians were limited to one, short, poorly controlled debate for Governor, one equally short, but slightly more substantive debate for Attorney General, and zero debates for Lt. Governor – unless, of course, you count the surreal [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/no-energy-crisis-debate-a-last-minute-redistricting-amendment-virginians-deserved-better-before-todays-vote/"&gt;No Energy Crisis Debate? A Last Minute Redistricting Amendment? Virginians Deserved Better Before Today&amp;#8217;s Vote&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 13:43:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] SNAP in Nebraska: Current Rules, Economic Impact, and What’s Next</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/snap-in-nebraska-current-rules-economic-impact-and-whats-next/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Program Overview  The Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP), formerly known as the Food Stamp Program, is the most extensive federal nutrition assistance program in the United States. It serves as a &amp;#8220;safety net&amp;#8221; program that helpslow-income individuals and families access and purchase healthy food. The program is funded by the Department of Agriculture (USDA) and...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/snap-in-nebraska-current-rules-economic-impact-and-whats-next/" rel="nofollow"&gt;SNAP in Nebraska: Current Rules, Economic Impact, and What’s Next&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 16:16:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Nebraska lost $300 million from tax migration in 2022</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-lost-300-million-from-tax-migration-in-2022/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Elections occur every other November. But taxpayers vote with their feet every day, and these votes should be counted and tallied just like the votes for a November election.  A “Great Pandemic Wealth Migration” began when the coronavirus pandemic caused Americans to move to work-from-home employment. This meant workers were no longer tied to aphysical...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-lost-300-million-from-tax-migration-in-2022/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Nebraska lost $300 million from tax migration in 2022&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 19:03:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Obamacare’s Policy Failures Come To Idaho</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/obamacares-policy-failures-come-to-idaho/</link><description>As the shutdown of the federal government extends beyond 30 days, the key reasons become apparent: it is about healthcare costs and who pays them. The debate over temporarily expanded healthcare premium subsidies and Medicaid eligibility is really about who pays what. You see, the notion that the Affordable Care Act (often referred to as [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 22:45:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] State Board of Education gets bad legal guidance from the Kansas Department of Education</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/state-board-of-education-bad-legal-guidance/</link><description>The October meeting of the Kansas State Board of Education contained another déjà vu moment: attempting to cover up another violation of state laws designed to improve student outcomes (see here and here for past examples.) State Board Chair Cathy Hopkins commented on a Kansas Policy Institute discovery that school districts were not complying with [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 23:33:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] November 2025 Beacon Poll Results</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/november-2025-beacon-poll/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=november-2025-beacon-poll</link><description>Today, we released the latest installment of the Beacon Poll, a statewide survey of 1,200 Tennessee voters featuring questions about voters&amp;#8217; views on socialism versus capitalism, the National Guard in Memphis, political violence, and more. In a surprising result that could have a national impact, a majority of Democrats in Tennessee hold a favorable view...</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 13:00:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] MA Teacher Kelley Brown on Founding Documents, U.S. History, &amp; Civics</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/ma-teacher-kelley-brown-on-founding-documents-u-s-history-civics/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In this week’s episode of The Learning Curve, co-hosts Center for Strong Public Schools’ Alisha Searcy and American Federation for Children’s Walter Blanks interview Kelley Brown, an award-winning civics and government teacher at Easthampton High School and former Massachusetts Teacher of the Year. Ms. Brown discusses her background as an educator, her work with the “We the People": The Citizen and the Constitution program, and how it helps students engage with America’s Founding Documents, U.S. history, and enduring civic ideals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/ma-teacher-kelley-brown-on-founding-documents-u-s-history-civics/"&gt;MA Teacher Kelley Brown on Founding Documents, U.S. History, &amp;#038; Civics&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 14:35:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] MSPC provides digital safety keynote address at Idaho Department of Education conference</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/mspc-provides-digital-safety-keynote-address-at-idaho-department-of-education-conference</link><description>On October 24 th , 2025, I was honored to be a keynote speaker at the Idaho Department of Education’s 10th Annual Family and Community Engagement Conference in Sun Valley, ID. Over 300 teachers, principals, and community leaders came together for this year's event, giving a state-wide perspective on all the things we should be doing to better equip our parents and students with what they need to succeed in educating their youth. The keynote addressed my most recent research project: “ The...</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 15:38:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] The Atlanta Journal-Constitution: Georgia Leaders Should Not Vilify Technology. Social Media and AI Hold Promise.</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/georgia-leaders-should-not-vilify-technology-social-media-and-ai-hold-promise/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In the waning hours of Georgia&amp;#8217;s brief 40-day legislative session this past April, state senators quietly passed Senate...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/georgia-leaders-should-not-vilify-technology-social-media-and-ai-hold-promise/"&gt;The Atlanta Journal-Constitution: Georgia Leaders Should Not Vilify Technology. Social Media and AI Hold Promise.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 16:04:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] California Just Blew Past Last Year’s Record — And We’re Still Climbing</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/california-just-blew-past-last-years-record-and-were-still-climbing/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;California public employees are opting out of their unions in record numbers thanks to the work of the Freedom Foundation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/california-just-blew-past-last-years-record-and-were-still-climbing/" rel="nofollow"&gt;California Just Blew Past Last Year’s Record — And We’re Still Climbing&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 23:30:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] NH’s youngest lawmakers to discuss civility in politics at Civil Discourses kickoff event</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/11/nhs-youngest-lawmakers-to-discuss-civility-in-politics-at-civil-discourses-kickoff-event/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Josiah Bartlett Center for Public Policy will bring a bipartisan group of New Hampshire’s youngest state representatives together on Dec. 1 for a frank and open conversation on the importance of civility in public life.  Josiah Bartlett Center President Andrew Cline will moderate a conversation among:: Rep. Jessica Grill, Democrat of Manchester; Rep. Sam [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/11/nhs-youngest-lawmakers-to-discuss-civility-in-politics-at-civil-discourses-kickoff-event/"&gt;NH&amp;#8217;s youngest lawmakers to discuss civility in politics at Civil Discourses kickoff event&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 13:31:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/11/the-outstater-300/</link><description>The&amp;#160;Mamdani Effect &amp;#8220;It is hard to imagine a more stupid or more dangerous way of making decisions than by putting those decisions in the hands of people who pay no price for being wrong.&amp;#8221; — Thomas Sowell HAVING WORKED with words all my career, I have admired the economists&amp;#8217; turn of phrase. Shakespearean almost, they pack a&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/11/the-outstater-300/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 15:44:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] CHALKBEAT: Interdistrict Public School Choice Program could expand with bipartisan support amid funding, equity hurdles</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/11/chalkbeat-interdistrict-public-school-choice-program-could-expand-with-bipartisan-support-amid-funding-equity-hurdles/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Interdistrict Public School Choice Program could expand with bipartisan support amid funding, equity hurdles By Jessie Gómez November 3, 2025 [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/11/chalkbeat-interdistrict-public-school-choice-program-could-expand-with-bipartisan-support-amid-funding-equity-hurdles/"&gt;CHALKBEAT: Interdistrict Public School Choice Program could expand with bipartisan support amid funding, equity hurdles&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 16:07:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] ROI-NJ: A blueprint for abundant, affordable energy for New Jersey families | Op-Ed</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/11/roi-nj-a-blueprint-for-abundant-affordable-energy-for-new-jersey-families-op-ed/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A blueprint for abundant, affordable energy for New Jersey families &amp;#124; Op-Ed By Erica Jedynak, New Jersey Policy Institute November [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/11/roi-nj-a-blueprint-for-abundant-affordable-energy-for-new-jersey-families-op-ed/"&gt;ROI-NJ: A blueprint for abundant, affordable energy for New Jersey families | Op-Ed&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 16:11:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] WFSE loses 1,000 members for second consecutive year</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/washington/wfse-loses-1000-members-for-second-consecutive-year/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For the second year in a row, the largest union representing Washington state employees has lost more than 1,000 members, thanks in large part to the ongoing outreach efforts of the Freedom Foundation to help of workers understand their right to opt out of paying union dues.&amp;#160; With annual union dues averaging around $1,000 per [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/washington/wfse-loses-1000-members-for-second-consecutive-year/" rel="nofollow"&gt;WFSE loses 1,000 members for second consecutive year&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 17:55:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] State Tax Competitiveness Index: Minnesota Falls to 44th out of 50!</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/state-tax-competitiveness-index-minnesota-falls-to-44th-out-of-50/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For 20 years, the Tax Foundation has released an annual report evaluating state tax codes – everything from income to property to sales taxes. Each state has its own summary including an interactive map that includes suggestions on how the state could become more competitive. Minnesota state leadership, however appears to be determined for our [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/state-tax-competitiveness-index-minnesota-falls-to-44th-out-of-50/"&gt;State Tax Competitiveness Index: Minnesota Falls to 44th out of 50!&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 19:06:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Extend enterprise zone benefits to incentivize all Maui businesses</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/11/extend-enterprise-zone-benefits-to-incentivize-all-maui-businesses/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Maui County Council on Nov. 7, 2025._____________ Nov. 7, 2025, 9 a.m.Kalana O Maui Building To: Maui County Council       Alice Lee, Chair       Yuki Lei Sugimura, Vice-Chair From: Grassroot Institute of Hawaii            Jonathan Helton, Policy Analyst RE: RESOLUTIONS 25-193 AND 25-194, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/11/extend-enterprise-zone-benefits-to-incentivize-all-maui-businesses/"&gt;Extend enterprise zone benefits to incentivize all Maui businesses&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 19:47:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] ‘Overhead encroachment’ rule blocking restoration of old Lahaina</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/11/overhead-encroachment-rule-blocking-restoration-of-old-lahaina/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Maui County Council on Nov. 7, 2025._____________ Nov. 7, 2025, 9 a.m.Kalana O Maui Building To: Maui County Council       Alice Lee, Chair       Yuki Lei Sugimura, Vice-Chair From: Grassroot Institute of Hawaii            Jonathan Helton, Policy Analyst Re: Bill 156 (2025) — [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/11/overhead-encroachment-rule-blocking-restoration-of-old-lahaina/"&gt;&amp;#8216;Overhead encroachment&amp;#8217; rule blocking restoration of old Lahaina&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 19:52:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Rights of nature and the wrongs inflicted on Wisconsinites</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/rights-of-nature-and-the-wrongs-inflicted-on-wisconsinites/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Assembly Democrats intend to introduce a bill to grant Devil’s Lake State Park legal rights, as if it weren’t a set of inanimate rocks, water, trees and lichens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/rights-of-nature-and-the-wrongs-inflicted-on-wisconsinites/"&gt;Rights of nature and the wrongs inflicted on Wisconsinites&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 20:10:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Voters Show Restraint in 2025 Bond Elections</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/voters-show-restraint-in-2025-bond-elections/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Voters Show Restraint in 2025 Bond Elections" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/lcoal-bond-election-results.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iowa voters considered 58 bond proposals totaling more than $1.7 billion in potential new borrowing. A majority (57%) of those proposals failed, with only 25 proposals (43%) gaining approval. Many repeat proposals were rejected again, showing continued taxpayer concern about property taxes and government spending. Just over $1 billion in new debt was approved, with nearly $700 million denied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/voters-show-restraint-in-2025-bond-elections/"&gt;Voters Show Restraint in 2025 Bond Elections&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 20:20:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] UW students turning away from gender and ethnic studies degrees</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/uw-students-turning-away-from-gender-and-ethnic-studies-degrees/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;About half as many students in the Universities of Wisconsin system are getting bachelor’s degrees in ethnic and gender studies as did at their peak in 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/uw-students-turning-away-from-gender-and-ethnic-studies-degrees/"&gt;UW students turning away from gender and ethnic studies degrees&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 20:47:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Want Cheaper Housing? Create More Units, Not More Rules</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/regulation/want-cheaper-housing-create-more-units-not-more-rules/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Recent data from The Wall Street Journal suggest that renters across the country—including in Kansas City—are gaining leverage. Rents are [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/regulation/want-cheaper-housing-create-more-units-not-more-rules/"&gt;Want Cheaper Housing? Create More Units, Not More Rules&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 22:07:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] $2 Trillion and No One Aboard</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/transportation/2-trillion-and-no-one-aboard/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Randal O&amp;#8217;Toole Since 1965, when Congress began subsidizing urban transit, taxpayers have...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/transportation/2-trillion-and-no-one-aboard/"&gt;$2 Trillion and No One Aboard&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 00:20:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Lines for Gas Coming to California</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/lines-for-gas-coming-to-california/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=lines-for-gas-coming-to-california</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Achieving California’s goal of net zero by 2045 requires rapidly transitioning away from combustible fuel. It’s a risky strategy. If the transition happens too fast, Californians confront energy shortages and high prices. When it comes to electricity, Newsom has so far managed to avoid an acute crisis by sensibly prolonging that transition. In 2023, he delayed the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/lines-for-gas-coming-to-california/"&gt;Lines for Gas Coming to California&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 01:24:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Traverse City borrows from Peter to pay Paul</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/traverse-city-borrows-from-peter-to-pay-paul</link><description>Troubled city-run internet project taps into funds intended for other purposes</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Enhanced Democratic Trifecta in Richmond Grants Them Control Over Energy Policy</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/enhanced-democratic-trifecta-in-richmond-grants-them-control-over-energy-policy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="720" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/Va-Dems-Energy.jpg" width="1280" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The return of the political trifecta Democrats enjoyed during the 2020 and 2021 General Assembly sessions – now bolstered with a 64-36 majority in the House of Delegates – leaves the question of how to deal with Virginia’s energy issues entirely in their hands. Only if the Democrats suffer a significant division within their own [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/enhanced-democratic-trifecta-in-richmond-grants-them-control-over-energy-policy/"&gt;Enhanced Democratic Trifecta in Richmond Grants Them Control Over Energy Policy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 13:42:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Budget Update Paints Less Alarming Picture of Federal Health Cuts</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/budget-update-paints-less-alarming-picture/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A new fiscal report from the state Budget Division suggests federal funding cuts will hit New York&amp;#8217;s health-care budget less....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/budget-update-paints-less-alarming-picture/"&gt;Budget Update Paints Less Alarming Picture of Federal Health Cuts&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 14:23:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] KCCI: Property tax reform looms after split Iowa school bond results</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/kcci-property-tax-reform-looms-after-split-iowa-school-bond-results/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="KCCI: Property tax reform looms after split Iowa school bond results" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/curry-kcci-11-07-25.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Property taxes are an issue. And I think voters are being more picky," said Sarah Curry with Iowans for Tax Relief, a group that advocates for lower taxes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Curry says that while some metro voters were willing to accept higher taxes to fund new schools, many Iowans elsewhere were not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"When we look statewide, there were actually 25 bonds that passed and 33 failed. Knoxville, Panorama, I-35 — all of those measures failed," Curry said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/kcci-property-tax-reform-looms-after-split-iowa-school-bond-results/"&gt;KCCI: Property tax reform looms after split Iowa school bond results&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 15:29:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] WILL Christmas Open House 2025</title><link>https://will-law.org/christmas2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/christmas2025/"&gt;WILL Christmas Open House 2025&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 16:32:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Occupational license reform will help the trades in Idaho</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/occupational-license-reform-will-help-the-trades-in-idaho</link><description>The trades, electrical, plumbing, and HVAC (Heating, Ventilation, and Air Conditioning), face a growing concern surrounding what could most accurately be labeled a retirement crisis. Some estimates say that for every five journeyman who retire from the trades , only two apprentices from a younger generation will replace them.  Licensure raises the price of entry into the trades’ labor market, artificially limiting the number of people who can enter it. Given the ever-important need for...</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 16:57:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Week in Review: Exposing School Stonewalling on Fox</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-exposing-school-stonewalling-on-fox/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Rhode Island taxpayers already pay a lot to educate public school students—so, “it’s outrageous” and “completely unreasonable” to expect a..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-exposing-school-stonewalling-on-fox/"&gt;Week in Review: Exposing School Stonewalling on Fox&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 17:08:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Winners &amp; Losers: Texas Wins, Country Loses</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/winners-losers-texas-wins-country-loses/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Every Friday morning, I join the Cardle &amp;#38; Woolley Show on Talk 1370 Radio in Austin to announce the week’s Winners &amp;#38; Losers. The dust is still setting after Tuesday’s election and I’m stuck in an airport dealing with a cancelled flight, so here’s how it looks to me: Election Night: Texas Wins, Country Loses...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/winners-losers-texas-wins-country-loses/"&gt;Winners &amp; Losers: Texas Wins, Country Loses&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 17:28:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Will Concord or Laconia reap the rewards of creating NH’s first social district?</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/11/will-concord-or-laconia-reap-the-rewards-of-creating-nhs-first-social-district/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The term “economic growth” seldom pops up in local news stories. But there it was in the third paragraph of the Concord Monitor’s story on Tuesday’s election results.  After quoting a former teacher who complained about the slow pace of change in Concord due to “a lot of governmental, bureaucratic red tape,” the Monitor described [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/11/will-concord-or-laconia-reap-the-rewards-of-creating-nhs-first-social-district/"&gt;Will Concord or Laconia reap the rewards of creating NH&amp;#8217;s first social district?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 17:30:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Prescription Politics: Understanding PBMs</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/legal-regulatory/prescription-politics-understanding-pbms/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Perhaps you received a text in June from your local CVS Pharmacy alerting you to a big legislative fight? Or maybe you’ve just read about it in the papers. Either way, there’s been a lot of debate over the last few months about “Pharmacy Benefit Managers,” colloquially known as PBMs. But what exactly is a...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/legal-regulatory/prescription-politics-understanding-pbms/"&gt;Prescription Politics: Understanding PBMs&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 18:29:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] Minnesotans Cannot Afford Four More Years of Walz Energy Policy</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/minnesotans-cannot-afford-four-more-years-of-walz-energy-policy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;What happens when working families see electric bills climb to meet the governor’s idealistic demands? By Annette Meeks Gov. Tim Walz officially announced that he wants to serve four more years leading Minnesota. He did not make this announcement in a public meeting, rally or policy speech, but with a carefully crafted video. It was a politically manufactured [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/minnesotans-cannot-afford-four-more-years-of-walz-energy-policy/"&gt;Minnesotans Cannot Afford Four More Years of Walz Energy Policy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 19:02:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Two Missouri Public School Districts Opt into MOScholars</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/school-choice/two-missouri-public-school-districts-opt-into-moscholars/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Two public school districts—Hallsville R-IV and Atlanta C-3—are the first districts in Missouri to participate in MOScholars. MOScholars is Missouri’s [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/school-choice/two-missouri-public-school-districts-opt-into-moscholars/"&gt;Two Missouri Public School Districts Opt into MOScholars&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 19:33:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Over a Decade at the Bottom: Connecticut’s Tax System Still Among America’s Worst</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/11/07/over-a-decade-at-the-bottom-connecticuts-tax-system-still-among-americas-worst/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the eleventh consecutive year, Connecticut has ranked among the worst states in America for tax competitiveness — a streak that’s starting to look less like bad luck and more [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/11/07/over-a-decade-at-the-bottom-connecticuts-tax-system-still-among-americas-worst/"&gt;Over a Decade at the Bottom: Connecticut’s Tax System Still Among America’s Worst&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 21:24:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] There Are Better Healthcare Options Out There</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/there-are-better-healthcare-options-out-there/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Open Enrollment Season is upon us. It’s that time of year where employees, self-employed, businesses, and local governments start crunching numbers to see how much health insurance will cost next year—and, surprise of surprises, the answer is almost always “a lot more.” Worse yet, the Federal Budget impasse and Government shutdown over ACA healthcare subsidies...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/there-are-better-healthcare-options-out-there/"&gt;There Are Better Healthcare Options Out There&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 22:05:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] News Release: Cascade Identifies Purchase Risk for PPS One North Building</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/education/news-release-cascade-identifies-purchase-risk-for-pps-one-north-building/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;11/06/2025 FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE Cascade Policy Institute4850 SW Scholls Ferry Rd., Ste 103Portland...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/education/news-release-cascade-identifies-purchase-risk-for-pps-one-north-building/"&gt;News Release: Cascade Identifies Purchase Risk for PPS One North Building&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 23:23:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/11/the-outstater-301/</link><description>The NIMBY of Data Centers AS USUAL,&amp;#160;the emotional argument is winning the day, this time against data centers. If you mingled with the crowd of anti-Google activists at a recent library town hall in Fort Wayne&amp;#160;you would have met precious few engineers and zero economists. Rather, the one hundred or so in attendance can be&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/11/the-outstater-301/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 22:16:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Illinois punishes independents, meaning just 1 got on 2024 ballot</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/illinois-punishes-independents-meaning-just-1-got-on-2024-ballot/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Illinois puts lots of restrictions on independent candidates. Just one got on the 2024 ballot in 155 races. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/illinois-punishes-independents-meaning-just-1-got-on-2024-ballot/"&gt;Illinois punishes independents, meaning just 1 got on 2024 ballot&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 11:00:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Hendrickson Presents Iowa Accomplishments to Top Policy Experts</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/hendrickson-presents-iowa-accomplishments-to-top-policy-experts/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Hendrickson Presents Iowa Accomplishments to Top Policy Experts" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/EFNA-2025.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iowans for Tax Relief Foundation Policy Director John Hendrickson recently joined leading economists and policy experts from across the continent at the 2025 Economic Freedom of North America (EFNA) Network Conference, sponsored by the Fraser Institute and the Bridwell Institute for Economic Freedom at Southern Methodist University. The EFNA network brings together organizations committed to advancing policies that expand individual liberty and economic opportunity. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/hendrickson-presents-iowa-accomplishments-to-top-policy-experts/"&gt;Hendrickson Presents Iowa Accomplishments to Top Policy Experts&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 01:00:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Woman who harassed Trump official is professor of … peace studies</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/woman-who-harassed-trump-official-is-professor-of-peace-studies/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Jessica Schwalb writes for the Washington Free Beacon about the interesting background of one member of the political left’s lunatic fringe. The woman who posted flyers exposing White House adviser Stephen Miller’s address and calling for &amp;#8220;NO NAZIS&amp;#8221; in Northern Virginia is a harmless academic &amp;#8220;in the field of peace studies,&amp;#8221; her lawyer claimed. On...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/woman-who-harassed-trump-official-is-professor-of-peace-studies/"&gt;Woman who harassed Trump official is professor of &amp;#8230; peace studies&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 10:39:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Progressives warn Democrats against alienating the left</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/progressives-warn-democrats-against-alienating-the-left/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Adriana Gomez Licon reports for the Associated Press on the political left’s response to the recent election. As Democrats savor their Election Day victories, some are capitalizing on the victory of New York City Mayor-Elect Zohran Mamdani and calling out party leaders for snubbing progressives, warning that alienating the left could cost them crucial House...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/progressives-warn-democrats-against-alienating-the-left/"&gt;Progressives warn Democrats against alienating the left&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 10:42:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Struggling Bay City rolls out plenty of red tape</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/struggling-bay-city-rolls-out-plenty-of-red-tape</link><description>Rigid regulations punish citizens and discourage civic traditions</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Rejecting the Evidence of Your Eyes and Ears</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/rejecting-the-evidence-of-your-eyes-and-ears/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;There’s an adage about crime statistics in progressive political and academic circles that can be summed up as the “perception exceeds reality school.” Put another way, Americans are simply wrong to be afraid of crime in the view of these so-called experts. Recently, the New York Times criticized President Trump for calling crime statistics showing [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/rejecting-the-evidence-of-your-eyes-and-ears/"&gt;Rejecting the Evidence of Your Eyes and Ears&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 11:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Six Years Later, Massachusetts Active Home Listings Remain 35% Below Pre-COVID Level</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/economic_opportunity/six-years-later-massachusetts-active-home-listings-remain-35-below-pre-covid-level/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Our November edition of The House Call covers the dwindling availability of homes on the market in Massachusetts since 2019, even as many other states have seen full recoveries in the number of market listings after COVID. It discusses the implications of lower home availability for buyers and sellers alike and identifies a couple of major solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/economic_opportunity/six-years-later-massachusetts-active-home-listings-remain-35-below-pre-covid-level/"&gt;Six Years Later, Massachusetts Active Home Listings Remain 35% Below Pre-COVID Level&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 13:30:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] Franke: Supreme Court Independence</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/11/franke-supreme-court-independence/</link><description>by Mark Franke Every year the Gallup organization conducts an opinion poll to determine the level of confidence Americans have for major institutions. It should come as no surprise that news organizations rank at the bottom with Congress and educational institutions also scoring high negatives.&amp;#160; The confidence level in the Supreme Court of the U.S.&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/11/franke-supreme-court-independence/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 13:55:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Restoring the Ties that Bind: America Needs Strong Civil Society</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/principles-of-liberty/restoring-the-ties-that-bind-america-needs-strong-civil-society/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;At the core of all America’s great progress and achievements lies civil society, a fundamental yet often overlooked element of American life. Civil society is the product of individual initiative and voluntary cooperation for the common good, fostering charity, trust, and feelings of goodwill. In a healthy society, citizens are not passive recipients of government...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/principles-of-liberty/restoring-the-ties-that-bind-america-needs-strong-civil-society/"&gt;Restoring the Ties that Bind: America Needs Strong Civil Society&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 14:47:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Empowering Idaho’s self-employed workforce with portable benefits</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/empowering-idaho-s-self-employed-workforce-with-portable-benefits</link><description>Note: This is a joint op-ed with Liya Palagashvili  of the Mercatus Center at George Mason University . Across Idaho, more than 160,000 people earn income—whether as a primary or supplemental source—through self-employment, contract work, or small business ownership. They include truckers, delivery drivers, freelance creatives, childcare providers, and self-employed farmers and tradespeople who remain central to Idaho’s economy. Together, they generate over $9 billion annually, according to...</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 14:49:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] How North Carolina legislative districts have shifted since 2024</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/how-north-carolina-legislative-districts-have-shifted-since-2024/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For the first time in several years, North Carolina will use all the same state legislative districts for two elections in a row. That, coupled with the release of the 2026 Civitas Partisan Index (CPI) on November 6, allows us to assess the political shifts in North Carolina General Assembly districts by comparing the 2026...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/how-north-carolina-legislative-districts-have-shifted-since-2024/"&gt;How North Carolina legislative districts have shifted since 2024&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 14:56:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] What Isn’t a Charter School?</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/education/what-isnt-a-charter-school/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Let’s imagine you have an important job to do. Some reasonable people consider it the most important job.  The future wellbeing of society is directly correlated to how successful you and your peers are.  There are a few oddities, however, for such a crucial job as yours. If you do a great job, you aren’t...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/education/what-isnt-a-charter-school/"&gt;What Isn’t a Charter School?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 15:17:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Kansas’s Tax Competitiveness Moment</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/kansas-tax-competitiveness/</link><description>Kansas stands in a better position today than it did just a few years ago. According to the Tax Foundation’s 2026 State Tax Competitiveness Index, the state now ranks 23rd overall in the nation. That’s respectable progress, but in a country where states are competing aggressively for people, jobs, and investment, “respectable” isn’t enough. The [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 16:00:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] The fantasy that cutting prison populations saves a lot of money</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/the-fantasy-that-cutting-prison-populations-saves-a-lot-of-money/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/the-fantasy-that-cutting-prison-populations-saves-a-lot-of-money/"&gt;The fantasy that cutting prison populations saves a lot of money&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 16:02:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Medicare’s Paltry Doctor Payments Are Price Controls In Disguise</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/medicares-paltry-doctor-payments-are-price-controls-in-disguise/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Specialist physicians will receive a significant pay cut from Medicare next year. That’s the main takeaway from the 2026 physician fee schedule released by the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services in October. For years, physician reimbursement from Medicare has stagnated, even declined. Doctors are responding by leaving the profession or limiting the number of [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/medicares-paltry-doctor-payments-are-price-controls-in-disguise/"&gt;Medicare’s Paltry Doctor Payments Are Price Controls In Disguise&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 16:41:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] The Great Climate Pivot: When Even Bill Gates Stops Catastrophizing</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/the-great-climate-pivot-when-even-bill-gates-stops-catastrophizing/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In a stunning reversal, Bill Gates—who literally wrote a book called “How to Avoid a Climate Disaster”—has declared that while “climate change will have serious consequences&amp;#8230; it will not lead to humanity’s demise.” The timing? Just days before COP30 convenes in Belém, Brazil from Nov. 10-21, and Gates specifically addresses his memo to that audience...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/the-great-climate-pivot-when-even-bill-gates-stops-catastrophizing/"&gt;The Great Climate Pivot: When Even Bill Gates Stops Catastrophizing&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 16:51:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] 340B Drug Pricing Program Overdue for Reform, GOP Can Help</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/340b-drug-pricing-program-overdue-for-reform-gop-can-help/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Members of the Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions Committee held a hearing in October to discuss a federal healthcare policy long overdue for reform — the 340B Drug Pricing Program. Created to expand access to affordable medicines for low-income people, 340B has since fallen victim to rampant abuse by hospitals. The result has been [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/340b-drug-pricing-program-overdue-for-reform-gop-can-help/"&gt;340B Drug Pricing Program Overdue for Reform, GOP Can Help&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 18:20:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Those Dark Clouds are the Debt</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/those-dark-clouds-are-the-debt/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The future for our state looks bright.  In just the past five years, Mississippi has seen more economic growth than in the entire fifteen years before that combined. We’re on track to phase out the state income tax entirely, allowing families to keep more of what they earn.  Mississippi has attracted a surge of new investment, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/those-dark-clouds-are-the-debt/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Those Dark Clouds are the Debt&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 18:39:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] New Report: Shapiro’s ‘Get Sh*t Done’ Slogan Doesn’t Match His Record</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/11/10/shapiro-get-sht-done-slogan-doesnt-match-record/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Gov. Josh Shapiro remains Pennsylvania’s least legislatively productive governor in the past 50 years. Harrisburg, Pa., November 10, 2025 — As presidential ambitions of Pennsylvania’s 48th governor become increasingly prominent, many question: Is Governor Shapiro as productive as he claims? A new report from the Commonwealth Foundation found Gov. Josh Shapiro to be the least [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/11/10/shapiro-get-sht-done-slogan-doesnt-match-record/"&gt;New Report: Shapiro’s ‘Get Sh*t Done’ Slogan Doesn’t Match His Record&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 19:58:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Tucson Held Liable for Dereliction on Homelessness</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/tucson-held-liable-for-dereliction-on-homelessness/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Time for Tucsonans to File Compensation Claims The Arizona Supreme Court last week declined to review a lower court judgment..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/tucson-held-liable-for-dereliction-on-homelessness/"&gt;Tucson Held Liable for Dereliction on Homelessness&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 20:43:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Lamont’s Hospital Takeover Plan is a Gamble Connecticut Cannot Afford</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/11/10/lamonts-hospital-takeover-plan-is-a-gamble-connecticut-cannot-afford/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="630" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/uconn_fb_1200x630.png" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UConn Health — the state’s public medical center that includes the UConn School of Medicine, the School of Dental Medicine, and John Dempsey Hospital — is now at the center [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/11/10/lamonts-hospital-takeover-plan-is-a-gamble-connecticut-cannot-afford/"&gt;Lamont’s Hospital Takeover Plan is a Gamble Connecticut Cannot Afford&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 21:10:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Per ride subsidy on Borealis train increases 66% in one year</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/per-ride-subsidy-on-borealis-train-increases-66-in-one-year/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In the first eleven days of its operation in May 2024, Amtrak&amp;#8217;s Borealis service between St. Paul and Chicago generated a “profit” of $100,000 which excited a few local people. In fact, as I and others noted shortly afterwards, this was based on a basic misreading of Amtrak&amp;#8217;s reports. True, subtracting “Operating Expense” from “Operating...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/per-ride-subsidy-on-borealis-train-increases-66-in-one-year/"&gt;Per ride subsidy on Borealis train increases 66% in one year&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 21:21:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] What’s new in the 2025 Critical Minerals List</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/whats-new-in-the-2025-critical-minerals-list/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Last week, the Department of the Interior finalized its 2025 Critical Minerals List, adding 10 new entries for a total of 60. What’s a critical mineral? There is a school of thought out there—and I’m sympathetic to it—that any mineral that the market demands is a “critical” mineral. It’s needed for something, and someone is...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/whats-new-in-the-2025-critical-minerals-list/"&gt;What’s new in the 2025 Critical Minerals List&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 21:40:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Minnesota Man of the Day</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/minnesota-man-of-the-day-2/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Carlos Guillermo Aragon-Baez is our Minnesota Man of the Day. He has been charged in federal court with one count of illegal re-entry of a previously deported alien. Aragon, aged 40 or so, is being held in the Sherburne County jail on the federal charge and also on a state-level felony drug charge. His name...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/minnesota-man-of-the-day-2/"&gt;Minnesota Man of the Day&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 22:15:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Flagged for being too efficient?</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/11/flagged-for-being-too-efficient/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Is Honolulu’s building permit process so broken that fast-moving approvals are automatically suspicious? A recent Honolulu Civil Beat article tells the strange story of Kim Kehrwieder, who was fired last year from her job as a building plans examiner for the Honolulu Department of Planning and Permitting. The problem? She expedited permits in violation of DPP policy. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/11/flagged-for-being-too-efficient/"&gt;Flagged for being too efficient?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 22:31:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Michigan State Turns Teacher Training into Ideological Indoctrination</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/michigan-state-turns-teacher-training-into-ideological-indoctrination/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Prospective teachers should spend their college years learning how to manage a classroom and teach kids to read and write...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/michigan-state-turns-teacher-training-into-ideological-indoctrination/"&gt;Michigan State Turns Teacher Training into Ideological Indoctrination&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 22:40:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Cook County property tax bills finally getting mailed, due Dec. 15</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/cook-county-property-tax-bills-finally-getting-mailed-due-dec-15/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Cook County leaders announced the second installment of property tax bills will be mailed by Nov. 14 with a Dec. 15 due date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/cook-county-property-tax-bills-finally-getting-mailed-due-dec-15/"&gt;Cook County property tax bills finally getting mailed, due Dec. 15&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 00:32:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Boring Company May Have a Viable Alternative for California Urban Transit</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/boring-company-may-have-a-viable-alternative-for-california-urban-transit/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=boring-company-may-have-a-viable-alternative-for-california-urban-transit</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Las Vegas is pioneering a new form of underground transportation that could one day benefit congested California cities at low cost. The Boring Company, founded by Elon Musk, is digging a series of narrow tunnels and transporting passengers through them in Tesla sedans. Ultimately, the Boring Company’s Vegas Loop can evolve into a viable alternative...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/boring-company-may-have-a-viable-alternative-for-california-urban-transit/"&gt;Boring Company May Have a Viable Alternative for California Urban Transit&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 01:05:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Baker &amp; Taylor library supplier closing, laying off 318</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/baker-taylor-library-supplier-closing-laying-off-318/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A major library supplier formerly employing 1,500 will cease operations at the end of the year, laying off 318 workers in October at its Momence distribution center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/baker-taylor-library-supplier-closing-laying-off-318/"&gt;Baker &amp;#038; Taylor library supplier closing, laying off 318&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 01:11:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Rochester School Board Censures Trustee for Speaking Out</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/pressroom/2025/rochester-school-board-censures-trustee-for-speaking-out</link><description>Mackinac Center: Silencing Elected Officials Violates Free Speech</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 03:08:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Honoring Our Veterans: Thank You for Your Service</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/uncategorized/honoring-our-veterans-thank-you-for-your-service/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Thank you to all who have served. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/uncategorized/honoring-our-veterans-thank-you-for-your-service/"&gt;Honoring Our Veterans: Thank You for Your Service&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 07:00:28 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>