<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>State-Policy Think-Tank Digest</title><link>https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml</link><description>Latest posts from free-market policy institutes across the U.S.</description><atom:link href="https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 11:03:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG Court Watch Report: Wisconsin Supreme Court Term in Review</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-court-watch-report-wisconsin-supreme-court-term-in-review/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;IRG Court Watch Report: Wisconsin Supreme Court Term in Review Court Delivers Progressive Wins in Wisconsin for the First Time in Over a Decade Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government’s (IRG) Court Watch released a report detailing the Wisconsin Supreme Court’s 2024-2025 term on Tuesday, analyzing the new path taken by the Court’s [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-court-watch-report-wisconsin-supreme-court-term-in-review/"&gt;IRG Court Watch Report: Wisconsin Supreme Court Term in Review&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 12:56:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG Announces New Leadership</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-announces-new-leadership/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;IRG Announces New Leadership Alison Prange to serve as the next Chair of the Board of Directors  THE NEWS The Board of Directors for the Institute for Reforming Government has elected Alison Prange to serve as the next Chair of the Board. Alison Prange was appointed to IRG’s Board in 2022. THE QUOTES Alison Prange, IRG [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-announces-new-leadership/"&gt;IRG Announces New Leadership&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 15:54:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Teacher Freedom Summit brings together educators anxious to cut ties with their union</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/teacher-conference/teacher-freedom-summit-brings-together-educators-anxious-to-cut-ties-with-their-union/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Despite the shocking news headlines from big unions like the American Federation of Teachers (AFT) and the National Education Association (NEA), 2025 has been a year of success and hope for America’s education system and educators alike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/teacher-conference/teacher-freedom-summit-brings-together-educators-anxious-to-cut-ties-with-their-union/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Teacher Freedom Summit brings together educators anxious to cut ties with their union&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 18:16:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Three issues Georgia parents are most concerned about</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/georgia-parent-top-concerns/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A new report on child well-being from Emory University reveals the issues that Georgia parents say are impacting kids—and their futures—most. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/georgia-parent-top-concerns/"&gt;Three issues Georgia parents are most concerned about&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 22:42:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Virginiainstitute] The State of Educational Opportunity in Virginia – A Survey of Virginia Parents</title><link>https://virginiainstitute.org/the-state-of-educational-opportunity-in-virginia-a-survey-of-virginia-parents/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=the-state-of-educational-opportunity-in-virginia-a-survey-of-virginia-parents</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 11:07:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Virginiainstitute] Press Release – 50CAN Reveals Call for More Education Choice in Virginia</title><link>https://virginiainstitute.org/press-release-50can-reveals-call-for-more-education-choice-in-virginia/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=press-release-50can-reveals-call-for-more-education-choice-in-virginia</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Summary A recent poll conducted by the Virginia Institute for Public Policy (VIPP) in partnership with 50CAN reveals a strong demand among Virginia parents for expanded educational choices ahead of&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org/press-release-50can-reveals-call-for-more-education-choice-in-virginia/"&gt;Press Release – 50CAN Reveals Call for More Education Choice in Virginia&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org"&gt;Virginia Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 14:47:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] ROI-NJ: New Jersey Policy Institute appoints Unity Bank exec Boyan as board member</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/07/roi-nj-new-jersey-policy-institute-appoints-unity-bank-exec-boyan-as-board-member/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;ROI-NJ recently featured the New Jersey Policy Institute&amp;#8217;s (NJPI) newest board member, George Boyan, Executive Vice President and CFO of [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/07/roi-nj-new-jersey-policy-institute-appoints-unity-bank-exec-boyan-as-board-member/"&gt;ROI-NJ: New Jersey Policy Institute appoints Unity Bank exec Boyan as board member&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 16:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] API Announces Support of the STUDENTS Act</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/08/01/api-announces-support-of-the-students-act/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Alabama Policy Institute (API) announced its endorsement of the federal Stopping Teachers Unions from Damaging Education Needs Today (STUDENTS) Act, which seeks to reform the federal charter of the country’s largest education union, the National Education Association (NEA).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/08/01/api-announces-support-of-the-students-act/"&gt;API Announces Support of the STUDENTS Act&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 01:32:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Conforming to Trump’s Tax Bill Would Save Virginians $1.4 Billion More</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/conforming-to-trumps-tax-bill-would-save-virginians-1-4-billion-more/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="630" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Virginia-and-Trump.jpg" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Should the 2026 Virginia General Assembly choose to conform state tax laws to the full set of new tax rules at the federal level, Virginia families and businesses might save as much at $1.4 billion annually. That is a fresh estimate from the Tax Foundation, which looked at the impact of full conformity in all 50 [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/conforming-to-trumps-tax-bill-would-save-virginians-1-4-billion-more/"&gt;Conforming to Trump&amp;#8217;s Tax Bill Would Save Virginians $1.4 Billion More&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 12:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Kansas Is Losing the Competition for People—and It’s Not Just a Kansas Problem</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/kansas-is-losing-the-competition-for-people/</link><description>Americans are voting with their feet, and states are either competing for them—or watching them leave. Data posted by the Committee to Unleash Prosperity at VoteWithYourFeet.net make it painfully clear: Kansas is hemorrhaging residents. Over the last decade, it had a net loss of nearly 100,000 people to other states. That’s not just bad optics—that’s [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 14:00:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] New York’s Medicaid Spending Rate Remains the Highest of Any State</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/new-yorks-medicaid-spending-rate-remains-the-highest-of-any-state/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New York&amp;#8217;s Medicaid program remained a spending outlier in 2024, with per-resident outlays that were 24 percent higher than those....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/new-yorks-medicaid-spending-rate-remains-the-highest-of-any-state/"&gt;New York&amp;#8217;s Medicaid Spending Rate Remains the Highest of Any State&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 14:10:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] Pennsylvania Enters Second Month of Budget Impasse</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/08/01/pennsylvania-enters-second-month-of-budget-impasse/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Harrisburg, Pa., August 1, 2025 — Pennsylvania is entering the second month operating without a state budget, with no end in sight. Amid the protracted impasse, many have begun to question the governor’s priorities as days pass without substantial progress. Andrew Lewis, President and CEO of the Commonwealth Foundation, issued the following statement in response: [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/08/01/pennsylvania-enters-second-month-of-budget-impasse/"&gt;Pennsylvania Enters Second Month of Budget Impasse&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 17:51:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Metro Council Votes to Approve $88.5 Million Bond for Road Diets: One Intern’s Reflection</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/transportation/metro-council-votes-to-approve-88-5-million-bond-for-road-diets-one-interns-reflection/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Connor Roberts The summer of 2025 brought Cascade three talented Research Associates...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/transportation/metro-council-votes-to-approve-88-5-million-bond-for-road-diets-one-interns-reflection/"&gt;Metro Council Votes to Approve $88.5 Million Bond for Road Diets: One Intern’s Reflection  &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 22:37:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] New Report Finds Pennsylvania Violating Law, Endangering Students in Dangerous Schools</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/08/05/new-report-finds-pennsylvania-violating-law-endangering-students-in-dangerous-schools/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Harrisburg, Pa., August 5, 2025—The Pennsylvania Department of Education (PDE) is violating state and federal law around “persistently dangerous schools,” endangering the safety of Pennsylvania’s most vulnerable students, and threatening billions in federal funding, according to a groundbreaking analysis from the Commonwealth Foundation.&amp;#160; More than 40 percent of Pennsylvania schools face dangerous incidents, but state [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/08/05/new-report-finds-pennsylvania-violating-law-endangering-students-in-dangerous-schools/"&gt;New Report Finds Pennsylvania Violating Law, Endangering Students in Dangerous Schools&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 14:42:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Blatant Lawlessness</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/08/05/blatant-lawlessness/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="948" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/Screenshot-2025-08-06-093200.jpg" width="1324" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new Yankee Institute report, Blatant Lawlessness: How the CT Department of Labor &amp;#38; Union Leaders Disrespect Union Workers and Ignore the Law, highlights the Connecticut Department of Labor’s (CT [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/08/05/blatant-lawlessness/"&gt;Blatant Lawlessness&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 20:35:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Speaker Jason White: Education Freedom and Mississippi’s Future</title><link>https://empowerms.org/speaker-jason-white-education-freedom-and-mississippis-future/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Speaker Jason White: Education Freedom and Mississippi&amp;#8217;s Future Fresh off his speech at the Neshoba County Fair, Mississippi&amp;#8217;s 62nd Speaker of the House, Jason White joins host Grant Callen for this episode of the Empower Podcast. We recap his fair speech and talk about the experience of walking out on that storied stage at Neshoba.&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/speaker-jason-white-education-freedom-and-mississippis-future/"&gt;Speaker Jason White: Education Freedom and Mississippi’s Future&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 21:13:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] The federal Jones Act is a case study in the power of special interests</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/08/the-federal-jones-act-is-a-case-study-in-the-power-of-special-interests/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following commentary first published by the Cato Institute on Aug. 4, 2025, under the headline &amp;#8220;How special interests keep bad laws on the books: The case of the Jones Act.&amp;#8221;_____________ Seven years ago, the Cato Institute launched its project on reforming the Jones Act — the 1920 law that restricts intra-U.S. water transport to vessels that [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/08/the-federal-jones-act-is-a-case-study-in-the-power-of-special-interests/"&gt;The federal Jones Act is a case study in the power of special interests&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 03:35:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] OP-ED by Stephanie Smith, API President/CEO and mother of seven</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/08/06/op-ed-by-stephanie-smith-api-president-ceo-and-mother-of-seven/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Fourth Circuit of the U.S. Court of Appeals recently upheld West Virginia’s near-total ban on chemical abortions — a major win for federalism, health safety, and the pro-life movement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/08/06/op-ed-by-stephanie-smith-api-president-ceo-and-mother-of-seven/"&gt;OP-ED by Stephanie Smith, API President/CEO and mother of seven&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 05:47:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Tina Kotek’s Energy Policy: Whichever Way the Wind Blows</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/environment/tina-koteks-energy-policy-whichever-way-the-wind-blows/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Maxwell Powers Governor Tina Kotek has long expressed support for wind power....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/environment/tina-koteks-energy-policy-whichever-way-the-wind-blows/"&gt;Tina Kotek’s Energy Policy: Whichever Way the Wind Blows&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 14:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] WILL Advises DPI to Improve Transparency and Accountability in School Report Card</title><link>https://will-law.org/will-advises-dpi-to-improve-transparency-and-accountability-in-school-report-card/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL submitted recommendations to the Department of Public Instruction (DPI) today, urging an overhaul of the state’s school report card standards. WILL’s analysis highlights DPI's track record of inflating ratings that masks a decades-long stagnation in student achievement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/will-advises-dpi-to-improve-transparency-and-accountability-in-school-report-card/"&gt;WILL Advises DPI to Improve Transparency and Accountability in School Report Card&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 15:13:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] DAILY CALLER: Don’t California-Ize The New Jersey Independent Workforce</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/08/daily-caller-dont-california-ize-the-new-jersey-independent-workforce/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Rosemary Becchi, President and Founder of NJPI, co-authored an op-ed in The Daily Caller with Patrice Onwuka, Director of the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/08/daily-caller-dont-california-ize-the-new-jersey-independent-workforce/"&gt;DAILY CALLER: Don’t California-Ize The New Jersey Independent Workforce&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 17:01:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Opt-out record falls for the third consecutive month</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/opt-out-record-falls-for-the-third-consecutive-month/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Freedom Foundation has done it again, setting yet another record for monthly union opt-outs. That’s three months in a row. In July alone, 5,381 government employees made the decision to leave their union, bringing the total financial impact to more than $5 million in annual dues redirected away from unions that can no longer [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/opt-out-record-falls-for-the-third-consecutive-month/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Opt-out record falls for the third consecutive month&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 17:11:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF weighs in on fraud investigation at Office of Insurance Superintendent</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-weighs-in-on-fraud-investigation-at-office-of-insurance-superintendent/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;There is a lawsuit and investigation going on at New Mexico&amp;#8217;s Office of the Superintendent of Insurance. The state is spending nearly half a million dollars of your money investigating what they call &amp;#8220;potential irregularities&amp;#8221; in New Mexico&amp;#8217;s insurance fraud fund. But, rather than investigating companies for alleged fraud they are investigating internally. They are [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-weighs-in-on-fraud-investigation-at-office-of-insurance-superintendent/"&gt;RGF weighs in on fraud investigation at Office of Insurance Superintendent&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 19:32:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Fate of Dominion Gas Plant Depends On Which Experts, Models the SCC Believes</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/fate-of-dominion-gas-plant-depends-on-which-experts-models-the-scc-believes/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="371" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/IMG_3006.png" width="737" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The State Corporation Commission’s (SCC) decision on whether Dominion Energy can build a new natural gas-fired power plant will depend on which expert or set of experts it believes, and which of the many computer models that dominate the testimony it judges best predict Virginia’s energy future. Dominion has filed testimony to the SCC from [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/fate-of-dominion-gas-plant-depends-on-which-experts-models-the-scc-believes/"&gt;Fate of Dominion Gas Plant Depends On Which Experts, Models the SCC Believes &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 02:15:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] First Statewide Poll Shows Marsha Blackburn as Clear Frontrunner Over John Rose in GOP Primary for Governor</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/blackburn-rose-beaconpoll/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=blackburn-rose-beaconpoll</link><description>In light of Senator Marsha Blackburn&amp;#8217;s recent announcement that she plans to run for governor of Tennessee, Beacon is releasing the poll results of the Republican gubernatorial primary a few days early. In the field before Senator Blackburn’s official announcement, the poll asked Tennesseans who they would support in the 2025 GOP primary for governor, Senator...</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 13:00:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Maine’s Soaring Electricity Prices Highlight Need for Smarter Energy Policy</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/maines-soaring-electricity-prices-highlight-need-for-smarter-energy-policy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This year, many Mainers felt a jolt when they opened their energy bills. According to data gathered from the U.S. Energy Information Administration (EIA), Maine experienced the largest year-over-year residential electricity price increase in the country: a staggering 36.3% jump between May 2024 and May 2025. That&amp;#8217;s more than five times the national average increase [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/maines-soaring-electricity-prices-highlight-need-for-smarter-energy-policy/"&gt;Maine&amp;#8217;s Soaring Electricity Prices Highlight Need for Smarter Energy Policy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 15:22:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] The Mississippi Center for Public Policy welcomes new Chief Development Officer</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/the-mississippi-center-for-public-policy-welcomes-new-chief-development-officer/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Jackson, MS&amp;#160;— The Mississippi Center for Public Policy (MCPP) is pleased to announce the addition of Richard Wilson as its new Chief Development Officer. With a distinguished background in campaign management, government affairs, and nonprofit fundraising, Wilson brings a wealth of experience and a proven track record of results-driven leadership to MCPP. “We are thrilled [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/the-mississippi-center-for-public-policy-welcomes-new-chief-development-officer/" rel="nofollow"&gt;The Mississippi Center for Public Policy welcomes new Chief Development Officer&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 18:26:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] EFA enrollment for this fall in line with Josiah Bartlett Center estimates</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/08/efa-enrollment-for-this-fall-in-line-with-josiah-bartlett-center-estimates/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New Hampshire’s Education Freedom Account program hit its enrollment cap of 10,000 students for the upcoming school year, the Children’s Scholarship Fund-NH confirmed this week. As talk of the program growing beyond expectations spread through social media, readers of this website shouldn’t have been surprised by the numbers.  They’re almost exactly what we predicted five [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/08/efa-enrollment-for-this-fall-in-line-with-josiah-bartlett-center-estimates/"&gt;EFA enrollment for this fall in line with Josiah Bartlett Center estimates&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 21:14:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Nampa’s Ford Idaho Center: A Multi-Million Dollar Giveaway?</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/nampas-ford-idaho-center-a-multi-million-dollar-giveaway/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/nampas-ford-idaho-center-a-multi-million-dollar-giveaway/" rel="nofollow" title="Nampa’s Ford Idaho Center: A Multi-Million Dollar Giveaway? "&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/Article-Headers-2025-08-07T185321.585.png" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;In what may well be the most extraordinary act of unsolicited civic generosity on this side of the Treasure Valley, Nampa Mayor Debbie Kling and the Nampa City Council are contemplating the “conveyance” of the Ford Idaho Center (FIC) to the College of Western Idaho (CWI) — no appraisal, no payment, and an utter lack [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 02:20:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Meet Our New Director of Research</title><link>https://empowerms.org/meet-our-new-director-of-research/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;We’re excited to welcome Dr. Kristin Vance Richards as the new Director of Research at Empower Mississippi. In this role, she will lead our research efforts and help shape data-driven strategies that advance our work in education, work, and criminal justice. Kristin brings deep expertise and a strong commitment to using research to drive meaningful&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/meet-our-new-director-of-research/"&gt;Meet Our New Director of Research&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 06:00:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Competition in education is an opportunity, not a crisis</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/08/competition-in-education-is-an-opportunity-not-a-crisis/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;There’s been a bit of a media freakout this week about the growing popularity of school choice programs nationwide.  The Children’s Scholarship Fund-NH confirmed this week that the Education Freedom Account program hit its 2025-26 enrollment cap of 10,000 students in early August.   “Record number of students matched with their preferred form of education,” [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/08/competition-in-education-is-an-opportunity-not-a-crisis/"&gt;Competition in education is an opportunity, not a crisis&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 16:56:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Connecticut’s New Law Lets Unions and the State Peek into School Budgets</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/08/08/connecticuts-new-law-lets-unions-and-the-state-peek-into-school-budgets/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senate Bill 1 was promoted as a $300 million investment in early childhood education and special education services. But buried in the bill is a provision with little to do [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/08/08/connecticuts-new-law-lets-unions-and-the-state-peek-into-school-budgets/"&gt;Connecticut’s New Law Lets Unions and the State Peek into School Budgets&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 20:06:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Welcome Our New Director of Outreach</title><link>https://empowerms.org/welcome-our-new-director-of-outreach/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;We’re excited to welcome Ashley Geen to the Empower Mississippi team as our new Outreach Director. In this role, Ashley will lead our efforts to connect with individuals most impacted by public policy in education, work, and criminal justice. Her work will focus on elevating community voices and ensuring those directly affected have a platform&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/welcome-our-new-director-of-outreach/"&gt;Welcome Our New Director of Outreach&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 01:42:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Spanberger Proposal Would Undermine Local Economic Growth</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/spanberger-proposal-would-undermine-local-economic-growth/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="598" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/Spanberger.jpg" width="1139" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Democratic gubernatorial candidate Abigail Spanberger wants voters to believe she’s a moderate. That’s understandable.&amp;#160; At a time when the Democratic Party’s favorability is at 33 percent and with an avowed socialist as the party’s nominee in the most highly visible election in the nation, the smart money is for Democrats in Virginia to run far [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/spanberger-proposal-would-undermine-local-economic-growth/"&gt;Spanberger Proposal Would Undermine Local Economic Growth&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 02:03:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] August 2025 Beacon Poll Results</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/august-2025-beacon-poll-results/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=august-2025-beacon-poll-results</link><description>A majority of Tennesseans, 56% of voters, believe the cap on Education Freedom Scholarships should be lifted from where it currently sits at 20,000 so that all eligible families who applied this year can use the program, while 30% of Tennesseans disagree and believe the cap should remain where it is. Polling has shown consistent support...</description><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 12:45:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Despite Statewide Legalization, Boston has a lot of Work to Do to Allow By-Right ADUs Within Its Borders</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/economic_opportunity/despite-statewide-legalization-boston-has-a-lot-of-work-to-do-to-allow-by-right-adus-within-its-borders/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This edition of The House Call explains why the City of Boston is behind the curve on broadly allowing accessory dwelling units by right, and what it's doing to catch up. The newsletter also explores the (limited) housing options for seasonal workers on Cape Cod and how some employers are housing workers in company-owned buildings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/economic_opportunity/despite-statewide-legalization-boston-has-a-lot-of-work-to-do-to-allow-by-right-adus-within-its-borders/"&gt;Despite Statewide Legalization, Boston has a lot of Work to Do to Allow By-Right ADUs Within Its Borders&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 15:45:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] WTOK looks at what School Choice might mean for Mississippi</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/wtok-looks-at-what-school-choice-might-mean-for-mississippi/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I’m thrilled to share that momentum for School Choice in Mississippi is growing!&amp;#160;Governor Tate Reeves, Speaker Jason White, and even the White House are championing this transformative opportunity to empower parents and enhance education for our children. This week, WTOK TV aired an in-depth segment exploring how School Choice could benefit families across our state.&amp;#160;I [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/wtok-looks-at-what-school-choice-might-mean-for-mississippi/" rel="nofollow"&gt;WTOK looks at what School Choice might mean for Mississippi&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 16:08:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Who protects the protectors? The harsh reality for Kansas prison staff</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/kansas/who-protects-the-protectors/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Americans working in the Department of Corrections (DOC) are overworked, understaffed and, simply put, underrepresented. Correction Officers (COs) and other DOC employees are often represented by unions that include a wide range of state employees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/kansas/who-protects-the-protectors/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Who protects the protectors? The harsh reality for Kansas prison staff&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 16:27:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] Keller leads in ABQ Mayoral Race Funding: RGF decries broken campaign finance system</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/keller-leads-in-abq-mayoral-race-funding-rgf-decries-broken-campaign-finance-system/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;What do you call a public financing for a mayor&amp;#8217;s race with 7 candidates but the ONLY candidate to get taxpayer dollars to run their campaign is the incumbent who is also looking for a 3rd term? Some terms that come to mind are &amp;#8220;failed,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;corrupt,&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;anti-democratic.&amp;#8221; RGF&amp;#8217;s president recently sat down with KOAT [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/keller-leads-in-abq-mayoral-race-funding-rgf-decries-broken-campaign-finance-system/"&gt;Keller leads in ABQ Mayoral Race Funding: RGF decries broken campaign finance system&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 17:31:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] How Nebraska Can Lead Industrial Reshoring with Full Expensing</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/how-nebraska-can-lead-industrial-reshoring-with-full-expensing/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;President Trump’s second term will be remembered for the rapid re-ordering of global supply chains. Trump’s tariffs target the reshoring of industrial production, and his tax plan in the One Big Beautiful Bill (OBBB) provides massive tax incentives to make capital expenditures in the United States.  Nebraska has an opportunity to put itself at the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/how-nebraska-can-lead-industrial-reshoring-with-full-expensing/" rel="nofollow"&gt;How Nebraska Can Lead Industrial Reshoring with Full Expensing&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 19:32:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Two years later, too little rebuilding in Lahaina</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/08/two-years-later-too-little-rebuilding-in-lahaina/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Maui County was forever changed two years ago when wildfires destroyed much of historic Lahaina. But it&amp;#8217;s also been tragic to witness how regulations and bureaucracy have made life so much more difficult for the survivors trying to rebuild. From the very beginning, my team at the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii knew that clearing away [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/08/two-years-later-too-little-rebuilding-in-lahaina/"&gt;Two years later, too little rebuilding in Lahaina&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 23:35:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Iowa Mom Threatened with Lawsuit for Criticizing Curriculum at School Board Meeting</title><link>https://will-law.org/iowa-mom-threatened-with-lawsuit-for-criticizing-curriculum-at-school-board-meeting/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;#038; Liberty (WILL) is representing an Iowa parent with respect to a potential defamation lawsuit after she, a newly naturalized citizen from the Dominican Republic, spoke at a public school board meeting about her concerns regarding certain curricula and instructional materials used in her son’s classroom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/iowa-mom-threatened-with-lawsuit-for-criticizing-curriculum-at-school-board-meeting/"&gt;Iowa Mom Threatened with Lawsuit for Criticizing Curriculum at School Board Meeting&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 13:59:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Arkansas PBM Law Enjoined</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/legal-regulatory/arkansas-pbm-law-enjoined/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Louisiana lawmakers considered a bill that would have prohibited companies from owning both pharmacy benefit managers (PBMs) and retail pharmacies in the closing days of the 2025 legislative session. The bill, HB 358, died when the Senate declined to vote on it; however, the talk around Baton Rouge is that the legislature will revisit the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/legal-regulatory/arkansas-pbm-law-enjoined/"&gt;Arkansas PBM Law Enjoined&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 15:26:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Texas Pursues Property Tax Reforms in Special Session</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/texas-pursues-property-tax-reforms-in-special-session/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Texas Governor Greg Abbott called lawmakers back for a special session to address Texas’ property tax burden. In his special session proclamation, Abbott has asked lawmakers to focus on two complementary items. The first is allocating more state money to reduce property taxes, and the second is to impose more strict spending restraints on local...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/texas-pursues-property-tax-reforms-in-special-session/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Texas Pursues Property Tax Reforms in Special Session&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 19:10:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] Snow: Gerrymandering Is a Distraction</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/08/snow-gerrymandering-is-a-distraction/</link><description>by Nathanael&amp;#160;Snow, Ph.D. Indiana, like most other states, redraws its Congressional voting districts every 10 years when a new Census comes out. Shifts in population within and among states require that new lines are drawn to balance the number of citizens represented in each district. This helps to preserve the connection of citizens to their&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/08/snow-gerrymandering-is-a-distraction/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 21:52:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] What to know about education in Georgia as students go back to school</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/what-to-know-about-education-in-georgia/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As August ushers in a new school year in Georgia, nearly two million students are headed back to our states 2,300 public schools. How are Georgia schools doing when it comes to preparing kids for work and life? Here's a look at some key measures. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/what-to-know-about-education-in-georgia/"&gt;What to know about education in Georgia as students go back to school&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 22:26:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] Pa. Senate Passes Budget Protecting Taxpayers, as Shapiro, House Democrats Continue Gridlock</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/08/12/pa-senate-passes-budget-protecting-taxpayers-as-shapiro-house-democrats-continue-gridlock/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Harrisburg, Pa., August 12, 2025&amp;#160;— Today, the Pennsylvania Senate is advancing a spending bill that provides the clearest path forward in months toward a sustainable state budget. The commonwealth is now well into the second month of a protracted impasse, operating without a state budget in place. Despite Gov. Josh Shapiro declaring in June that [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/08/12/pa-senate-passes-budget-protecting-taxpayers-as-shapiro-house-democrats-continue-gridlock/"&gt;Pa. Senate Passes Budget Protecting Taxpayers, as Shapiro, House Democrats Continue Gridlock&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 23:11:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Goldwater Sues Indiana School District that Retaliated Against Mom</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/goldwater-sues-indiana-school-district-that-retaliated-against-mom/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A Northeast Indiana mom sued her school district in Federal Court this week with the help of the Goldwater Institute..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/goldwater-sues-indiana-school-district-that-retaliated-against-mom/"&gt;Goldwater Sues Indiana School District that Retaliated Against Mom&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 10:37:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Nebraska’s Top Property Tax Targets</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/nebraskas-top-property-tax-targets/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Property tax relief is always top of the agenda in Lincoln, as Nebraskans struggle under the weight of one of the nation’s heaviest property tax burdens. Nebraska should target two taxes to take off the rolls, and two technical changes to restructure the property tax system to deliver better relief.   Currently, Nebraska puts $1 billion...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/nebraskas-top-property-tax-targets/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Nebraska’s Top Property Tax Targets&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 13:50:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] DOGE Taskforce Considers Pension Overhaul for New Hires</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/doge-taskforce-considers-pension-overhaul-for-new-hires/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Reforming public pensions isn’t easy. Whether it’s Social Security at the federal level or Iowa’s IPERS program, these systems come with deep political roots—and big financial consequences. But as the cost of benefits grows, so does the need to keep promises without overburdening taxpayers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s why Iowa’s DOGE Taskforce is weighing a reform that could affect future public employees. The Taskforce’s Return on Investment Committee, chaired by the former mayor of Fort Dodge, Terry Lutz, has suggested Iowa consider shifting new public workers into a retirement model that resembles a 401(k). In other words, future employees—not current ones—would participate in a system based on contributions and investment performance, similar to what most private sector workers use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/doge-taskforce-considers-pension-overhaul-for-new-hires/"&gt;DOGE Taskforce Considers Pension Overhaul for New Hires&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 14:37:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] After 50 years, the Snake River Dams have been a blessing and will continue to be</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/after-50-years-the-snake-river-dams-have-been-a-blessing-and-will-continue-to-be</link><description>Note: This is a guest op-ed by Todd Myers of the Washington Policy Center. It has been fifty years since the four dams on the Lower Snake...</description><pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 14:42:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Pepperdine Law’s Pulitzer Winner Edward Larson on 100th Anniv. of Scopes Monkey Trial</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/pepperdine-laws-pulitzer-winner-edward-larson-on-100th-anniv-of-scopes-monkey-trial/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This week on The Learning Curve, co-hosts U-Arkansas Prof. Albert Cheng and Ret. MN Supreme Court Justice Barry Anderson interview Pulitzer Prize-winning historian and Pepperdine Law’s, Prof. Edward Larson. Prof. Larson marks the 100th anniversary of the Scopes “Monkey Trial,” a landmark case in America’s long-running debate over science, religion, and public education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/pepperdine-laws-pulitzer-winner-edward-larson-on-100th-anniv-of-scopes-monkey-trial/"&gt;Pepperdine Law&amp;#8217;s Pulitzer Winner Edward Larson on 100th Anniv. of Scopes Monkey Trial&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 14:49:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] New WILL Report: Trump Tax Bill Creates Major Opportunity to Expand Educational Opportunities for Wisconsin Families</title><link>https://will-law.org/new-will-report-trump-tax-bill-creates-major-opportunity-to-expand-educational-opportunities-for-wisconsin-families/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL unveiled a new report detailing how Wisconsin can unlock a major stream of education funding for Wisconsin families – all at no expense to the state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/new-will-report-trump-tax-bill-creates-major-opportunity-to-expand-educational-opportunities-for-wisconsin-families/"&gt;New WILL Report: Trump Tax Bill Creates Major Opportunity to Expand Educational Opportunities for Wisconsin Families&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 17:35:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Average New NYC Fire Pensions Surpass $170K</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/average-new-nyc-fire-pensions-surpass-170k/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New York City firefighters and fire officers retiring last year after full careers were entitled to average annual pension benefits....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/average-new-nyc-fire-pensions-surpass-170k/"&gt;Average New NYC Fire Pensions Surpass $170K&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 18:25:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Special Session Should Use Emergency Funds, Not Punish Oregonians</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/transportation/special-session-should-use-emergency-funds-not-punish-oregonians/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Connor Roberts The Oregon Department of Transportation (ODOT) has a $350 million...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/transportation/special-session-should-use-emergency-funds-not-punish-oregonians/"&gt;Special Session Should Use Emergency Funds, Not Punish Oregonians&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 21:30:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] The Case for Carbon Sequestration via Natural Gas Power Plants</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/the-case-for-carbon-sequestration-via-natural-gas-power-plants/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=the-case-for-carbon-sequestration-via-natural-gas-power-plants</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In the case Massachusetts v. EPA in 2007, the U.S. Supreme Court ruled that the Environmental Protection Agency can regulate greenhouse gases because they qualify as air pollutants. And ever since, electric power plants using “thermal” fuels have faced escalating regulatory pressure. How this has played out for coal fired power plants in the Western United States is summarized...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/the-case-for-carbon-sequestration-via-natural-gas-power-plants/"&gt;The Case for Carbon Sequestration via Natural Gas Power Plants&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 23:16:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] (Machine) Learning in Louisiana Schools</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/machine-learning-in-louisiana-schools/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For many around the state, last week marked the first day of school. Students, teachers, and parents alike are preparing for the academic year with all its challenges and excitement. Louisiana is a growing hub for tech innovation, and our schools are no exception. The schools and businesses of our state are investing in the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/machine-learning-in-louisiana-schools/"&gt;(Machine) Learning in Louisiana Schools&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 13:20:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Get to Know Kathryn Beale, Beacon’s New Director of Development</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/get-to-know-kat-beale-beacons-new-director-of-development/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=get-to-know-kat-beale-beacons-new-director-of-development</link><description>Tell us about you—where you’re from, any fun facts about yourself, and where you spent your career prior to Beacon. I’m originally from Benton, Kentucky, a small town in the very western corner of the Bluegrass State. But, important to my upbringing, I am not a Wildcat! I spent four years in Nashville at Lipscomb...</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 15:13:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Beloit-area public school teacher loss</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/beloit-area-public-school-teacher-loss/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The School District of Beloit annually lost almost a quarter of its teachers on average during or right after the 2021-22, 2022-23 and 2023-24 school years — far higher than the loss rates for those years for both the adjacent School District of Beloit Turner and the state as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/beloit-area-public-school-teacher-loss/"&gt;Beloit-area public school teacher loss &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 16:21:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] Justin Bogie: Alabama’s grocery tax cut is a win – but lawmakers should finish the job</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/08/14/justin-bogie-alabamas-grocery-tax-cut-is-a-win-but-lawmakers-should-finish-the-job/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On September 1st, Alabama families will receive another dose of relief at the checkout line. The state’s sales tax on groceries will drop from 3% to 2%, continuing a rollback that began in 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/08/14/justin-bogie-alabamas-grocery-tax-cut-is-a-win-but-lawmakers-should-finish-the-job/"&gt;Justin Bogie: Alabama’s grocery tax cut is a win – but lawmakers should finish the job&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 17:41:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] A Free Market Fix for Health Insurance</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/a-free-market-fix-for-health-insurance/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;America’s health insurance system is pricing out the very people who drive our economy: small business owners and the self-employed...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/a-free-market-fix-for-health-insurance/"&gt;A Free Market Fix for Health Insurance&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 18:02:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Kansas Can’t Afford to Lose Trust in the Jobs Numbers</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/kansas-lose-trust-in-the-jobs-numbers/</link><description>The latest Bureau of Labor Statistics (BLS) jobs report landed like a thunderclap in Washington — and it could send shockwaves to Topeka. For July, the BLS reported 73,000 net new jobs nationwide, 83,000 in the private sector, offset by a loss of 10,000 in government jobs. The unemployment rate ticked up to 4.2%, and [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 18:18:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] New York’s Hospital Quality Remains Among the Worst in the U.S.</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/new-yorks-hospital-quality-remains-among-the-worst-in-the-u-s/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The federal government recently updated its hospital quality ratings, and New York once again fell near the bottom. Among 132....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/new-yorks-hospital-quality-remains-among-the-worst-in-the-u-s/"&gt;New York&amp;#8217;s Hospital Quality Remains Among the Worst in the U.S.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 18:44:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] NJ ED REPORT: Amplifying Student Voices: Advocating for Younger and More Inclusive Representation in IEP Meetings</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/08/nj-ed-report-amplifying-student-voices-advocating-for-younger-and-more-inclusive-representation-in-iep-meetings/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;NJPI policy research intern David Fishkin, a Political Science student at Rutgers University – New Brunswick, has published an op-ed [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/08/nj-ed-report-amplifying-student-voices-advocating-for-younger-and-more-inclusive-representation-in-iep-meetings/"&gt;NJ ED REPORT: Amplifying Student Voices: Advocating for Younger and More Inclusive Representation in IEP Meetings&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 18:52:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] PNELF Admonishes DOR for Inaction on Unauthorized and Unconstitutional Commercial Tax Overcharges</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/nelf-admonishes-dor-for-inaction-on-unauthorized-and-unconstitutional-commercial-tax-overcharges/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Pioneer New England Legal Foundation (PNELF) is calling out the Massachusetts Department of Revenue (DOR) for refusing to act on clear evidence that the City of Boston is penalizing commercial taxpayers for exercising their constitutional right to appeal overassessments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/nelf-admonishes-dor-for-inaction-on-unauthorized-and-unconstitutional-commercial-tax-overcharges/"&gt;PNELF Admonishes DOR for Inaction on Unauthorized and Unconstitutional Commercial Tax Overcharges&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 21:08:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Economics: The Rodney Dangerfield of modern politics</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/economics-the-rodney-dangerfield-of-modern-politics/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In both Washington and Madison, basic economic principles are routinely ignored, as if policymakers believe they can repeal the laws of supply and demand with campaign slogans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/economics-the-rodney-dangerfield-of-modern-politics/"&gt;Economics: The Rodney Dangerfield of modern politics&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 21:18:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Private schools in Wisconsin’s choice programs prove far more effective with taxpayer money</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/private-schools-in-wisconsins-choice-programs-prove-far-more-effective-with-taxpayer-money/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;School choice is 41 percent more effective in Racine, and in the rest of Wisconsin, money going to choice is spent 33 percent more effectively than in district schools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/private-schools-in-wisconsins-choice-programs-prove-far-more-effective-with-taxpayer-money/"&gt;Private schools in Wisconsin’s choice programs prove far more effective with taxpayer money&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 22:03:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Parental Rights and Responsibilities in Louisiana: A Free Market Approach to Child Protection and Guidance</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/parental-rights-and-responsibilities-in-louisiana-a-free-market-approach-to-child-protection-and-guidance/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In Louisiana, the legal framework governing parental rights and responsibilities strikes a delicate balance between empowering families and ensuring child safety. Rooted in statutes like the Civil Code and Children’s Code, these laws affirm that parents are the primary guardians of their children’s well-being, with the state intervening only in cases of clear neglect or...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/parental-rights-and-responsibilities-in-louisiana-a-free-market-approach-to-child-protection-and-guidance/"&gt;Parental Rights and Responsibilities in Louisiana: A Free Market Approach to Child Protection and Guidance&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 23:12:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Helton hopeful that Lahaina recovery will move faster</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/08/helton-hopeful-that-lahaina-recovery-will-move-faster/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The rebuilding of Lahaina has been slow for myriad reasons, but that doesn’t have to continue, according to&amp;#160;Jonathan Helton, Grassroot Institute of Hawaii policy analyst. Speaking this past Sunday with host&amp;#160;Johnny Miro&amp;#160;of the H. Hawaii Media radio network, Helton, author of Grassroot&amp;#8217;s&amp;#160;newest report concerning Lahaina&amp;#8217;s recovery, said the rebuilding could move along faster if the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/08/helton-hopeful-that-lahaina-recovery-will-move-faster/"&gt;Helton hopeful that Lahaina recovery will move faster&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 01:18:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Repeal the EPA's Carbon Pollution Standards</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/repeal-the-epas-carbon-pollution-standards</link><description>Comments submitted to the Environmental Protection Agency</description><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Every school, public or private, should have to prove its worth</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/every-school-public-or-private-should-have-to-prove-its-worth</link><description>Idaho’s new school choice program is turning up the heat. That’s great news — because every school, public or private, should have to prove its worth.</description><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 15:05:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] The Empire Strikes Back: Britain’s War on American Cloud Supremacy</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/the-empire-strikes-back-britains-war-on-american-cloud-supremacy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For the average American, &amp;#8220;cloud computing&amp;#8221; summons visions of precious family photos and business documents vanishing into the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/the-empire-strikes-back-britains-war-on-american-cloud-supremacy/"&gt;The Empire Strikes Back: Britain&amp;#8217;s War on American Cloud Supremacy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 15:35:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] New, Flawed Rating Changes Cover Up for Underperforming Schools, Again</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/new-flawed-rating-changes-cover-up-for-underperforming-schools-again/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New, Flawed Rating Changes Cover Up for Underperforming Schools, Again IRG uncovers changes that hide low-performing districts from parents Delafield, Wis. — The Institute for Reforming Government (IRG) issued a statement after the Wisconsin DPI again changed its 1–5 star school ratings at an August 12–14 Madison meeting, leaving parents unclear on local school performance. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/new-flawed-rating-changes-cover-up-for-underperforming-schools-again/"&gt;New, Flawed Rating Changes Cover Up for Underperforming Schools, Again&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 16:17:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Week in Review: Going to Court for Parents Rights</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-going-to-court-for-parents-rights/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The First Amendment guarantees Americans the right to record government officials performing their duties. But last year, a mom in..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-going-to-court-for-parents-rights/"&gt;Week in Review: Going to Court for Parents Rights&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 17:36:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] State Board of Ed votes to reduce proficiency standards; legislators should implement a different state assessment</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/state-board-of-ed-reduces-proficiency-standards/</link><description>The Kansas State Board of Education voted 7-3 this week to accept new cut scores for determining proficiency levels on the state assessment test, setting the stage for the Kansas Legislature to hopefully halt the imposition of less rigorous performance standards. More on that shortly after a brief recap of the fraud being perpetrated on [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 18:03:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] A Champion for Iowa Taxpayers: Remembering David Stanley’s Quest for Taxpayer Protections</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/a-champion-for-iowa-taxpayers-remembering-david-stanleys-quest-for-taxpayer-protections/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The late David M. Stanley (1928–2015) does not receive enough credit for building the conservative movement in Iowa. Stanley served in both the House and Senate of the Iowa Legislature, including leadership positions. He served as chair of the House Ways and Means Committee and as Senate Majority Leader. Stanley also ran twice to win election as a United States Senator, although unsuccessfully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David Stanley’s public service did not end once he left the legislature. He was a conservative who believed strongly in constitutional limited government. His public service therefore continued with founding and participating in numerous organizations that contributed to the conservative movement in Iowa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/a-champion-for-iowa-taxpayers-remembering-david-stanleys-quest-for-taxpayer-protections/"&gt;A Champion for Iowa Taxpayers: Remembering David Stanley’s Quest for Taxpayer Protections&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 20:05:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Governor Little: “Idaho will further improve government efficiency and reduce government spending”</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/governor-little-idaho-will-further-improve-government-efficiency-and-reduce-government-spending</link><description>Changes are coming to Idaho’s current budget with Governor Little acting swiftly to focus on government efficiencies in response to...</description><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 20:10:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] A Risky Proposal to Divert Connecticut’s Surplus</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/08/15/a-risky-proposal-to-divert-connecticuts-surplus/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connecticut&amp;#8217;s budget surplus presents a critical choice: use the one-time windfall to address the state&amp;#8217;s deep-rooted financial problems or spend it on new, permanent government programs. Progressive activists are pushing [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/08/15/a-risky-proposal-to-divert-connecticuts-surplus/"&gt;A Risky Proposal to Divert Connecticut&amp;#8217;s Surplus&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 20:11:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] State financial inputs aren’t the measure of a university system</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/08/state-financial-inputs-arent-the-measure-of-a-university-system/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;How do you measure the success of a business? You might look at financial measures such as profits, dividends or share price, industry dominance such as market share, or how well it achieves its mission. A law firm could measure success in client wins, a sports team in championships.  What do all of those measures [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/08/state-financial-inputs-arent-the-measure-of-a-university-system/"&gt;State financial inputs aren&amp;#8217;t the measure of a university system&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 20:17:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Testimony on Property Tax Reform</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/state-and-local-government/testimony-on-property-tax-reform/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On August 20, Show-Me Institute Director of Municipal Policy David Stokes submits testimony to the Missouri House of Representatives Special [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/state-and-local-government/testimony-on-property-tax-reform/"&gt;Testimony on Property Tax Reform&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 20:35:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] The Cost of Transit in California</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/the-cost-of-transit-in-california/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=the-cost-of-transit-in-california</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This study analyzes the financial performance of 85 California transit operators for fiscal year 2023, revealing a significant gap between revenue and expenses that necessitates over $10 billion in annual taxpayer subsidies. The report identifies long-term cost escalation, driven by what economist William Baumol termed “Cost Disease,” as a core issue. It concludes that without...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/the-cost-of-transit-in-california/"&gt;The Cost of Transit in California&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 21:02:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Cook County homeowners paid $2 billion extra in property taxes because of appeal process</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/cook-county-homeowners-paid-2-billion-extra-in-property-taxes-because-of-appeal-process/</link><description>When a Cook County business successfully appeals their property taxes, the county just shifts that burden to homeowners. This meant an extra $2 billion in residential property taxes instead of a lower property tax levy.</description><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 21:10:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] The Economic Wisdom of Alexander Hamilton</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/the-economic-wisdom-of-alexander-hamilton/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In Federalist Paper 11, Alexander Hamilton argued that one of the benefits of the proposed Constitution was the strengthening of the economy and ensuring the nation’s economic independence.[1] Hamilton closed by calling for the states to come together “in a strict and indissoluble union,” and creating a “great American system” of economy.[2] As a leading Federalist, Hamilton not only helped with the ratification of the Constitution, but he was selected by President George Washington to serve as the first Secretary of the Treasury. Hamilton is credited for being the “father of American capitalism” and he was the architect of President Washington’s economic policies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/the-economic-wisdom-of-alexander-hamilton/"&gt;The Economic Wisdom of Alexander Hamilton&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Nampans Are Speaking. Will the Mayor and City Council Listen?</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/nampans-are-speaking-will-the-mayor-and-city-council-listen/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/nampans-are-speaking-will-the-mayor-and-city-council-listen/" rel="nofollow" title="Nampans Are Speaking. Will the Mayor and City Council Listen?"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/Article-Headers-2025-08-15T172539.543.png" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Since our last article, criticism of the proposed transfer of the Ford Idaho Center (FIC) to the College of Western Idaho (CWI) has escalated monumentally. Nampans are speaking out to express their disapproval — and they are not being quiet about it.&amp;#160; At the August 11, 2025, “listening” town hall, the Mayor and members of [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2025 01:00:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Listen: Skyrocketing Energy Costs on Inside Maine</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/listen-skyrocketing-energy-costs-on-inside-maine/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Policy analyst, Harris Van Pate, joined Inside Maine on WGAN to discuss new data from the U.S. Energy Information Administration showing steep electricity price increases in Maine, price increases which far outpace the rest of the country. Van Pate diagnoses the problem, explains what is driving costs in Maine, and outlines a better path forward. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/listen-skyrocketing-energy-costs-on-inside-maine/"&gt;Listen: Skyrocketing Energy Costs on Inside Maine&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2025 20:38:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] WHITE PAPER: Financing Hoosier Healthcare</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/08/white-paper-financing-hoosier-healthcare/</link><description>The foundation&amp;#8217;s white papers are intended to make scholarly research on Indiana issues more widely available to policy analysts and researchers. White Papers represent research in progress and are published to invite comment and discussion as preparation for their submission to academic journals and other professional publications. by Maryann O. Keating, Ph.D. Shuffling through&amp;#160; health&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/08/white-paper-financing-hoosier-healthcare/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2025 12:10:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Ohio’s energy policy outshines Michigan’s</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/ohios-energy-policy-outshines-michigans</link><description>Buckeye State makes power production easier and more transparent</description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Back to school in Chicago: fewer than 1-in-3 students read at grade level</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/back-to-school-in-chicago-fewer-than-1-in-3-students-read-at-grade-level/</link><description>Students returned to their Chicago public schools on Aug. 18. The most recent test data available for Chicago students shows there’s a lot of room for improvement in the new school year.</description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 10:00:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] Albuquerque Mayoral candidate information: surveys and conversations</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/albuquerque-mayoral-candidate-information-surveys-and-conversations/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;There are seven candidates on the ballot this fall for mayor of Albuquerque. The Rio Grande Foundation invited all of them to complete candidate surveys and come on our podcast, Tipping Point New Mexico. The election is Tuesday, November 4 (with a runoff likely to follow). In alphabetical order by last name here are the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/albuquerque-mayoral-candidate-information-surveys-and-conversations/"&gt;Albuquerque Mayoral candidate information: surveys and conversations&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 15:16:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] “It cost what?”  —KC Streetcar Announces Opening of New Extension</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/budget-and-spending/it-cost-what-kc-streetcar-announces-opening-of-new-extension/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A friend called me the other night. Fox4KC had just aired a story about the opening date of the latest [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/budget-and-spending/it-cost-what-kc-streetcar-announces-opening-of-new-extension/"&gt;“It cost what?”  —KC Streetcar Announces Opening of New Extension&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 16:07:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Catherine Reheis-Boyd – Ensuring Fuel is Plentiful and Affordable in California</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/catherine-reheis-boyd-ensuring-fuel-is-plentiful-and-affordable-in-california/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This week, we start a series of podcasts featuring conversations on some of the hottest issues being debated at the State Capitol in the final weeks of the 2025 legislative session. We&amp;#8217;re pleased to be joined by Western States Petroleum Association president and CEO Catherine Reheis-Boyd, one of the most important legislative advocates in Sacramento. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/catherine-reheis-boyd-ensuring-fuel-is-plentiful-and-affordable-in-california/"&gt;Catherine Reheis-Boyd &amp;#8211; Ensuring Fuel is Plentiful and Affordable in California&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 16:28:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] The Trump Administration Is Reviving Its Worst Drug Pricing Policies</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/the-trump-administration-is-reviving-its-worst-drug-pricing-policies/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been a big year for revivals. There’s a new Jurassic Park movie, a reunion tour featuring 1990s rock band Oasis, and a Harry Potter television series in the works. President Trump is also looking to revive some of the policies he tried to enact during his first term. He recently issued an executive order [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/the-trump-administration-is-reviving-its-worst-drug-pricing-policies/"&gt;The Trump Administration Is Reviving Its Worst Drug Pricing Policies&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 16:50:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Shenna Bellows’ Response to DOJ Misses the Mark on Election Law</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/shenna-bellows-response-to-doj-misses-the-mark-on-election-law/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier this month, U.S. Department of Justice officials requested an electronic copy of Maine’s statewide voter registration list under the National Voter Registration Act (NVRA). In her official reply, Secretary of State Shenna Bellows rejected the request, citing state law and concerns about personal information. Unfortunately, her memo misstates constitutional authority, misapplies case law, misinterprets [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/shenna-bellows-response-to-doj-misses-the-mark-on-election-law/"&gt;Shenna Bellows’ Response to DOJ Misses the Mark on Election Law&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 16:52:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Analysis finds that Minnesotans will see an average tax cut of $3,500 per filer from OBBB</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/analysis-finds-that-minnesotans-will-see-an-average-tax-cut-of-3500-per-filer-from-obbb/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Much of the discussion around the “One Big Beautiful Bill” (OBBB) has centered around&amp;#160;its reforms to Medicaid eligibility&amp;#160;but, of course, the bill contained much else — it was “Big,” after all. Indeed, the OBBB makes the most significant legislative changes to federal tax policy since the&amp;#160;Tax Cuts and Jobs Act (TCJA)&amp;#160;which was passed back in...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/analysis-finds-that-minnesotans-will-see-an-average-tax-cut-of-3500-per-filer-from-obbb/"&gt;Analysis finds that Minnesotans will see an average tax cut of $3,500 per filer from OBBB&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 17:18:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] School Choice is Coming to Mississippi!</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/school-choice-is-coming-to-mississippi/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;What would it take for Mississippi to embrace School Choice?&amp;#160;How can we join our neighboring states in empowering families to control their child's share of the education budget? For School Choice to happen, we would need to see several steps.&amp;#160; &amp;#160;&amp;#160;Number one, we would need a committed Governor, ready to invest his political capital in [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/school-choice-is-coming-to-mississippi/" rel="nofollow"&gt;School Choice is Coming to Mississippi!&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 17:23:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Rifreedom] Center Cosigns Letter Supporting Seafreeze Petition to Suspend VINEYARD WIND Construction</title><link>https://rifreedom.org/2025/08/center-cosigns-letter-supporting-seafreeze-petition-to-suspend-vineyard-wind-construction/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Today, CEO for the Rhode Island Center for Freedom &amp;#038; Prosperity, Mike Stenhouse, co-signed a letter, along with national energy expert, G. Allen Brooks, requesting Doug Brugum, Secretary of the US Department Of the Interior (DOI), and other federal officials to accept the formal petition previously filed Seafreeze Inc (and others) that calls upon the government to immediately suspend "further construction and energy generation activity" of the near-completed Vineyard Wind off-shore wind project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org/2025/08/center-cosigns-letter-supporting-seafreeze-petition-to-suspend-vineyard-wind-construction/"&gt;Center Cosigns Letter Supporting Seafreeze Petition to Suspend VINEYARD WIND Construction&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org"&gt;RI Center for Freedom and Prosperity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 17:38:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] The Taxman Cometh: City of Plano</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/the-taxman-cometh-city-of-plano/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Most cities, counties, and school districts are right now in the process of adopting budgets and determining tax rates for the next fiscal year. In some cases, these local decisions will increase the cost of government and put upward pressure on property tax bills. In a few cases, local government action will cause tax bills...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/the-taxman-cometh-city-of-plano/"&gt;The Taxman Cometh: City of Plano&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 18:36:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] The Taxman Cometh: City of Robinson</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/the-taxman-cometh-city-of-robinson/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Most cities, counties, and school districts are right now in the process of adopting budgets and determining tax rates for the next fiscal year. In some cases, these local decisions will increase the cost of government and put upward pressure on property tax bills. In a few cases, local government action will cause tax bills...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/the-taxman-cometh-city-of-robinson/"&gt;The Taxman Cometh: City of Robinson&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 18:38:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] The Taxman Cometh: City of Burleson</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/the-taxman-cometh-city-of-burleson/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Most cities, counties, and school districts are right now in the process of adopting budgets and determining tax rates for the next fiscal year. In some cases, these local decisions will increase the cost of government and put upward pressure on property tax bills. In a few cases, local government action will cause tax bills...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/the-taxman-cometh-city-of-burleson/"&gt;The Taxman Cometh: City of Burleson&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 18:40:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Faith-Based Charter Schools and the Future of School Choice with Andy Smarick</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/education/faith-based-charter-schools-and-the-future-of-school-choice-with-andy-smarick/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Susan Pendergrass speaks with Andy Smarick, senior fellow at the Manhattan Institute, about a recent U.S. Supreme Court case that [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/education/faith-based-charter-schools-and-the-future-of-school-choice-with-andy-smarick/"&gt;Faith-Based Charter Schools and the Future of School Choice with Andy Smarick&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 18:47:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Idaho’s DOGE wants efficiency? This proposal checks all the boxes</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/idahos-doge-wants-efficiency-this-proposal-checks-all-the-boxes/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/idahos-doge-wants-efficiency-this-proposal-checks-all-the-boxes/" rel="nofollow" title="Idaho’s DOGE wants efficiency? This proposal checks all the boxes"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/Cream-Neutral-Minimalist-New-Business-Pitch-Deck-Presentation-5.jpg" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I have, so far, sent one and only one recommendation to the Idaho Legislature’s new DOGE task force that is supposed to be on the hunt for efficiencies in government. I could send more, but I wanted to offer something that checks all the boxes for legislators who want to: Make government more efficient. Save [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 19:16:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/08/the-outstater-283/</link><description>Cracking Down on Crime “Your race card has been denied, do you have another form of argument?” — anonymous. WE CAN HOPE that our city is learning something from the crime crackdown in Washington, D.C. It turns out that if you arrest people for breaking the law, other people, regardless of their background or upbringing, decide&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/08/the-outstater-283/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 19:40:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Judge rules “omnibus bill” rammed through in 2024 unconstitutional</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/judge-rules-omnibus-bill-rammed-through-in-2024-unconstitutional/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In May last year, I wrote about how: &amp;#8230;the DFL, in scenes that would embarrass a banana republic, [rammed] through&amp;#160;a 1,400 page Omnibus Bill that nobody had read and was blocking any debate on the bill whatsoever. The bill included everything from increased penalties for straw gun purchases to a&amp;#160;hike in the payroll tax&amp;#160;required to...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/judge-rules-omnibus-bill-rammed-through-in-2024-unconstitutional/"&gt;Judge rules &amp;#8220;omnibus bill&amp;#8221; rammed through in 2024 unconstitutional&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 20:58:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] KING NEWSOM DRAWS HIS DISTRICTS</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/king-newsom/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=king-newsom</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Newsom’s gerrymandering scheme not only disenfranchises independent and conservative voters in California, but all citizens of this State. The California Constitution guarantees citizens the right to meaningfully participate in the democratic process and be informed regarding legislation. In order to effectuate this guarantee, the people of California insisted on a minimum 30-day waiting period between...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/king-newsom/"&gt;KING NEWSOM DRAWS HIS DISTRICTS&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 21:55:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Florida’s Election Reform Sets the Standard Nationwide</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/floridas-election-reform-sets-the-standard-nationwide/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE August 19, 2025 CONTACT Logan Elizabeth Padgett 850-386-3131 Florida’s Election Reform Sets the Standard Nationwide...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/floridas-election-reform-sets-the-standard-nationwide/"&gt;Florida’s Election Reform Sets the Standard Nationwide &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 04:01:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Florida: The Gold Standard in Elections Administration From Bush v. Gore to Present 2000-2025</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/florida-the-gold-standard-in-elections-administration-from-bush-v-gore-to-present-2000-2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Ben Gibson — Senior Fellow, The James Madison Institute Doug Wheeler — Director, George Gibbs Center for Economic...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/florida-the-gold-standard-in-elections-administration-from-bush-v-gore-to-present-2000-2025/"&gt;Florida: The Gold Standard in Elections Administration From Bush v. Gore to Present 2000-2025&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 04:01:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Taxpayers on the hook for 12 million “Phantom” Obamacare plans that no one will ever use</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/taxpayers-on-the-hook-for-12-million-phantom-obamacare-plans-that-no-one-will-ever-use/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Recent data from the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services (CMS) shows that 12 million Obamacare enrollees in the individual market never went to the doctor, took a pill or used their policy. This number tripled during the Biden presidency. The Paragon institute released a report  showing an astonishing increase of nearly 80%  in the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/taxpayers-on-the-hook-for-12-million-phantom-obamacare-plans-that-no-one-will-ever-use/"&gt;Taxpayers on the hook for 12 million “Phantom&amp;#8221; Obamacare plans that no one will ever use&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 04:29:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] California’s Counterproductive Approach to Reducing GHG Emissions</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/californias-counterproductive-approach-to-reducing-ghg-emissions/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;California’s Counterproductive Approach to Reducing GHG Emissions by Wayne Winegarden &amp;#124; August 19, 2025 The state of California, along with a host of other cities and municipalities, is suing American energy companies. The lawsuit alleges that these private U.S. companies misled the public about greenhouse gases’ impact on the climate and consequently are responsible for [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/californias-counterproductive-approach-to-reducing-ghg-emissions/"&gt;California’s Counterproductive Approach to Reducing GHG Emissions&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 09:00:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] UN peacekeepers spent US dollars on gender diversity, yoga</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/un-peacekeepers-spent-us-dollars-on-gender-diversity-yoga/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Adam Kredo writes for the Washington Free Beacon about a dubious United Nations priority. The U.N. peacekeeping force in Lebanon is largely funded with U.S. taxpayer dollars, money it has used to pursue left-wing programs like &amp;#8220;gender diversity&amp;#8221; training and lessons on &amp;#8220;gender mainstreaming in military operations,&amp;#8221; as well as therapeutic yoga instruction. Those expenditures...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/un-peacekeepers-spent-us-dollars-on-gender-diversity-yoga/"&gt;UN peacekeepers spent US dollars on gender diversity, yoga&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 09:36:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Left-wing bureaucrats ‘subvert’ governments in red states</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/left-wing-bureaucrats-subvert-governments-in-red-states/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Shawn Fleetwood writes for the Federalist about a problem plaguing red-state governments. Left-wing bureaucracies are quietly undercutting the will of Republican voters in so-called “red states” across the country, according to a new report. Published this week by the State Leadership Initiative (SLI), the group’s “Shadow Government” analysis reveals how “Republican voters elect Republican governors...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/left-wing-bureaucrats-subvert-governments-in-red-states/"&gt;Left-wing bureaucrats ‘subvert’ governments in red states&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 09:39:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Western media echo Soviet-era Pravda</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/western-media-echo-soviet-era-pravda/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Andrea Widburg writes for the American Thinker about the regrettable decline of legacy media outlets. “In the Soviet Union, there is no truth in Pravda and no news in Izvestia.” Readers of a certain age recognize that old joke, which played on the fact that the names of those two Soviet newspapers, when translated into...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/western-media-echo-soviet-era-pravda/"&gt;Western media echo Soviet-era Pravda&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 09:42:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Trump artificial intelligence plan a good start</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/trump-artificial-intelligence-plan-a-good-start</link><description>Order includes more than 90 policy changes</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] It’s been 1,805 days since Chicago Teachers Union’s last “annual audit”</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/its-been-1805-days-since-chicago-teachers-unions-last-annual-audit/</link><description>The Chicago Teachers Union has shirked its own rules for years, causing members to sue the union to release a required annual audit. Members concerned about the union’s finances can opt out in August.</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 10:00:27 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>