<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>State-Policy Think-Tank Digest</title><link>https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml</link><description>Latest posts from free-market policy institutes across the U.S.</description><atom:link href="https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 05:03:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>[Mspolicy] WTOK looks at what School Choice might mean for Mississippi</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/wtok-looks-at-what-school-choice-might-mean-for-mississippi/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I’m thrilled to share that momentum for School Choice in Mississippi is growing!&amp;#160;Governor Tate Reeves, Speaker Jason White, and even the White House are championing this transformative opportunity to empower parents and enhance education for our children. This week, WTOK TV aired an in-depth segment exploring how School Choice could benefit families across our state.&amp;#160;I [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/wtok-looks-at-what-school-choice-might-mean-for-mississippi/" rel="nofollow"&gt;WTOK looks at what School Choice might mean for Mississippi&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 16:08:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] What to know about education in Georgia as students go back to school</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/what-to-know-about-education-in-georgia/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As August ushers in a new school year in Georgia, nearly two million students are headed back to our states 2,300 public schools. How are Georgia schools doing when it comes to preparing kids for work and life? Here's a look at some key measures. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/what-to-know-about-education-in-georgia/"&gt;What to know about education in Georgia as students go back to school&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 22:26:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Get to Know Kathryn Beale, Beacon’s New Director of Development</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/get-to-know-kat-beale-beacons-new-director-of-development/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=get-to-know-kat-beale-beacons-new-director-of-development</link><description>Tell us about you—where you’re from, any fun facts about yourself, and where you spent your career prior to Beacon. I’m originally from Benton, Kentucky, a small town in the very western corner of the Bluegrass State. But, important to my upbringing, I am not a Wildcat! I spent four years in Nashville at Lipscomb...</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 15:13:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] New York’s Hospital Quality Remains Among the Worst in the U.S.</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/new-yorks-hospital-quality-remains-among-the-worst-in-the-u-s/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The federal government recently updated its hospital quality ratings, and New York once again fell near the bottom. Among 132....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/new-yorks-hospital-quality-remains-among-the-worst-in-the-u-s/"&gt;New York&amp;#8217;s Hospital Quality Remains Among the Worst in the U.S.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 18:44:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] NJ ED REPORT: Amplifying Student Voices: Advocating for Younger and More Inclusive Representation in IEP Meetings</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/08/nj-ed-report-amplifying-student-voices-advocating-for-younger-and-more-inclusive-representation-in-iep-meetings/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;NJPI policy research intern David Fishkin, a Political Science student at Rutgers University – New Brunswick, has published an op-ed [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/08/nj-ed-report-amplifying-student-voices-advocating-for-younger-and-more-inclusive-representation-in-iep-meetings/"&gt;NJ ED REPORT: Amplifying Student Voices: Advocating for Younger and More Inclusive Representation in IEP Meetings&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 18:52:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] New, Flawed Rating Changes Cover Up for Underperforming Schools, Again</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/new-flawed-rating-changes-cover-up-for-underperforming-schools-again/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New, Flawed Rating Changes Cover Up for Underperforming Schools, Again IRG uncovers changes that hide low-performing districts from parents Delafield, Wis. — The Institute for Reforming Government (IRG) issued a statement after the Wisconsin DPI again changed its 1–5 star school ratings at an August 12–14 Madison meeting, leaving parents unclear on local school performance. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/new-flawed-rating-changes-cover-up-for-underperforming-schools-again/"&gt;New, Flawed Rating Changes Cover Up for Underperforming Schools, Again&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 16:17:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] State Board of Ed votes to reduce proficiency standards; legislators should implement a different state assessment</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/state-board-of-ed-reduces-proficiency-standards/</link><description>The Kansas State Board of Education voted 7-3 this week to accept new cut scores for determining proficiency levels on the state assessment test, setting the stage for the Kansas Legislature to hopefully halt the imposition of less rigorous performance standards. More on that shortly after a brief recap of the fraud being perpetrated on [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 18:03:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] State financial inputs aren’t the measure of a university system</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/08/state-financial-inputs-arent-the-measure-of-a-university-system/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;How do you measure the success of a business? You might look at financial measures such as profits, dividends or share price, industry dominance such as market share, or how well it achieves its mission. A law firm could measure success in client wins, a sports team in championships.  What do all of those measures [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/08/state-financial-inputs-arent-the-measure-of-a-university-system/"&gt;State financial inputs aren&amp;#8217;t the measure of a university system&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 20:17:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] School Choice is Coming to Mississippi!</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/school-choice-is-coming-to-mississippi/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;What would it take for Mississippi to embrace School Choice?&amp;#160;How can we join our neighboring states in empowering families to control their child's share of the education budget? For School Choice to happen, we would need to see several steps.&amp;#160; &amp;#160;&amp;#160;Number one, we would need a committed Governor, ready to invest his political capital in [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/school-choice-is-coming-to-mississippi/" rel="nofollow"&gt;School Choice is Coming to Mississippi!&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 17:23:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Rifreedom] Center Cosigns Letter Supporting Seafreeze Petition to Suspend VINEYARD WIND Construction</title><link>https://rifreedom.org/2025/08/center-cosigns-letter-supporting-seafreeze-petition-to-suspend-vineyard-wind-construction/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Today, CEO for the Rhode Island Center for Freedom &amp;#038; Prosperity, Mike Stenhouse, co-signed a letter, along with national energy expert, G. Allen Brooks, requesting Doug Brugum, Secretary of the US Department Of the Interior (DOI), and other federal officials to accept the formal petition previously filed Seafreeze Inc (and others) that calls upon the government to immediately suspend "further construction and energy generation activity" of the near-completed Vineyard Wind off-shore wind project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org/2025/08/center-cosigns-letter-supporting-seafreeze-petition-to-suspend-vineyard-wind-construction/"&gt;Center Cosigns Letter Supporting Seafreeze Petition to Suspend VINEYARD WIND Construction&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org"&gt;RI Center for Freedom and Prosperity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 17:38:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Florida’s Election Reform Sets the Standard Nationwide</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/floridas-election-reform-sets-the-standard-nationwide/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE August 19, 2025 CONTACT Logan Elizabeth Padgett 850-386-3131 Florida’s Election Reform Sets the Standard Nationwide...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/floridas-election-reform-sets-the-standard-nationwide/"&gt;Florida’s Election Reform Sets the Standard Nationwide &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 04:01:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Florida: The Gold Standard in Elections Administration From Bush v. Gore to Present 2000-2025</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/florida-the-gold-standard-in-elections-administration-from-bush-v-gore-to-present-2000-2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Ben Gibson — Senior Fellow, The James Madison Institute Doug Wheeler — Director, George Gibbs Center for Economic...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/florida-the-gold-standard-in-elections-administration-from-bush-v-gore-to-present-2000-2025/"&gt;Florida: The Gold Standard in Elections Administration From Bush v. Gore to Present 2000-2025&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 04:01:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] What’s at stake in Albuquerque’s City Elections?</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/whats-at-stake-in-albuquerques-city-elections/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Paul recently sat down with Diane Kinderwater for an episode of &amp;#8220;Issues and Answers&amp;#8221; on KCHF TV. The show airs statewide and can be streamed live right here. In a recent conversation Paul had a chance to discuss what&amp;#8217;s at stake in the City of Albuquerque elections this fall. We discuss crime, homelessness, the economy, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/whats-at-stake-in-albuquerques-city-elections/"&gt;What&amp;#8217;s at stake in Albuquerque&amp;#8217;s City Elections?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 19:34:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Deficits on the horizon as state spending explodes</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/state-spending-explodes-deficits/</link><description>How do you go from having a $3 billion budget surplus and stable tax revenue to broke in just a few years? By repeatedly spending more than you take in. General Fund spending has pretty much been out of control since 2018, the year after the Legislature passed the largest tax increase in state history. [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 20:51:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cardinalinstitute] West Virginia’s Certificate of Need Laws Are Failing You</title><link>https://cardinalinstitute.com/west-virginias-certificate-of-need-laws-are-failing-you/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;West Virginia’s Certificate of Need Laws Are Failing You The West Virginia Hospital Association’s recent op-ed defending West Virginia’s Certificate of Need (CON) laws is a masterclass in elite protectionism, dressed in concern, framed as a noble stand for community health. Make no mistake—the heart of the piece is about hospital bottom lines rather than how [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com/west-virginias-certificate-of-need-laws-are-failing-you/"&gt;West Virginia’s Certificate of Need Laws Are Failing You&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com"&gt;Cardinal Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 16:22:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Corrected: As Math and Reading Proficiency Went Up, ‘Cut Scores’ Went Down</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/as-math-and-reading-proficiency-went-up-cut-scores-went-down/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;(Corrected on Aug. 27: The original version of this post inappropriately combined &amp;#8220;scale scores&amp;#8221; calculated by the Albany Times Union....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/as-math-and-reading-proficiency-went-up-cut-scores-went-down/"&gt;Corrected: As Math and Reading Proficiency Went Up, &amp;#8216;Cut Scores&amp;#8217; Went Down&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 13:46:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Colorado’s AI Catastrophe: A Cautionary Tale</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/colorados-ai-catastrophe-a-cautionary-tale/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On May 27, 2024, Colorado became the unfortunate pioneer in a troubling new frontier of government overreach. The...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/colorados-ai-catastrophe-a-cautionary-tale/"&gt;Colorado&amp;#8217;s AI Catastrophe: A Cautionary Tale&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 15:20:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] In child care, as in housing, maybe the government’s doing a bit too much?</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/08/in-child-care-as-in-housing-maybe-the-governments-doing-a-bit-too-much/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Surging child care prices have grabbed the media’s attention here in New Hampshire, and rightly so. The price of full-time care in a licensed center “jumped 48 percent between 2013 and 2023,” landing at nearly $32,000 a year, according to an analysis last year by the Carsey School of Public Policy at UNH.   Child [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/08/in-child-care-as-in-housing-maybe-the-governments-doing-a-bit-too-much/"&gt;In child care, as in housing, maybe the government’s doing a bit too much?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 17:00:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF in National Review: The Return of Car Choice, Hopefully</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-in-national-review-the-return-of-car-choice-hopefully/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following appeared in National Review&amp;#8217;s Capital Matters on August 20, 2025. Whatever happens to the future of EVs, they should compete on an even playing field with other vehicles. While the courts have yet to have their say, one of the Trump administration’s most important accomplishments, perhaps second only to his successful crackdown on illegal [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-in-national-review-the-return-of-car-choice-hopefully/"&gt;RGF in National Review: The Return of Car Choice, Hopefully&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 17:56:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Poor Solar Energy Performance is More Evidence the VCEA is Failing</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/poor-solar-energy-performance-is-more-evidence-the-vcea-is-failing/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="630" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/IMG_3224.png" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every solar facility in Dominion Energy Virginia’s expanding fleet of silicone panels is failing to perform up to its initial energy promises, according to a State Corporation Commission staff analysis.&amp;#160;In many cases the shortfalls are dramatic. A high confidence in the ability of solar power to replace Virginia’s dominant natural gas and coal electricity generators [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/poor-solar-energy-performance-is-more-evidence-the-vcea-is-failing/"&gt;Poor Solar Energy Performance is More Evidence the VCEA is Failing&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] SEPTA’s Manufactured Crisis Has Delayed State Budget Long Enough</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/08/22/septas-manufactured-crisis-has-delayed-state-budget-long-enough/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Harrisburg, Pa., August 22, 2025 — This Sunday, after eight consecutive weeks of public fearmongering, the Southeastern Pennsylvania Transportation Authority (SEPTA) will enact self-imposed service cuts. Though completely avoidable, these cuts aim to extract yet another taxpayer-funded bailout. This is not a true emergency; it is a manufactured crisis, fueled and exploited by Gov. Josh [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/08/22/septas-manufactured-crisis-has-delayed-state-budget-long-enough/"&gt;SEPTA’s Manufactured Crisis Has Delayed State Budget Long Enough&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 16:12:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Listen: The Folly of Portland’s Social Housing Task Force</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/listen-the-folly-of-portlands-social-housing-task-force/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Policy analyst, Harris Van Pate, joined the WGAN Morning News to discuss the pitfalls of Portland&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8220;Social Housing Task Force&amp;#8221; and how the city&amp;#8217;s existing policies – like rent control and inclusionary zoning – are distorting the greater region&amp;#8217;s housing market to the detriment of renters and those looking to buy a home. Listen to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/listen-the-folly-of-portlands-social-housing-task-force/"&gt;Listen: The Folly of Portland&amp;#8217;s Social Housing Task Force&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 21:15:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] John Charles’ Testimony Re: ’25 Special Session Transportation Funding</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/testimony/john-charles-testimony-re-25-special-session-transportation-funding/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Testimony of John A. Charles, Jr.Regarding LC 2Before the Joint Interim Committee on...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/testimony/john-charles-testimony-re-25-special-session-transportation-funding/"&gt;John Charles’ Testimony Re: &amp;#8217;25 Special Session Transportation Funding &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 22:22:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Rifreedom] After Federal Action, Rhode Island Desperately Needs a Realistic Energy Strategy</title><link>https://rifreedom.org/2025/08/after-federal-action-rhode-island-desperately-needs-a-realistic-energy-strategy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Cranston, RI – The Rhode Island Center for Freedom &amp;#38; Prosperity advises state policymakers to immediately begin work to construct a new and realistic energy strategy that will put the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org/2025/08/after-federal-action-rhode-island-desperately-needs-a-realistic-energy-strategy/"&gt;After Federal Action, Rhode Island Desperately Needs a Realistic Energy Strategy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org"&gt;RI Center for Freedom and Prosperity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 15:41:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Hochul’s $17B Medicaid Surge Leaves Little to Brag About</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/hochuls-17b-medicaid-surge/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Governor Hochul has made Medicaid her dominant budget priority over the past four years, increasing the state&amp;#8217;s annual share of....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/hochuls-17b-medicaid-surge/"&gt;Hochul&amp;#8217;s $17B Medicaid Surge Leaves Little to Brag About&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 13:27:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Spending Solutions for ODOT’s Spending Problems</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/tax-and-budget/spending-solutions-for-odots-spending-problems/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Naomi Inman The Oregon Legislature’s Joint Committee on Transportation Funding will consider...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/tax-and-budget/spending-solutions-for-odots-spending-problems/"&gt;Spending Solutions for ODOT’s Spending Problems&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 14:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] NYT Bestseller Jane Leavy on Reforming Major League Baseball</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/nyt-bestseller-jane-leavy-on-reforming-major-league-baseball/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In this week’s episode of The Learning Curve, co-hosts U-Arkansas Prof. Albert Cheng and Pioneer Senior Fellow Charlie Chieppo interview award-winning journalist and New York Times bestselling author Jane Leavy. Ms. Leavy discusses her lifelong love of baseball, and her forthcoming book, Make Me Commissioner: I Know What’s Wrong with Baseball and How to Fix It, which comes out in September.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/nyt-bestseller-jane-leavy-on-reforming-major-league-baseball/"&gt;NYT Bestseller Jane Leavy on Reforming Major League Baseball&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 15:20:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Trump Administration Agrees with WILL Lawsuit: Federal Programs Illegally Discriminate Against Farmers</title><link>https://will-law.org/trump-administration-agrees-with-will-lawsuit-federal-programs-illegally-discriminate-against-farmers/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Trump Administration has filed a motion declining to defend multiple Biden-era aid programs within the Department of Agriculture (USDA), each of which currently discriminate against white male farmers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/trump-administration-agrees-with-will-lawsuit-federal-programs-illegally-discriminate-against-farmers/"&gt;Trump Administration Agrees with WILL Lawsuit: Federal Programs Illegally Discriminate Against Farmers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 15:00:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Building costs heading upward in first impact of bureaucrats being unleashed</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/building-costs-heading-upward-in-first-impact-of-bureaucrats-being-unleashed/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A new requirement to hire a “special inspector” to be on hand during construction will add an estimated $20,000 to any store, school, office, factory or apartment building in the Wisconsin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/building-costs-heading-upward-in-first-impact-of-bureaucrats-being-unleashed/"&gt;Building costs heading upward in first impact of bureaucrats being unleashed&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 20:40:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Connecticut’s Legislature is Busy. That Doesn’t Mean It’s Effective</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/08/29/connecticuts-legislature-is-busy-that-doesnt-mean-its-effective/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If lawmaking were graded on quantity not quality, Connecticut would be on the honor roll. In 2025 the General Assembly introduced 4,064 bills — eighth most in the nation for [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/08/29/connecticuts-legislature-is-busy-that-doesnt-mean-its-effective/"&gt;Connecticut’s Legislature is Busy. That Doesn’t Mean It’s Effective &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 16:49:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/08/the-outstater-286/</link><description>The Party that Doesn&amp;#8217;t Pray MARK AUG. 27, 2025, as the day the Democrat Party, or at least its prominent spokesmen, dismissed the prayers of children shot to death in their pews. That is the partisan interpretation. A more charitable one would be that Democrats believe that such an act, shooting children at prayer, deserves action (gun control)&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/08/the-outstater-286/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 16:53:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Humanity and Abortion</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/humanity-and-abortion/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/humanity-and-abortion/" rel="nofollow" title="Humanity and Abortion"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1350" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/Cream-Neutral-Minimalist-New-Business-Pitch-Deck-Presentation-6.jpg" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="2400" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Idaho has one of the most comprehensive abortion laws in the United States, effectively banning the procedure at all stages of pregnancy with narrow exceptions. The state's framework consists of multiple overlapping statutes, primarily enacted or triggered after the U.S. Supreme Court's 2022 decision in Dobbs v. Jackson Women's Health Organization, which overturned Roe v. [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2025 19:43:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Public Recommendations to Idaho's DOGE Task Force to Increase Government Efficiency</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/public-recommendations-to-idahos-doge-task-force-to-increase-government-efficiency/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/public-recommendations-to-idahos-doge-task-force-to-increase-government-efficiency/" rel="nofollow" title="Public Recommendations to Idaho&amp;#039;s DOGE Task Force to Increase Government Efficiency"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Article-Headers-2025-09-01T114655.975.png" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Dear Members of the Idaho DOGE Task Force,&amp;#160; At the request of members of this Task Force, we have attached our analysis and recommendations for the committee's consideration. Each proposed reduction, consolidation, or elimination falls within the committee's stated purpose and offers realistic options for waste reduction.&amp;#160; The Idaho DOGE Task Force is positioned to [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 18:06:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] Beyond the Beach: Honoring the Dignity of Work</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/09/01/labor-day-honoring-the-dignity-of-work/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A free and prosperous society is built on a foundation of responsible, creative, and purposeful work. When government is limited and economic freedom is upheld, individuals are empowered to pursue their callings, provide for their families, and contribute to the common good. Labor Day, therefore, becomes a day to honor not just the physical act of labor, but the sacred dignity of work—the opportunity we have to use our gifts to create, serve, and build, all while reflecting the image of our Creator. It is a day to be grateful for the freedom to work and to be a part of a society where that freedom is protected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/09/01/labor-day-honoring-the-dignity-of-work/"&gt;Beyond the Beach: Honoring the Dignity of Work&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 19:46:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] The First Amendment, Flag Burning and the Limits of Executive Power</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/the-first-amendment-flag-burning-and-the-limits-of-executive-power/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On August 25, 2025, President Donald Trump issued an executive order directing federal agencies to prosecute acts of flag desecration where they allegedly coincide with criminal behavior. Additionally, the order claims to target only instances that incite violence or violate “content-neutral” laws on flag burning. But even a cursory reading of the First Amendment, and [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/the-first-amendment-flag-burning-and-the-limits-of-executive-power/"&gt;The First Amendment, Flag Burning and the Limits of Executive Power&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 01:26:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Revenue-neutral law is helping; additional property tax reform is needed</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/revenue-neutral-helps-more-tax-reform-needed/</link><description>The Revenue-Neutral law that went into effect in 2021 is helping many Kansans, with nearly two-thirds of taxing entities deciding NOT to raise property taxes this year. It requires cities, counties, school districts, and other local taxing authorities to notify taxpayers if they want to collect more property tax revenue the following year, hold a [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 12:49:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Kim Reynolds is America’s ‘Iron Lady’ reflecting Margaret Thatcher’s spirit</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/https-www-desmoinesregister-com-story-opinion-columnists-iowa-view-2025-08-31-kim-reynolds-reflects-iron-lady-margaret-thatcher-spirit-85853542007-gnt-cfr1gca-catpgca-uirtruegca-eptiz116054p000250c000/</link><description>&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="80" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Des-Moines-Register.jpg" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;" width="300" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Kim Reynolds is America&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8216;Iron Lady&amp;#8217; reflecting Margaret Thatcher&amp;#8217;s spirit" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Des-Moines-Register.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gov. Kim Reynolds is a conservative leader who knows what she believes and has the courage to defend her values and convictions. “One of the great debates of our time is about how much of your money should be spent by the State and how much you should keep to spend on your family. Let us never forget this fundamental truth: the State has no source of money other than money which people earn themselves. If the State wishes to spend more it can do so only by borrowing your savings or by taxing you more. It is no good thinking that someone else will pay — that “someone else” is you. There is no such thing as public money; there is only taxpayers' money,” stated British Prime Minister Margaret Thatcher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/https-www-desmoinesregister-com-story-opinion-columnists-iowa-view-2025-08-31-kim-reynolds-reflects-iron-lady-margaret-thatcher-spirit-85853542007-gnt-cfr1gca-catpgca-uirtruegca-eptiz116054p000250c000/"&gt;Kim Reynolds is America&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8216;Iron Lady&amp;#8217; reflecting Margaret Thatcher&amp;#8217;s spirit&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 13:33:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] New federal school choice law is a historic breakthrough for children</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/new-federal-school-choice-law-is-a-historic-breakthrough-for-children</link><description>Note: This is a joint op-ed with Peter Murphy ( Invest in Education Coalition ). The old saying that states are the “laboratories of...</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 14:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Mississippi's Progress and the Push for School Choice</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/mississippis-progress-and-the-push-for-school-choice/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This week, I’ll be traveling to Washington, D.C. talking about Mississippi’s remarkable progress, including our elimination of the income tax and how we might best advance school choice in our state. Mississippi is gaining national attention for our transformative public policies. Once seen as a perennial underdog, our state is now recognized as a leader in free-market [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/mississippis-progress-and-the-push-for-school-choice/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi&amp;#039;s Progress and the Push for School Choice&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 17:09:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Non-working adults concentrated in Georgia’s distressed communities</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/adults-not-working-in-georgia/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Many Georgia counties face high rates of non-working adults, fueling distress and limiting opportunities in struggling communities. See the percentages for your county. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/adults-not-working-in-georgia/"&gt;Non-working adults concentrated in Georgia’s distressed communities&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 18:51:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Attorney General Lynn Fitch: Breaking Barriers &amp; Defending Life</title><link>https://empowerms.org/attorney-general-lynn-fitch-breaking-barriers-defending-life/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Attorney General Lynn Fitch: Breaking Barriers &amp;#38; Defending Life  On this episode, host Grant Callen sits down with Mississippi’s 40th Attorney General Lynn Fitch. A Holly Springs native, General Fitch has 35 years in public and private legal service, made history as the state’s first female Attorney General, and earned national recognition for her leadership.&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/attorney-general-lynn-fitch-breaking-barriers-defending-life/"&gt;Attorney General Lynn Fitch: Breaking Barriers &amp; Defending Life &lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 20:00:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] It is Time to End Northern Virginia’s Outdated and Unnecessary Vehicle Emissions Program</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/it-is-time-to-end-northern-virginias-outdated-and-unnecessary-vehicle-emissions-program/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="630" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Clean-Emissions-Cars-Virginia.jpg" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 1982, residents of these Northern Virginia counties: Arlington, Fairfax, Loudoun, Prince William, Stafford and the cities of Alexandria, Fairfax, Falls Church, Manassas, and Manassas Park, have been subject to a mandatory&amp;#160;vehicle emissions testing program, a policy enacted in 1982 under the&amp;#160;1970 Clean Air Act&amp;#160;to combat significant regional air pollution. While Virginians outside of Northern [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/it-is-time-to-end-northern-virginias-outdated-and-unnecessary-vehicle-emissions-program/"&gt;It is Time to End Northern Virginia&amp;#8217;s Outdated and Unnecessary Vehicle Emissions Program&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Florida’s John Kirtley on School Choice</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/floridas-john-kirtley-on-school-choice/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In this week’s episode of The Learning Curve, co-hosts U-Arkansas Prof. Albert Cheng and American Federation for Children Senior Fellow Shaka Mitchell interview John Kirtley, Managing Partner and co-founder of Keswick Partners, and founder and Chairman of Step Up for Students, a nonprofit that manages Florida’s state-funded K-12 scholarship programs serving over half a million students. Kirtley shares his journey from the private sector into education reform in the late 1990s, and why business leaders must actively engage in shaping K-12 policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/floridas-john-kirtley-on-school-choice/"&gt;Florida&amp;#8217;s John Kirtley on School Choice&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 13:51:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Separate but Equitable at Portland Public Schools</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/education/separate-but-equitable-at-portland-public-schools/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By John A. Charles, Jr. In 1954 the U.S. Supreme Court ruled that...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/education/separate-but-equitable-at-portland-public-schools/"&gt;Separate but Equitable at Portland Public Schools&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 14:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] CALIFORNIA: New teachers relieved to hear the truth</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/california/california-new-teachers-relieved-to-hear-the-truth/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As I’ve done many times before, I explained that teachers have the right to opt out of the union and that thousands across the country have already done so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/california/california-new-teachers-relieved-to-hear-the-truth/" rel="nofollow"&gt;CALIFORNIA: New teachers relieved to hear the truth&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 14:39:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] New Poll: Inflation, Economy, Taxes, and Crime Top Voter Concerns, Pennsylvanians Hold Shapiro Responsible for Budget Impasse</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/09/03/new-poll-inflation-economy-taxes-and-crime-top-voter-concerns-pennsylvanians-hold-shapiro-responsible-for-budget-impasse/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Harrisburg, Pa., September 3, 2025 — Fewer than 4-in-10 Pennsylvania voters believe the state is on the right track, according to new polling released today by the Commonwealth Foundation. Inflation, the economy, taxes, and crime top their list of concerns facing the state, with nearly two-thirds of Pennsylvanians saying economic conditions are worsening for them [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/09/03/new-poll-inflation-economy-taxes-and-crime-top-voter-concerns-pennsylvanians-hold-shapiro-responsible-for-budget-impasse/"&gt;New Poll: Inflation, Economy, Taxes, and Crime Top Voter Concerns, Pennsylvanians Hold Shapiro Responsible for Budget Impasse &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 15:24:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] A conversation on New Mexico’s health care provider shortage w/ RGF’s Paul Gessing &amp; Think New Mexico’s Fred Nathan</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/a-conversation-on-new-mexicos-health-care-provider-shortage-w-rgfs-paul-gessing-think-new-mexicos-fred-nathan/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Most New Mexicans are abundantly aware of the dire medical provider shortage facing our state. The Rio Grande Foundation has been researching and discussing solutions to this problem for several years. The same is true for Think New Mexico which is led by Fred Nathan. While we don&amp;#8217;t always agree with the approach of Think [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/a-conversation-on-new-mexicos-health-care-provider-shortage-w-rgfs-paul-gessing-think-new-mexicos-fred-nathan/"&gt;A conversation on New Mexico&amp;#8217;s health care provider shortage w/ RGF&amp;#8217;s Paul Gessing &amp;#038; Think New Mexico&amp;#8217;s Fred Nathan&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 15:42:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] “Superhero” Special Education Teacher Challenges Madison’s Race-Laden Scoring System</title><link>https://will-law.org/superhero-special-education-teacher-challenges-madisons-race-laden-scoring-system/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL has filed a complaint with the U.S. Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (“EEOC”) on behalf of Kally Bishop, a highly skilled special education teacher at Thoreau Elementary, a part of the Madison Metropolitan School District.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/superhero-special-education-teacher-challenges-madisons-race-laden-scoring-system/"&gt;“Superhero” Special Education Teacher Challenges Madison’s Race-Laden Scoring System&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 17:21:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] WASHINGTON: WFSE a net loser despite recruiting drive</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/washington/washington-wfse-a-net-loser-despite-recruiting-drive/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Washington Federation of State Employees (WFSE) recently hit the streets to recruit new members, but the results aren’t exactly something to brag about.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/washington/washington-wfse-a-net-loser-despite-recruiting-drive/" rel="nofollow"&gt;WASHINGTON: WFSE a net loser despite recruiting drive &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 18:28:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] The Gold Standard</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/the-gold-standard/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A recent post on substack authored by Dr. Ed Timmons caught our eye. This particular post highlighted rankings of universal recognition laws for occupational licenses around the country, and Nebraska met the &amp;#8220;Gold Standard&amp;#8221; as can be seen from the image below. This image is just one of many to be found in the most...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/the-gold-standard/" rel="nofollow"&gt;The Gold Standard&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 18:44:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Fighting an Illegal Government Monopoly at the Arkansas Supreme Court</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/fighting-an-illegal-government-monopoly-at-the-arkansas-supreme-court/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When the local government banned Steven Hedrick from operating his small business in rural Arkansas, the Goldwater Institute took action,..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/fighting-an-illegal-government-monopoly-at-the-arkansas-supreme-court/"&gt;Fighting an Illegal Government Monopoly at the Arkansas Supreme Court&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 21:04:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] Distinctions Between Social Justice and Biblical Justice</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/09/04/distinctions-between-social-justice-and-biblical-justice/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The use of governmental imposition to force social justice on its people is a path that leads to more government, less freedom, and deeper division. The true path forward can be found in a return to the principles of biblical justice—impartiality, righteousness, and individual responsibility. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/09/04/distinctions-between-social-justice-and-biblical-justice/"&gt;Distinctions Between Social Justice and Biblical Justice&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 06:49:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Public lands need protection and future flexibility</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/public-lands-need-protection-and-future-flexibility</link><description>Protecting public lands has become the rallying call this year for groups and individuals across the political spectrum. In June, when...</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 11:19:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Fact Checking Claims on Enrollment Declines</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/fact-checking-claims-on-enrollment-declines/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=fact-checking-claims-on-enrollment-declines</link><description>Despite declining enrollment occurring all across the nation, recent news reports have claimed that the problem is specific to Tennessee because of the state's new Education Freedom Scholarships (EFS) program. Not only do these accusations wrongly place blame, many critics simply get the basics of the EFS program wrong. Let’s set the record straight.</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 16:04:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] SEIU 1000 negotiates pay raise that really isn’t</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/california/seiu-1000-negotiates-pay-raise-that-really-isnt/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;SEIU Local 1000 just cut a backroom deal with California Gov. Gavin Newsom that leaves state workers holding the bag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/california/seiu-1000-negotiates-pay-raise-that-really-isnt/" rel="nofollow"&gt;SEIU 1000 negotiates pay raise that really isn’t&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 16:14:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Massachusetts Joins NYC and KC in Shifting Fees to Landlords</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/economy/massachusetts-joins-nyc-and-kc-in-shifting-fees-to-landlords/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Massachusetts lawmakers recently approved a measure requiring landlords—not tenants—to cover apartment broker fees, which often equal one month’s rent. The [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/economy/massachusetts-joins-nyc-and-kc-in-shifting-fees-to-landlords/"&gt;Massachusetts Joins NYC and KC in Shifting Fees to Landlords&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 17:01:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] The $137 Billion Question: What Are California’s Schools Delivering?</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/the-137-billion-question-what-are-californias-schools-delivering/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=the-137-billion-question-what-are-californias-schools-delivering</link><description>&lt;p&gt;With schools back in session and the state budget finalized, the question of what California spends on public education — and what it delivers in return — is at the forefront of many parents’ and taxpayers’ minds. California has among the highest per-pupil spending in the nation, but questions persist about whether California families are...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/the-137-billion-question-what-are-californias-schools-delivering/"&gt;The $137 Billion Question: What Are California’s Schools Delivering?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 19:47:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] ITR Foundation Wins National Award for Most Influential Research</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/itr-foundation-wins-national-award-for-most-influential-research/</link><description>&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="629" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/ITRF-SPN-2025-Award.jpg" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="ITR Foundation Wins National Award for Most Influential Research" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/ITRF-SPN-2025-Award-600x315.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iowans for Tax Relief Foundation (ITRF) is honored to announce that our work on the ITR Report Card was recognized with the Bob Williams Award for Most Influential Research at the State Policy Network’s Annual Meeting in New Orleans on August 27.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bob Williams Awards celebrate state-based think tanks that achieve exceptional results advancing free-market policy reforms. Named after Bob Williams—one of the conservative movement’s most respected policy leaders—the awards are given annually to recognize research and achievements that not only make a difference locally, but also serve as models for the nation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/itr-foundation-wins-national-award-for-most-influential-research/"&gt;ITR Foundation Wins National Award for Most Influential Research&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 19:48:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] The Economic Development Paradigm – City-Created Problems and Taxpayer-Funded Fixes</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/taxpayer-funded-fixes/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=taxpayer-funded-fixes</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Economic development departments are often celebrated as promoters of prosperity and local employment. Each year, local governments spend tens of billions of dollars on economic development incentives—tax abatements, fee waivers, and direct subsidies—intended to lure private investment. Cities across the nation tout their ability to entice marquee employers, generate buzz with ribbon-cuttings, and implement incentive...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/taxpayer-funded-fixes/"&gt;The Economic Development Paradigm – City-Created Problems and Taxpayer-Funded Fixes&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 20:11:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] A new concern in Wisconsin: young slouches</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/a-new-concern-in-wisconsin-young-slouches/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Business leaders and educators are concerned about the future of the workforce in the Badger State — and debating whether many young Wisconsinites are just lazy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/a-new-concern-in-wisconsin-young-slouches/"&gt;A new concern in Wisconsin: young slouches&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 20:20:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] The hills are alive with the, well, approval of leftist politicians</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/wisconsin-rights-of-nature-law/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;State Rep. Joy Goeben and state Sen. Steve Nass have introduced a bill that would prohibit local governments from enacting a “rights of nature” ordinance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/wisconsin-rights-of-nature-law/"&gt;The hills are alive with the, well, approval of leftist politicians&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 20:45:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] New Hampshire rated the least corrupt state</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/09/new-hampshire-rated-the-least-corrupt-state/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;America’s freest state has just been rated its least corrupt too. Using U.S. Department of Justice data on corruption convictions in all 94 federal judicial districts from 2003-2024, the Cato Institute calculated the rate of corruption convictions per 10,000 government employees, then recently ranked states by their conviction rates. New Hampshire ranked dead last, with [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/09/new-hampshire-rated-the-least-corrupt-state/"&gt;New Hampshire rated the least corrupt state&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 00:17:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] ‘Everyone already agrees that tariffs are bad, and everyone agrees that we should do something about national debt’</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/podcasts/the-overton-window/dave-hebert-on-why-many-voters-believe-economists-have-conned-the-american-people</link><description>Dave Hebert on why many voters believe economists have conned the American people</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Research Note: Nebraska’s Neighboring States’ conditional use permitting processes</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/research-note-nebraskas-neighboring-states-conditional-use-permitting-processes/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;[Note: This is the fifth in a series of Research Notes by Platte’s intern, focusing on county zoning and agriculture issues. The final (sixth) note will include discussion of a bill currently before the Legislature.] In addition to Iowa, Nebraska’s other neighboring states have faced zoning challenges related to permitting new livestock operations. While Iowa...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/research-note-nebraskas-neighboring-states-conditional-use-permitting-processes/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Research Note: Nebraska&amp;#8217;s Neighboring States&amp;#8217; conditional use permitting processes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 12:34:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Break Point for Transparency</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/break-point-for-transparency/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Why and how is Highland Park ISD hiding information about an employee-run kick-back scheme that could have bilked the district for over $1 million? The answer could have far-reaching consequences for government transparency throughout Texas. In 2020, a former employee of the district’s tennis center alleged that some other employees had been skimming cash that...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/break-point-for-transparency/"&gt;Break Point for Transparency &lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 15:14:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] School Choice Improves Public School Performance</title><link>https://empowerms.org/school-choice-improves-public-school-performance/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#8217;s an argument going around that deserves a response: The Parents’ Campaign has repeatedly claimed that Mississippi is gaining academically while the &amp;#8220;top choice states&amp;#8221; plummeted. This is naive, lacking any academic rigor, and a dishonest interpretation of the data.   First, the phrase &amp;#8220;top choice states&amp;#8221; is misleading. Half the states in their top 10&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/school-choice-improves-public-school-performance/"&gt;School Choice Improves Public School Performance&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 15:41:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] First Principles Series: The Plight of Property Taxes</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/first-principles-series-the-plight-of-property-taxes/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=first-principles-series-the-plight-of-property-taxes</link><description>Tennessee joins Hawaii, Vermont, and New Hampshire as the outliers where property taxes can go up without limit.</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 16:02:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] From Waterloo to Keokuk: Where Property Taxes Hit Hardest in Iowa</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/from-waterloo-to-keokuk-where-property-taxes-hit-hardest-in-iowa/</link><description>&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="630" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/effective-property-tax-rates.jpg" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="From Waterloo to Keokuk: Where Property Taxes Hit Hardest in Iowa" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/effective-property-tax-rates-600x315.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Property taxes in Iowa are unpredictable and burdensome, driven by many layers of government that often leave homeowners frustrated as bills rise faster than their ability to pay.&lt;br /&gt;
Effective property tax rates vary widely across the state, with homeowners in places like Eldridge and Le Mars paying under 1.3%, while residents in Waterloo and Keokuk face rates above 2%.&lt;br /&gt;
 Without meaningful reform to limit local government spending, these disparities and rising bills will continue, making property tax relief one of the most pressing issues for Iowa families and businesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/from-waterloo-to-keokuk-where-property-taxes-hit-hardest-in-iowa/"&gt;From Waterloo to Keokuk: Where Property Taxes Hit Hardest in Iowa&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 16:59:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] SNAP Back to Reality</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/welfare/snap-back-to-reality/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Medicaid wasn’t the only welfare program that received significant reforms in the One Big Beautiful Bill (OBBB). The Supplemental Nutrition [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/welfare/snap-back-to-reality/"&gt;SNAP Back to Reality&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 17:54:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Week in Review: Free Speech Showdown</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-free-speech-showdown/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;No one should be subject to violent retaliation just for supporting causes they believe in. But across the country, Americans..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-free-speech-showdown/"&gt;Week in Review: Free Speech Showdown&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 19:49:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/09/the-outstater-287/</link><description>&amp;#8216;Chicago Is Indiana&amp;#8217;s Fault&amp;#8217; iT CAN BE HOPED that Mayor Brandon Johnson, who this week blamed Indiana for Chicago crime, will be thrown from office the next election cycle. I have my doubts, though, realizing that his message of envy and resentment is a powerful one with a large constituency. Envy, please know, is a&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/09/the-outstater-287/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 20:55:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Cost of Democrat-Supported Carbon Tax Reaches $500 Million Per Year</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/cost-of-democrat-supported-carbon-tax-reaches-500-million-per-year/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="630" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Democrats-Carbon-Tax-Virginia.jpg" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the&amp;#160;most recent&amp;#160;carbon tax imposed on the member states of the Regional Greenhouse Gas Initiative (RGGI), Virginians will pay about $500 million more per year for electricity if Virginia again becomes one of those member states.&amp;#160;Your vote in November may determine that.&amp;#160; Democratic nominee for governor Abigail Spanberger&amp;#160;has pledged&amp;#160;to rejoin the RGGI compact and [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/cost-of-democrat-supported-carbon-tax-reaches-500-million-per-year/"&gt;Cost of Democrat-Supported Carbon Tax Reaches $500 Million Per Year&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 23:20:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Michigan education budget fight centers on local decision-making</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/michigan-education-budget-fight-centers-on-local-decision-making</link><description>House proposal would wind down “categorical grants” and give more freedom to school districts</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Ukraine proves America’s secret weapon works — now we must double down on it</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/ukraine-proves-americas-secret-weapon-works-now-we-must-double-down-on-it/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The OODA Loop has been a key advantage for Ukraine. When Russia invaded Ukraine in February 2022, many experts predicted Kyiv’s quick fall. When Ukraine pushed back overextended Russian forces, the same experts confidently said that Russia’s mass — a population almost four times larger than Ukraine — would certainly grind Ukraine down. Triumph for Putin was...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/ukraine-proves-americas-secret-weapon-works-now-we-must-double-down-on-it/"&gt;Ukraine proves America’s secret weapon works — now we must double down on it&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 12:32:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] ‘Workforce housing’ fees make homes more expensive for everyone</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/workforce-housing-fees-make-homes-more-expensive-for-everyone</link><description>The most expensive county in Wyoming to build a house thinks everyone should pay more to build a house. Does that make sense? In Teton...</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 14:26:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] Commonwealth Foundation Urges Legal Protection of State’s Rainy Day Fund</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/09/08/commonwealth-foundation-urges-legal-protection-of-states-rainy-day-fund/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Letter calls on Treasurer Garrity to withhold any transfer from the budget stabilization reserve fund, pending legal adjudication. Harrisburg, Pa., September 8, 2025 — Today, the Commonwealth Foundation sent a letter to leaders of the General Assembly and Pennsylvania State Treasurer Stacy Garrity, urging the legal protection of the commonwealth’s Rainy Day Fund. Gov. Josh [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/09/08/commonwealth-foundation-urges-legal-protection-of-states-rainy-day-fund/"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation Urges Legal Protection of State&amp;#8217;s Rainy Day Fund&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 15:28:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] For Isleton (and other small California cities), disincorporation is the answer</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/for-isleton-and-other-small-california-cities-disincorporation-is-the-answer/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=for-isleton-and-other-small-california-cities-disincorporation-is-the-answer</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The small Sacramento Delta city of Isleton has been making news for all the wrong reasons this summer. It is facing a financial crisis and talk of bankruptcy is in the air. But a better option is to cease being a city at all by disincorporating. As the accompanying population chart suggests, Isleton has seen...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/for-isleton-and-other-small-california-cities-disincorporation-is-the-answer/"&gt;For Isleton (and other small California cities), disincorporation is the answer&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 17:36:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Business Leaders Urge CT to Cut Taxes, Energy Bills</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/09/08/business-leaders-urge-ct-to-cut-taxes-energy-bills/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="1438" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/shutterstock_2462256253-scaled.jpg" width="2560" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new report by the Connecticut Business &amp;#38; Industry Association (CBIA), reveals a divided outlook among the state&amp;#8217;s business leaders. While state finances have stabilized in recent years, persistent affordability [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/09/08/business-leaders-urge-ct-to-cut-taxes-energy-bills/"&gt;Business Leaders Urge CT to Cut Taxes, Energy Bills&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 17:47:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Announcing Pelican Institute Center for Justice’s Fall CLE/CE Series</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/justice/announcing-pelican-institute-center-for-justices-fall-cle-ce-series/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been a busy year in Baton Rouge and in Washington. The Pelican Institute Center for Justice is once again hosting a series of free Continuing Legal Education and Continuing Education courses for lawyers and accountants to keep you up to date on the latest developments in the law. Thursday, October 9 Zoom Webinar AI...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/justice/announcing-pelican-institute-center-for-justices-fall-cle-ce-series/"&gt;Announcing Pelican Institute Center for Justice’s Fall CLE/CE Series&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 18:26:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Fact Check: No, Offshore Wind Wouldn’t Have Saved New England Ratepayers ‘Millions’</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/fact-check-no-offshore-wind-wouldnt-have-saved-new-england-ratepayers-millions/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On September 4, the Portland Press Herald published an article titled “Offshore wind could have saved New England ratepayers millions last winter.” Like many headlines in the renewable energy space, this one is misleading and contradicts the real-world economics of offshore wind development. Let’s set the record straight. Claim: Offshore wind “would have” saved money [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/fact-check-no-offshore-wind-wouldnt-have-saved-new-england-ratepayers-millions/"&gt;Fact Check: No, Offshore Wind Wouldn’t Have Saved New England Ratepayers &amp;#8216;Millions&amp;#8217;&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 18:47:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] The Taxman Cometh: City of Whitesboro</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/the-taxman-cometh-city-of-whitesboro/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Most city, county, and school district officials are right now in the process of adopting budgets and determining tax rates for the next fiscal year. In some cases, these local decisions will increase the cost of government and put upward pressure on property tax bills. In a few cases, local government action will cause tax...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/the-taxman-cometh-city-of-whitesboro/"&gt;The Taxman Cometh: City of Whitesboro&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 18:59:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] California’s lawsuit against energy companies will increase greenhouse gas emissions</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/californias-lawsuit-against-energy-companies-will-increase-greenhouse-gas-emissions/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This fall the San Francisco Superior Court is holding a hearing on California’s lawsuit against American energy companies. The lawsuit alleges that these private U.S. companies misled the public about greenhouse gases’ impact and are responsible for covering the costs associated with climate disasters. But California and the federal government have been aware that GHGs [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/californias-lawsuit-against-energy-companies-will-increase-greenhouse-gas-emissions/"&gt;California’s lawsuit against energy companies will increase greenhouse gas emissions&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 19:49:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Massachusetts’ Capital Investment Plan Earmarks $415 Million for Housing in FY2026</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/massachusetts-capital-investment-plan-earmarks-415-million-for-housing-in-fy2026/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This edition of The House Call breaks down the housing items in Massachusetts' FY2026-FY2030 Capital Investment Plan. It also explains a new policy ordered by the Department of Public Utilities that would require natural gas customers to pay more for new hookups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/massachusetts-capital-investment-plan-earmarks-415-million-for-housing-in-fy2026/"&gt;Massachusetts&amp;#8217; Capital Investment Plan Earmarks $415 Million for Housing in FY2026&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 20:13:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Platte County Agreement Could Be a Model for Missouri</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/taxes/platte-county-agreement-could-be-a-model-for-missouri/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Platte County has had a difficult 2025 reassessment cycle. Most stories I have read and heard put the blame on [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/taxes/platte-county-agreement-could-be-a-model-for-missouri/"&gt;Platte County Agreement Could Be a Model for Missouri&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 20:16:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Kudos to the counties for considering housing reforms</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/09/kudos-to-the-counties-for-considering-housing-reforms/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;You’ve heard much from me lately about how the state Legislature seems to have gotten serious about addressing Hawaii’s extreme lack of affordable housing — and there is recent progress at the county level to highlight as well. I’ve said it before, but it bears repeating: There is no silver-bullet solution to our state’s housing [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/09/kudos-to-the-counties-for-considering-housing-reforms/"&gt;Kudos to the counties for considering housing reforms&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 20:31:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Set standards on manufactured housing to ramp up homebuilding</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/09/set-standards-on-manufactured-housing-to-ramp-up-homebuilding/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Maui County Council on September 8, 2025._____________ Sept. 8, 2025, 9 a.m.Kalana O Maui Building To: Maui County Council       Alice Lee, Chair       Yuki Lei Sugimura, Vice Chair From: Grassrot Institute of Hawaii            Jonathan Helton, Policy Analyst RE: Bill 122 (2025) [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/09/set-standards-on-manufactured-housing-to-ramp-up-homebuilding/"&gt;Set standards on manufactured housing to ramp up homebuilding&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 20:35:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Bill 123 crucial to economic recovery of bed and breakfasts in Lahaina</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/09/bill-123-crucial-to-economic-recovery-of-bed-and-breakfasts-in-lahaina/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Maui County Council on September 8, 2025._____________ Sept. 8, 2025, 9 a.m.Kalana O Maui Building To: Maui County Council&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Alice Lee, Chair&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Yuki Lei Sugimura, Vice Chair From: Grassrot Institute of Hawaii&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Jonathan Helton, Policy Analyst RE: Bill 123 (2025) [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/09/bill-123-crucial-to-economic-recovery-of-bed-and-breakfasts-in-lahaina/"&gt;Bill 123 crucial to economic recovery of bed and breakfasts in Lahaina&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 20:37:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] How Much Does Private School Really Cost in Mississippi?</title><link>https://empowerms.org/how-much-does-private-school-really-cost-in-mississippi/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For many Mississippi families, private school feels financially out of reach. However new research shows that private education may be more affordable than most people think—and that smart policy could make it accessible to thousands more students.  Research conducted by Empower Mississippi reveals that the average tuition for private schools varies from approximately $6,710 for&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/how-much-does-private-school-really-cost-in-mississippi/"&gt;How Much Does Private School Really Cost in Mississippi?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 21:15:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Valley residents are growing alarmed by solar-and-battery project taking over farmland. Here’s why.</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/valley-residents-are-growing-alarmed-by-solar-and-battery-project-taking-over-farmland-heres-why/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;We’ve been assured for quite some time that wind and solar are the energy sources of the future. If so, their development needs to be accelerated because they are not being well received by locals. Their low energy density is partly, if not largely, to blame. Fresno County residents are unhappy with a planned solar-and-battery [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/valley-residents-are-growing-alarmed-by-solar-and-battery-project-taking-over-farmland-heres-why/"&gt;Valley residents are growing alarmed by solar-and-battery project taking over farmland. Here’s why.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 22:07:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] When will Cook County expect 2nd property tax payment? Good question.</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/when-will-cook-county-expect-2nd-property-tax-payment-good-question/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The second installment of Cook County property taxes should have been paid Aug. 1. The county can’t get the calculations completed, so the bills are on hold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/when-will-cook-county-expect-2nd-property-tax-payment-good-question/"&gt;When will Cook County expect 2nd property tax payment? Good question.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 22:14:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] New iPhone launching soon, but Illinoisans will pay nation’s highest taxes to use it</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/new-iphone-launching-soon-but-illinoisans-will-pay-nations-highest-taxes-to-use-it/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Apple’s new iPhone launch on Sept. 9 may be a celebration for tech consumers, but it also makes the Illinois taxman smile. Illinois already had the nation’s highest tax rate on cell phone plans before it bumped up even more July 1. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/new-iphone-launching-soon-but-illinoisans-will-pay-nations-highest-taxes-to-use-it/"&gt;New iPhone launching soon, but Illinoisans will pay nation’s highest taxes to use it&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 22:22:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Delivering a warning about Democrats’ lawfare</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/delivering-a-warning-about-democrats-lawfare/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Peter Navarro writes for the Federalist about his experience with Democrats’ legal machinery. I Went to Prison So You Won’t Have To is both a line from my speech that brought the house down at the Republican National Convention on the day I walked out of prison, and a cautionary tale about the new age...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/delivering-a-warning-about-democrats-lawfare/"&gt;Delivering a warning about Democrats’ lawfare&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 09:36:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Big Mamdani donor also backs ‘woke math’</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/big-mamdani-donor-also-backs-woke-math/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Rich Calder writes for the New York Post about an interesting fact involving a key backer of New York’s socialist mayoral candidate. The billionaire heiress who recently donated $250,000 to a super PAC supporting socialist Zohran Mamdani’s NYC mayoral campaign is bankrolling a national push to bring “woke math” into public schools — a twisted...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/big-mamdani-donor-also-backs-woke-math/"&gt;Big Mamdani donor also backs ‘woke math’&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 09:39:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Documenting collapse of ‘judicial coup’</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/documenting-collapse-of-judicial-coup/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;David Catron writes for the American Spectator about a significant development for the American judiciary. Late last week NBC ran a “news” story featuring a dozen disgruntled federal judges whose rulings against various Trump administration policies have been stayed or overturned by the Supreme Court. These lower court judges, none of whom had the courage...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/documenting-collapse-of-judicial-coup/"&gt;Documenting collapse of ‘judicial coup’&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 09:42:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Education blob orders more of the same after test scores collapse</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/education-blob-orders-more-of-the-same-after-test-scores-collapse</link><description>Michigan students show another alarming decline in 2025 M-STEP results</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Chicago pensions carry more debt than 44 states</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/chicago-pensions-carry-more-debt-than-44-states/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Chicago’s pension systems carry over $53 billion in debt, leaving taxpayers with rising bills and no reform in sight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/chicago-pensions-carry-more-debt-than-44-states/"&gt;Chicago pensions carry more debt than 44 states&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 10:00:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Wage regulation roll back is a step in the right direction for the H-2A program</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/wage-regulation-roll-back-is-a-step-in-the-right-direction-for-the-h-2a-program/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Adverse Effect Wage Rate (AEWR) is the de facto minimum wage for H-2A workers in the United States. It is set annually and differs from state-to-state depending upon the prevailing wage of the local agricultural workforce. Because all H-2A workers are in the United States temporarily to work in seasonal agricultural jobs, and employers [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/wage-regulation-roll-back-is-a-step-in-the-right-direction-for-the-h-2a-program/"&gt;Wage regulation roll back is a step in the right direction for the H-2A program&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 10:00:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Research Note: current efforts to address ag zoning issues</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/research-note-current-efforts-to-address-ag-zoning-issues/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;[Note: This is the final in a series of Research Notes by Platte’s intern, focusing on county zoning and agriculture issues. A full paper dealing with these issues will be published later this fall.] Over the past decade, Nebraska’s legislature has repeatedly sought to address issues related to the Conditional Use Permits (CUPs) and Special...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/research-note-current-efforts-to-address-ag-zoning-issues/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Research Note: current efforts to address ag zoning issues&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 12:59:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Louisiana Still Needs a Government Growth Limit</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/tax-budget/louisiana-still-needs-a-government-growth-limit-2/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Limited government is a core American value that has empowered individuals to prosper across the nation. The framers of the Constitution understood government as a necessary evil: “If men were angels, no government would be necessary,” wrote James Madison. He went on to say, “In framing a government which is to be administered by men...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/tax-budget/louisiana-still-needs-a-government-growth-limit-2/"&gt;Louisiana Still Needs a Government Growth Limit&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 17:03:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] WILL Applauds Wisconsin State Assembly for Tackling Education Priorities</title><link>https://will-law.org/will-applauds-wisconsin-state-assembly-for-tackling-education-priorities/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL supports new efforts by WI legislators to tackle these pressing issues in education. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/will-applauds-wisconsin-state-assembly-for-tackling-education-priorities/"&gt;WILL Applauds Wisconsin State Assembly for Tackling Education Priorities&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 17:11:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Amazon leaves Becker in the lurch with loss of data center</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/amazon-leaves-becker-in-the-lurch-with-loss-of-data-center/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Today, the Minnesota Star Tribune’s Walker Orenstein published an assessment of the challenges facing Becker after Amazon abandoned its planned data center: For now, the land will remain vacant. In May, the tech giant from Seattle&amp;#160;abruptly halted its plans&amp;#160;during a fight over state regulations, making the project the latest promising business venture to flame out...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/amazon-leaves-becker-in-the-lurch-with-loss-of-data-center/"&gt;Amazon leaves Becker in the lurch with loss of data center&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 17:53:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] The ITD Money Pit of Idaho: Stop Digging!</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/the-itd-money-pit-of-idaho-stop-digging/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/the-itd-money-pit-of-idaho-stop-digging/" rel="nofollow" title="The ITD Money Pit of Idaho: Stop Digging!"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Article-Headers-2025-09-09T110039.106.png" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Want to save the state nearly $100 million and help fix the budget hole created by years of overspending? Stop digging the money pit of the Idaho Transportation Department (ITD) headquarters on State Street.&amp;#160;&amp;#160; A couple of weeks ago, the governor’s office of the Division of Financial Management revised its tax collections forecast and reported [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 18:15:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Avon Rep. Eleni Kavros Degraw Calls Non-Degree Workers a ‘Burden’ at Debt Relief Meeting</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/09/09/avon-rep-eleni-kavros-degraw-calls-non-degree-workers-a-burden-at-debt-relief-meeting/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="578" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Screenshot-2025-09-09-at-2.13.19-PM.png" width="1016" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A legislative working group created to explore student debt relief in Connecticut took an unexpected turn last week when one of its co-chairs, Rep. Eleni Kavros DeGraw (D-Avon), suggested that [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/09/09/avon-rep-eleni-kavros-degraw-calls-non-degree-workers-a-burden-at-debt-relief-meeting/"&gt;Avon Rep. Eleni Kavros Degraw Calls Non-Degree Workers a ‘Burden’ at Debt Relief Meeting&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 18:20:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] National Poverty Rate Fails to Capture the Problem of Poverty Concentration in Georgia and Beyond</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/press-release-poverty-rate-2024/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/press-release-poverty-rate-2024/"&gt;National Poverty Rate Fails to Capture the Problem of Poverty Concentration in Georgia and Beyond&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 18:26:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] A Public School’s DEI Cover-Up Fails in Pennsylvania Court</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/dei-fails-in-court/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;It’s not a recipe. It’s not a patented algorithm. It’s not the secret to a billion-dollar product line. It’s a..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/dei-fails-in-court/"&gt;A Public School’s DEI Cover-Up Fails in Pennsylvania Court&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 18:36:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] Wong: The Abuse of Intercity Bus Subsidies</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/09/wong-the-abuse-of-intercity-bus-subsidies/</link><description>by J.D. Wong Since 1978, a federal subsidy program (49 U.S.C. 5311) has funneled taxpayer money into intercity bus routes. Fast forward to today&amp;#160;and this initiative has failed. Instead of attracting riders, politicians have often crafted routes to win votes. As a result, subsidized buses have been squandering taxpayer money for 46 years. Meanwhile, unsubsidized&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/09/wong-the-abuse-of-intercity-bus-subsidies/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 18:55:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Ilhan Omar: The Marxist Millionaire</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/ilhan-omar-the-marxist-millionaire/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome back to the American Experiment Podcast! This week, Grace and Kathryn are joined by Bill Walsh to break down the latest Minnesota and national news. First, Governor Walz is calling for a special session in the Minnesota Legislature—but with no details. Is it just a political show, or is there more to it? We...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/ilhan-omar-the-marxist-millionaire/"&gt;Ilhan Omar: The Marxist Millionaire&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 19:22:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Energy Victories: Commonwealth LNG Gets Final DOE Approval; US LNG Exports Hit Record High Thanks to Plaquemines LNG</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/energy/energy-victories-commonwealth-lng-gets-final-doe-approval-us-lng-exports-hit-record-high-thanks-to-plaquemines-lng/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Louisiana&amp;#8217;s energy sector recently scored two major victories that demonstrate the power of free markets over government interference. The U.S. Department of Energy (DOE) granted final permit approval for the Commonwealth Liquified Natural Gas (LNG) export terminal in Cameron Parish, while U.S. LNG exports hit an all-time record of 9.33 million metric tons in August—driven...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/energy/energy-victories-commonwealth-lng-gets-final-doe-approval-us-lng-exports-hit-record-high-thanks-to-plaquemines-lng/"&gt;Energy Victories: Commonwealth LNG Gets Final DOE Approval; US LNG Exports Hit Record High Thanks to Plaquemines LNG&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 19:28:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Omar Fateh shilled for HSS</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/omar-fateh-shilled-for-hss/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;KARE-11 TV is out with a report, KARE 11 Investigates: Ethics questions emerge over Sen. Fateh’s housing bill and wife’s company ties. Sen. Omar Fateh (DFL-Minneapolis) is by some accounts the front-runner to be elected Minneapolis mayor in November. The station is referring to Senate File 2741, a bill Sen. Fateh introduced back in March...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/omar-fateh-shilled-for-hss/"&gt;Omar Fateh shilled for HSS&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 23:12:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] As PEEHIP Faces Funding Shortfall, it is Time for Healthcare and Pension Reforms</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/09/10/as-peehip-faces-funding-shortfall-it-is-time-for-healthcare-and-pension-reforms/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This week, the Retirement Systems of Alabama’s (RSA) Public Education Employees’ Health Insurance Plan (PEEHIP) Control Board met to discuss rising healthcare costs for state employees. The discussion highlights a stark reality: Alabama’s taxpayer funded benefit system for public employees is on an unsustainable path. PEEHIP and RSA, which includes the Teachers’ Retirement System (TRS) and Employees’ Retirement System (ERS), are consuming billions annually while carrying massive unfunded liabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/09/10/as-peehip-faces-funding-shortfall-it-is-time-for-healthcare-and-pension-reforms/"&gt;As PEEHIP Faces Funding Shortfall, it is Time for Healthcare and Pension Reforms&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 02:32:02 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>