<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>State-Policy Think-Tank Digest</title><link>https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml</link><description>Latest posts from free-market policy institutes across the U.S.</description><atom:link href="https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 21:02:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>[Mspolicy] WTOK looks at what School Choice might mean for Mississippi</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/wtok-looks-at-what-school-choice-might-mean-for-mississippi/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I’m thrilled to share that momentum for School Choice in Mississippi is growing!&amp;#160;Governor Tate Reeves, Speaker Jason White, and even the White House are championing this transformative opportunity to empower parents and enhance education for our children. This week, WTOK TV aired an in-depth segment exploring how School Choice could benefit families across our state.&amp;#160;I [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/wtok-looks-at-what-school-choice-might-mean-for-mississippi/" rel="nofollow"&gt;WTOK looks at what School Choice might mean for Mississippi&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 16:08:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] What to know about education in Georgia as students go back to school</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/what-to-know-about-education-in-georgia/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As August ushers in a new school year in Georgia, nearly two million students are headed back to our states 2,300 public schools. How are Georgia schools doing when it comes to preparing kids for work and life? Here's a look at some key measures. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/what-to-know-about-education-in-georgia/"&gt;What to know about education in Georgia as students go back to school&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 22:26:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Get to Know Kathryn Beale, Beacon’s New Director of Development</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/get-to-know-kat-beale-beacons-new-director-of-development/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=get-to-know-kat-beale-beacons-new-director-of-development</link><description>Tell us about you—where you’re from, any fun facts about yourself, and where you spent your career prior to Beacon. I’m originally from Benton, Kentucky, a small town in the very western corner of the Bluegrass State. But, important to my upbringing, I am not a Wildcat! I spent four years in Nashville at Lipscomb...</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 15:13:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] New York’s Hospital Quality Remains Among the Worst in the U.S.</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/new-yorks-hospital-quality-remains-among-the-worst-in-the-u-s/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The federal government recently updated its hospital quality ratings, and New York once again fell near the bottom. Among 132....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/new-yorks-hospital-quality-remains-among-the-worst-in-the-u-s/"&gt;New York&amp;#8217;s Hospital Quality Remains Among the Worst in the U.S.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 18:44:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] NJ ED REPORT: Amplifying Student Voices: Advocating for Younger and More Inclusive Representation in IEP Meetings</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/08/nj-ed-report-amplifying-student-voices-advocating-for-younger-and-more-inclusive-representation-in-iep-meetings/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;NJPI policy research intern David Fishkin, a Political Science student at Rutgers University – New Brunswick, has published an op-ed [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/08/nj-ed-report-amplifying-student-voices-advocating-for-younger-and-more-inclusive-representation-in-iep-meetings/"&gt;NJ ED REPORT: Amplifying Student Voices: Advocating for Younger and More Inclusive Representation in IEP Meetings&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 18:52:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] New, Flawed Rating Changes Cover Up for Underperforming Schools, Again</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/new-flawed-rating-changes-cover-up-for-underperforming-schools-again/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New, Flawed Rating Changes Cover Up for Underperforming Schools, Again IRG uncovers changes that hide low-performing districts from parents Delafield, Wis. — The Institute for Reforming Government (IRG) issued a statement after the Wisconsin DPI again changed its 1–5 star school ratings at an August 12–14 Madison meeting, leaving parents unclear on local school performance. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/new-flawed-rating-changes-cover-up-for-underperforming-schools-again/"&gt;New, Flawed Rating Changes Cover Up for Underperforming Schools, Again&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 16:17:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] State Board of Ed votes to reduce proficiency standards; legislators should implement a different state assessment</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/state-board-of-ed-reduces-proficiency-standards/</link><description>The Kansas State Board of Education voted 7-3 this week to accept new cut scores for determining proficiency levels on the state assessment test, setting the stage for the Kansas Legislature to hopefully halt the imposition of less rigorous performance standards. More on that shortly after a brief recap of the fraud being perpetrated on [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 18:03:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] State financial inputs aren’t the measure of a university system</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/08/state-financial-inputs-arent-the-measure-of-a-university-system/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;How do you measure the success of a business? You might look at financial measures such as profits, dividends or share price, industry dominance such as market share, or how well it achieves its mission. A law firm could measure success in client wins, a sports team in championships.  What do all of those measures [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/08/state-financial-inputs-arent-the-measure-of-a-university-system/"&gt;State financial inputs aren&amp;#8217;t the measure of a university system&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 20:17:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Shenna Bellows’ Response to DOJ Misses the Mark on Election Law</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/shenna-bellows-response-to-doj-misses-the-mark-on-election-law/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier this month, U.S. Department of Justice officials requested an electronic copy of Maine’s statewide voter registration list under the National Voter Registration Act (NVRA). In her official reply, Secretary of State Shenna Bellows rejected the request, citing state law and concerns about personal information. Unfortunately, her memo misstates constitutional authority, misapplies case law, misinterprets [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/shenna-bellows-response-to-doj-misses-the-mark-on-election-law/"&gt;Shenna Bellows’ Response to DOJ Misses the Mark on Election Law&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 16:52:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] School Choice is Coming to Mississippi!</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/school-choice-is-coming-to-mississippi/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;What would it take for Mississippi to embrace School Choice?&amp;#160;How can we join our neighboring states in empowering families to control their child's share of the education budget? For School Choice to happen, we would need to see several steps.&amp;#160; &amp;#160;&amp;#160;Number one, we would need a committed Governor, ready to invest his political capital in [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/school-choice-is-coming-to-mississippi/" rel="nofollow"&gt;School Choice is Coming to Mississippi!&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 17:23:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Rifreedom] Center Cosigns Letter Supporting Seafreeze Petition to Suspend VINEYARD WIND Construction</title><link>https://rifreedom.org/2025/08/center-cosigns-letter-supporting-seafreeze-petition-to-suspend-vineyard-wind-construction/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Today, CEO for the Rhode Island Center for Freedom &amp;#038; Prosperity, Mike Stenhouse, co-signed a letter, along with national energy expert, G. Allen Brooks, requesting Doug Brugum, Secretary of the US Department Of the Interior (DOI), and other federal officials to accept the formal petition previously filed Seafreeze Inc (and others) that calls upon the government to immediately suspend "further construction and energy generation activity" of the near-completed Vineyard Wind off-shore wind project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org/2025/08/center-cosigns-letter-supporting-seafreeze-petition-to-suspend-vineyard-wind-construction/"&gt;Center Cosigns Letter Supporting Seafreeze Petition to Suspend VINEYARD WIND Construction&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org"&gt;RI Center for Freedom and Prosperity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 17:38:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Florida’s Election Reform Sets the Standard Nationwide</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/floridas-election-reform-sets-the-standard-nationwide/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE August 19, 2025 CONTACT Logan Elizabeth Padgett 850-386-3131 Florida’s Election Reform Sets the Standard Nationwide...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/floridas-election-reform-sets-the-standard-nationwide/"&gt;Florida’s Election Reform Sets the Standard Nationwide &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 04:01:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Florida: The Gold Standard in Elections Administration From Bush v. Gore to Present 2000-2025</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/florida-the-gold-standard-in-elections-administration-from-bush-v-gore-to-present-2000-2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Ben Gibson — Senior Fellow, The James Madison Institute Doug Wheeler — Director, George Gibbs Center for Economic...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/florida-the-gold-standard-in-elections-administration-from-bush-v-gore-to-present-2000-2025/"&gt;Florida: The Gold Standard in Elections Administration From Bush v. Gore to Present 2000-2025&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 04:01:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] What’s at stake in Albuquerque’s City Elections?</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/whats-at-stake-in-albuquerques-city-elections/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Paul recently sat down with Diane Kinderwater for an episode of &amp;#8220;Issues and Answers&amp;#8221; on KCHF TV. The show airs statewide and can be streamed live right here. In a recent conversation Paul had a chance to discuss what&amp;#8217;s at stake in the City of Albuquerque elections this fall. We discuss crime, homelessness, the economy, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/whats-at-stake-in-albuquerques-city-elections/"&gt;What&amp;#8217;s at stake in Albuquerque&amp;#8217;s City Elections?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 19:34:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Nebraska’s State Funding for K-12 Education Has Doubled Since 2020</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/nebraskas-state-funding-for-k-12-education-has-doubled-since-2020/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Nebraska’s education funding has historically been heavily weighted on the property tax, but that is beginning to change. Through new sources of funding and property tax offsets, the implicit state funding of education is growing rapidly.  Over the last decade, state aid through the TEEOSA formula has increased by $200 million. Meanwhile, property tax funding...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/nebraskas-state-funding-for-k-12-education-has-doubled-since-2020/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Nebraska’s State Funding for K-12 Education Has Doubled Since 2020 &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 19:56:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Deficits on the horizon as state spending explodes</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/state-spending-explodes-deficits/</link><description>How do you go from having a $3 billion budget surplus and stable tax revenue to broke in just a few years? By repeatedly spending more than you take in. General Fund spending has pretty much been out of control since 2018, the year after the Legislature passed the largest tax increase in state history. [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 20:51:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cardinalinstitute] West Virginia’s Certificate of Need Laws Are Failing You</title><link>https://cardinalinstitute.com/west-virginias-certificate-of-need-laws-are-failing-you/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;West Virginia’s Certificate of Need Laws Are Failing You The West Virginia Hospital Association’s recent op-ed defending West Virginia’s Certificate of Need (CON) laws is a masterclass in elite protectionism, dressed in concern, framed as a noble stand for community health. Make no mistake—the heart of the piece is about hospital bottom lines rather than how [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com/west-virginias-certificate-of-need-laws-are-failing-you/"&gt;West Virginia’s Certificate of Need Laws Are Failing You&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com"&gt;Cardinal Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 16:22:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Corrected: As Math and Reading Proficiency Went Up, ‘Cut Scores’ Went Down</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/as-math-and-reading-proficiency-went-up-cut-scores-went-down/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;(Corrected on Aug. 27: The original version of this post inappropriately combined &amp;#8220;scale scores&amp;#8221; calculated by the Albany Times Union....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/as-math-and-reading-proficiency-went-up-cut-scores-went-down/"&gt;Corrected: As Math and Reading Proficiency Went Up, &amp;#8216;Cut Scores&amp;#8217; Went Down&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 13:46:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Colorado’s AI Catastrophe: A Cautionary Tale</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/colorados-ai-catastrophe-a-cautionary-tale/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On May 27, 2024, Colorado became the unfortunate pioneer in a troubling new frontier of government overreach. The...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/colorados-ai-catastrophe-a-cautionary-tale/"&gt;Colorado&amp;#8217;s AI Catastrophe: A Cautionary Tale&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 15:20:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] In child care, as in housing, maybe the government’s doing a bit too much?</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/08/in-child-care-as-in-housing-maybe-the-governments-doing-a-bit-too-much/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Surging child care prices have grabbed the media’s attention here in New Hampshire, and rightly so. The price of full-time care in a licensed center “jumped 48 percent between 2013 and 2023,” landing at nearly $32,000 a year, according to an analysis last year by the Carsey School of Public Policy at UNH.   Child [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/08/in-child-care-as-in-housing-maybe-the-governments-doing-a-bit-too-much/"&gt;In child care, as in housing, maybe the government’s doing a bit too much?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 17:00:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] The Perils of Populism: A Free Market Warning for Louisiana</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/tax-budget/the-perils-of-populism-a-free-market-warning-for-louisiana/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In an era where political rhetoric often pits the “little guy” against the “big guy,” populism has resurfaced as a potent force, captivating voters with promises of empowerment and justice. From a free market perspective, however, populism is not a savior but a siren song that leads economies astray. As Louisiana experienced with Huey Long,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/tax-budget/the-perils-of-populism-a-free-market-warning-for-louisiana/"&gt;The Perils of Populism: A Free Market Warning for Louisiana&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 17:47:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF in National Review: The Return of Car Choice, Hopefully</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-in-national-review-the-return-of-car-choice-hopefully/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following appeared in National Review&amp;#8217;s Capital Matters on August 20, 2025. Whatever happens to the future of EVs, they should compete on an even playing field with other vehicles. While the courts have yet to have their say, one of the Trump administration’s most important accomplishments, perhaps second only to his successful crackdown on illegal [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-in-national-review-the-return-of-car-choice-hopefully/"&gt;RGF in National Review: The Return of Car Choice, Hopefully&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 17:56:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Portland’s Social Housing Task Force: Another Wrong Turn for Housing Policy</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/portlands-social-housing-task-force-another-wrong-turn-for-housing-policy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Portland officials are once again reaching for the wrong tool to solve Maine’s housing crisis. In March, the City Council voted to create a “Social Housing Task Force” with the stated goal of exploring a system where the government owns, develops, and manages housing for residents. At first glance, this may sound like a bold [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/portlands-social-housing-task-force-another-wrong-turn-for-housing-policy/"&gt;Portland’s Social Housing Task Force: Another Wrong Turn for Housing Policy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] New TV/Digital Ad: Shapiro’s Budget Impasse is Failing Kids &amp; Families</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/08/22/new-tv-digital-ad-shapiros-budget-impasse-is-failing-kids-families/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Harrisburg, Pa., August 22, 2025 — Today, the Commonwealth Foundation launched a new ad, calling for Gov. Josh Shapiro to end the budget impasse with a compromise that protects families from tax hikes and offers educational choice. The ad is running statewide on digital beginning this weekend, and will air on TV from Sunday, August [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/08/22/new-tv-digital-ad-shapiros-budget-impasse-is-failing-kids-families/"&gt;New TV/Digital Ad: Shapiro’s Budget Impasse is Failing Kids &amp;#038; Families&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 13:32:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] CT’s Low “Fun” Rank Linked to High Taxes, Strict Regulations</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/08/22/cts-low-fun-rank-linked-to-high-taxes-strict-regulations/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="1709" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/shutterstock_1487599832-scaled.jpg" width="2560" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connecticut is not considered a “fun” state, ranking 43rd overall in a new WalletHub report. This quirky detail reveals a deeper problem plaguing the state: that high taxes and burdensome [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/08/22/cts-low-fun-rank-linked-to-high-taxes-strict-regulations/"&gt;CT’s Low “Fun” Rank Linked to High Taxes, Strict Regulations&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 13:49:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] BEAD for Speed: Louisiana’s Broadband Efforts Lead Once Again</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/bead-for-speed-louisianas-broadband-efforts-lead-once-again/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When the National Telecommunications and Information Administration announced an overhaul of the $42.45 billion Broadband Equity, Access, and  Deployment (BEAD) program that had been slowly unrolling since 2021, broadband offices across the country were tasked with revising years of work under tight deadlines. Louisiana’s ConnectLA rose to the occasion and executed a revised plan with swift determination,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/bead-for-speed-louisianas-broadband-efforts-lead-once-again/"&gt;BEAD for Speed: Louisiana’s Broadband Efforts Lead Once Again&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 14:20:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] SEPTA’s Manufactured Crisis Has Delayed State Budget Long Enough</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/08/22/septas-manufactured-crisis-has-delayed-state-budget-long-enough/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Harrisburg, Pa., August 22, 2025 — This Sunday, after eight consecutive weeks of public fearmongering, the Southeastern Pennsylvania Transportation Authority (SEPTA) will enact self-imposed service cuts. Though completely avoidable, these cuts aim to extract yet another taxpayer-funded bailout. This is not a true emergency; it is a manufactured crisis, fueled and exploited by Gov. Josh [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/08/22/septas-manufactured-crisis-has-delayed-state-budget-long-enough/"&gt;SEPTA’s Manufactured Crisis Has Delayed State Budget Long Enough&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 16:12:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] The State’s War on Homeschooling Rests on Bad Data</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/08/22/the-states-war-on-homeschooling-rests-on-bad-data/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connecticut’s Office of the Child Advocate (OCA) is using a high-profile tragedy as a springboard to regulate homeschooling, but critics say the state’s case is built on flawed data and [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/08/22/the-states-war-on-homeschooling-rests-on-bad-data/"&gt;The State’s War on Homeschooling Rests on Bad Data&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 18:48:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Listen: The Folly of Portland’s Social Housing Task Force</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/listen-the-folly-of-portlands-social-housing-task-force/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Policy analyst, Harris Van Pate, joined the WGAN Morning News to discuss the pitfalls of Portland&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8220;Social Housing Task Force&amp;#8221; and how the city&amp;#8217;s existing policies – like rent control and inclusionary zoning – are distorting the greater region&amp;#8217;s housing market to the detriment of renters and those looking to buy a home. Listen to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/listen-the-folly-of-portlands-social-housing-task-force/"&gt;Listen: The Folly of Portland&amp;#8217;s Social Housing Task Force&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 21:15:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] John Charles’ Testimony Re: ’25 Special Session Transportation Funding</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/testimony/john-charles-testimony-re-25-special-session-transportation-funding/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Testimony of John A. Charles, Jr.Regarding LC 2Before the Joint Interim Committee on...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/testimony/john-charles-testimony-re-25-special-session-transportation-funding/"&gt;John Charles’ Testimony Re: &amp;#8217;25 Special Session Transportation Funding &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 22:22:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Rifreedom] After Federal Action, Rhode Island Desperately Needs a Realistic Energy Strategy</title><link>https://rifreedom.org/2025/08/after-federal-action-rhode-island-desperately-needs-a-realistic-energy-strategy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Cranston, RI – The Rhode Island Center for Freedom &amp;#38; Prosperity advises state policymakers to immediately begin work to construct a new and realistic energy strategy that will put the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org/2025/08/after-federal-action-rhode-island-desperately-needs-a-realistic-energy-strategy/"&gt;After Federal Action, Rhode Island Desperately Needs a Realistic Energy Strategy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org"&gt;RI Center for Freedom and Prosperity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 15:41:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] New Study Highlights Tax Reforms that Would Enhance Massachusetts’ Competitiveness</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/economic_opportunity/new-study-highlights-tax-reforms-that-would-enhance-massachusetts-competitiveness/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Research indicates that tax policy plays a key role in outmigration from Massachusetts, and a new study published by Pioneer Institute highlights six tax reforms that would help the Commonwealth address its outmigration and competitiveness challenges. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/economic_opportunity/new-study-highlights-tax-reforms-that-would-enhance-massachusetts-competitiveness/"&gt;New Study Highlights Tax Reforms that Would Enhance Massachusetts’ Competitiveness&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 04:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Hochul’s $17B Medicaid Surge Leaves Little to Brag About</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/hochuls-17b-medicaid-surge/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Governor Hochul has made Medicaid her dominant budget priority over the past four years, increasing the state&amp;#8217;s annual share of....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/hochuls-17b-medicaid-surge/"&gt;Hochul&amp;#8217;s $17B Medicaid Surge Leaves Little to Brag About&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 13:27:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Spending Solutions for ODOT’s Spending Problems</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/tax-and-budget/spending-solutions-for-odots-spending-problems/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Naomi Inman The Oregon Legislature’s Joint Committee on Transportation Funding will consider...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/tax-and-budget/spending-solutions-for-odots-spending-problems/"&gt;Spending Solutions for ODOT’s Spending Problems&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 14:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] NYT Bestseller Jane Leavy on Reforming Major League Baseball</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/nyt-bestseller-jane-leavy-on-reforming-major-league-baseball/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In this week’s episode of The Learning Curve, co-hosts U-Arkansas Prof. Albert Cheng and Pioneer Senior Fellow Charlie Chieppo interview award-winning journalist and New York Times bestselling author Jane Leavy. Ms. Leavy discusses her lifelong love of baseball, and her forthcoming book, Make Me Commissioner: I Know What’s Wrong with Baseball and How to Fix It, which comes out in September.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/nyt-bestseller-jane-leavy-on-reforming-major-league-baseball/"&gt;NYT Bestseller Jane Leavy on Reforming Major League Baseball&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 15:20:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Wisconsin Village Quickly Backs Down on Unconstitutional “Farmers Market” Restriction</title><link>https://will-law.org/wisconsin-village-quickly-backs-down-on-unconstitutional-farmers-market-restriction/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;#038; Liberty (WILL) issued a warning to the Village of Bonduel of an unconstitutional rule governing the sale of “politically or religiously affiliated merchandise,” at a village-operated farmers market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/wisconsin-village-quickly-backs-down-on-unconstitutional-farmers-market-restriction/"&gt;Wisconsin Village Quickly Backs Down on Unconstitutional “Farmers Market” Restriction&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 17:54:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Trump Administration Agrees with WILL Lawsuit: Federal Programs Illegally Discriminate Against Farmers</title><link>https://will-law.org/trump-administration-agrees-with-will-lawsuit-federal-programs-illegally-discriminate-against-farmers/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Trump Administration has filed a motion declining to defend multiple Biden-era aid programs within the Department of Agriculture (USDA), each of which currently discriminate against white male farmers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/trump-administration-agrees-with-will-lawsuit-federal-programs-illegally-discriminate-against-farmers/"&gt;Trump Administration Agrees with WILL Lawsuit: Federal Programs Illegally Discriminate Against Farmers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 15:00:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/08/the-outstater-285/</link><description>Crime Is a Root Cause MY CITY&amp;#160;is addressing public policy in the starkest terms. Youth violence and encampments of derelicts are problems without easy answers. Yet, answers, however imperfect, can be sought, social order can be attempted. Nobody likes to send a young man to jail or to order a troubled mind for treatment. In&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/08/the-outstater-285/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 19:55:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Building costs heading upward in first impact of bureaucrats being unleashed</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/building-costs-heading-upward-in-first-impact-of-bureaucrats-being-unleashed/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A new requirement to hire a “special inspector” to be on hand during construction will add an estimated $20,000 to any store, school, office, factory or apartment building in the Wisconsin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/building-costs-heading-upward-in-first-impact-of-bureaucrats-being-unleashed/"&gt;Building costs heading upward in first impact of bureaucrats being unleashed&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 20:40:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Where Has All The Money Gone?: Why Idaho’s Spending Bomb is Global</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/where-has-all-the-money-gone-why-idahos-spending-bomb-is-global/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/where-has-all-the-money-gone-why-idahos-spending-bomb-is-global/" rel="nofollow" title="Where Has All The Money Gone?: Why Idaho’s Spending Bomb is Global"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/Article-Headers-2025-08-29T094830.923.png" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Those of us of a certain age remember the old anti-war song, most famously sung by the lefty folk rock band, Peter, Paul and Mary: “Where Have All the Flowers Gone?” The song tells the story of the cycle of life, with the flowers ending up on military graves. Remember, this was during the Vietnam [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 16:26:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Connecticut’s Legislature is Busy. That Doesn’t Mean It’s Effective</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/08/29/connecticuts-legislature-is-busy-that-doesnt-mean-its-effective/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If lawmaking were graded on quantity not quality, Connecticut would be on the honor roll. In 2025 the General Assembly introduced 4,064 bills — eighth most in the nation for [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/08/29/connecticuts-legislature-is-busy-that-doesnt-mean-its-effective/"&gt;Connecticut’s Legislature is Busy. That Doesn’t Mean It’s Effective &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 16:49:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/08/the-outstater-286/</link><description>The Party that Doesn&amp;#8217;t Pray MARK AUG. 27, 2025, as the day the Democrat Party, or at least its prominent spokesmen, dismissed the prayers of children shot to death in their pews. That is the partisan interpretation. A more charitable one would be that Democrats believe that such an act, shooting children at prayer, deserves action (gun control)&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/08/the-outstater-286/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 16:53:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Humanity and Abortion</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/humanity-and-abortion/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/humanity-and-abortion/" rel="nofollow" title="Humanity and Abortion"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1350" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/Cream-Neutral-Minimalist-New-Business-Pitch-Deck-Presentation-6.jpg" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="2400" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Idaho has one of the most comprehensive abortion laws in the United States, effectively banning the procedure at all stages of pregnancy with narrow exceptions. The state's framework consists of multiple overlapping statutes, primarily enacted or triggered after the U.S. Supreme Court's 2022 decision in Dobbs v. Jackson Women's Health Organization, which overturned Roe v. [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2025 19:43:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Public Recommendations to Idaho's DOGE Task Force to Increase Government Efficiency</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/public-recommendations-to-idahos-doge-task-force-to-increase-government-efficiency/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/public-recommendations-to-idahos-doge-task-force-to-increase-government-efficiency/" rel="nofollow" title="Public Recommendations to Idaho&amp;#039;s DOGE Task Force to Increase Government Efficiency"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Article-Headers-2025-09-01T114655.975.png" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Dear Members of the Idaho DOGE Task Force,&amp;#160; At the request of members of this Task Force, we have attached our analysis and recommendations for the committee's consideration. Each proposed reduction, consolidation, or elimination falls within the committee's stated purpose and offers realistic options for waste reduction.&amp;#160; The Idaho DOGE Task Force is positioned to [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 18:06:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] API to AHSAA: Don’t Sideline School Choice Families – Follow the Law!</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/09/01/api-to-ahsaa-stop-penalizing-school-choice-students-and-follow-the-law/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On September 1st, Alabama families will receive another dose of relief at the checkout line. The state’s sales tax on groceries will drop from 3% to 2%, continuing a rollback that began in 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/09/01/api-to-ahsaa-stop-penalizing-school-choice-students-and-follow-the-law/"&gt;API to AHSAA: Don’t Sideline School Choice Families &amp;#8211; Follow the Law!&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 19:38:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] Beyond the Beach: Honoring the Dignity of Work</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/09/01/labor-day-honoring-the-dignity-of-work/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A free and prosperous society is built on a foundation of responsible, creative, and purposeful work. When government is limited and economic freedom is upheld, individuals are empowered to pursue their callings, provide for their families, and contribute to the common good. Labor Day, therefore, becomes a day to honor not just the physical act of labor, but the sacred dignity of work—the opportunity we have to use our gifts to create, serve, and build, all while reflecting the image of our Creator. It is a day to be grateful for the freedom to work and to be a part of a society where that freedom is protected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/09/01/labor-day-honoring-the-dignity-of-work/"&gt;Beyond the Beach: Honoring the Dignity of Work&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 19:46:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] From Jerome to your town: Time for every meeting on camera</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/from-jerome-to-your-town-time-for-every-meeting-on-camera</link><description>Think about that: a school board, funded by taxpayers, making decisions that affect families, students, and teachers—telling the press and the public to put their cameras away.</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 21:15:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Revenue-neutral law is helping; additional property tax reform is needed</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/revenue-neutral-helps-more-tax-reform-needed/</link><description>The Revenue-Neutral law that went into effect in 2021 is helping many Kansans, with nearly two-thirds of taxing entities deciding NOT to raise property taxes this year. It requires cities, counties, school districts, and other local taxing authorities to notify taxpayers if they want to collect more property tax revenue the following year, hold a [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 12:49:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Kim Reynolds is America’s ‘Iron Lady’ reflecting Margaret Thatcher’s spirit</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/https-www-desmoinesregister-com-story-opinion-columnists-iowa-view-2025-08-31-kim-reynolds-reflects-iron-lady-margaret-thatcher-spirit-85853542007-gnt-cfr1gca-catpgca-uirtruegca-eptiz116054p000250c000/</link><description>&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="80" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Des-Moines-Register.jpg" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;" width="300" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Kim Reynolds is America&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8216;Iron Lady&amp;#8217; reflecting Margaret Thatcher&amp;#8217;s spirit" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Des-Moines-Register.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/https-www-desmoinesregister-com-story-opinion-columnists-iowa-view-2025-08-31-kim-reynolds-reflects-iron-lady-margaret-thatcher-spirit-85853542007-gnt-cfr1gca-catpgca-uirtruegca-eptiz116054p000250c000/"&gt;Kim Reynolds is America&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8216;Iron Lady&amp;#8217; reflecting Margaret Thatcher&amp;#8217;s spirit&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 13:33:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] New federal school choice law is a historic breakthrough for children</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/new-federal-school-choice-law-is-a-historic-breakthrough-for-children</link><description>Note: This is a joint op-ed with Peter Murphy ( Invest in Education Coalition ). The old saying that states are the “laboratories of...</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 14:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Donor Privacy Heads to the Arizona Supreme Court</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/donor-privacy-heads-to-the-arizona-supreme-court/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Donors to non-profit organizations in Arizona have a target on their backs, all because of a 2022 state law that..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/donor-privacy-heads-to-the-arizona-supreme-court/"&gt;Donor Privacy Heads to the Arizona Supreme Court&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 16:49:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Mississippi's Progress and the Push for School Choice</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/mississippis-progress-and-the-push-for-school-choice/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This week, I’ll be traveling to Washington, D.C. talking about Mississippi’s remarkable progress, including our elimination of the income tax and how we might best advance school choice in our state. Mississippi is gaining national attention for our transformative public policies. Once seen as a perennial underdog, our state is now recognized as a leader in free-market [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/mississippis-progress-and-the-push-for-school-choice/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi&amp;#039;s Progress and the Push for School Choice&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 17:09:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Non-working adults concentrated in Georgia’s distressed communities</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/adults-not-working-in-georgia/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Many Georgia counties face high rates of non-working adults, fueling distress and limiting opportunities in struggling communities. See the percentages for your county. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/adults-not-working-in-georgia/"&gt;Non-working adults concentrated in Georgia’s distressed communities&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 18:51:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Attorney General Lynn Fitch: Breaking Barriers &amp; Defending Life</title><link>https://empowerms.org/attorney-general-lynn-fitch-breaking-barriers-defending-life/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Attorney General Lynn Fitch: Breaking Barriers &amp;#38; Defending Life  On this episode, host Grant Callen sits down with Mississippi’s 40th Attorney General Lynn Fitch. A Holly Springs native, General Fitch has 35 years in public and private legal service, made history as the state’s first female Attorney General, and earned national recognition for her leadership.&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/attorney-general-lynn-fitch-breaking-barriers-defending-life/"&gt;Attorney General Lynn Fitch: Breaking Barriers &amp; Defending Life &lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 20:00:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Marquette housing earmark is a bad pork deal</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/marquette-housing-earmark-is-a-bad-pork-deal</link><description>Let builders build</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Florida’s John Kirtley on School Choice</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/floridas-john-kirtley-on-school-choice/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In this week’s episode of The Learning Curve, co-hosts U-Arkansas Prof. Albert Cheng and American Federation for Children Senior Fellow Shaka Mitchell interview John Kirtley, Managing Partner and co-founder of Keswick Partners, and founder and Chairman of Step Up for Students, a nonprofit that manages Florida’s state-funded K-12 scholarship programs serving over half a million students. Kirtley shares his journey from the private sector into education reform in the late 1990s, and why business leaders must actively engage in shaping K-12 policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/floridas-john-kirtley-on-school-choice/"&gt;Florida&amp;#8217;s John Kirtley on School Choice&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 13:51:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Separate but Equitable at Portland Public Schools</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/education/separate-but-equitable-at-portland-public-schools/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By John A. Charles, Jr. In 1954 the U.S. Supreme Court ruled that...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/education/separate-but-equitable-at-portland-public-schools/"&gt;Separate but Equitable at Portland Public Schools&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 14:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] CALIFORNIA: New teachers relieved to hear the truth</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/california/california-new-teachers-relieved-to-hear-the-truth/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As I’ve done many times before, I explained that teachers have the right to opt out of the union and that thousands across the country have already done so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/california/california-new-teachers-relieved-to-hear-the-truth/" rel="nofollow"&gt;CALIFORNIA: New teachers relieved to hear the truth&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 14:39:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Dwellings outside residential zones could support housing demand</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/09/dwellings-outside-residential-zones-could-support-housing-demand/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Hawai‘i County Windward Planning Commission on September 4, 2025._____________ Sept. 4, 2025, 9 a.m.Hawai‘i County Council Chambers in Hilo To: Hawai‘i County Windward Planning Commission&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Louis Daniele III, Chair&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Chantel Perrin, Vice Chair From: Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Jonathan Helton, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/09/dwellings-outside-residential-zones-could-support-housing-demand/"&gt;Dwellings outside residential zones could support housing demand&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 14:39:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Allow home henneries as food and income source for residents</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/09/allow-home-henneries-as-food-and-income-source-for-residents/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Hawai‘i County Windward Planning Commission on September 4, 2025._____________ Sept. 4, 2025, 9 a.m.Hawai‘i County Council Chambers in Hilo To: Hawai‘i County Windward Planning Commission       Louis Daniele III, Chair       Chantel Perrin, Vice Chair From: Grassroot Institute of Hawaii            Jonathan Helton, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/09/allow-home-henneries-as-food-and-income-source-for-residents/"&gt;Allow home henneries as food and income source for residents&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 14:40:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] New Poll: Inflation, Economy, Taxes, and Crime Top Voter Concerns, Pennsylvanians Hold Shapiro Responsible for Budget Impasse</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/09/03/new-poll-inflation-economy-taxes-and-crime-top-voter-concerns-pennsylvanians-hold-shapiro-responsible-for-budget-impasse/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Harrisburg, Pa., September 3, 2025 — Fewer than 4-in-10 Pennsylvania voters believe the state is on the right track, according to new polling released today by the Commonwealth Foundation. Inflation, the economy, taxes, and crime top their list of concerns facing the state, with nearly two-thirds of Pennsylvanians saying economic conditions are worsening for them [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/09/03/new-poll-inflation-economy-taxes-and-crime-top-voter-concerns-pennsylvanians-hold-shapiro-responsible-for-budget-impasse/"&gt;New Poll: Inflation, Economy, Taxes, and Crime Top Voter Concerns, Pennsylvanians Hold Shapiro Responsible for Budget Impasse &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 15:24:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] A conversation on New Mexico’s health care provider shortage w/ RGF’s Paul Gessing &amp; Think New Mexico’s Fred Nathan</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/a-conversation-on-new-mexicos-health-care-provider-shortage-w-rgfs-paul-gessing-think-new-mexicos-fred-nathan/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Most New Mexicans are abundantly aware of the dire medical provider shortage facing our state. The Rio Grande Foundation has been researching and discussing solutions to this problem for several years. The same is true for Think New Mexico which is led by Fred Nathan. While we don&amp;#8217;t always agree with the approach of Think [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/a-conversation-on-new-mexicos-health-care-provider-shortage-w-rgfs-paul-gessing-think-new-mexicos-fred-nathan/"&gt;A conversation on New Mexico&amp;#8217;s health care provider shortage w/ RGF&amp;#8217;s Paul Gessing &amp;#038; Think New Mexico&amp;#8217;s Fred Nathan&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 15:42:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] “Superhero” Special Education Teacher Challenges Madison’s Race-Laden Scoring System</title><link>https://will-law.org/superhero-special-education-teacher-challenges-madisons-race-laden-scoring-system/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL has filed a complaint with the U.S. Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (“EEOC”) on behalf of Kally Bishop, a highly skilled special education teacher at Thoreau Elementary, a part of the Madison Metropolitan School District.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/superhero-special-education-teacher-challenges-madisons-race-laden-scoring-system/"&gt;“Superhero” Special Education Teacher Challenges Madison’s Race-Laden Scoring System&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 17:21:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] WASHINGTON: WFSE a net loser despite recruiting drive</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/washington/washington-wfse-a-net-loser-despite-recruiting-drive/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Washington Federation of State Employees (WFSE) recently hit the streets to recruit new members, but the results aren’t exactly something to brag about.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/washington/washington-wfse-a-net-loser-despite-recruiting-drive/" rel="nofollow"&gt;WASHINGTON: WFSE a net loser despite recruiting drive &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 18:28:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] The Gold Standard</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/the-gold-standard/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A recent post on substack authored by Dr. Ed Timmons caught our eye. This particular post highlighted rankings of universal recognition laws for occupational licenses around the country, and Nebraska met the &amp;#8220;Gold Standard&amp;#8221; as can be seen from the image below. This image is just one of many to be found in the most...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/the-gold-standard/" rel="nofollow"&gt;The Gold Standard&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 18:44:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Most Teachers Don’t Like Equitable Grading Practices Either</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/accountability/most-teachers-dont-like-equitable-grading-practices-either/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Rather than being viewed as accurate indicators of knowledge and skills, traditional grades are viewed by some as contributing to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/accountability/most-teachers-dont-like-equitable-grading-practices-either/"&gt;Most Teachers Don’t Like Equitable Grading Practices Either&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 19:19:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Fighting an Illegal Government Monopoly at the Arkansas Supreme Court</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/fighting-an-illegal-government-monopoly-at-the-arkansas-supreme-court/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When the local government banned Steven Hedrick from operating his small business in rural Arkansas, the Goldwater Institute took action,..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/fighting-an-illegal-government-monopoly-at-the-arkansas-supreme-court/"&gt;Fighting an Illegal Government Monopoly at the Arkansas Supreme Court&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 21:04:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Will the Sites Reservoir Ever Get Built?</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/will-the-sites-reservoir-ever-get-built/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=will-the-sites-reservoir-ever-get-built</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The short answer is no. Never. What is happening with the Sites Reservoir is a case study in why, if the people running California today were in charge in the 1950s and 1960s, the California Water Project would never have been built. This reservoir, approved by voters in 2014, could have been built by now....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/will-the-sites-reservoir-ever-get-built/"&gt;Will the Sites Reservoir Ever Get Built?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 22:40:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] Distinctions Between Social Justice and Biblical Justice</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/09/04/distinctions-between-social-justice-and-biblical-justice/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The use of governmental imposition to force social justice on its people is a path that leads to more government, less freedom, and deeper division. The true path forward can be found in a return to the principles of biblical justice—impartiality, righteousness, and individual responsibility. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/09/04/distinctions-between-social-justice-and-biblical-justice/"&gt;Distinctions Between Social Justice and Biblical Justice&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 06:49:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Defund the MEDC. Period.</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/defund-the-medc-period</link><description>Global Link fiasco isn’t an aberration</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] L.A. homeless counts fall before World Cup, Olympics</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/l-a-homeless-counts-fall-before-world-cup-olympics/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;According to the 2025 Greater Los Angeles Homeless Count from July, “For the second straight year, homelessness is down across Los Angeles County, falling 4% to 72,308. Homelessness also declined in the city of Los Angeles, falling by 3.4% to 43,699.” That contrasts with a 3% increase in California in 2024 and 18% for the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/l-a-homeless-counts-fall-before-world-cup-olympics/"&gt;L.A. homeless counts fall before World Cup, Olympics&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 10:00:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Public lands need protection and future flexibility</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/public-lands-need-protection-and-future-flexibility</link><description>Protecting public lands has become the rallying call this year for groups and individuals across the political spectrum. In June, when...</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 11:19:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Why Trump’s Deployment Of The National Guard In California Was Perfectly Legal</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/why-trumps-deployment-of-the-national-guard-in-california-was-perfectly-legal/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The administration argues, correctly, that the Posse Comitatus Act didn’t apply to President Trump’s deployment of the Guard to California. In a stunning display of judicial overreach, Senior U.S. District Judge Charles Breyer — a Clinton appointee and brother of retired liberal Supreme Court Justice Stephen Breyer — ruled this week that President Donald Trump...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/why-trumps-deployment-of-the-national-guard-in-california-was-perfectly-legal/"&gt;Why Trump’s Deployment Of The National Guard In California Was Perfectly Legal&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 12:20:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Prevent permitting delays and strain on DPP; reject Bill 56</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/09/prevent-permitting-delays-and-strain-on-dpp-reject-bill-56/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Honolulu City Council on September 3, 2025._____________ Sept. 3, 2025, 10 a.m.Honolulu Hale To: Honolulu City Council&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Tommy Waters, Chair&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Andria Tupola, Vice Chair From: Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Ted Kefalas, Director of Strategic Campaigns RE: Bill 56 (2025) — [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/09/prevent-permitting-delays-and-strain-on-dpp-reject-bill-56/"&gt;Prevent permitting delays and strain on DPP; reject Bill 56&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 15:27:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] The Progressive Government Union War on America</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/the-progressive-government-union-war-on-america/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=the-progressive-government-union-war-on-america</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Public sector unions constitute the bedrock of progressive power in the United States. The estimated total nationwide membership exceeds 7 million, or 32 percent of all public employees. This compares to an equal number of unionized employees in the private sector, 7 million, but that only represents 6 percent of private sector employees. The fact...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/the-progressive-government-union-war-on-america/"&gt;The Progressive Government Union War on America&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 15:49:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Fact Checking Claims on Enrollment Declines</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/fact-checking-claims-on-enrollment-declines/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=fact-checking-claims-on-enrollment-declines</link><description>Despite declining enrollment occurring all across the nation, recent news reports have claimed that the problem is specific to Tennessee because of the state's new Education Freedom Scholarships (EFS) program. Not only do these accusations wrongly place blame, many critics simply get the basics of the EFS program wrong. Let’s set the record straight.</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 16:04:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] SEIU 1000 negotiates pay raise that really isn’t</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/california/seiu-1000-negotiates-pay-raise-that-really-isnt/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;SEIU Local 1000 just cut a backroom deal with California Gov. Gavin Newsom that leaves state workers holding the bag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/california/seiu-1000-negotiates-pay-raise-that-really-isnt/" rel="nofollow"&gt;SEIU 1000 negotiates pay raise that really isn’t&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 16:14:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Spies in School: China, Others Stealing our Intellectual Property</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/spies-in-school-china-others-stealing-our-intellectual-property/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Texans were shocked when they learned of the foreign espionage scandal at Texas A&amp;#38;M. But now we have learned that the corruption at College Station was not a one-off event. A University of Texas researcher has been charged with espionage, attempting to steal sensitive, federally funded cancer research and smuggle it to China. The case...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/spies-in-school-china-others-stealing-our-intellectual-property/"&gt;Spies in School: China, Others Stealing our Intellectual Property&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 16:23:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Massachusetts Joins NYC and KC in Shifting Fees to Landlords</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/economy/massachusetts-joins-nyc-and-kc-in-shifting-fees-to-landlords/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Massachusetts lawmakers recently approved a measure requiring landlords—not tenants—to cover apartment broker fees, which often equal one month’s rent. The [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/economy/massachusetts-joins-nyc-and-kc-in-shifting-fees-to-landlords/"&gt;Massachusetts Joins NYC and KC in Shifting Fees to Landlords&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 17:01:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] ITR Foundation Wins National Award for Most Influential Research</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/itr-foundation-wins-national-award-for-most-influential-research/</link><description>&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="629" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/ITRF-SPN-2025-Award.jpg" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="ITR Foundation Wins National Award for Most Influential Research" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/ITRF-SPN-2025-Award-600x315.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iowans for Tax Relief Foundation (ITRF) is honored to announce that our work on the ITR Report Card was recognized with the Bob Williams Award for Most Influential Research at the State Policy Network’s Annual Meeting in New Orleans on August 27.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bob Williams Awards celebrate state-based think tanks that achieve exceptional results advancing free-market policy reforms. Named after Bob Williams—one of the conservative movement’s most respected policy leaders—the awards are given annually to recognize research and achievements that not only make a difference locally, but also serve as models for the nation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/itr-foundation-wins-national-award-for-most-influential-research/"&gt;ITR Foundation Wins National Award for Most Influential Research&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 19:48:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] The Economic Development Paradigm – City-Created Problems and Taxpayer-Funded Fixes</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/taxpayer-funded-fixes/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=taxpayer-funded-fixes</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Economic development departments are often celebrated as promoters of prosperity and local employment. Each year, local governments spend tens of billions of dollars on economic development incentives—tax abatements, fee waivers, and direct subsidies—intended to lure private investment. Cities across the nation tout their ability to entice marquee employers, generate buzz with ribbon-cuttings, and implement incentive...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/taxpayer-funded-fixes/"&gt;The Economic Development Paradigm – City-Created Problems and Taxpayer-Funded Fixes&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 20:11:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] A new concern in Wisconsin: young slouches</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/a-new-concern-in-wisconsin-young-slouches/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Business leaders and educators are concerned about the future of the workforce in the Badger State — and debating whether many young Wisconsinites are just lazy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/a-new-concern-in-wisconsin-young-slouches/"&gt;A new concern in Wisconsin: young slouches&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 20:20:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] The hills are alive with the, well, approval of leftist politicians</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/wisconsin-rights-of-nature-law/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;State Rep. Joy Goeben and state Sen. Steve Nass have introduced a bill that would prohibit local governments from enacting a “rights of nature” ordinance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/wisconsin-rights-of-nature-law/"&gt;The hills are alive with the, well, approval of leftist politicians&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 20:45:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] New Hampshire rated the least corrupt state</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/09/new-hampshire-rated-the-least-corrupt-state/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;America’s freest state has just been rated its least corrupt too. Using U.S. Department of Justice data on corruption convictions in all 94 federal judicial districts from 2003-2024, the Cato Institute calculated the rate of corruption convictions per 10,000 government employees, then recently ranked states by their conviction rates. New Hampshire ranked dead last, with [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/09/new-hampshire-rated-the-least-corrupt-state/"&gt;New Hampshire rated the least corrupt state&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 00:17:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Violent crime lessons from D.C., as it faces spike in carjackings</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/violent-crime-lessons-from-d-c-as-it-faces-spike-in-carjackings/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Violent crime lessons from D.C., as it faces spike in carjackings Jeremy Lott &amp;#124; September 5, 2025 Editor’s Note: This is the first of two columns addressing crime in Washington, D.C. This one addresses the problem that has grown over the first half of this decade. The next one will address President Donald Trump’s extraordinary [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/violent-crime-lessons-from-d-c-as-it-faces-spike-in-carjackings/"&gt;Violent crime lessons from D.C., as it faces spike in carjackings&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 09:24:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Atlantic shines light on Democrats’ lawfare strategy</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/atlantic-shines-light-on-democrats-lawfare-strategy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Joy Pullmann writes for the Federalist about recent publicity for Democrats’ legal campaign against the Trump administration. Democrat Party leaders invited an Atlantic reporter to tell the world their current political strategy is to use U.S. courts to reject the consequences of losing a presidential election. “The Anti-Trump Strategy That’s Actually Working,” say Michael Scherer’s...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/atlantic-shines-light-on-democrats-lawfare-strategy/"&gt;Atlantic shines light on Democrats’ lawfare strategy&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 09:36:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] New data paint poor picture of Biden economy</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/new-data-paint-poor-picture-of-biden-economy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Stephen Moore writes for the New York Post about important new economic data. One of the bitter fruits of President Joe Biden’s single term in office is this: An administration obsessed with policies designed to reduce income inequality actually widened the gap between rich and poor. That’s the conclusion from Unleash Prosperity’s advance analysis of...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/new-data-paint-poor-picture-of-biden-economy/"&gt;New data paint poor picture of Biden economy&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 09:39:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Deal points toward more conservative CBS News</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/deal-points-toward-more-conservative-cbs-news/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Sharon Waxman and Adam Chitwood write for The Wrap about a significant development within the legacy media. Paramount is on the verge of acquiring Bari Weiss’ right-leaning Free Press news organization, with Weiss set for a top role in running CBS News, TheWrap has learned. The deal, which is being finalized by Paramount’s lawyers and...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/deal-points-toward-more-conservative-cbs-news/"&gt;Deal points toward more conservative CBS News&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 09:42:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] ‘Everyone already agrees that tariffs are bad, and everyone agrees that we should do something about national debt’</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/podcasts/the-overton-window/dave-hebert-on-why-many-voters-believe-economists-have-conned-the-american-people</link><description>Dave Hebert on why many voters believe economists have conned the American people</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Research Note: Nebraska’s Neighboring States’ conditional use permitting processes</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/research-note-nebraskas-neighboring-states-conditional-use-permitting-processes/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;[Note: This is the fifth in a series of Research Notes by Platte’s intern, focusing on county zoning and agriculture issues. The final (sixth) note will include discussion of a bill currently before the Legislature.] In addition to Iowa, Nebraska’s other neighboring states have faced zoning challenges related to permitting new livestock operations. While Iowa...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/research-note-nebraskas-neighboring-states-conditional-use-permitting-processes/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Research Note: Nebraska&amp;#8217;s Neighboring States&amp;#8217; conditional use permitting processes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 12:34:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Winners &amp; Losers: Texas Tech Wins Big — And Be Grateful You Don’t Live in NYC</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/winners-losers-texas-tech-wins-big-and-be-grateful-you-dont-live-in-nyc/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Every Friday morning, I join the Cardle &amp;#38; Woolley Show on 1370 Talk Radio in Austin to announce the week’s Winners &amp;#38; Losers. Many dreams died last week with Texas’ big loss on the opening day of college football, and the list got longer when the Second Called Special Session of the Texas Legislature adjourned...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/winners-losers-texas-tech-wins-big-and-be-grateful-you-dont-live-in-nyc/"&gt;Winners &amp; Losers: Texas Tech Wins Big — And Be Grateful You Don’t Live in NYC&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 15:00:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Chicago Teachers Union invests nearly $1.8M, but 2-in-5 are lawmakers from outside Chicago</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/chicago-teachers-union-invests-nearly-1-8m-but-2-in-5-are-lawmakers-from-outside-chicago/</link><description>The Chicago Teachers Union is more political machine than labor union, putting nearly $1.8 million into the campaigns of 84 of 177 current lawmakers since 2010. But it may be losing its hold on Springfield.</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 15:34:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] School Choice Improves Public School Performance</title><link>https://empowerms.org/school-choice-improves-public-school-performance/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#8217;s an argument going around that deserves a response: The Parents’ Campaign has repeatedly claimed that Mississippi is gaining academically while the &amp;#8220;top choice states&amp;#8221; plummeted. This is naive, lacking any academic rigor, and a dishonest interpretation of the data.   First, the phrase &amp;#8220;top choice states&amp;#8221; is misleading. Half the states in their top 10&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/school-choice-improves-public-school-performance/"&gt;School Choice Improves Public School Performance&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 15:41:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Thanks to Obamacare, Insurance Fraud Irresistible</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/thanks-to-obamacare-insurance-fraud-irresistible/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Something strange is afoot on the Obamacare exchanges. According to a new study by the Paragon Health Institute, an astounding number of patients with premium-free exchange plans filed no claims whatsoever last year. It&amp;#8217;s possible that none of these individuals required medical care in 2024. Read the op-ed here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/thanks-to-obamacare-insurance-fraud-irresistible/"&gt;Thanks to Obamacare, Insurance Fraud Irresistible&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 15:42:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Packed house as MPCA pits mining against… wild rice?</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/packed-house-as-mpca-pits-mining-against-wild-rice/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Duluth News Tribune reported yesterday that a crowd of miners packed the house at the Iron Trail Motors Event Center in Virginia this week. The miners warned that the Minnesota Pollution Control Agency — which has preliminarily denied a water permit variance for U.S. Steel’s Keetac iron ore mine — would lead to closures...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/packed-house-as-mpca-pits-mining-against-wild-rice/"&gt;Packed house as MPCA pits mining against… wild rice?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 15:53:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] First Principles Series: The Plight of Property Taxes</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/first-principles-series-the-plight-of-property-taxes/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=first-principles-series-the-plight-of-property-taxes</link><description>Tennessee joins Hawaii, Vermont, and New Hampshire as the outliers where property taxes can go up without limit.</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 16:02:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Can your family get federal school choice grants? Likely, if Pritzker OKs</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/can-your-family-get-federal-school-choice-grants-likely-if-pritzker-oks/</link><description>Use our calculator to see if your family is eligible to receive a school choice grant from the Educational Choice for Children Act. Then, sign the petition to tell Gov. J.B. Pritzker to let Illinois join the federal program.</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 16:35:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] From Waterloo to Keokuk: Where Property Taxes Hit Hardest in Iowa</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/from-waterloo-to-keokuk-where-property-taxes-hit-hardest-in-iowa/</link><description>&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="630" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/effective-property-tax-rates.jpg" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="From Waterloo to Keokuk: Where Property Taxes Hit Hardest in Iowa" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/effective-property-tax-rates-600x315.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Property taxes in Iowa are unpredictable and burdensome, driven by many layers of government that often leave homeowners frustrated as bills rise faster than their ability to pay.&lt;br /&gt;
Effective property tax rates vary widely across the state, with homeowners in places like Eldridge and Le Mars paying under 1.3%, while residents in Waterloo and Keokuk face rates above 2%.&lt;br /&gt;
 Without meaningful reform to limit local government spending, these disparities and rising bills will continue, making property tax relief one of the most pressing issues for Iowa families and businesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/from-waterloo-to-keokuk-where-property-taxes-hit-hardest-in-iowa/"&gt;From Waterloo to Keokuk: Where Property Taxes Hit Hardest in Iowa&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 16:59:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] SNAP Back to Reality</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/welfare/snap-back-to-reality/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Medicaid wasn’t the only welfare program that received significant reforms in the One Big Beautiful Bill (OBBB). The Supplemental Nutrition [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/welfare/snap-back-to-reality/"&gt;SNAP Back to Reality&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 17:54:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Protected: How Much Does Private School Really Cost in Mississippi?</title><link>https://empowerms.org/how-much-does-private-school-really-cost-in-mississippi/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;There is no excerpt because this is a protected post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/how-much-does-private-school-really-cost-in-mississippi/"&gt;Protected: How Much Does Private School Really Cost in Mississippi? &lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 18:27:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] A Swing and a Miss(issippi): An Alternative to Mississippi’s Ill-Fated Age Verification Legislation</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/a-swing-and-a-mississippi-an-alternative-to-mississippis-ill-fated-age-verification-legislation/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In the last few years, state legislatures across the nation have introduced age verification measures. While the nuances of the age verification mandates are mixed, and some never progress past introduction, a lengthy legal battle is standard. Mississippi’s social media age verification law, House Bill (HB) 1126 of its 2024 Regular Session, is one of...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/a-swing-and-a-mississippi-an-alternative-to-mississippis-ill-fated-age-verification-legislation/"&gt;A Swing and a Miss(issippi): An Alternative to Mississippi’s Ill-Fated Age Verification Legislation&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 19:09:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Week in Review: Free Speech Showdown</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-free-speech-showdown/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;No one should be subject to violent retaliation just for supporting causes they believe in. But across the country, Americans..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-free-speech-showdown/"&gt;Week in Review: Free Speech Showdown&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 19:49:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Minnesota Man of the week</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/minnesota-man-of-the-week/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Nicholas Lopez-Juarez, age 28, billed out of St. James, then St. Peter, then Melrose, is our Minnesota Man of the week. A Guatemalan national, Lopez has been charged with one federal felony count of illegal re-entry of a previously deported alien. Prosecutors document an entry into America by Lopez in 2012. In 2017, he recorded...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/minnesota-man-of-the-week/"&gt;Minnesota Man of the week&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 20:29:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Southwestern Illinois taxpayers hand airport $160M to keep it open</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/southwestern-illinois-taxpayers-hand-airport-160m-to-keep-it-open/</link><description>MidAmerica St. Louis Airport has been a drain on taxpayers since it opened in 1995, requiring money from other county funds to keep it open. That total jumped last year to $14.83 million, bringing total subsidies since 2002 to $160 million.</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 21:07:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Minnesota’s Economic News — W/E 9/5/25</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/minnesotas-economic-news-w-e-9-5-25/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;State and local taxes and spending KTTC: Digging Deeper: Rochester’s state aid shortfalls lead to rising taxes Ely Echo: County tax increase coming Duluth News Tribune: St. Louis County Board prepares to boost levy limit as costs climb Duluth News Tribune: Pro/Con: Powerful and political, public unions drive up taxes Rochester Post Bulletin: Rochester council...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/minnesotas-economic-news-w-e-9-5-25/"&gt;Minnesota’s Economic News — W/E 9/5/25&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 12:40:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/09/the-outstater-287/</link><description>&amp;#8216;Chicago Is Indiana&amp;#8217;s Fault&amp;#8217; iT CAN BE HOPED that Mayor Brandon Johnson, who this week blamed Indiana for Chicago crime, will be thrown from office the next election cycle. I have my doubts, though, realizing that his message of envy and resentment is a powerful one with a large constituency. Envy, please know, is a&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/09/the-outstater-287/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 20:55:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>