<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>State-Policy Think-Tank Digest</title><link>https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml</link><description>Latest posts from free-market policy institutes across the U.S.</description><atom:link href="https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 16:03:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] DAILY CALLER: Don’t California-Ize The New Jersey Independent Workforce</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/08/daily-caller-dont-california-ize-the-new-jersey-independent-workforce/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Rosemary Becchi, President and Founder of NJPI, co-authored an op-ed in The Daily Caller with Patrice Onwuka, Director of the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/08/daily-caller-dont-california-ize-the-new-jersey-independent-workforce/"&gt;DAILY CALLER: Don’t California-Ize The New Jersey Independent Workforce&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 17:01:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Fate of Dominion Gas Plant Depends On Which Experts, Models the SCC Believes</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/fate-of-dominion-gas-plant-depends-on-which-experts-models-the-scc-believes/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="371" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/IMG_3006.png" width="737" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The State Corporation Commission’s (SCC) decision on whether Dominion Energy can build a new natural gas-fired power plant will depend on which expert or set of experts it believes, and which of the many computer models that dominate the testimony it judges best predict Virginia’s energy future. Dominion has filed testimony to the SCC from [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/fate-of-dominion-gas-plant-depends-on-which-experts-models-the-scc-believes/"&gt;Fate of Dominion Gas Plant Depends On Which Experts, Models the SCC Believes &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 02:15:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] First Statewide Poll Shows Marsha Blackburn as Clear Frontrunner Over John Rose in GOP Primary for Governor</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/blackburn-rose-beaconpoll/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=blackburn-rose-beaconpoll</link><description>In light of Senator Marsha Blackburn&amp;#8217;s recent announcement that she plans to run for governor of Tennessee, Beacon is releasing the poll results of the Republican gubernatorial primary a few days early. In the field before Senator Blackburn’s official announcement, the poll asked Tennesseans who they would support in the 2025 GOP primary for governor, Senator...</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 13:00:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] The Mississippi Center for Public Policy welcomes new Chief Development Officer</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/the-mississippi-center-for-public-policy-welcomes-new-chief-development-officer/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Jackson, MS&amp;#160;— The Mississippi Center for Public Policy (MCPP) is pleased to announce the addition of Richard Wilson as its new Chief Development Officer. With a distinguished background in campaign management, government affairs, and nonprofit fundraising, Wilson brings a wealth of experience and a proven track record of results-driven leadership to MCPP. “We are thrilled [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/the-mississippi-center-for-public-policy-welcomes-new-chief-development-officer/" rel="nofollow"&gt;The Mississippi Center for Public Policy welcomes new Chief Development Officer&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 18:26:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Competition in education is an opportunity, not a crisis</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/08/competition-in-education-is-an-opportunity-not-a-crisis/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;There’s been a bit of a media freakout this week about the growing popularity of school choice programs nationwide.  The Children’s Scholarship Fund-NH confirmed this week that the Education Freedom Account program hit its 2025-26 enrollment cap of 10,000 students in early August.   “Record number of students matched with their preferred form of education,” [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/08/competition-in-education-is-an-opportunity-not-a-crisis/"&gt;Competition in education is an opportunity, not a crisis&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 16:56:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Welcome Our New Director of Outreach</title><link>https://empowerms.org/welcome-our-new-director-of-outreach/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;We’re excited to welcome Ashley Geen to the Empower Mississippi team as our new Outreach Director. In this role, Ashley will lead our efforts to connect with individuals most impacted by public policy in education, work, and criminal justice. Her work will focus on elevating community voices and ensuring those directly affected have a platform&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/welcome-our-new-director-of-outreach/"&gt;Welcome Our New Director of Outreach&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 01:42:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Spanberger Proposal Would Undermine Local Economic Growth</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/spanberger-proposal-would-undermine-local-economic-growth/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="598" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/Spanberger.jpg" width="1139" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Democratic gubernatorial candidate Abigail Spanberger wants voters to believe she’s a moderate. That’s understandable.&amp;#160; At a time when the Democratic Party’s favorability is at 33 percent and with an avowed socialist as the party’s nominee in the most highly visible election in the nation, the smart money is for Democrats in Virginia to run far [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/spanberger-proposal-would-undermine-local-economic-growth/"&gt;Spanberger Proposal Would Undermine Local Economic Growth&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 02:03:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] August 2025 Beacon Poll Results</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/august-2025-beacon-poll-results/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=august-2025-beacon-poll-results</link><description>A majority of Tennesseans, 56% of voters, believe the cap on Education Freedom Scholarships should be lifted from where it currently sits at 20,000 so that all eligible families who applied this year can use the program, while 30% of Tennesseans disagree and believe the cap should remain where it is. Polling has shown consistent support...</description><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 12:45:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] WTOK looks at what School Choice might mean for Mississippi</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/wtok-looks-at-what-school-choice-might-mean-for-mississippi/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I’m thrilled to share that momentum for School Choice in Mississippi is growing!&amp;#160;Governor Tate Reeves, Speaker Jason White, and even the White House are championing this transformative opportunity to empower parents and enhance education for our children. This week, WTOK TV aired an in-depth segment exploring how School Choice could benefit families across our state.&amp;#160;I [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/wtok-looks-at-what-school-choice-might-mean-for-mississippi/" rel="nofollow"&gt;WTOK looks at what School Choice might mean for Mississippi&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 16:08:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Who protects the protectors? The harsh reality for Kansas prison staff</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/kansas/who-protects-the-protectors/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Americans working in the Department of Corrections (DOC) are overworked, understaffed and, simply put, underrepresented. Correction Officers (COs) and other DOC employees are often represented by unions that include a wide range of state employees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/kansas/who-protects-the-protectors/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Who protects the protectors? The harsh reality for Kansas prison staff&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 16:27:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Texas Pursues Property Tax Reforms in Special Session</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/texas-pursues-property-tax-reforms-in-special-session/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Texas Governor Greg Abbott called lawmakers back for a special session to address Texas’ property tax burden. In his special session proclamation, Abbott has asked lawmakers to focus on two complementary items. The first is allocating more state money to reduce property taxes, and the second is to impose more strict spending restraints on local...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/texas-pursues-property-tax-reforms-in-special-session/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Texas Pursues Property Tax Reforms in Special Session&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 19:10:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] What to know about education in Georgia as students go back to school</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/what-to-know-about-education-in-georgia/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As August ushers in a new school year in Georgia, nearly two million students are headed back to our states 2,300 public schools. How are Georgia schools doing when it comes to preparing kids for work and life? Here's a look at some key measures. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/what-to-know-about-education-in-georgia/"&gt;What to know about education in Georgia as students go back to school&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 22:26:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] Pa. Senate Passes Budget Protecting Taxpayers, as Shapiro, House Democrats Continue Gridlock</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/08/12/pa-senate-passes-budget-protecting-taxpayers-as-shapiro-house-democrats-continue-gridlock/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Harrisburg, Pa., August 12, 2025&amp;#160;— Today, the Pennsylvania Senate is advancing a spending bill that provides the clearest path forward in months toward a sustainable state budget. The commonwealth is now well into the second month of a protracted impasse, operating without a state budget in place. Despite Gov. Josh Shapiro declaring in June that [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/08/12/pa-senate-passes-budget-protecting-taxpayers-as-shapiro-house-democrats-continue-gridlock/"&gt;Pa. Senate Passes Budget Protecting Taxpayers, as Shapiro, House Democrats Continue Gridlock&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 23:11:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Nebraska’s Top Property Tax Targets</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/nebraskas-top-property-tax-targets/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Property tax relief is always top of the agenda in Lincoln, as Nebraskans struggle under the weight of one of the nation’s heaviest property tax burdens. Nebraska should target two taxes to take off the rolls, and two technical changes to restructure the property tax system to deliver better relief.   Currently, Nebraska puts $1 billion...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/nebraskas-top-property-tax-targets/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Nebraska’s Top Property Tax Targets&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 13:50:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Get to Know Kathryn Beale, Beacon’s New Director of Development</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/get-to-know-kat-beale-beacons-new-director-of-development/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=get-to-know-kat-beale-beacons-new-director-of-development</link><description>Tell us about you—where you’re from, any fun facts about yourself, and where you spent your career prior to Beacon. I’m originally from Benton, Kentucky, a small town in the very western corner of the Bluegrass State. But, important to my upbringing, I am not a Wildcat! I spent four years in Nashville at Lipscomb...</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 15:13:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] Justin Bogie: Alabama’s grocery tax cut is a win – but lawmakers should finish the job</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/08/14/justin-bogie-alabamas-grocery-tax-cut-is-a-win-but-lawmakers-should-finish-the-job/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On September 1st, Alabama families will receive another dose of relief at the checkout line. The state’s sales tax on groceries will drop from 3% to 2%, continuing a rollback that began in 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/08/14/justin-bogie-alabamas-grocery-tax-cut-is-a-win-but-lawmakers-should-finish-the-job/"&gt;Justin Bogie: Alabama’s grocery tax cut is a win – but lawmakers should finish the job&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 17:41:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] New York’s Hospital Quality Remains Among the Worst in the U.S.</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/new-yorks-hospital-quality-remains-among-the-worst-in-the-u-s/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The federal government recently updated its hospital quality ratings, and New York once again fell near the bottom. Among 132....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/new-yorks-hospital-quality-remains-among-the-worst-in-the-u-s/"&gt;New York&amp;#8217;s Hospital Quality Remains Among the Worst in the U.S.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 18:44:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] NJ ED REPORT: Amplifying Student Voices: Advocating for Younger and More Inclusive Representation in IEP Meetings</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/08/nj-ed-report-amplifying-student-voices-advocating-for-younger-and-more-inclusive-representation-in-iep-meetings/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;NJPI policy research intern David Fishkin, a Political Science student at Rutgers University – New Brunswick, has published an op-ed [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/08/nj-ed-report-amplifying-student-voices-advocating-for-younger-and-more-inclusive-representation-in-iep-meetings/"&gt;NJ ED REPORT: Amplifying Student Voices: Advocating for Younger and More Inclusive Representation in IEP Meetings&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 18:52:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] New, Flawed Rating Changes Cover Up for Underperforming Schools, Again</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/new-flawed-rating-changes-cover-up-for-underperforming-schools-again/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New, Flawed Rating Changes Cover Up for Underperforming Schools, Again IRG uncovers changes that hide low-performing districts from parents Delafield, Wis. — The Institute for Reforming Government (IRG) issued a statement after the Wisconsin DPI again changed its 1–5 star school ratings at an August 12–14 Madison meeting, leaving parents unclear on local school performance. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/new-flawed-rating-changes-cover-up-for-underperforming-schools-again/"&gt;New, Flawed Rating Changes Cover Up for Underperforming Schools, Again&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 16:17:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] State Board of Ed votes to reduce proficiency standards; legislators should implement a different state assessment</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/state-board-of-ed-reduces-proficiency-standards/</link><description>The Kansas State Board of Education voted 7-3 this week to accept new cut scores for determining proficiency levels on the state assessment test, setting the stage for the Kansas Legislature to hopefully halt the imposition of less rigorous performance standards. More on that shortly after a brief recap of the fraud being perpetrated on [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 18:03:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] State financial inputs aren’t the measure of a university system</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/08/state-financial-inputs-arent-the-measure-of-a-university-system/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;How do you measure the success of a business? You might look at financial measures such as profits, dividends or share price, industry dominance such as market share, or how well it achieves its mission. A law firm could measure success in client wins, a sports team in championships.  What do all of those measures [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/08/state-financial-inputs-arent-the-measure-of-a-university-system/"&gt;State financial inputs aren&amp;#8217;t the measure of a university system&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 20:17:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] Albuquerque Mayoral candidate information: surveys and conversations</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/albuquerque-mayoral-candidate-information-surveys-and-conversations/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;There are seven candidates on the ballot this fall for mayor of Albuquerque. The Rio Grande Foundation invited all of them to complete candidate surveys and come on our podcast, Tipping Point New Mexico. The election is Tuesday, November 4 (with a runoff likely to follow). In alphabetical order by last name here are the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/albuquerque-mayoral-candidate-information-surveys-and-conversations/"&gt;Albuquerque Mayoral candidate information: surveys and conversations&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 15:16:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Shenna Bellows’ Response to DOJ Misses the Mark on Election Law</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/shenna-bellows-response-to-doj-misses-the-mark-on-election-law/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier this month, U.S. Department of Justice officials requested an electronic copy of Maine’s statewide voter registration list under the National Voter Registration Act (NVRA). In her official reply, Secretary of State Shenna Bellows rejected the request, citing state law and concerns about personal information. Unfortunately, her memo misstates constitutional authority, misapplies case law, misinterprets [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/shenna-bellows-response-to-doj-misses-the-mark-on-election-law/"&gt;Shenna Bellows’ Response to DOJ Misses the Mark on Election Law&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 16:52:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] School Choice is Coming to Mississippi!</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/school-choice-is-coming-to-mississippi/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;What would it take for Mississippi to embrace School Choice?&amp;#160;How can we join our neighboring states in empowering families to control their child's share of the education budget? For School Choice to happen, we would need to see several steps.&amp;#160; &amp;#160;&amp;#160;Number one, we would need a committed Governor, ready to invest his political capital in [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/school-choice-is-coming-to-mississippi/" rel="nofollow"&gt;School Choice is Coming to Mississippi!&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 17:23:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Rifreedom] Center Cosigns Letter Supporting Seafreeze Petition to Suspend VINEYARD WIND Construction</title><link>https://rifreedom.org/2025/08/center-cosigns-letter-supporting-seafreeze-petition-to-suspend-vineyard-wind-construction/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Today, CEO for the Rhode Island Center for Freedom &amp;#038; Prosperity, Mike Stenhouse, co-signed a letter, along with national energy expert, G. Allen Brooks, requesting Doug Brugum, Secretary of the US Department Of the Interior (DOI), and other federal officials to accept the formal petition previously filed Seafreeze Inc (and others) that calls upon the government to immediately suspend "further construction and energy generation activity" of the near-completed Vineyard Wind off-shore wind project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org/2025/08/center-cosigns-letter-supporting-seafreeze-petition-to-suspend-vineyard-wind-construction/"&gt;Center Cosigns Letter Supporting Seafreeze Petition to Suspend VINEYARD WIND Construction&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org"&gt;RI Center for Freedom and Prosperity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 17:38:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Florida’s Election Reform Sets the Standard Nationwide</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/floridas-election-reform-sets-the-standard-nationwide/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE August 19, 2025 CONTACT Logan Elizabeth Padgett 850-386-3131 Florida’s Election Reform Sets the Standard Nationwide...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/floridas-election-reform-sets-the-standard-nationwide/"&gt;Florida’s Election Reform Sets the Standard Nationwide &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 04:01:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Florida: The Gold Standard in Elections Administration From Bush v. Gore to Present 2000-2025</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/florida-the-gold-standard-in-elections-administration-from-bush-v-gore-to-present-2000-2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Ben Gibson — Senior Fellow, The James Madison Institute Doug Wheeler — Director, George Gibbs Center for Economic...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/florida-the-gold-standard-in-elections-administration-from-bush-v-gore-to-present-2000-2025/"&gt;Florida: The Gold Standard in Elections Administration From Bush v. Gore to Present 2000-2025&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 04:01:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] What’s at stake in Albuquerque’s City Elections?</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/whats-at-stake-in-albuquerques-city-elections/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Paul recently sat down with Diane Kinderwater for an episode of &amp;#8220;Issues and Answers&amp;#8221; on KCHF TV. The show airs statewide and can be streamed live right here. In a recent conversation Paul had a chance to discuss what&amp;#8217;s at stake in the City of Albuquerque elections this fall. We discuss crime, homelessness, the economy, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/whats-at-stake-in-albuquerques-city-elections/"&gt;What&amp;#8217;s at stake in Albuquerque&amp;#8217;s City Elections?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 19:34:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Nebraska’s State Funding for K-12 Education Has Doubled Since 2020</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/nebraskas-state-funding-for-k-12-education-has-doubled-since-2020/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Nebraska’s education funding has historically been heavily weighted on the property tax, but that is beginning to change. Through new sources of funding and property tax offsets, the implicit state funding of education is growing rapidly.  Over the last decade, state aid through the TEEOSA formula has increased by $200 million. Meanwhile, property tax funding...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/nebraskas-state-funding-for-k-12-education-has-doubled-since-2020/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Nebraska’s State Funding for K-12 Education Has Doubled Since 2020 &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 19:56:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Deficits on the horizon as state spending explodes</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/state-spending-explodes-deficits/</link><description>How do you go from having a $3 billion budget surplus and stable tax revenue to broke in just a few years? By repeatedly spending more than you take in. General Fund spending has pretty much been out of control since 2018, the year after the Legislature passed the largest tax increase in state history. [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 20:51:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] WASHINGTON: Helping workers gain independence in record numbers</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/washington-helping-workers-gain-independence-in-record-numbers/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;During the month we were celebrating this nation’s 249 years of independence, the Freedom Foundation helped free well over 500 public employees from union tyranny in the state named for its first president.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/washington-helping-workers-gain-independence-in-record-numbers/" rel="nofollow"&gt;WASHINGTON: Helping workers gain independence in record numbers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 21:45:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Mike Hurst: School Choice Showdown</title><link>https://empowerms.org/mike-hurst-school-choice-showdown/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Mike Hurst: School Choice Showdown With Speaker Jason White and Governor Tate Reeves signaling school choice as the top priority for the 2026 legislative session, momentum is building—but so is the opposition. On this episode, host Grant Callen sits down with the Chairman of the Mississippi Republican Party for a deep dive into the heated&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/mike-hurst-school-choice-showdown/"&gt;Mike Hurst: School Choice Showdown&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 01:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] The Tapeworm Eating ODOT’s Record Gas Tax Revenue</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/tax-and-budget/simple-solutions-for-the-odot-funding-crisis/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By John A. Charles, Jr. Governor Tina Kotek has called a special session...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/tax-and-budget/simple-solutions-for-the-odot-funding-crisis/"&gt;The Tapeworm Eating ODOT’s Record Gas Tax Revenue&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 14:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Banking on Freedom: Executive Order Takes Aim at Reputational Debanking</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/tax-budget/banking-on-freedom-executive-order-takes-aim-at-reputational-debanking/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The free market necessitates voluntary exchange, free from government coercion. Mutual cooperation through this socio-economic structure once propelled America from a fledgling nation into a global leader in innovation and prosperity. However, in recent years, government-driven debanking has undermined this system—cutting off individuals and businesses from basic financial services based on subjective judgments about their...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/tax-budget/banking-on-freedom-executive-order-takes-aim-at-reputational-debanking/"&gt;Banking on Freedom: Executive Order Takes Aim at Reputational Debanking&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 14:50:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cardinalinstitute] West Virginia’s Certificate of Need Laws Are Failing You</title><link>https://cardinalinstitute.com/west-virginias-certificate-of-need-laws-are-failing-you/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;West Virginia’s Certificate of Need Laws Are Failing You The West Virginia Hospital Association’s recent op-ed defending West Virginia’s Certificate of Need (CON) laws is a masterclass in elite protectionism, dressed in concern, framed as a noble stand for community health. Make no mistake—the heart of the piece is about hospital bottom lines rather than how [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com/west-virginias-certificate-of-need-laws-are-failing-you/"&gt;West Virginia’s Certificate of Need Laws Are Failing You&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com"&gt;Cardinal Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 16:22:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] NEW YORK: Opt-outs up by 63 percent</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/new-york-opt-outs-up-by-63-percent/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Public employees in New York are walking away from their unions at record speed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/new-york-opt-outs-up-by-63-percent/" rel="nofollow"&gt;NEW YORK: Opt-outs up by 63 percent&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 17:27:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Corrected: As Math and Reading Proficiency Went Up, ‘Cut Scores’ Went Down</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/as-math-and-reading-proficiency-went-up-cut-scores-went-down/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;(Corrected on Aug. 27: The original version of this post inappropriately combined &amp;#8220;scale scores&amp;#8221; calculated by the Albany Times Union....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/as-math-and-reading-proficiency-went-up-cut-scores-went-down/"&gt;Corrected: As Math and Reading Proficiency Went Up, &amp;#8216;Cut Scores&amp;#8217; Went Down&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 13:46:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Colorado’s AI Catastrophe: A Cautionary Tale</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/colorados-ai-catastrophe-a-cautionary-tale/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On May 27, 2024, Colorado became the unfortunate pioneer in a troubling new frontier of government overreach. The...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/colorados-ai-catastrophe-a-cautionary-tale/"&gt;Colorado&amp;#8217;s AI Catastrophe: A Cautionary Tale&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 15:20:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] School Choice is Expanding like Never Before—Now Comes the Real Test</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/news/school-choice-is-expanding-like-never-before-now-comes-the-real-test/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;School choice is sometimes sold as a cure-all for underperforming public schools, other times it is deemed ineffective and a siphon of public resources. Both can be true, but this debate misses the point: school choice is not a guarantor of student success, nor was it ever intended to be. Its purpose is to provide choices, and most agree that choice is good. Not all choices will be good, to be sure. Indeed, there are poor-performing charter and private schools, just as there are ineffective district schools. When systems with school choice features fail, we ought to blame and reform the choices—they are clearly of poor quality—not ban the freedom to choose. It is grossly undemocratic to suggest otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/news/school-choice-is-expanding-like-never-before-now-comes-the-real-test/"&gt;School Choice is Expanding like Never Before—Now Comes the Real Test&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 16:05:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] In child care, as in housing, maybe the government’s doing a bit too much?</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/08/in-child-care-as-in-housing-maybe-the-governments-doing-a-bit-too-much/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Surging child care prices have grabbed the media’s attention here in New Hampshire, and rightly so. The price of full-time care in a licensed center “jumped 48 percent between 2013 and 2023,” landing at nearly $32,000 a year, according to an analysis last year by the Carsey School of Public Policy at UNH.   Child [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/08/in-child-care-as-in-housing-maybe-the-governments-doing-a-bit-too-much/"&gt;In child care, as in housing, maybe the government’s doing a bit too much?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 17:00:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] The Perils of Populism: A Free Market Warning for Louisiana</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/tax-budget/the-perils-of-populism-a-free-market-warning-for-louisiana/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In an era where political rhetoric often pits the “little guy” against the “big guy,” populism has resurfaced as a potent force, captivating voters with promises of empowerment and justice. From a free market perspective, however, populism is not a savior but a siren song that leads economies astray. As Louisiana experienced with Huey Long,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/tax-budget/the-perils-of-populism-a-free-market-warning-for-louisiana/"&gt;The Perils of Populism: A Free Market Warning for Louisiana&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 17:47:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF in National Review: The Return of Car Choice, Hopefully</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-in-national-review-the-return-of-car-choice-hopefully/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following appeared in National Review&amp;#8217;s Capital Matters on August 20, 2025. Whatever happens to the future of EVs, they should compete on an even playing field with other vehicles. While the courts have yet to have their say, one of the Trump administration’s most important accomplishments, perhaps second only to his successful crackdown on illegal [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-in-national-review-the-return-of-car-choice-hopefully/"&gt;RGF in National Review: The Return of Car Choice, Hopefully&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 17:56:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Portland’s Social Housing Task Force: Another Wrong Turn for Housing Policy</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/portlands-social-housing-task-force-another-wrong-turn-for-housing-policy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Portland officials are once again reaching for the wrong tool to solve Maine’s housing crisis. In March, the City Council voted to create a “Social Housing Task Force” with the stated goal of exploring a system where the government owns, develops, and manages housing for residents. At first glance, this may sound like a bold [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/portlands-social-housing-task-force-another-wrong-turn-for-housing-policy/"&gt;Portland’s Social Housing Task Force: Another Wrong Turn for Housing Policy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Wisconsin breweries no longer chugging along</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/wisconsin-breweries-no-longer-chugging-along/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Beer production in Wisconsin, a state that prides itself on its brewing heritagen is down more than 15 percent in just the last four years, a victim of a confluence of local and national drinking trends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/wisconsin-breweries-no-longer-chugging-along/"&gt;Wisconsin breweries no longer chugging along&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 21:09:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Poor Solar Energy Performance is More Evidence the VCEA is Failing</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/poor-solar-energy-performance-is-more-evidence-the-vcea-is-failing/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="630" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/IMG_3224.png" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every solar facility in Dominion Energy Virginia’s expanding fleet of silicone panels is failing to perform up to its initial energy promises, according to a State Corporation Commission staff analysis.&amp;#160;In many cases the shortfalls are dramatic. A high confidence in the ability of solar power to replace Virginia’s dominant natural gas and coal electricity generators [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/poor-solar-energy-performance-is-more-evidence-the-vcea-is-failing/"&gt;Poor Solar Energy Performance is More Evidence the VCEA is Failing&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] New TV/Digital Ad: Shapiro’s Budget Impasse is Failing Kids &amp; Families</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/08/22/new-tv-digital-ad-shapiros-budget-impasse-is-failing-kids-families/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Harrisburg, Pa., August 22, 2025 — Today, the Commonwealth Foundation launched a new ad, calling for Gov. Josh Shapiro to end the budget impasse with a compromise that protects families from tax hikes and offers educational choice. The ad is running statewide on digital beginning this weekend, and will air on TV from Sunday, August [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/08/22/new-tv-digital-ad-shapiros-budget-impasse-is-failing-kids-families/"&gt;New TV/Digital Ad: Shapiro’s Budget Impasse is Failing Kids &amp;#038; Families&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 13:32:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] CT’s Low “Fun” Rank Linked to High Taxes, Strict Regulations</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/08/22/cts-low-fun-rank-linked-to-high-taxes-strict-regulations/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="1709" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/shutterstock_1487599832-scaled.jpg" width="2560" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connecticut is not considered a “fun” state, ranking 43rd overall in a new WalletHub report. This quirky detail reveals a deeper problem plaguing the state: that high taxes and burdensome [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/08/22/cts-low-fun-rank-linked-to-high-taxes-strict-regulations/"&gt;CT’s Low “Fun” Rank Linked to High Taxes, Strict Regulations&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 13:49:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] BEAD for Speed: Louisiana’s Broadband Efforts Lead Once Again</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/bead-for-speed-louisianas-broadband-efforts-lead-once-again/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When the National Telecommunications and Information Administration announced an overhaul of the $42.45 billion Broadband Equity, Access, and  Deployment (BEAD) program that had been slowly unrolling since 2021, broadband offices across the country were tasked with revising years of work under tight deadlines. Louisiana’s ConnectLA rose to the occasion and executed a revised plan with swift determination,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/bead-for-speed-louisianas-broadband-efforts-lead-once-again/"&gt;BEAD for Speed: Louisiana’s Broadband Efforts Lead Once Again&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 14:20:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] SEPTA’s Manufactured Crisis Has Delayed State Budget Long Enough</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/08/22/septas-manufactured-crisis-has-delayed-state-budget-long-enough/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Harrisburg, Pa., August 22, 2025 — This Sunday, after eight consecutive weeks of public fearmongering, the Southeastern Pennsylvania Transportation Authority (SEPTA) will enact self-imposed service cuts. Though completely avoidable, these cuts aim to extract yet another taxpayer-funded bailout. This is not a true emergency; it is a manufactured crisis, fueled and exploited by Gov. Josh [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/08/22/septas-manufactured-crisis-has-delayed-state-budget-long-enough/"&gt;SEPTA’s Manufactured Crisis Has Delayed State Budget Long Enough&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 16:12:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Week in Review: The University of Kentucky Just Won’t Quit DEI</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-the-university-of-kentucky-just-wont-quit-dei/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When Kentucky lawmakers passed a law this year eliminating diversity, equity, and inclusion programs in public colleges and universities, their..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-the-university-of-kentucky-just-wont-quit-dei/"&gt;Week in Review: The University of Kentucky Just Won’t Quit DEI&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 17:46:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] The State’s War on Homeschooling Rests on Bad Data</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/08/22/the-states-war-on-homeschooling-rests-on-bad-data/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connecticut’s Office of the Child Advocate (OCA) is using a high-profile tragedy as a springboard to regulate homeschooling, but critics say the state’s case is built on flawed data and [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/08/22/the-states-war-on-homeschooling-rests-on-bad-data/"&gt;The State’s War on Homeschooling Rests on Bad Data&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 18:48:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Listen: The Folly of Portland’s Social Housing Task Force</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/listen-the-folly-of-portlands-social-housing-task-force/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Policy analyst, Harris Van Pate, joined the WGAN Morning News to discuss the pitfalls of Portland&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8220;Social Housing Task Force&amp;#8221; and how the city&amp;#8217;s existing policies – like rent control and inclusionary zoning – are distorting the greater region&amp;#8217;s housing market to the detriment of renters and those looking to buy a home. Listen to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/listen-the-folly-of-portlands-social-housing-task-force/"&gt;Listen: The Folly of Portland&amp;#8217;s Social Housing Task Force&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 21:15:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] John Charles’ Testimony Re: ’25 Special Session Transportation Funding</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/testimony/john-charles-testimony-re-25-special-session-transportation-funding/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Testimony of John A. Charles, Jr.Regarding LC 2Before the Joint Interim Committee on...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/testimony/john-charles-testimony-re-25-special-session-transportation-funding/"&gt;John Charles’ Testimony Re: &amp;#8217;25 Special Session Transportation Funding &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 22:22:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/08/the-outstater-284/</link><description>A $100,000 Audience with the Guv “That government is the strongest of which every man feels himself a part.&amp;#8221; — Thomas Jefferson FINANCING POLITICS should be a simple matter, or so we argue in “Indiana Mandate: A Return to Founding Principles”: Just ensure that anyone funding a political effort use his own name and money&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/08/the-outstater-284/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2025 00:53:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] What is the Physical Plant and Equipment Levy (PPEL)?</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/what-is-the-physical-plant-and-equipment-levy-ppel/</link><description>&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1920" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/IMG_5089-scaled.jpg" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;" width="2560" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="What is the Physical Plant and Equipment Levy (PPEL)?" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/IMG_5089-533x400.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frequently referred to as PPEL, this property tax is used by a majority of school districts amounting to hundreds of millions of dollars each year to pay for infrastructure. n Iowa, a PPEL (Physical Plant and Equipment Levy) is a property tax used by most school districts to spend on infrastructure and equipment, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;School building construction, repairs, and maintenance&lt;br /&gt;
Purchase of technology and equipment&lt;br /&gt;
Transportation (e.g., school buses)&lt;br /&gt;
Safety and security improvements&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/what-is-the-physical-plant-and-equipment-levy-ppel/"&gt;What is the Physical Plant and Equipment Levy (PPEL)?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2025 14:17:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] High-speed rail CEO’s new plan is an improvement, but probably is not legal</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/high-speed-rail-ceos-new-plan-is-an-improvement-but-probably-is-not-legal/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=high-speed-rail-ceos-new-plan-is-an-improvement-but-probably-is-not-legal</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Ian Choudri, the California High-Speed Rail Authority’s relatively new CEO has rolled out a new proposal for the bullet train’s future. His newly released supplemental project update report offers more realistic projections and some worthwhile ideas, but they are not consistent with current law. If Choudri wants to reimagine the high-speed rail program, the Authority...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/high-speed-rail-ceos-new-plan-is-an-improvement-but-probably-is-not-legal/"&gt;High-speed rail CEO’s new plan is an improvement, but probably is not legal&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2025 03:32:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Rifreedom] After Federal Action, Rhode Island Desperately Needs a Realistic Energy Strategy</title><link>https://rifreedom.org/2025/08/after-federal-action-rhode-island-desperately-needs-a-realistic-energy-strategy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Cranston, RI – The Rhode Island Center for Freedom &amp;#38; Prosperity advises state policymakers to immediately begin work to construct a new and realistic energy strategy that will put the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org/2025/08/after-federal-action-rhode-island-desperately-needs-a-realistic-energy-strategy/"&gt;After Federal Action, Rhode Island Desperately Needs a Realistic Energy Strategy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org"&gt;RI Center for Freedom and Prosperity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 15:41:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Gov. Reynolds channels the conviction of Margaret Thatcher</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/gov-reynolds-channels-the-conviction-of-margaret-thatcher/</link><description>&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="80" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/The-Center-Square.jpg" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;" width="300" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Gov. Reynolds channels the conviction of Margaret Thatcher" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/The-Center-Square.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“One of the great debates of our time is about how much of your money should be spent by the State and how much you should keep to spend on your family. Let us never forget this fundamental truth: the State has no source of money other than money which people earn themselves. If the State wishes to spend more it can do so only by borrowing your savings or by taxing you more. It is no good thinking that someone else will pay – that 'someone else' is you. There is no such thing as public money; there is only taxpayers' money,” stated Prime Minister Margaret Thatcher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/gov-reynolds-channels-the-conviction-of-margaret-thatcher/"&gt;Gov. Reynolds channels the conviction of Margaret Thatcher&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 16:58:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Goldwater to Supreme Court: Protect Parental Rights</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/goldwater-to-u-s-supreme-court-protect-parental-rights-in-foote-v-ludlow/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Two Massachusetts parents were blindsided when they learned that middle school officials had been referring to their two pre-teens by..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/goldwater-to-u-s-supreme-court-protect-parental-rights-in-foote-v-ludlow/"&gt;Goldwater to Supreme Court: Protect Parental Rights&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 17:00:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Are you ready for another boondoggle?</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/08/are-you-ready-for-another-boondoggle/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The work of Grassroot Institute of Hawaii cartoonist Dave Swann — pictured here — was recently featured in a report issued by Sen. Joni Ernst of Iowa. It’s always nice to have the work of my colleagues at Grassroot acknowledged, especially on the national stage. What&amp;#8217;s not so nice is that the report featured Honolulu&amp;#8217;s [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/08/are-you-ready-for-another-boondoggle/"&gt;Are you ready for another boondoggle?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 20:53:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] WILL Toolkit Equips Parents to Know and Protect Their Rights</title><link>https://will-law.org/will-toolkit-equips-parents-to-know-and-protect-their-rights/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As parents in Wisconsin and across the country return to classrooms, WILL is releasing a comprehensive and up-to-date parental toolkit to help parents understand their Constitutional rights and how they can opt their children out of curricula when it conflicts with their values at home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/will-toolkit-equips-parents-to-know-and-protect-their-rights/"&gt;WILL Toolkit Equips Parents to Know and Protect Their Rights&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 20:49:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] New Study Highlights Tax Reforms that Would Enhance Massachusetts’ Competitiveness</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/economic_opportunity/new-study-highlights-tax-reforms-that-would-enhance-massachusetts-competitiveness/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Research indicates that tax policy plays a key role in outmigration from Massachusetts, and a new study published by Pioneer Institute highlights six tax reforms that would help the Commonwealth address its outmigration and competitiveness challenges. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/economic_opportunity/new-study-highlights-tax-reforms-that-would-enhance-massachusetts-competitiveness/"&gt;New Study Highlights Tax Reforms that Would Enhance Massachusetts’ Competitiveness&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 04:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Michigan Economic Development Corp. is not developing Michigan’s economy</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/michigan-economic-development-corp-is-not-developing-michigans-economy</link><description>Lawmakers should eliminate failed agency</description><pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Hochul’s $17B Medicaid Surge Leaves Little to Brag About</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/hochuls-17b-medicaid-surge/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Governor Hochul has made Medicaid her dominant budget priority over the past four years, increasing the state&amp;#8217;s annual share of....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/hochuls-17b-medicaid-surge/"&gt;Hochul&amp;#8217;s $17B Medicaid Surge Leaves Little to Brag About&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 13:27:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Spending Solutions for ODOT’s Spending Problems</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/tax-and-budget/spending-solutions-for-odots-spending-problems/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Naomi Inman The Oregon Legislature’s Joint Committee on Transportation Funding will consider...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/tax-and-budget/spending-solutions-for-odots-spending-problems/"&gt;Spending Solutions for ODOT’s Spending Problems&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 14:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] NYT Bestseller Jane Leavy on Reforming Major League Baseball</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/nyt-bestseller-jane-leavy-on-reforming-major-league-baseball/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In this week’s episode of The Learning Curve, co-hosts U-Arkansas Prof. Albert Cheng and Pioneer Senior Fellow Charlie Chieppo interview award-winning journalist and New York Times bestselling author Jane Leavy. Ms. Leavy discusses her lifelong love of baseball, and her forthcoming book, Make Me Commissioner: I Know What’s Wrong with Baseball and How to Fix It, which comes out in September.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/nyt-bestseller-jane-leavy-on-reforming-major-league-baseball/"&gt;NYT Bestseller Jane Leavy on Reforming Major League Baseball&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 15:20:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Wisconsin Village Quickly Backs Down on Unconstitutional “Farmers Market” Restriction</title><link>https://will-law.org/wisconsin-village-quickly-backs-down-on-unconstitutional-farmers-market-restriction/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;#038; Liberty (WILL) issued a warning to the Village of Bonduel of an unconstitutional rule governing the sale of “politically or religiously affiliated merchandise,” at a village-operated farmers market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/wisconsin-village-quickly-backs-down-on-unconstitutional-farmers-market-restriction/"&gt;Wisconsin Village Quickly Backs Down on Unconstitutional “Farmers Market” Restriction&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 17:54:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] I am Grateful for Hurricane Katrina</title><link>https://empowerms.org/i-am-grateful-for-hurricane-katrina/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Twenty years later, I am grateful for Hurricane Katrina. I can hear my dad now, God rest his soul, saying, “Son, why would anyone be grateful for Katrina?” The truth is, August 29, 2005, was a terrible day. I remember waking up at a quarter past 6:00 AM and hearing my mother crying on the&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/i-am-grateful-for-hurricane-katrina/"&gt;I am Grateful for Hurricane Katrina&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 06:00:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] MSPC announces blockbuster 2026 dinner plans, featuring Dana Perino</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/mspc-announces-blockbuster-2026-dinner-plans-featuring-dana-perino</link><description>Perino, one of the most respected voices in American media and politics, served as Press Secretary for President George W. Bush, becoming only the second woman ever to hold the position.</description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 12:36:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Trump Administration Agrees with WILL Lawsuit: Federal Programs Illegally Discriminate Against Farmers</title><link>https://will-law.org/trump-administration-agrees-with-will-lawsuit-federal-programs-illegally-discriminate-against-farmers/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Trump Administration has filed a motion declining to defend multiple Biden-era aid programs within the Department of Agriculture (USDA), each of which currently discriminate against white male farmers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/trump-administration-agrees-with-will-lawsuit-federal-programs-illegally-discriminate-against-farmers/"&gt;Trump Administration Agrees with WILL Lawsuit: Federal Programs Illegally Discriminate Against Farmers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 15:00:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Is the Jones Act invincible?</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/08/is-the-jones-act-invincible/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Bad laws become entrenched when the dialogue around them is controlled by people who have a financial interest in keeping them on the books. Such is the case with the Jones Act, according to Grassroot scholar Colin Grabow, who spoke this past Sunday with radio host Johnny Miro of the H. Hawaii Media network of [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/08/is-the-jones-act-invincible/"&gt;Is the Jones Act invincible?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 19:25:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/08/the-outstater-285/</link><description>Crime Is a Root Cause MY CITY&amp;#160;is addressing public policy in the starkest terms. Youth violence and encampments of derelicts are problems without easy answers. Yet, answers, however imperfect, can be sought, social order can be attempted. Nobody likes to send a young man to jail or to order a troubled mind for treatment. In&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/08/the-outstater-285/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 19:55:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Want to truly help Wisconsin’s children? Stop using them as plaintiffs</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/want-to-truly-help-wisconsins-children-stop-using-them-as-plaintiffs/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Fifteen kids — one only eight years old — just filed a lawsuit in Dane County, claiming that they are particularly vulnerable to air pollution and fossil fuel-caused climate change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/want-to-truly-help-wisconsins-children-stop-using-them-as-plaintiffs/"&gt;Want to truly help Wisconsin’s children? Stop using them as plaintiffs&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 20:19:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Building costs heading upward in first impact of bureaucrats being unleashed</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/building-costs-heading-upward-in-first-impact-of-bureaucrats-being-unleashed/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A new requirement to hire a “special inspector” to be on hand during construction will add an estimated $20,000 to any store, school, office, factory or apartment building in the Wisconsin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/building-costs-heading-upward-in-first-impact-of-bureaucrats-being-unleashed/"&gt;Building costs heading upward in first impact of bureaucrats being unleashed&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 20:40:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Leaders have solutions; they just need problems</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/leaders-have-solutions-they-just-need-problems</link><description>Many of today’s high-profile political issues were solved long ago</description><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Let’s Privatize the Post Office</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/economy/lets-privatize-the-post-office/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A version of the following commentary appeared in the St. Louis Post-Dispatch. I will admit that calling for the privatization [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/economy/lets-privatize-the-post-office/"&gt;Let’s Privatize the Post Office&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 16:23:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Where Has All The Money Gone?: Why Idaho’s Spending Bomb is Global</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/where-has-all-the-money-gone-why-idahos-spending-bomb-is-global/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/where-has-all-the-money-gone-why-idahos-spending-bomb-is-global/" rel="nofollow" title="Where Has All The Money Gone?: Why Idaho’s Spending Bomb is Global"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/Article-Headers-2025-08-29T094830.923.png" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Those of us of a certain age remember the old anti-war song, most famously sung by the lefty folk rock band, Peter, Paul and Mary: “Where Have All the Flowers Gone?” The song tells the story of the cycle of life, with the flowers ending up on military graves. Remember, this was during the Vietnam [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 16:26:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Connecticut’s Legislature is Busy. That Doesn’t Mean It’s Effective</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/08/29/connecticuts-legislature-is-busy-that-doesnt-mean-its-effective/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If lawmaking were graded on quantity not quality, Connecticut would be on the honor roll. In 2025 the General Assembly introduced 4,064 bills — eighth most in the nation for [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/08/29/connecticuts-legislature-is-busy-that-doesnt-mean-its-effective/"&gt;Connecticut’s Legislature is Busy. That Doesn’t Mean It’s Effective &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 16:49:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/08/the-outstater-286/</link><description>The Party that Doesn&amp;#8217;t Pray MARK AUG. 27, 2025, as the day the Democrat Party, or at least its prominent spokesmen, dismissed the prayers of children shot to death in their pews. That is the partisan interpretation. A more charitable one would be that Democrats believe that such an act, shooting children at prayer, deserves action (gun control)&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/08/the-outstater-286/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 16:53:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Grassroot testimonies — August 2025</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/08/grassroot-testimonies-august-2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Below are testimonies submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii during August, 2025, for consideration by the Hawai‘i and Honolulu county councils. HAWAI‘I COUNTY COUNCIL &amp;#62;&amp;#62;&amp;#160;Bill 52 (2025)&amp;#160;— “Allow backyard-raised poultry to encourage food self-sufficiency” &amp;#62;&amp;#62;&amp;#160;Bill 63 (2025)&amp;#160;— “Expand mixed-use zoning to help address demand for housing” HONOLULU COUNTY COUNCIL &amp;#62;&amp;#62;&amp;#160;Bill 34 (2024)&amp;#160;— “Don&amp;#8217;t add [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/08/grassroot-testimonies-august-2025/"&gt;Grassroot testimonies — August 2025&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 17:06:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Week in Review: 16 States!</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-16-states/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New Hampshire patients suffering from rare diseases have new hope now that the state has enacted Goldwater’s Right to Try..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-16-states/"&gt;Week in Review: 16 States!&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 17:25:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Vallas: Chicago Public Schools’ new budget will fail, hurt taxpayers</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/vallas-chicago-public-schools-new-budget-will-fail-hurt-taxpayers/</link><description>The vote is over on the Chicago Public Schools budget. It dodged some immediate problems, but the financial mess will continue. Taxpayers will feel the pain long into the future.</description><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 17:54:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Trump Embraces Disastrous Most Favored Nation Drug Pricing</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/trump-embraces-disastrous-most-favored-nation-drug-pricing/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;President Donald Trump gave American drug companies an ultimatum last month. Either they agree to adopt foreign-style price controls, or the administration &amp;#8220;will deploy every tool in [its] arsenal&amp;#8221; to do it for them. More specifically, the president asked drug firms to base U.S. drug prices for a given drug on the lowest price offered [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/trump-embraces-disastrous-most-favored-nation-drug-pricing/"&gt;Trump Embraces Disastrous Most Favored Nation Drug Pricing&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 20:36:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Humanity and Abortion</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/humanity-and-abortion/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/humanity-and-abortion/" rel="nofollow" title="Humanity and Abortion"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1350" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/Cream-Neutral-Minimalist-New-Business-Pitch-Deck-Presentation-6.jpg" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="2400" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Idaho has one of the most comprehensive abortion laws in the United States, effectively banning the procedure at all stages of pregnancy with narrow exceptions. The state's framework consists of multiple overlapping statutes, primarily enacted or triggered after the U.S. Supreme Court's 2022 decision in Dobbs v. Jackson Women's Health Organization, which overturned Roe v. [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2025 19:43:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] The Taxman Cometh: City of Kerrville</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/the-taxman-cometh-city-of-kerrville/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Most city, county, and school district officials are right now in the process of adopting budgets and determining tax rates for the next fiscal year. In some cases, these local decisions will increase the cost of government and put upward pressure on property tax bills. In a few cases, local government action will cause tax...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/the-taxman-cometh-city-of-kerrville/"&gt;The Taxman Cometh: City of Kerrville&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2025 23:28:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Illinois sets U.S. record: over 2 years late with state spending audit</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/illinois-sets-u-s-record-over-2-years-late-with-state-spending-audit/</link><description>Accounting standards call for annual spending reports within 180 days of the year’s end. Illinois took 774 days to produce its 2023 report, setting a national record for tardiness.</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 10:00:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Public Recommendations to Idaho's DOGE Task Force to Increase Government Efficiency</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/public-recommendations-to-idahos-doge-task-force-to-increase-government-efficiency/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/public-recommendations-to-idahos-doge-task-force-to-increase-government-efficiency/" rel="nofollow" title="Public Recommendations to Idaho&amp;#039;s DOGE Task Force to Increase Government Efficiency"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Article-Headers-2025-09-01T114655.975.png" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Dear Members of the Idaho DOGE Task Force,&amp;#160; At the request of members of this Task Force, we have attached our analysis and recommendations for the committee's consideration. Each proposed reduction, consolidation, or elimination falls within the committee's stated purpose and offers realistic options for waste reduction.&amp;#160; The Idaho DOGE Task Force is positioned to [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 18:06:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] API to AHSAA: Don’t Sideline School Choice Families – Follow the Law!</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/09/01/api-to-ahsaa-stop-penalizing-school-choice-students-and-follow-the-law/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On September 1st, Alabama families will receive another dose of relief at the checkout line. The state’s sales tax on groceries will drop from 3% to 2%, continuing a rollback that began in 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/09/01/api-to-ahsaa-stop-penalizing-school-choice-students-and-follow-the-law/"&gt;API to AHSAA: Don’t Sideline School Choice Families &amp;#8211; Follow the Law!&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 19:38:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] Beyond the Beach: Honoring the Dignity of Work</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/09/01/labor-day-honoring-the-dignity-of-work/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A free and prosperous society is built on a foundation of responsible, creative, and purposeful work. When government is limited and economic freedom is upheld, individuals are empowered to pursue their callings, provide for their families, and contribute to the common good. Labor Day, therefore, becomes a day to honor not just the physical act of labor, but the sacred dignity of work—the opportunity we have to use our gifts to create, serve, and build, all while reflecting the image of our Creator. It is a day to be grateful for the freedom to work and to be a part of a society where that freedom is protected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/09/01/labor-day-honoring-the-dignity-of-work/"&gt;Beyond the Beach: Honoring the Dignity of Work&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 19:46:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] From Jerome to your town: Time for every meeting on camera</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/from-jerome-to-your-town-time-for-every-meeting-on-camera</link><description>Think about that: a school board, funded by taxpayers, making decisions that affect families, students, and teachers—telling the press and the public to put their cameras away.</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 21:15:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] A Conversation with Assemblyman Joe Patterson</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/a-conversation-with-assemblyman-joe-patterson/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;We wrap up our series of podcasts on the hot issues being debated in the final weeks of the 2025 legislative session with a conversation with Assemblyman Joe Patterson, R-Rocklin.  They discuss the Gavin Newsom redistricting proposal, the bills that aren&amp;#8217;t getting the attention they should be at the end of session, and his efforts [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/a-conversation-with-assemblyman-joe-patterson/"&gt;A Conversation with Assemblyman Joe Patterson&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 01:30:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Boosting American pharmaceutical innovation</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/boosting-american-pharmaceutical-innovation/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Scott Gottlieb focuses on a little-discussed American advantage over global competitors. At a time when the federal government is reducing funding for biomedical research at the National Institutes of Health—thereby fraying the partnership between government and academia that made US biomedicine the envy of the world—and as large-scale staff reductions at the Food and Drug...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/boosting-american-pharmaceutical-innovation/"&gt;Boosting American pharmaceutical innovation&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 09:36:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Conservatives have opportunity to win teacher support</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/conservatives-have-opportunity-to-win-teacher-support/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Daniel Buck and Will Flanders write for National Review Online about a political opportunity involving America’s teachers. During the 2024 election cycle, an internal survey of the Teamsters showed that members preferred Donald Trump two to one over Kamala Harris, suggesting that the long-term cozy relationship between unions and the Democratic Party was cooling. Something...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/conservatives-have-opportunity-to-win-teacher-support/"&gt;Conservatives have opportunity to win teacher support&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 09:39:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Taxpayer money pulled from ‘doomed’ offshore wind</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/taxpayer-money-pulled-from-doomed-offshore-wind/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Victor Nava writes for the New York Post about a welcome development in American energy policy. Transportation Secretary Sean Duffy announced Friday that $679 million in federal funding has been withdrawn for 12 “doomed” offshore wind projects – including three in New York, New Jersey and Connecticut. The scrapped funding includes $10.5 million for Connecticut’s...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/taxpayer-money-pulled-from-doomed-offshore-wind/"&gt;Taxpayer money pulled from ‘doomed’ offshore wind&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 09:42:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Courts side with colleges over students in lockdown fights</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/courts-side-with-colleges-over-students-in-lockdown-fights</link><description>School promises dynamic campus life, delivers nothing but pixels; and paying students can’t do anything about it</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] A Free-Market Guide for Missouri Municipalities, Part Three: Planning and Zoning</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/state-and-local-government/a-free-market-guide-for-missouri-municipalities-part-three-planning-and-zoning/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This third installment in the free-market municipality series examines the use of planning and zoning in Missouri cities and suggests [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/state-and-local-government/a-free-market-guide-for-missouri-municipalities-part-three-planning-and-zoning/"&gt;A Free-Market Guide for Missouri Municipalities, Part Three: Planning and Zoning&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 11:24:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Revenue-neutral law is helping; additional property tax reform is needed</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/revenue-neutral-helps-more-tax-reform-needed/</link><description>The Revenue-Neutral law that went into effect in 2021 is helping many Kansans, with nearly two-thirds of taxing entities deciding NOT to raise property taxes this year. It requires cities, counties, school districts, and other local taxing authorities to notify taxpayers if they want to collect more property tax revenue the following year, hold a [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 12:49:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Victory, 80 years on</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/victory-80-years-on/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In summer 1945, Japan’s war in China — which had consumed an estimated 20 million Chinese lives since 1937, the true beginning of World War Two — raged on.&amp;#160; So did fighting in the Philippines where, on May 21, Darvin Lange from Wanda “died of injuries, which he had received at the explosion of a...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/victory-80-years-on/"&gt;Victory, 80 years on&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Jury Still Deliberating On California’s Push To Build More Homes</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/jury-still-deliberating-on-californias-push-to-build-more-homes/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This year’s devastating wildfires decimated upwards of 13,000 homes. In response, California has passed two new laws that seek to streamline the process of housing development. Will they have the desired effect? That remains to be seen. Under AB130, new housing developments that meet certain size, density, location, and use requirements will be exempt from the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/jury-still-deliberating-on-californias-push-to-build-more-homes/"&gt;Jury Still Deliberating On California&amp;#8217;s Push To Build More Homes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 13:04:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Woke or a joke? Study finds students admit to pretending to be more progressive</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/woke-or-a-joke-study-finds-students-admit-to-pretending-to-be-more-progressive/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;To succeed socially or academically, students &amp;#8220;have pretended to hold more progressive views than [they] truly endorse,&amp;#8221; according to a first-of-its-kind study of Northwestern University and University of Michigan students by researchers Forest Romm and Kevin Waldman. Eighty-eight percent of 1,452 undergraduate students privately interviewed at these institutions admitted to pretending to be more liberal...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/woke-or-a-joke-study-finds-students-admit-to-pretending-to-be-more-progressive/"&gt;Woke or a joke? Study finds students admit to pretending to be more progressive&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 13:15:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] TPPF Comments on Repeal of the New Clean Power Plan</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/tppf-comments-on-repeal-of-the-new-clean-power-plan/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Read TPPF&amp;#8217;s comments on the repeal of the new Clean Power Plan here. Key Points Section 111 of the Clean Air Act requires the EPA to find that emissions of a pollutant from a source category “contributes significantly” to air pollution that endangers the public health. Because carbon dioxide (CO2) is not directly harmful to...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/tppf-comments-on-repeal-of-the-new-clean-power-plan/"&gt;TPPF Comments on Repeal of the New Clean Power Plan&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 13:24:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Kim Reynolds is America’s ‘Iron Lady’ reflecting Margaret Thatcher’s spirit</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/https-www-desmoinesregister-com-story-opinion-columnists-iowa-view-2025-08-31-kim-reynolds-reflects-iron-lady-margaret-thatcher-spirit-85853542007-gnt-cfr1gca-catpgca-uirtruegca-eptiz116054p000250c000/</link><description>&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="80" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Des-Moines-Register.jpg" style="display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;" width="300" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Kim Reynolds is America&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8216;Iron Lady&amp;#8217; reflecting Margaret Thatcher&amp;#8217;s spirit" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Des-Moines-Register.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/https-www-desmoinesregister-com-story-opinion-columnists-iowa-view-2025-08-31-kim-reynolds-reflects-iron-lady-margaret-thatcher-spirit-85853542007-gnt-cfr1gca-catpgca-uirtruegca-eptiz116054p000250c000/"&gt;Kim Reynolds is America&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8216;Iron Lady&amp;#8217; reflecting Margaret Thatcher&amp;#8217;s spirit&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 13:33:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] An unforced error in the case of a DC violent offender</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/an-unforced-error-in-the-case-of-a-dc-violent-offender/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New Policy A new policy put in place by the United States Attorney’s Office for the District of Columbia (DC) is playing out in a troubling manner and deserves another look in the case of Tinsley Bowman. In mid-August, US Attorney Jeanine Pirro (DC), announced that her office would no longer be charging people in...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/an-unforced-error-in-the-case-of-a-dc-violent-offender/"&gt;An unforced error in the case of a DC violent offender&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 13:50:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] New federal school choice law is a historic breakthrough for children</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/new-federal-school-choice-law-is-a-historic-breakthrough-for-children</link><description>Note: This is a joint op-ed with Peter Murphy ( Invest in Education Coalition ). The old saying that states are the “laboratories of...</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 14:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Selling every NBA team wouldn’t be enough to fill Illinois’ pension hole</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/selling-every-nba-team-wouldnt-be-enough-to-fill-illinois-pension-hole/</link><description>The five pension systems run by the state of Illinois only have 46 cents on hand for every $1 of benefits they owe. Filling that $144 billion hole would require more money than the price of every NBA team combined.</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 14:47:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Why Texas Taxpayers Need Senate Bill 10</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/why-texas-taxpayers-need-senate-bill-10/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Later today, both the Texas House and Senate will consider the conference committee report for Senate Bill 10, a proposal to reduce certain taxing units’ voter-approval tax rate (VATR) from 3.5% to 2.5%. In so doing, lawmakers hope to create the conditions for increased public participation in the tax rate-setting process and slow the relentless...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/why-texas-taxpayers-need-senate-bill-10/"&gt;Why Texas Taxpayers Need Senate Bill 10&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 15:12:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Missouri Should Rethink Fire Code Rules that Block Small Apartments</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/regulation/missouri-should-rethink-fire-code-rules-that-block-small-apartments/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New research suggests Missouri cities could allow more apartment buildings—without compromising safety—by rethinking outdated fire code requirements. The study by [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/regulation/missouri-should-rethink-fire-code-rules-that-block-small-apartments/"&gt;Missouri Should Rethink Fire Code Rules that Block Small Apartments&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 15:32:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Without Gerrymandering, Would the Dominant Party Run the Table?</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/without-gerrymandering-would-the-dominant-party-run-the-table/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=without-gerrymandering-would-the-dominant-party-run-the-table</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The argument against gerrymandering begins with visuals. Across the U.S., almost without exception, if you view a map of state and federal electoral districts, they appear as convoluted, obviously contrived jigsaw puzzles, drawn with no regard for geographic features or municipal boundaries. In the face of such obvious manipulation, so the argument goes, the process...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/without-gerrymandering-would-the-dominant-party-run-the-table/"&gt;Without Gerrymandering, Would the Dominant Party Run the Table?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 15:46:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] John Moorlach: The predictably harmful consequences of Assembly Bill 218</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/assembly-bill-218/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=assembly-bill-218</link><description>&lt;p&gt;California’s school districts, counties and cities are fiscally strapped.  And the public employee unions just cut their noses off to spite their faces, adding to the consternation. As a member of the California Assembly, Lorena Gonzalez-Fletcher felt that organizations and school districts should be held financially responsible for the bad acts of their employees who...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/assembly-bill-218/"&gt;John Moorlach: The predictably harmful consequences of Assembly Bill 218&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 15:56:48 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>