<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>State-Policy Think-Tank Digest</title><link>https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml</link><description>Latest posts from free-market policy institutes across the U.S.</description><atom:link href="https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 08:04:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] NJBIZ: OPINION: Why New Jersey should repeal its bag ban</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/11/njbiz-opinion-why-new-jersey-should-repeal-its-bag-ban-wells-winegar/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;OPINION: Why New Jersey should repeal its bag ban by Wells Winegar November 10, 2025 &amp;#160; Walk into any New [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/11/njbiz-opinion-why-new-jersey-should-repeal-its-bag-ban-wells-winegar/"&gt;NJBIZ: OPINION: Why New Jersey should repeal its bag ban&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 18:56:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Dr. Brad Wilcox: Get Married</title><link>https://empowerms.org/dr-brad-wilcox-get-married/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Dr. Brad Wilcox: Get Married On this episode of The Empower Podcast, host Grant Callen talks with Dr. Brad Wilcox, Director of the National Marriage Project at the University of Virginia and author of Get Married: Why Americans Must Defy the Elites, Forge Strong Families, and Save Civilization. Dr. Wilcox shares striking research on how&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/dr-brad-wilcox-get-married/"&gt;Dr. Brad Wilcox: Get Married&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 00:00:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] Rio Grande Foundation Soiree a Huge Success!</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rio-grande-foundation-soiree-a-huge-success/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;What do you call 175 freedom loving New Mexicans gathered in one place? A good start! In all seriousness the Rio Grande Foundation hosted its 25th anniversary Laissez Faire Soiree this past Saturday night and we are pleased to report  the event was a smashing success with 175 attendees and lots of fun. Thanks to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rio-grande-foundation-soiree-a-huge-success/"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation Soiree a Huge Success!&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 19:40:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alaskapolicyforum] Is Anchorage’s New Proposed “Short-Term Rental-Only” Tax Really the Answer?</title><link>https://alaskapolicyforum.org/2025/11/is-anchorages-new-proposed-short-term-rental-only-tax-really-the-answer/#utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=is-anchorages-new-proposed-short-term-rental-only-tax-really-the-answer</link><description>&lt;div style="margin: 5px 5% 10px 5%;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" height="675" src="https://alaskapolicyforum.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/jon-tyson-XS_o-Iuf9Go-unsplash-scaled-e1762980183585.jpg" title="" width="506" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This blog looks at an urgent issue for Anchorage, which is considering a new short-term rental tax next week. That may seem like an easy fix for housing, but in reality, it raises seriousRead More&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alaskapolicyforum.org/2025/11/is-anchorages-new-proposed-short-term-rental-only-tax-really-the-answer/"&gt;Is Anchorage’s New Proposed “Short-Term Rental-Only” Tax Really the Answer?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://alaskapolicyforum.org"&gt;Alaska Policy Forum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 21:06:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Before the Ink Dried, the Union Was Already Calling the Shots at Waterbury Hospital</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/11/14/before-the-ink-dried-the-union-was-already-calling-the-shots-at-waterbury-hospital/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bill authorizing UConn Health to purchase Waterbury Hospital wasn’t even written when one of Connecticut’s most politically influential healthcare unions began issuing demands.   On Oct. 17 — weeks before [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/11/14/before-the-ink-dried-the-union-was-already-calling-the-shots-at-waterbury-hospital/"&gt;Before the Ink Dried, the Union Was Already Calling the Shots at Waterbury Hospital&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 20:33:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] A legacy of healing — Documentary tells ReCAST Lawrenceville’s journey through residents’ stories</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/recast-lawrenceville-documentary/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/recast-lawrenceville-documentary/"&gt;A legacy of healing — Documentary tells ReCAST Lawrenceville’s journey through residents’ stories&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:43:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] New Jersey Policy Institute Announces Inaugural Class of 2026 Junior Fellows</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/11/new-jersey-policy-institute-announces-inaugural-class-of-2026-junior-fellows/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Parsippany, NJ – The New Jersey Policy Institute (NJPI) is proud to announce the inaugural class of its 2026 Junior Fellowship [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/11/new-jersey-policy-institute-announces-inaugural-class-of-2026-junior-fellows/"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute Announces Inaugural Class of 2026 Junior Fellows&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 18:43:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Study: Accessory Dwelling Units Now Legal Statewide, but Construction Still Lags</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/study-accessory-dwelling-units-now-legal-statewide-but-construction-still-lags/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;BOSTON – Even after statewide legalization in 2024, production of accessory dwelling units (ADUs) in Massachusetts remains far from that of other states due to local zoning and permitting practices that continue to discourage development, according to a new Pioneer Institute study. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/study-accessory-dwelling-units-now-legal-statewide-but-construction-still-lags/"&gt;Study: Accessory Dwelling Units Now Legal Statewide, but Construction Still Lags&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 12:51:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Aaron Withe Statement on Trump Administration’s Bold Action to Dismantle Education Bureaucracy</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/education/aaron-withe-statement-on-trump-administrations-bold-action-to-dismantle-education-bureaucracy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Freedom Foundation CEO and Teacher Freedom Alliance President Aaron Withe issued the following statement regarding President Trump’s plans to dismantle the Department of Education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/education/aaron-withe-statement-on-trump-administrations-bold-action-to-dismantle-education-bureaucracy/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Aaron Withe Statement on Trump Administration&amp;#8217;s Bold Action to Dismantle Education Bureaucracy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 16:15:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Mississippi is globally recognized!</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/mississippi-is-globally-recognized/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/mississippi-is-globally-recognized/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi is globally recognized!&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 18:55:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Newly Retired NYPD Retirees Average $100,000+ in Pension</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/newly-retired-nypd-retirees-average-100000-in-pension/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Newly retired1 “full career”2 members of the New York Police Department (NYPD) collected an average of $103,859, according to new....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/newly-retired-nypd-retirees-average-100000-in-pension/"&gt;Newly Retired NYPD Retirees Average $100,000+ in Pension&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 14:07:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] “Inspire Oregon” Tackles Rural Housing Crisis</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/land-use/inspire-oregon-tackles-rural-housing-crisis/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Madilynne Clark The University of Oregon’s Institute for Policy Research and Engagement...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/land-use/inspire-oregon-tackles-rural-housing-crisis/"&gt;“Inspire Oregon” Tackles Rural Housing Crisis&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Tennessee Tax System &amp; Reform Efforts Webinar</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/tennessee-tax-system-reform-efforts-webinar/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=tennessee-tax-system-reform-efforts-webinar</link><description>Join the Beacon Center for a timely discussion on Tennessee’s tax system, ongoing reform efforts, and how tax policy impacts families, workers, and businesses across the state. We’ll be joined by a panel of experts: Carey Bringle, Nashville business owner Patrick Gleason, Americans for Tax Reform, Beacon Senior Fellow for Tax Policy Justin Owen, CEO,...</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 20:38:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Property tax reform won’t reduce student achievement</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/property-tax-reform-student-achievement/</link><description>Kansas Representative Shannon Francis (R-Liberal) told KSNT-TV that he thinks higher property taxes may be bringing people to Kansas. He said higher property taxes have led to investment in schools, and that, as a result, “Kansas schools are a lot better than Oklahoma.” It may be intuitive to think that more spending translates to better [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 16:03:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Connecticut Cannot Solve Its Housing Crisis While Ignoring Union-Driven Costs</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/11/21/connecticut-cannot-solve-its-housing-crisis-while-ignoring-union-driven-costs/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Connecticut’s 2025 State of Housing Conference on Nov. 17 and 18, one panel stood out for all the wrong reasons. The session titled “Union-Built Affordable Housing” was billed as [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/11/21/connecticut-cannot-solve-its-housing-crisis-while-ignoring-union-driven-costs/"&gt;Connecticut Cannot Solve Its Housing Crisis While Ignoring Union-Driven Costs&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 19:01:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Listen: Maine Human Rights Commission Lawsuit on WGAN</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/listen-maine-human-rights-commission-lawsuit-on-wgan/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Policy analyst, Harris Van Pate, joined the WGAN Morning News to discuss the Maine Human Rights Commission&amp;#8217;s lawsuit against five Maine school districts for adopting policies which conform with the federal government&amp;#8217;s Title IX interpretation instead of the Maine Human Rights Act. Listen to the full segment below. Newsradio WGAN · Maine Policy Institute&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/listen-maine-human-rights-commission-lawsuit-on-wgan/"&gt;Listen: Maine Human Rights Commission Lawsuit on WGAN&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 01:06:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Rifreedom] Center Mourns the Loss of Board Member Michael G. Riley, Civic Leader</title><link>https://rifreedom.org/2025/11/center-mourns-the-loss-of-board-member-michael-g-riley-civic-leader/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org/2025/11/center-mourns-the-loss-of-board-member-michael-g-riley-civic-leader/"&gt;Center Mourns the Loss of Board Member Michael G. Riley, Civic Leader&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org"&gt;RI Center for Freedom and Prosperity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 16:51:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Trouble on the Right – Why Conservatives Need to be Wary</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/trouble-on-the-right-why-conservatives-need-to-be-wary/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I only recently learned what a “groyper” is - you may or may not be familiar with the term?&amp;#160;From what I can tell, a groyper is a hardline white nationalist.&amp;#160; Often anti-Semitic, groypers are hostile to mainstream conservatives.&amp;#160; To the extent they have a coherent agenda, groypers seem more national socialism than free-market capitalism.&amp;#160;Having been [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/trouble-on-the-right-why-conservatives-need-to-be-wary/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Trouble on the Right – Why Conservatives Need to be Wary&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 18:29:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] NEW POLL: Louisiana Voters Call for Fiscal Restraint, Bold Tax Reforms, and Expanded School Choice as Costs Rise; Thanksgiving Traditions Add Flavor to Findings</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/press-release/new-poll-louisiana-voters-call-for-fiscal-restraint-bold-tax-reforms-and-expanded-school-choice-as-costs-rise-thanksgiving-traditions-add-flavor-to-findings/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As families across Louisiana prepare to gather for Thanksgiving, the Pelican Institute for Public Policy today released its latest Pelican Pulse poll, revealing strong voter demand for a leaner state government, deeper tax relief, and greater education options. The statewide survey shows clear support for solutions to curb spending, tackle lawsuit abuse, and empower families—while...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/press-release/new-poll-louisiana-voters-call-for-fiscal-restraint-bold-tax-reforms-and-expanded-school-choice-as-costs-rise-thanksgiving-traditions-add-flavor-to-findings/"&gt;NEW POLL: Louisiana Voters Call for Fiscal Restraint, Bold Tax Reforms, and Expanded School Choice as Costs Rise; Thanksgiving Traditions Add Flavor to Findings&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 13:49:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Lowering the bar on proficiency standards is a frightening fad sweeping public education</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/states-lowering-proficiency-standards/</link><description>State education administrators often say,  “It’s all about the kids,” yet their actions suggest it’s more about protecting adult reputations than improving student outcomes. They all want students to do better, but not if it means adults changing their behavior to make it happen. The most recent example of this is lowering the bar on [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 17:21:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Sen. Rod Hickman: Rural revitalization, public safety, and education opportunity</title><link>https://empowerms.org/sen-rod-hickman-rural-revitalization-public-safety-and-education-opportunity/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Sen. Rod Hickman: Rural revitalization, public safety, and education opportunity On this episode of The Empower Podcast, host Grant Callen sits down with Mississippi State Senator Rod Hickman, a lawyer, educator, and public servant representing a stretch of communities across East Mississippi from Macon to Louisville to Meridian. Sen. Hickman shares how growing up in&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/sen-rod-hickman-rural-revitalization-public-safety-and-education-opportunity/"&gt;Sen. Rod Hickman: Rural revitalization, public safety, and education opportunity&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 18:48:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG Expands Oversight and Legal Work with Hire of Kevin Zielinski as Associate Counsel</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-expands-oversight-and-legal-work-with-hire-of-kevin-zielinski-as-associate-counsel/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government (IRG) announced that Kevin Zielinski has joined the organization as Associate Counsel for Legal Reform &amp;#38; Oversight, expanding the IRG team to 9.5 employees. WHY IT MATTERS: In this role, Kevin will support IRG’s work to promote accountable, limited, and effective governance through legal research, oversight initiatives, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-expands-oversight-and-legal-work-with-hire-of-kevin-zielinski-as-associate-counsel/"&gt;IRG Expands Oversight and Legal Work with Hire of Kevin Zielinski as Associate Counsel&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 19:18:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Decoding bureaucracy: how AI could aid regulatory reform</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/decoding-bureaucracy-how-ai-could-aid-regulatory-reform/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For decades, the image of government regulation has been synonymous with dusty, overflowing binders and legal jargon. State regulatory codes tend to accumulate year after year, sometimes contradicting themselves and complicating life for those navigating the process. This accumulation of &amp;#8220;red tape&amp;#8221; creates significant burdens for small business owners trying to remain compliant, citizens trying...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/decoding-bureaucracy-how-ai-could-aid-regulatory-reform/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Decoding bureaucracy: how AI could aid regulatory reform&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 21:18:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] WILL Plans to Protect Lawful Congressional Maps Already in Place</title><link>https://will-law.org/will-plans-to-protect-lawful-congressional-maps-already-in-place/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Wisconsin Supreme Court allowed two new legal challenges to the state’s congressional maps to continue forward by appointing two separate three-judge panels to hear the cases. The Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;#038; Liberty (WILL) had argued against such an appointment as any attempt to redraw the Congressional district lines in this manner would violate the U.S. Constitution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/will-plans-to-protect-lawful-congressional-maps-already-in-place/"&gt;WILL Plans to Protect Lawful Congressional Maps Already in Place&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 21:24:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] NEW YORK: The numbers show workers are done being misled</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/new-york-the-numbers-show-workers-are-done-being-misled/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Something real is happening in New York. Public employees across the state are waking up to the truth. They don’t have to fund a union to keep their job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/new-york-the-numbers-show-workers-are-done-being-misled/" rel="nofollow"&gt;NEW YORK: The numbers show workers are done being misled&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 23:03:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Gratitude for the Forgotten Mayflower Compact</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/gratitude-for-the-forgotten-mayflower-compact/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Gratitude for the Forgotten Mayflower Compact" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/mayflower-compact.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In November 1620, after arriving in Cape Cod, the Pilgrims signed the Mayflower Compact before setting foot on land. Though often overlooked today, the Compact remains a foundational document in the development of American constitutionalism and self-government. Constitutional scholar James McClellan wrote that by adopting the Compact, the Pilgrims brought a contractual theory of government to the New World—an idea that would later influence colonial charters, state constitutions, and even the U.S. Constitution itself.&lt;br /&gt;
This Thanksgiving, remembering the Mayflower Compact highlights the deep historical roots of American freedom and why these early commitments to self-rule remain a blessing worth celebrating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/gratitude-for-the-forgotten-mayflower-compact/"&gt;Gratitude for the Forgotten Mayflower Compact&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 13:48:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Madison is a perfect example of why cities should stay out of grocery business</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/madison-perfect-example-of-why-cities-should-stay-out-of-grocery-business/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Plans for a municipally-owned grocery store in Madison is the perfect illustration of why government should stay out of an intensely competitive business it knows nothing about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/madison-perfect-example-of-why-cities-should-stay-out-of-grocery-business/"&gt;Madison is a perfect example of why cities should stay out of grocery business&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 19:58:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] The safety net ‘system’ that isn’t</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/the-safety-net-system-that-isnt/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/the-safety-net-system-that-isnt/"&gt;The safety net ‘system’ that isn’t&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 21:18:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] On Thanksgiving, remember that gratitude makes good citizens, heals divisions</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/gratitude-makes-good-citizens-and-heals-divisions/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/gratitude-makes-good-citizens-and-heals-divisions/"&gt;On Thanksgiving, remember that gratitude makes good citizens, heals divisions&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 23:00:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Oregon’s 19th Century Energy Strategy</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/economic-opportunity/oregons-19th-century-energy-strategy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By John A. Charles, Jr. Recently the Oregon Department of Energy (ODOE) published...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/economic-opportunity/oregons-19th-century-energy-strategy/"&gt;Oregon’s 19th Century Energy Strategy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 00:31:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] The War of Visions</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/11/28/the-war-of-visions/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Across the country, Americans are no longer divided simply by policy or party but by rival moral imaginations—two incompatible visions of truth, freedom, and even human nature itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/11/28/the-war-of-visions/"&gt;The War of Visions&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 00:23:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] NH public schools post nation’s largest enrollment decline and 4th highest per-pupil spending growth</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/11/nh-public-schools-post-nations-largest-enrollment-decline-and-4th-highest-per-pupil-spending-growth/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As New Hampshire’s K-12 public schools experienced the largest enrollment decline of any state this century, they enjoyed the fourth-highest increase in per-pupil spending, according to a new analysis from the Reason Foundation’s K-12 Education Spending Spotlight. Per-pupil public education spending in New Hampshire grew by 60.5% from 2002-2023, the fourth-highest growth rate in the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/11/nh-public-schools-post-nations-largest-enrollment-decline-and-4th-highest-per-pupil-spending-growth/"&gt;NH public schools post nation&amp;#8217;s largest enrollment decline and 4th highest per-pupil spending growth&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 15:55:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] Schansberg: ‘Greatness’ — a Biblical Perspective</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/12/schansberg-greatness/</link><description>by Eric Schansberg, Ph.D. Noah is repeatedly commended for his righteousness, and then&amp;#160;for building the Ark in obedience. Not only does he save his family and pairs of each animal,&amp;#160;more broadly&amp;#160;he saves “mankind” and the animal kingdom — in what turns out to be a fresh start, a new beginning, another opportunity for man to&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/12/schansberg-greatness/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 13:39:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Florida Politics: The 340B Drug Program — Accountability Needed To Protect Patients, Taxpayers</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/karen-van-caulil-doug-wheeler-the-340b-drug-program-accountability-needed-to-protect-patients-taxpayers/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The&amp;#160;340B Drug Discount Program&amp;#160;was created to improve access to medications for low-income patients. But, like too many well-intentioned...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/karen-van-caulil-doug-wheeler-the-340b-drug-program-accountability-needed-to-protect-patients-taxpayers/"&gt;Florida Politics: The 340B Drug Program — Accountability Needed To Protect Patients, Taxpayers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 14:49:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Fort Meyers News-Press: Polling Shows Rural Areas More Receptive to Data Centers</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/polling-shows-rural-areas-more-receptive-to-data-centers-opinion/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;November 29, 2025 Late September in Indianapolis, residents filled a city council meeting with applause as Google&amp;#160;withdrew&amp;#160;its planned...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/polling-shows-rural-areas-more-receptive-to-data-centers-opinion/"&gt;Fort Meyers News-Press: Polling Shows Rural Areas More Receptive to Data Centers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 15:12:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] RGF opinion piece: Federal shutdown highlights New Mexico dependence</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-opinion-piece-federal-shutdown-highlights-new-mexico-dependence/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following appeared in the Santa Fe New Mexican on December 1, 2025. Among other things, the recent federal shutdown highlighted just how dependent New Mexico is on the federal government. According to the website Virtual Capitalist, New Mexico is the most dependent state in the nation on federal dollars. There are some good reasons for this. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/rgf-opinion-piece-federal-shutdown-highlights-new-mexico-dependence/"&gt;RGF opinion piece: Federal shutdown highlights New Mexico dependence&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 16:47:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] YAF v SBA</title><link>https://will-law.org/yaf-v-sba/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL and the Center for Individual Rights (CIR) filed a major lawsuit against the Trump Administration today, targeting the foundation for many of the remaining federal DEI programs: the preference for so-called “socially disadvantaged individuals.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/yaf-v-sba/"&gt;YAF v SBA&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 18:10:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] A Very Grateful Immigrant’s Thanksgiving</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/a-very-grateful-immigrants-thanksgiving/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Having just celebrated Thanksgiving across the United States, I’ve been reminded of what makes this holiday truly special.&amp;#160;&amp;#160;If you’re an American who’s grown up with the holiday your whole life, it’s easy to take it for granted. Speaking as an immigrant, let me tell you: there’s something genuinely magical about a country setting aside a [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/a-very-grateful-immigrants-thanksgiving/" rel="nofollow"&gt;A Very Grateful Immigrant’s Thanksgiving&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 21:11:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] The Fight Over America’s Institutions is a Test of Our Republic</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/the-fight-over-americas-institutions-is-a-test-of-our-republic/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="The Fight Over America’s Institutions is a Test of Our Republic" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/franklin.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A prediction of Supreme Court expansion sparks a deeper debate about whether sweeping institutional reforms align with or undermine the constitutional framework the Founders designed.&lt;br /&gt;
America was built as a republic, not a pure democracy, with federalism, separation of powers, the Electoral College, and an independent judiciary intentionally structured to restrain majority impulses and protect liberty.&lt;br /&gt;
Modern proposals to reshape long-standing institutions, from court packing to weakening states’ authority, reflect frustration with constitutional guardrails, but those guardrails are essential to preserving the republic “if we can keep it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/the-fight-over-americas-institutions-is-a-test-of-our-republic/"&gt;The Fight Over America’s Institutions is a Test of Our Republic&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 22:31:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Serving Country &amp; Serving Time</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/serving-country-serving-time/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Our attitude should remain one of gratitude when our veterans commit crimes as a result of psychological and physical wounds they received during their time of service. Key Points: Far too many of our nation’s veterans are encountering the criminal justice system due to service-related conditions. Veteran Treatment Courts (VTCs) have been the default solution...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/serving-country-serving-time/"&gt;Serving Country &amp; Serving Time&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 11:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] New Hampshire ranked freest state in North America for 24th time</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/12/new-hampshire-ranked-freest-state-in-north-america-for-24th-time/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New Hampshire ranks as the freest state in North America, as measured in this year’s Economic Freedom of North America report, released today by the Josiah Bartlett Center for Public Policy in conjunction with Canada’s Fraser Institute. For the 24th time, New Hampshire is the freest state among all U.S. states, having scored 8.34 out [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/12/new-hampshire-ranked-freest-state-in-north-america-for-24th-time/"&gt;New Hampshire ranked freest state in North America for 24th time&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 12:52:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/12/the-outstater-311/</link><description>Keeping the Peace The King’s Peace (pax regis) — Prior to the English Civil War, the common-law concept of&amp;#160;maintaining&amp;#160;public order.&amp;#160; CRIMINOLOGISTS TELL US&amp;#160;that only a sliver of humanity is inherently&amp;#160;“criminal,” that is, persons with a pathological disregard for others or their property. In New York City, for instance, just 327 offenders among 8 million citizens&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/12/the-outstater-311/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 13:43:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] The Holiday Season Is Here — But Affordability Still Isn’t</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/the-holiday-season-is-here/</link><description>If it feels like Christmas keeps getting more expensive, that’s because it is,  and Kansans are feeling it more sharply than policymakers care to admit. The rising cost of living is no longer a blip on a chart; it’s a full-blown pocketbook problem showing up in everything from family grocery runs to holiday gift lists. [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 15:17:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Parents should act now to be ready for the Parental Choice Tax Credit application</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/parents-should-act-now-to-be-ready-for-the-parental-choice-tax-credit-application</link><description>The Idaho Parental Choice Tax Credit is a new refundable tax credit program that allows parents to apply for a tax credit of up to $5,000 for each eligible student, and up to $7,500 for each eligible special needs student, for qualified education expenses. The Idaho Tax Commission has been tasked with administering the program and is responsible for registration, verifying eligibility, and prioritizing applicants based on the receipt of a 2024 Form 40 Idaho Individual Income Tax Return. In...</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 18:41:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Young v. Lee: Defending Universal School Choice for Tennesseans</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/young-v-lee-defending-universal-school-choice-for-tennesseans/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=young-v-lee-defending-universal-school-choice-for-tennesseans</link><description>Current status: Along with EdChoice, we represent parents who have asked to intervene in defense of Tennessee&amp;#8217;s EFS program in chancery court. A decision on our motion to intervene is expected later this year.  The Beacon Center of Tennessee, along with EdChoice, is intervening to defend Tennessee&amp;#8217;s Education Freedom Scholarship (EFS) Program from legal attack....</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 19:12:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG Polling: April 2025</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-polling-april-2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;April 16, 2025 NEW IRG Poll: Voters Decided Election on Abortion, Musk &amp;#38; Trump’s Agenda Despite all the emphasis on crime, voters were focused elsewhere  Delafield, Wis. –  The Institute for Reforming Government (IRG) is continuing its public polling project with Napolitan News Service and Scott Rasmussen in 2025, with the focus in this poll on Wisconsin’s [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-polling-april-2025/"&gt;IRG Polling: April 2025&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 20:28:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Use Your IRA to Advance Liberty</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/use-your-ira-to-advance-liberty/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Use Your IRA to Advance Liberty: How a Qualified Charitable Distribution to JMI Maximizes Your Impact As a...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/use-your-ira-to-advance-liberty/"&gt;Use Your IRA to Advance Liberty&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 21:18:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Oregon ethics board lets teachers union lobbyist off the hook for falsified Freedom Foundation mailer</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/oregon/oregon-ethics-board-lets-teachers-union-lobbyist-off-the-hook-for-falsified-freedom-foundation-mailer/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Oregon Government Ethics Commission (OGEC) has decided not to investigate a lobbyist for the state’s largest teachers union who provided an incomplete and falsified copy of a Freedom Foundation mailer to legislators earlier this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/oregon/oregon-ethics-board-lets-teachers-union-lobbyist-off-the-hook-for-falsified-freedom-foundation-mailer/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Oregon ethics board lets teachers union lobbyist off the hook for falsified Freedom Foundation mailer&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 00:12:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Zoning is not the only tool local governments have</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/zoning-is-not-the-only-tool-local-governments-have</link><description>More effective, less-restrictive options are open to them</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 10:52:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Pioneer New England Legal Foundation Files Lawsuit Challenging Cambridge Inclusionary Zoning Ordinance</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/pioneer-new-england-legal-foundation-files-lawsuit-challenging-cambridge-inclusionary-zoning-ordinance/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Requirement that 20 percent of a housing project remain permanently affordable places burden on developers that should be borne by the public as a whole Cambridge – Pioneer New England Legal Foundation filed a lawsuit in state Land Court against the City...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/pioneer-new-england-legal-foundation-files-lawsuit-challenging-cambridge-inclusionary-zoning-ordinance/"&gt;Pioneer New England Legal Foundation Files Lawsuit Challenging Cambridge Inclusionary Zoning Ordinance&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 11:48:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Book Highlights Advances in Digital Education, Policies to Unlock Its Benefits</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/book-highlights-advances-in-digital-education-policies-to-unlock-its-benefits/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;BOSTON – A new book co-edited by national digital education leader Julie Young draws on best practices and multiple studies published by Pioneer Institute to recount three decades of advances in digital education and highlights the policies necessary for students to fully...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/book-highlights-advances-in-digital-education-policies-to-unlock-its-benefits/"&gt;Book Highlights Advances in Digital Education, Policies to Unlock Its Benefits &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 12:06:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] WILL Moves to Intervene in Wisconsin Redistricting Cases on Behalf of Wisconsin Voters</title><link>https://will-law.org/will-moves-to-intervene-in-wisconsin-redistricting-cases-on-behalf-of-wisconsin-voters/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL filed motions to intervene in two lawsuits seeking to overturn Wisconsin’s Congressional Maps. Seeking again to defend those maps on behalf of a group of Wisconsin voters, WILL argues that these new lawsuits are time-barred, the three-judge panel lacks authority to overrule the Wisconsin Supreme Court, and any attempt to impose new maps in this manner would violate federal law and the U.S. Constitution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/will-moves-to-intervene-in-wisconsin-redistricting-cases-on-behalf-of-wisconsin-voters/"&gt;WILL Moves to Intervene in Wisconsin Redistricting Cases on Behalf of Wisconsin Voters&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 14:16:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] What Key Bills Will Lawmakers Debate in 2026?</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/what-key-bills-will-lawmakers-debate-in-2026/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Maine Legislature meets again in January 2026 and lawmakers have already planned out which bills will be carried over from the 2025 session, and which new legislation will be added to that list. While dozens of bills remain alive, only a small number of them have statewide impact and clear implications for Maine taxpayers, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/what-key-bills-will-lawmakers-debate-in-2026/"&gt;What Key Bills Will Lawmakers Debate in 2026?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 18:37:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] A new Montana Constitutional Convention?</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/a-new-montana-constitutional-convention</link><description>In less than five years, Montana voters will decide whether to have a convention to propose either an updated state constitution or amendments to the existing one.   This will be a momentous decision, so it is not too early to begin public discussion now. Moreover, Montanans are entitled to hear all sides of the issue: All too often, opinion makers have celebrated the existing state constitution without admitting that it has flaws.   This is the first in a series of articles that will discuss...</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 20:03:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] New York’s Population Is Struggling to Recover from Covid-19</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/new-yorks-population-is-struggling-to-recover/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Most parts of New York remain less populated in 2024 than they were in 2020 as the state struggled to....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/new-yorks-population-is-struggling-to-recover/"&gt;New York&amp;#8217;s Population Is Struggling to Recover from Covid-19&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 20:28:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Report: New York’s Diminished Population Shows Lasting Damage from Covid-19</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/report-new-yorks-diminished-population-shows-lasting-damage-from-covid-19/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Most parts of New York remained less populated in 2024 than in 2020 as the state struggled to bounce back....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/report-new-yorks-diminished-population-shows-lasting-damage-from-covid-19/"&gt;Report: New York&amp;#8217;s Diminished Population Shows Lasting Damage from Covid-19&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 20:31:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] ICYMI: Bringing Benjamin Franklin to Life—A Conversation with Descendant Dr. Mark Skousen</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/icymi-bringing-benjamin-franklin-to-life-a-conversation-with-descendant-dr-mark-skousen/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Benjamin Franklin—statesman, inventor, and journalist—stands among the great heroes of American history. And who better to tell his story than..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/icymi-bringing-benjamin-franklin-to-life-a-conversation-with-descendant-dr-mark-skousen/"&gt;ICYMI: Bringing Benjamin Franklin to Life—A Conversation with Descendant Dr. Mark Skousen&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 22:00:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Texas International Produce Association v. OSHA</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/texas-international-produce-association-v-osha/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Date Filed: December 3, 2025 Original Court: U.S. District Court for the Northern District of Texas Case Status: Pending While workplace safety is unquestionably important, Congress gave OSHA an extraordinarily broad mandate: the power to issue any rules it considers “reasonably necessary or appropriate” for workplace safety. For decades, OSHA has relied on that open-ended...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/texas-international-produce-association-v-osha/"&gt;Texas International Produce Association v. OSHA&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 22:32:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Michigan would benefit from independent nurse practitioners</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/michigan-would-benefit-from-independent-nurse-practitioners</link><description>More than 30 states allow the practice</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Robotaxis offer real-world solution for urban traffic congestion</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/robotaxis-offer-real-world-solution-for-urban-traffic-congestion/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Waymo is the Autonomous Vehicle division of Alphabet/Google, which for two decades has mapped almost every road in America. The cars are electric I-Pace Jaguars made in Austria by Magna Steyr and, he said, quite luxurious. Other cities hosting Waymos include Los Angeles, Austin, Atlanta and San Francisco, also covering parts of Silicon Valley, such [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/robotaxis-offer-real-world-solution-for-urban-traffic-congestion/"&gt;Robotaxis offer real-world solution for urban traffic congestion&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 11:00:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Idaho’s “C.O.W.” problem is great for economic growth</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/idaho-s-c-o-w-problem-is-great-for-economic-growth</link><description>Idaho Governor Brad Little is known for being a rancher . He was raised on his family’s sheep and cattle ranching operation and worked in the ranching industry for his professional life. Realizing this background, it should come as no surprise that he’s happy to wrangle up fleeing taxpayers from high-tax states. During his recent speech at the Associated Taxpayers of Idaho (ATI) conference, Governor Little noted how “C.O.W.s” are one of the state’s current challenges, but also an opportunity....</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 14:56:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] New Mexico falls to 50th among US states in latest “Index of Economic Freedom”</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/new-mexico-falls-to-50th-among-us-states-in-latest-index-of-economic-freedom/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Rio Grande Foundation has never seen &amp;#8220;eye to eye&amp;#8221; with Gov. Lujan Grisham and the leftists in Santa Fe who have failed to improve New Mexico even with the benefit of billions of dollars in oil and gas revenues. And, while these policy differences and failures may seem trivial to some, they have real [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/new-mexico-falls-to-50th-among-us-states-in-latest-index-of-economic-freedom/"&gt;New Mexico falls to 50th among US states in latest &amp;#8220;Index of Economic Freedom&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 15:40:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] New Revenue Forecast Shows Why Maine Should Cut Taxes, Not Grow Government</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/new-revenue-forecast-shows-why-maine-should-cut-taxes-not-grow-government/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Maine’s latest revenue forecast shows the state will bring in roughly $248 million more than expected over the next two years. However, instead of asking how to give this money back to taxpayers, state leaders are already discussing what government spending to prioritize. This framing is backwards. Maine families are the ones who generated this [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/new-revenue-forecast-shows-why-maine-should-cut-taxes-not-grow-government/"&gt;New Revenue Forecast Shows Why Maine Should Cut Taxes, Not Grow Government&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 16:03:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] “We Need to Put the Taxpayer In Control”</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/we-need-to-put-the-taxpayer-in-control/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="“We Need to Put the Taxpayer In Control”" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="337" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/itr-adel-12-03-25.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Central Iowa taxpayers and legislators voiced overwhelming frustration with high property taxes, citing rising local spending and a lack of transparency. Audience testimony highlighted widespread concern about school spending priorities and commercial property burdens, with many noting that facilities expansion has outpaced academic results and that high property taxes are discouraging business investment. Participants agreed that meaningful property tax relief must address the root cause—local spending growth—and put taxpayers back at the center of the system, not simply tweak levy rates or formulas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/we-need-to-put-the-taxpayer-in-control/"&gt;“We Need to Put the Taxpayer In Control”&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 16:13:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Nebraska Tax Reform: Why Full Expensing Is the Smart Move</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-tax-reform-why-full-expensing-is-the-smart-move/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The federal One Big Beautiful Bill (OBBB) creates the opportunity for Nebraska to adopt the most “America First” tax reform: full expensing. In an era of reshoring and friend-shoring critical supply chains, full expensing is the tax reform that properly defines “income” and incentivizes production in the U.S.A.   Full expensing is the policy of allowing...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-tax-reform-why-full-expensing-is-the-smart-move/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Nebraska Tax Reform: Why Full Expensing Is the Smart Move&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 16:55:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] Court Watch: Wisconsin Supreme Court Reverses, Consolidates Power Through New Court Management Order</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/court-watch-wisconsin-supreme-court-reverses-consolidates-power-through-new-court-management-order/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Court Watch: Wisconsin Supreme Court Reverses, Consolidates Power Through New Court Management Order Progressive majority reshapes internal court governance to cement its control of the judicial branch Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government’s Court Watch issued the following statement after the Wisconsin Supreme Court quietly issued a new court management order just days [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/court-watch-wisconsin-supreme-court-reverses-consolidates-power-through-new-court-management-order/"&gt;Court Watch: Wisconsin Supreme Court Reverses, Consolidates Power Through New Court Management Order&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 16:58:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Virginia’s Warning and a National 19-step Plan: Social Media Restriction and Age Verification Mandates</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/virginias-warning-and-a-national-19-step-plan-social-media-restriction-and-age-verification-mandates/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;NetChoice, a trade association advocating for free expression and enterprise online, filed a lawsuit against Virginia to stop a new age verification law last month. This challenge is hardly the first of its kind; age verification measures and government-designed social media mandates historically have faced a litany of challenges to their constitutionality and workability. Despite...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/virginias-warning-and-a-national-19-step-plan-social-media-restriction-and-age-verification-mandates/"&gt;Virginia’s Warning and a National 19-step Plan: Social Media Restriction and Age Verification Mandates&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 17:31:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] The Hidden Gem: Why Education Freedom is the New Economic Development</title><link>https://empowerms.org/the-hidden-gem-why-education-freedom-is-the-new-economic-development/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Forget industrial parks. The driver for economic growth in rural Mississippi is education freedom, which is the most powerful yet often overlooked tool in our economic development chest. I’ve dedicated my academic research to the topic, stemming from a comment I heard years ago at Starkville City Hall: “Education is the biggest driver of community-economic&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/the-hidden-gem-why-education-freedom-is-the-new-economic-development/"&gt;The Hidden Gem: Why Education Freedom is the New Economic Development&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 17:46:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] A4121 Is a Hatchet When New Jersey Needs a Scalpel</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/12/a4121-is-a-hatchet-when-new-jersey-needs-a-scalpel/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Today, I had the opportunity to testify before the Assembly Education Committee on A4121, a bill that would eliminate New [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/12/a4121-is-a-hatchet-when-new-jersey-needs-a-scalpel/"&gt;A4121 Is a Hatchet When New Jersey Needs a Scalpel&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 21:24:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Kansas City Homicide Rate May Be National Leader for 2025</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/criminal-justice/kansas-city-homicide-rate-may-be-national-leader-for-2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A story in the November 20 issue of The Washington Post examines homicide rates in large cities across the United [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/criminal-justice/kansas-city-homicide-rate-may-be-national-leader-for-2025/"&gt;Kansas City Homicide Rate May Be National Leader for 2025&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 21:40:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Over 292K Illinoisans remain jobless despite 318K jobs</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/over-292k-illinoisans-remain-jobless-despite-318k-jobs/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Despite 318,000 job openings, Illinois’ unemployment remained above national average in the latest economic measures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/over-292k-illinoisans-remain-jobless-despite-318k-jobs/"&gt;Over 292K Illinoisans remain jobless despite 318K jobs&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 22:37:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Majority of Wisconsin kids fall short in math as legislators consider fix</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/majority-of-wisconsin-kids-fall-short-in-math-as-legislators-consider-fix/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As math proficiency continues to decline in Wisconsin schools, the Legislature is considering a plan to improve numeracy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/majority-of-wisconsin-kids-fall-short-in-math-as-legislators-consider-fix/"&gt;Majority of Wisconsin kids fall short in math as legislators consider fix&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 22:48:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Working folks get short shrift while city funds vanity streetcar</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/working-folks-get-short-shrift-while-city-funds-vanity-streetcar/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Money wasted on Hop while bus access for people who really need it is at risk Milwaukee County’s bus network has swerved back from the fiscal brink, one tire halfway over the void as officials shuffle money, trim back some routes’ hours and wonder what they’ll do next year. Pay attention, Wisconsin taxpayers: You’re financing [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/working-folks-get-short-shrift-while-city-funds-vanity-streetcar/"&gt;Working folks get short shrift while city funds vanity streetcar&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 22:48:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Is your school district on track to fail? The massive fiscal shift in LA County</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/is-your-school-district-on-track-to-fail-the-massive-fiscal-shift-in-la-county/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=is-your-school-district-on-track-to-fail-the-massive-fiscal-shift-in-la-county</link><description>&lt;p&gt;It’s amazing what can happen in five years, especially when Gov. Gavin Newsom unilaterally imposed an overbearing pandemic lockdown on California’s school districts during this time period. And for an age group least likely to become ill with COVID-19. The coronavirus had a significant impact on local school district finances and they seemed to survive...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/is-your-school-district-on-track-to-fail-the-massive-fiscal-shift-in-la-county/"&gt;Is your school district on track to fail? The massive fiscal shift in LA County&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 23:15:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Politically Viable Water Supply Projects</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/politically-viable-water-supply-projects/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=politically-viable-water-supply-projects</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A few years ago I was involved in an effort to qualify a ballot initiative, the “Water Infrastructure Funding Act.” While we failed to gather sufficient signatures to get it onto the November 2022 state ballot, if it had been approved by voters, water scarcity in California would have been eliminated forever. Unfortunately, certain provisions...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/politically-viable-water-supply-projects/"&gt;Politically Viable Water Supply Projects&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 01:13:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] EVs and California’s Future Demand for Electricity</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/evs-and-californias-future-demand-for-electricity/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=evs-and-californias-future-demand-for-electricity</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When it comes to the achievement of “carbon neutrality” and the requisite energy policies to get there, few choices carry with them more consequences than the planned, nearly total electrification of our economy. And when it comes to electrification, few categories of consumption are likely to outweigh the demands of EVs. With a focus on...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/evs-and-californias-future-demand-for-electricity/"&gt;EVs and California’s Future Demand for Electricity&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 01:18:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Portland Public Schools’ Risky Real Estate Gamble</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/education/portland-public-schools-risky-real-estate-gamble/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Eric Fruits, Ph.D. On December 2,Portland Public Schools (PPS) board voted unanimously...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/education/portland-public-schools-risky-real-estate-gamble/"&gt;Portland Public Schools’ Risky Real Estate Gamble&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 01:25:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Fresno council balks at sensible housing-streamlining proposal</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/fresno-council-balks-at-sensible-housing-streamlining-proposal/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Fresno council balks at sensible housing-streamlining proposal by Sal Rodriguez &amp;#124; December 5, 2025 The answer to the housing shortage plaguing cities across the country isn’t really that hard – it’s to build more housing. But as a recent debate in Fresno, Calif., shows, it’s a lot easier said than done when city councilmembers feel [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/fresno-council-balks-at-sensible-housing-streamlining-proposal/"&gt;Fresno council balks at sensible housing-streamlining proposal&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 10:26:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Democrats don’t see Britain’s cautionary tale</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/democrats-dont-see-britains-cautionary-tale/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;John Daniel Davidson writes for the Federalist about lessons to be learned from Britain’s political decline. It’s easy to look at a collapsing civil society in a foreign country and comfort ourselves that, despite all our problems, we’re not as bad off as those people. Americans are especially apt to do this with our cousins...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/democrats-dont-see-britains-cautionary-tale/"&gt;Democrats don&amp;#8217;t see Britain&amp;#8217;s cautionary tale&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 10:39:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Government watchdog exposes Obamacare subsidy scam</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/government-watchdog-exposes-obamacare-subsidy-scam/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Victor Nava writes for the New York Post about the recent exposure of Obamacare subsidies’ flaws. Affordable Care Act subsidies have been granted, without the required documentation, to 90% of fictitious applicants over the last two years, according to a damning government watchdog report released Wednesday.&amp;#160; The Government Accountability Office’s (GAO) preliminary findings of ongoing...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/government-watchdog-exposes-obamacare-subsidy-scam/"&gt;Government watchdog exposes Obamacare subsidy scam&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 10:42:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] ‘Real Jobs’ unlikely to bring real jobs</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/real-jobs-unlikely-to-bring-real-jobs</link><description>Better is different from effective</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Week in Review: Exposing Academic Rot</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-exposing-academic-rot/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Academic journals play a key role in higher education’s advancement of human knowledge—universities use them to judge the quality of..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-exposing-academic-rot/"&gt;Week in Review: Exposing Academic Rot &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 16:21:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Arkansas Supreme Court Strikes Down City’s Illegal Trash Monopoly</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/arkansas-supreme-court-strikes-down-citys-illegal-trash-monopoly/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In an important victory for the right to earn a living, the Arkansas Supreme Court has ruled in favor of..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/arkansas-supreme-court-strikes-down-citys-illegal-trash-monopoly/"&gt;Arkansas Supreme Court Strikes Down City&amp;#8217;s Illegal Trash Monopoly&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 16:28:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] New Observations Confirm Skepticism of Creative Class Urbanism</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/municipal-policy/new-observations-confirm-skepticism-of-creative-class-urbanism/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In a recent Vox column, Rachel Cohen Booth argues that many American cities pursued a “creative‑class” strategy in the 2000s [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/municipal-policy/new-observations-confirm-skepticism-of-creative-class-urbanism/"&gt;New Observations Confirm Skepticism of Creative Class Urbanism&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 17:22:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] California Looking For ‘Foreign’ Aid</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/california-looking-for-foreign-aid/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;If there were a list of faltering, ineffective and counterproductive programs and projects that California policymakers are bitterly clinging to, the “bullet train” would be at the top. Voters asked for an ambitious high-speed rail that never leaves the state, but California cannot get the job done alone. The rest of the country has been [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/california-looking-for-foreign-aid/"&gt;California Looking For ‘Foreign’ Aid&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 17:26:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Debt Is the Fire—And Louisiana Is in the Path</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/tax-budget/debt-is-the-fire-and-louisiana-is-in-the-path/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Federal spending is out of control. Washington is racking up debt faster than at any time outside a world war or national emergency, and the consequences aren’t theoretical. They’re hitting state and local governments hard, especially in Louisiana. The national debt just blew past $38 trillion. This year’s deficit alone will be about $2 trillion,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/tax-budget/debt-is-the-fire-and-louisiana-is-in-the-path/"&gt;Debt Is the Fire—And Louisiana Is in the Path&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 18:16:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Before Spending Millions to Replace Federal Subsidies, Connecticut Should Audit Its Own Data</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/12/05/before-spending-millions-to-replace-federal-subsidies-connecticut-should-audit-its-own-data/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Access Health CT — the state’s health insurance exchange — recently warned that as many as 30 to 35 percent of its 150,000 marketplace enrollees may lose coverage in the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/12/05/before-spending-millions-to-replace-federal-subsidies-connecticut-should-audit-its-own-data/"&gt;Before Spending Millions to Replace Federal Subsidies, Connecticut Should Audit Its Own Data &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 19:18:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Extend Lahaina property tax waivers to prevent costs for unusable land</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/12/extend-lahaina-property-tax-waivers-to-prevent-costs-for-unusable-land/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Maui County Council on Dec. 5, 2025._____________ Dec. 5, 2025, 9 a.m.Kalana O Maui Building To: Maui County Council       Alice Lee, Chair       Yuki Lei Sugimura, Vice Chair From: Grassroot Institute of Hawaii            Jonathan Helton, Policy Analyst Re: Bill 171 (2025) [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/12/extend-lahaina-property-tax-waivers-to-prevent-costs-for-unusable-land/"&gt;Extend Lahaina property tax waivers to prevent costs for unusable land&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 19:21:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Joint development agreements could provide housing flexibility</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/12/joint-development-agreements-could-provide-housing-flexibility/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Maui County Council on Dec. 5, 2025._____________ Dec. 5, 2025, 9 a.m.Kalana O Maui Building To: Maui County Council       Alice Lee, Chair       Yuki Lei Sugimura, Vice Chair From: Grassroot Institute of Hawaii            Jonathan Helton, Policy Analyst Re: Resolution 25-222 — [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/12/joint-development-agreements-could-provide-housing-flexibility/"&gt;Joint development agreements could provide housing flexibility&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 19:26:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Grassroot testimonies submitted in December 2025</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/12/grassroot-testimonies-submitted-in-december-2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following are testimonies submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii in the first week of December 2025 for consideration by the Hawai‘i, Honolulu and Maui county councils: HAWAI‘I COUNTY &amp;#62;&amp;#62;&amp;#160;Bill 63 — “Allow single-family dwellings by-right in mixed-use zoning districts” &amp;#62;&amp;#62; Bill 103 — “Provide tax relief to aging farmers; cap ag land value [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/12/grassroot-testimonies-submitted-in-december-2025/"&gt;Grassroot testimonies submitted in December 2025&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 19:34:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Missouri’s Reading Crisis: 42% of Fourth-Graders Can Barely Read</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/education/missouris-reading-crisis-42-of-fourth-graders-can-barely-read/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Missouri is in a reading crisis. Forty-two percent of the state’s fourth-graders can barely read, the worst results in twenty [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/education/missouris-reading-crisis-42-of-fourth-graders-can-barely-read/"&gt;Missouri’s Reading Crisis: 42% of Fourth-Graders Can Barely Read&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 20:02:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Chicago Teachers Union protests trash fee hike while its president skips hers</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/chicago-teachers-union-protests-trash-fee-hike-while-its-president-skips-hers/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Chicago Teachers Union is grumbling about a proposed garbage fee hike. Yet union President Stacy Davis Gates has repeatedly failed to pay her own trash bill. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/chicago-teachers-union-protests-trash-fee-hike-while-its-president-skips-hers/"&gt;Chicago Teachers Union protests trash fee hike while its president skips hers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 20:03:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] A ‘Repeal Day’ glance at Liquor Commission revenues</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/12/a-repeal-day-glance-at-liquor-commission-revenues/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;December 5 is neither a federal nor state day of celebration, but it probably should be. On Dec. 5, 1933, Pennsylvania, Ohio and Utah became the final states to ratify the 21st Amendment to the U.S. Constitution.  The night before, toasting your Aunt Gertrude’s 92nd birthday with a glass of champagne was illegal. That evening, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/12/a-repeal-day-glance-at-liquor-commission-revenues/"&gt;A &amp;#8216;Repeal Day&amp;#8217; glance at Liquor Commission revenues&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 22:09:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Small Cost, Big Returns: Technical Schools Building Tennessee</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/small-cost-big-returns-technical-schools-building-tennessee/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=small-cost-big-returns-technical-schools-building-tennessee</link><description>Technical schools may not be the right choice for every high school graduate. Still, for those who have graduated from such programs, data shows they have the potential to make a good living while supporting their local communities, all while avoiding years of student loan payments.</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 22:10:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Norvax, CVS lead layoffs as Illinois loses 1,192 jobs</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/norvax-cvs-lead-layoffs-as-illinois-loses-1192-jobs/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Illinois’ saw 1,192 mass layoffs in November. Norvax and CVS Health/Oak Street accounted for most of the job losses announced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/norvax-cvs-lead-layoffs-as-illinois-loses-1192-jobs/"&gt;Norvax, CVS lead layoffs as Illinois loses 1,192 jobs&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 22:43:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Winners &amp; Losers: Big Map Wins &amp; Other Victories</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/winners-losers-big-map-wins-other-victories/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Every Friday morning, I join the Cardle &amp;#38; Woolley Show on Talk 1370 Radio in Austin to announce the week’s Winners &amp;#38; Losers. Not sure why there are so many more winners than losers this week, but here’s who made the list. WINNER: Texas Congressional District Map Stands The U.S. Supreme Court ruled yesterday that...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/winners-losers-big-map-wins-other-victories/"&gt;Winners &amp; Losers: Big Map Wins &amp; Other Victories&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 23:15:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Illegal Immigration and Elections: Only Idaho Votes in Idaho</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/illegal-immigration-and-elections-only-idaho-votes-in-idaho/</link><description>And now for some good news on the immigration issue in Idaho.&amp;#160; Our laws and our constitutional amendment prohibiting anyone but U.S. citizens from voting in Idaho elections seem to be working.&amp;#160; Recall, in 2024, House Joint Resolution 5 (carried by Rep. Kevin Andrus), referred to as "Idaho's only citizens vote measure," passed the Legislature [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 02:20:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Minnesota’s Economic News — W/E 12/5/25</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/minnesotas-economic-news-w-e-12-5-25/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;State and local taxes and spending Star Tribune: Budget battle brewing between mayor and outgoing Minneapolis City Council Duluth News Tribune: Local View: Minnesota has to stop treating taxpayers like an ATM West Central Tribune: Chippewa County commissioners concerned by more tax burden on local governments New Ulm Journal: Rate of taxation for city will...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/minnesotas-economic-news-w-e-12-5-25/"&gt;Minnesota’s Economic News — W/E 12/5/25&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 06:01:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/12/the-outstater-312/</link><description>THE LEADERSHIP&amp;#160;of my community is excited about a new economic boost that the mayor says is &amp;#8220;too good to pass up.&amp;#8221; Is it a tax break for local businesses? How about zoning reform, or more starter homes for young families? No? Reducing outdated permit requirements and regulations? None of that. They are excited about a&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/12/the-outstater-312/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 14:58:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] The Somali factor</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/the-somali-factor/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Former Star Tribune editor Patricia Lopez wrote on Bloomberg November 26, under the headline, We can stop fraud in Minnesota without attacking Somalis In a perfect world, Lopez is absolutely correct. She writes (non-paywall version here) that, It is true that Minnesota has seen an extraordinary rash of fraud in taxpayer-funded programs recently. More than...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/the-somali-factor/"&gt;The Somali factor&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 17:57:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Supreme Court will review Trump’s birthright citizenship order</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/the-un-supreme-court-will-review-trumps-birthright-citizenship-order/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The court made the announcement yesterday. Interested readers may want to consult my &amp;#8220;guide to the birthright citizenship debate.&amp;#8221; Here&amp;#8217;s an excerpt: Prof. Yoo makes what many will regard as a persuasive argument for its implementation. Yoo reminds us that when Kamala Harris was born in California in 1964, both her parents were in the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/the-un-supreme-court-will-review-trumps-birthright-citizenship-order/"&gt;Supreme Court will review Trump&amp;#8217;s birthright citizenship order&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 20:02:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Sanctuary Schools: Illegal Immigration’s Toll on Public Education</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/sanctuary-schools-illegal-immigrations-toll-on-public-education/</link><description>In October 2025, a law enforcement operation at a horse track in Wilder, Idaho, turned into the state’s largest immigration raid, resulting in the arrest of 105 suspected adult illegal aliens. Subsequently, the day following the raid, nearly 20% of students in the Wilder School District were reported absent. This incident reveals how mass immigration [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 01:04:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Fraud? What fraud?</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/fraud-what-fraud-2/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;From today&amp;#8217;s Star Tribune, Trump claims Minnesota lost billions to fraud. The evidence to date isn’t close. The Star Tribune&amp;#8216;s figure? $152 million. Or $0. I&amp;#8217;m not kidding. They write, A review of court records shows the alleged fraud uncovered to date is closer to $152 million Alleged? Convictions in federal court now exceed 60...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/fraud-what-fraud-2/"&gt;Fraud? What fraud?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 19:56:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Week in Review: The Invasion of Idaho</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/week-in-review-the-invasion-of-idaho/</link><description>The United States of America is in a crisis. For nearly five decades our nation has been under invasion from hordes of foreign nationals who have introduced crime, suppressed domestic wages, driven up the cost of living, overwhelmed our public services, and undermined our culture. Our Founding Fathers warned against the threat mass immigration posed [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 01:00:57 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>