<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>State-Policy Think-Tank Digest</title><link>https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml</link><description>Latest posts from free-market policy institutes across the U.S.</description><atom:link href="https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 21:03:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>[Alaskapolicyforum] Want better schools? Healthy competition is the difference</title><link>https://alaskapolicyforum.org/2025/06/want-better-schools-healthy-competition-is-the-difference/#utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=want-better-schools-healthy-competition-is-the-difference</link><description>&lt;div style="margin: 5px 5% 10px 5%;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" height="1440" src="https://alaskapolicyforum.org/wp-content/uploads/school-6900381_1920.jpg" title="" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite significant disparities in funding and adequacy, Florida dramatically outperforms Alaska in the quality of high school graduates. This is despite having a higher poverty rate than Alaska and twice the rate ofRead More&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alaskapolicyforum.org/2025/06/want-better-schools-healthy-competition-is-the-difference/"&gt;Want better schools? Healthy competition is the difference&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://alaskapolicyforum.org"&gt;Alaska Policy Forum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 00:54:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Rep. Lee Yancey: Kratom, Underground Markets, and the Demon Chipmunk</title><link>https://empowerms.org/rep-lee-yancey-kratom-underground-markets-and-the-demon-chipmunk/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;﻿ Rep. Lee Yancey: Kratom, Underground Markets, and the Demon Chipmunk In this episode, host, Grant Callen sits down with State Representative Lee Yancey, a seasoned lawmaker with 11 years of service in the Mississippi Legislature. A one-time Senator, Rep. Yancey now chairs the House Business and Commerce Committee and serves on eight other committees&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/rep-lee-yancey-kratom-underground-markets-and-the-demon-chipmunk/"&gt;Rep. Lee Yancey: Kratom, Underground Markets, and the Demon Chipmunk&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 01:00:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Arkansaspolicyfoundation] RIGHT TO TRY 2.0</title><link>https://arkansaspolicyfoundation.org/right-to-try-2-0/</link><description>RIGHT TO TRY 2.0   (2025-2Q) The idea behind Right-To-Try is that &amp;#8220;terminally ill patients who have exhausted their government-approved options&amp;#8221; should have the freedom to access treatments that may help them.(1)  The idea originated with the Goldwater Institute of Arizona, a member of the State Policy Network (SPN), a market-based group that includes the [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 06:11:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Virginiainstitute] How to navigate and improve Virginia’s education options</title><link>https://virginiainstitute.org/how-to-navigate-and-improve-virginias-education-options/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=how-to-navigate-and-improve-virginias-education-options</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 14:25:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Virginiainstitute] Elections in Virginia: Your Guide to Navigating the Law</title><link>https://virginiainstitute.org/elections-in-virginia-your-guide-to-navigating-the-law/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=elections-in-virginia-your-guide-to-navigating-the-law</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Lindsey Zea Senior Fellow Dr. Clara Belle Wheeler Senior Fellow&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org/elections-in-virginia-your-guide-to-navigating-the-law/"&gt;Elections in Virginia: Your Guide to Navigating the Law&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org"&gt;Virginia Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 14:49:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Rifreedom] Center CEO Mike Stenhouse To Be Inducted Into College Baseball Hall Of Fame</title><link>https://rifreedom.org/2025/06/center-ceo-mike-stenhouse-to-be-inducted-into-college-baseball-hall-of-fame/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;?The Rhode Island Center for Freedom &amp;#38; Prosperity Congratulates CEO Mike Stenhouse on Induction into College Baseball Hall of Fame Providence, RI &amp;#8211; The Rhode Island Center for Freedom &amp;#38; [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org/2025/06/center-ceo-mike-stenhouse-to-be-inducted-into-college-baseball-hall-of-fame/"&gt;Center CEO Mike Stenhouse To Be Inducted Into College Baseball Hall Of Fame&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org"&gt;RI Center for Freedom and Prosperity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 18:23:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Research Note: LB106 and the Nebraska livestock siting assessment matrix</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/research-note-lb106-and-the-nebraska-livestock-siting-assessment-matrix/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Note: This is the first in a series of Research Notes authored by this year&amp;#8217;s Platte Institute Summer Intern, Jakob Myers. Jakob is researching information related to zoning issues involving livestock facilities. The continued growth of Nebraska’s agricultural sector depends significantly on the development and expansion of livestock operations across the state. These projects typically...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/research-note-lb106-and-the-nebraska-livestock-siting-assessment-matrix/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Research Note: LB106 and the Nebraska livestock siting assessment matrix&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 20:32:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alaskapolicyforum] Alaska’s schools are rolling in cash, so why aren’t the results better?</title><link>https://alaskapolicyforum.org/2025/06/alaskas-schools-are-rolling-in-cash-so-why-arent-the-results-better/#utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=alaskas-schools-are-rolling-in-cash-so-why-arent-the-results-better</link><description>&lt;div style="margin: 5px 5% 10px 5%;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" height="1707" src="https://alaskapolicyforum.org/wp-content/uploads/Money-scaled.jpg" title="" width="2560" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alaska was ranked the second most adequately funded school system in the US by a 2024 study from Rutgers University. The rest of the story — the study actually understates how well neighborhood schoolsRead More&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alaskapolicyforum.org/2025/06/alaskas-schools-are-rolling-in-cash-so-why-arent-the-results-better/"&gt;Alaska’s schools are rolling in cash, so why aren’t the results better?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://alaskapolicyforum.org"&gt;Alaska Policy Forum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 02:25:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Virginiainstitute] Press Release – VIPP Champions AI Moratorium, Invokes Commerce Clause</title><link>https://virginiainstitute.org/5850-2/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=5850-2</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Virginia Institute for Public Policy’s statement for memorandum highlights the urgent need for a coordinated federal approach to AI regulation, leveraging constitutional authority to avoid a fragmented and counterproductive patchwork of state laws. The proposed moratorium offers a pragmatic pathway to safeguard innovation, support small businesses, and ensure U.S. leadership in the rapidly evolving global AI landscape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org/5850-2/"&gt;Press Release – VIPP Champions AI Moratorium, Invokes Commerce Clause&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org"&gt;Virginia Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 14:10:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] WILL Statement on Wisconsin Supreme Court Rejecting Partisan Efforts to Redraw Congressional Maps</title><link>https://will-law.org/will-statement-on-wisconsin-supreme-court-rejecting-partisan-efforts-to-redraw-congressional-maps/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The News: The Wisconsin Supreme Court today declined to hear challenges seeking to redraw the state’s current congressional district maps, effectively ensuring the maps will remain in place for the 2026 midterm elections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/will-statement-on-wisconsin-supreme-court-rejecting-partisan-efforts-to-redraw-congressional-maps/"&gt;WILL Statement on Wisconsin Supreme Court Rejecting Partisan Efforts to Redraw Congressional Maps&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 23:25:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cardinalinstitute] Colleges Must Educate for Freedom</title><link>https://cardinalinstitute.com/colleges-must-educate-for-freedom/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Colleges Must Educate for Freedom A great American college or university will prepare students for self-governance as both a wise human being and a prudent, productive citizen. Rightly understood, the liberal arts are the intellectual potentials shared by the leaders of a free people. That is, education policy should consider, first of all, how to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com/colleges-must-educate-for-freedom/"&gt;Colleges Must Educate for Freedom&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com"&gt;Cardinal Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 16:31:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Education Freedom: A Lifeline for Tennessee Families</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/education-freedom-a-lifeline-for-tennessee-families/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=education-freedom-a-lifeline-for-tennessee-families</link><description>Education Freedom Scholarships won’t just change where kids go to school. They’ll change who they become.</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 18:15:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Group II pension compromise allows, but limits, pension spiking</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/06/group-ii-pension-compromise-allows-but-limits-pension-spiking/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Legislative leaders and Gov. Kelly Ayotte worked out a compromise on Group II pension benefits on Wednesday, the day before the House and Senate were scheduled to vote on the budget the governor had threatened to veto over those benefits. The late deal settles six main points of disagreement, including one of the big disputes [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/06/group-ii-pension-compromise-allows-but-limits-pension-spiking/"&gt;Group II pension compromise allows, but limits, pension spiking&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 19:15:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Arkansaspolicyfoundation] MEDICAL CARE IDEAS ADVANCE</title><link>https://arkansaspolicyfoundation.org/medical-care-ideas-advance/</link><description>(2025-2Q) The Arkansas Policy Foundation was founded by business leaders to serve the community and advance ideas to create more prosperity for Arkansans. The Policy Foundation was founded 30 years ago as a 501(c)(3) nonprofit, nonpartisan think tank that publishes credible research, hosts forums to encourage citizenship and is cited in national and state news [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 06:09:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] Paul sits down with Vance Ginn for “Let People Prosper” podcast</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/paul-sits-down-with-vance-ginn-for-let-people-prosper-podcast/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Why does New Mexico, rich in resources and culture, remain poor in economic freedom? That’s the question I explore in this week’s Let People Prosper Show with Paul Gessing, president of the Rio Grande Foundation. Paul brings nearly two decades of insight into New Mexico’s political and economic trends, offering a sobering look at why the state is falling behind and [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/paul-sits-down-with-vance-ginn-for-let-people-prosper-podcast/"&gt;Paul sits down with Vance Ginn for &amp;#8220;Let People Prosper&amp;#8221; podcast&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 17:59:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Frontierinstitute] Recent Permitting Reforms Are Protecting Property Rights</title><link>https://frontierinstitute.org/recent-permitting-reforms-are-protecting-property-rights/</link><description>"What property rights are unequivocally not, however, is a license to control what others do with their own property."</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 18:27:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] WILL Reacts to SCOTUS Parental Rights Ruling</title><link>https://will-law.org/will-reacts-to-scotus-parental-rights-ruling/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL released a statement praising the U.S. Supreme Court’s (SCOTUS) 6–3 ruling in Mahmoud v. Taylor—a landmark parental rights case that confirms parents’ ability to challenge school curricula and potentially other school policies and practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/will-reacts-to-scotus-parental-rights-ruling/"&gt;WILL Reacts to SCOTUS Parental Rights Ruling&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 21:56:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Job Licensing Reviews: Business and Labor Committee and General Affairs Committee</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/job-licensing-reviews-business-general-affairs-and-labor-committee-and-general-affairs-committee/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;[Note: This is the second in a group of articles reviewing occupational licensing reviews for the first five-plus years of the Occupational Board Reform Act. For more context, see this post.] The Business and Labor Committee has reviewed a number of licenses from 2019 to 2024. Their areas of review included: Boiler Safety/Pressure Vessel Inspectors...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/job-licensing-reviews-business-general-affairs-and-labor-committee-and-general-affairs-committee/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Job Licensing Reviews: Business and Labor Committee and General Affairs Committee&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 13:19:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] Shapiro, House Democrats Miss the Budget Deadline Again, With No Deal in Sight</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/06/30/shapiro-house-democrats-miss-the-budget-deadline-again-with-no-deal-in-sight/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Harrisburg, Pa., June 30, 2025 —Today marks the end of Pennsylvania’s fiscal year and the deadline for lawmakers to pass the FY 2025–26 state budget, with no apparent deal in sight. Pennsylvania stares down yet another budget impasse under Gov. Josh Shapiro, his third in as many years. In this year’s proposed budget, Democratic leaders [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/06/30/shapiro-house-democrats-miss-the-budget-deadline-again-with-no-deal-in-sight/"&gt;Shapiro, House Democrats Miss the Budget Deadline Again, With No Deal in Sight&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 20:15:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] A better way to get welfare recipients back into the labor force</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/better-way-to-get-welfare-recipients-back-into-labor-force/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;If the One Big Beautiful Bill becomes law, states will quickly discover that their administrative systems are ill-equipped to move recipients from welfare to work. To succeed, states should adopt a more integrated approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/better-way-to-get-welfare-recipients-back-into-labor-force/"&gt;A better way to get welfare recipients back into the labor force&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 07:20:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] 2025 City Freedom Index: How Free is Your City?</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/2025-city-freedom-index/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=2025-city-freedom-index</link><description>In 2020, Beacon released its first-ever City Freedom Index to shed light on the ways taxpayers are impacted by local government policies. Five years and many changed local policies later, the time has come for an update.</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 11:30:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] WATCH: Megan Martin on PCN Discussing State Budget, Mass Transit Bail-out, and More</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/07/01/watch-megan-martin-on-pcn-discussing-state-budget-mass-transit-bail-out-and-more/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Megan Martin, Commonwealth Foundation&amp;#8217;s Chief Operating Officer and General Counsel, joins PCN&amp;#8217;s Capitol Preview to talk all things state budget. From public transit to Lifeline Scholarships, Martin outlines what good looks like in this year&amp;#8217;s budget, and which proposals will damage Pennsylvania&amp;#8217;s economic future. Watch below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/07/01/watch-megan-martin-on-pcn-discussing-state-budget-mass-transit-bail-out-and-more/"&gt;WATCH: Megan Martin on PCN Discussing State Budget, Mass Transit Bail-out, and More&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 13:27:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] How both sides lost the ConVal school funding case</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/07/how-both-sides-lost-the-conval-school-funding-case/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday morning, the New Hampshire Supreme Court for the first time ordered the state to spend a minimum amount of money—$7,356.01 per pupil—to educate public school students.  The state therefore lost this landmark school funding case, Contoocook Valley School District v. State, as it had tried to avoid such a decree. But a closer [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/07/how-both-sides-lost-the-conval-school-funding-case/"&gt;How both sides lost the ConVal school funding case&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 17:57:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Cascade Quarterly Spring 2025</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/newsletters/cascade-quarterly-spring-2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Download the full PDF here&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/newsletters/cascade-quarterly-spring-2025/"&gt;Cascade Quarterly Spring 2025&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:59:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Education officials top the 2024 KPERS ‘millionaires’ list</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/2024-kpers-millionaires/</link><description>Data provided by the Kansas Public Employees Retirement System shows that Kansas has 4,758 KPERS ‘millionaires’—state and local government retirees who will collect at least $1 million in pension benefits over their first 20 years of retirement. That is an increase of 380 over last year. The complete list of KPERS ‘millionaires’ can be found at KansasOpenGov.org. [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 13:25:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Voters Aren’t Interested in New Transportation Taxes</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/transportation/voters-arent-interested-in-new-transportation-taxes/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By John A. Charles, Jr. The Oregon legislature ended on June 27 without...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/transportation/voters-arent-interested-in-new-transportation-taxes/"&gt;Voters Aren’t Interested in New Transportation Taxes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 14:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Press Release: Mississippi Center for Public Policy Named Finalist for National Bob Williams Award</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/press-release-mississippi-center-for-public-policy-named-finalist-for-national-bob-williams-award/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE (Jackson, MS) Mississippi Center for Public Policy Named Finalist for National Bob Williams Award The Mississippi Center for Public Policy (MCPP) has been selected as a finalist for the prestigious Bob Williams Award for Outstanding Policy Achievement in the “Biggest Home State Win” category. This national recognition, awarded by the State Policy [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/press-release-mississippi-center-for-public-policy-named-finalist-for-national-bob-williams-award/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Press Release: Mississippi Center for Public Policy Named Finalist for National Bob Williams Award&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 15:02:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Closing the Gap: How Wisconsin’s Budget Continues to Close the Funding Gap Between Public &amp; Parental Choice Options</title><link>https://will-law.org/closing-the-gap-how-wisconsins-budget-continues-to-close-the-funding-gap-between-public-parental-choice-options/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Like any budget that is a result of compromise in divided government, there are positive and negative aspects.  But one definite positive to come from this year's budget agreement is the continued closing of the spending gap between private, charter, and traditional public schools.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/closing-the-gap-how-wisconsins-budget-continues-to-close-the-funding-gap-between-public-parental-choice-options/"&gt;Closing the Gap: How Wisconsin’s Budget Continues to Close the Funding Gap Between Public &amp;#038; Parental Choice Options&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 18:57:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Lawmakers and Activists Celebrate Toothless Climate Bills</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/07/02/lawmakers-and-activists-celebrate-toothless-climate-bills/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="675" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/thumbnail_facebook_x_4.png" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On July 1, environmental activists, alongside state officials and lawmakers, praised Gov. Ned Lamont for signing two climate bills, H.B. 5004 and S.B. 9, heralded as groundbreaking legislation. Yet, despite [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/07/02/lawmakers-and-activists-celebrate-toothless-climate-bills/"&gt;Lawmakers and Activists Celebrate Toothless Climate Bills&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 21:45:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] Court Watch: Karofsky Court Leans Into Partisan Rhetoric In Abortion Decision</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/court-watch-karofsky-court-leans-into-partisan-rhetoric-in-abortion-decision/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Court Watch: Karofsky Court Leans Into Partisan Rhetoric In Abortion Decision Court uses rarely used doctrine to achieve preferred policy outcome Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government (IRG) released the following statement following the Wisconsin Supreme Court’s ruling in Josh Kaul v. Joel Urmanski. The majority’s decision utilized implied repeal to strike down [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/court-watch-karofsky-court-leans-into-partisan-rhetoric-in-abortion-decision/"&gt;Court Watch: Karofsky Court Leans Into Partisan Rhetoric In Abortion Decision&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 15:53:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Welfare stands in the way of the American dream</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/welfare-stands-in-the-way-of-the-american-dream/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Meaningful relationships and a strong sense of community are as much a part of the American dream as any economic measure. What’s rarely discussed is how systemic obstacles are undermining these important aspects of a flourishing life. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/welfare-stands-in-the-way-of-the-american-dream/"&gt;Welfare stands in the way of the American dream&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 18:55:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] The truth about MPS, who makes it to graduation and who doesn’t</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/the-truth-about-mps-who-makes-it-to-graduation-and-who-doesnt/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The big picture: For every kid who enters MPS as a freshman each fall and goes on post-secondary education, there are at least two who do not, at least not in the year after high school ended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/the-truth-about-mps-who-makes-it-to-graduation-and-who-doesnt/"&gt;The truth about MPS, who makes it to graduation and who doesn’t &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 19:04:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] OBBB Delivers Historic Expansion of Educational Choice, Sweeping Reforms</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/07/03/obbb-delivers-historic-expansion-of-educational-choice-sweeping-reforms/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Harrisburg, Pa., July 3, 2025 —&amp;#160;After much anticipation and debate, the One Big, Beautiful Bill (OBBB) is now passed and set to be enacted—delivering policy accomplishments that Pennsylvanians can celebrate: Protecting Taxpayers: Preventing an average $2,500 tax hike per Pennsylvania taxpayer. Nearly every Pennsylvanian has benefited from the 2017 Tax Cuts and Job Act, which [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/07/03/obbb-delivers-historic-expansion-of-educational-choice-sweeping-reforms/"&gt;OBBB Delivers Historic Expansion of Educational Choice, Sweeping Reforms&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 19:17:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Are we witnessing a Baltimore Miracle in the fight against crime?</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/baltimore-miracle-in-fight-against-crime/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Baltimore has struggled with crime, especially drugs and violent crime, in both reality and in the imaginations of the American people for decades. That is, until recently. What changed and what can other high-crime cities learn from Baltimore's approach? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/baltimore-miracle-in-fight-against-crime/"&gt;Are we witnessing a Baltimore Miracle in the fight against crime?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 19:33:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Fiscal Restraint Worked. So Obviously, It Has to Go</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/07/03/fiscal-restraint-worked-so-obviously-it-has-to-go/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The General Assembly adjourned less than a month ago, but progressive activists are already calling for more taxes, more spending, and another round of fiscal recklessness — wasting no time [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/07/03/fiscal-restraint-worked-so-obviously-it-has-to-go/"&gt;Fiscal Restraint Worked. So Obviously, It Has to Go &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 19:35:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] Tipping Point NM episode 722 Daniel Chavez – Candidate for Mayor of Albuquerque</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/tipping-point-nm-episode-722-daniel-chavez-candidate-for-mayor-of-albuquerque/</link><description>&lt;p&gt; Albuquerque Mayoral candidate Daniel Chavez has completed the Rio Grande Foundation&amp;#8217;s candidate survey.  You can find that completed survey here and below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/tipping-point-nm-episode-722-daniel-chavez-candidate-for-mayor-of-albuquerque/"&gt;Tipping Point NM episode 722 Daniel Chavez – Candidate for Mayor of Albuquerque&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 19:38:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/07/the-outstater-277/</link><description>We&amp;#8217;re All Greta Thunberg Now SOME OF US&amp;#160;no longer&amp;#160;pay&amp;#160;attention to opinion surveys. We assume, politics and media being what they are, that the public is too ill-informed to have anything useful to say. One recent poll, though, begs analysis. It&amp;#160;finds that a good majority of&amp;#160;young Americans&amp;#160;are not proud to be Americans. Now, it is wise&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/07/the-outstater-277/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 21:53:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] How Washington’s Budget Bill Will Affect Health Care in New York</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/how-washingtons-budget-bill-will-affect/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: The final version of the federal budget bill omitted a handful of provisions that had been included in earlier....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/how-washingtons-budget-bill-will-affect/"&gt;How Washington&amp;#8217;s Budget Bill Will Affect Health Care in New York&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 23:24:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Norman Rockwell</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/norman-rockwell/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/norman-rockwell/" rel="nofollow" title="Norman Rockwell"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="580" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Prop-1-Exposed-2-27.png" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;In celebration of our national heritage, we continue our Pride in America series by honoring Norman Rockwell, an artist whose work didn't just illustrate America, but helped define its soul. For decades, his captivating images on the covers of the Saturday Evening Post chronicled the idealized spirit of American life, capturing moments of everyday joy, [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 22:01:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Andrew Jackson</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/andrew-jackson/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/andrew-jackson/" rel="nofollow" title="Andrew Jackson"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="580" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Prop-1-Exposed-2-28.png" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;In celebration of our national heritage, we finish our Pride in America series by honoring a duelist, frontiersman, populist, war hero, statesman, and patriot: Andrew Jackson.  Well before Jackson ascended to the Presidency, he earned renown as one of the nation’s first military heroes. During the War of 1812, Jackson rallied a force of several [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2025 00:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] Franke: Population Worries</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/07/franke-population-worries/</link><description>by Mark Franke During the 50 plus years of my adult lifetime, world population has been an issue but with a change in perspective. In the 1960s the concern was uncontrolled and unsupportable growth especially in the poorer parts of the globe. The doomsayers predicted mass starvation and other unpleasant outcomes unless the rate of&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/07/franke-population-worries/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2025 22:06:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Schools After the Storm with Noah Devine</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/education/schools-after-the-storm-with-noah-devine/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Susan Pendergrass speaks with Noah Devine, executive director of the Missouri Charter Public Schools Association, about how charter schools in [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/education/schools-after-the-storm-with-noah-devine/"&gt;Schools After the Storm with Noah Devine&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 11:55:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] New school finance formula should focus on accountability</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/new-school-finance-accountability/</link><description>Funding for public K-12 education is complex—let alone increasing every year. The formula for determining how much money each district receives– available here – requires an Excel workbook with 12 individual spreadsheets. The main spreadsheet, Legalmax, is essentially a roll-up of the other 11. It takes 85 columns of data to determine the Legalmax and [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 14:00:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] A Game-Changer for School Choice in Our State!</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/a-game-changer-for-school-choice-in-our-state/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Some groundbreaking news for Mississippi!&amp;#160; With the passage of the&amp;#160;One Big Beautiful Bill, a federal tax credit is due to transform the school choice landscape in our state. &amp;#160;This new tax credit enables individual donors to fund scholarships for local Mississippi families, who will now be able to select the schools that best suit their [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/a-game-changer-for-school-choice-in-our-state/" rel="nofollow"&gt;A Game-Changer for School Choice in Our State!&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 17:57:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] 97 NYSLRS Retirees Eligible for Pensions Over $200K in FY2025</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/97-nyslrs-retirees-eligible-for-pensions-over-200k-in-fy2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A total of 97 retirees from the New York State and Local Retirement System (NYSLRS) were eligible for pensions of....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/97-nyslrs-retirees-eligible-for-pensions-over-200k-in-fy2025/"&gt;97 NYSLRS Retirees Eligible for Pensions Over $200K in FY2025&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 13:50:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] Court Watch: Wisconsin Supreme Court Concentrates Even More Power in the Evers Administration</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/court-watch-wisconsin-supreme-court-concentrates-even-more-power-in-the-evers-administration/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Court Watch: Wisconsin Supreme Court Concentrates Even More Power in the Evers Administration Ruling in Evers v. Marklein takes away ability of legislature’s JCRAR Committee to suspend administrative rules Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government (IRG) released the following statement following the Wisconsin Supreme Court’s ruling in Evers v. Marklein. The majority’s decision [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/court-watch-wisconsin-supreme-court-concentrates-even-more-power-in-the-evers-administration/"&gt;Court Watch: Wisconsin Supreme Court Concentrates Even More Power in the Evers Administration&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 15:03:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Saving America’s Family Farms: A Rural Revival</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/saving-americas-family-farms-a-rural-revival/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;States like Nebraska – and my native Wisconsin – face one of the biggest challenges, and public policy opportunities, you are likely to find in America.  Our family farms in rural areas across the country have been disappearing at the staggering rate of 45,000 per year on average for the past century. The incredible thing...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/saving-americas-family-farms-a-rural-revival/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Saving America’s Family Farms: A Rural Revival&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 16:54:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Frontierinstitute] Montana Leading with Free Market Healthcare</title><link>https://frontierinstitute.org/montana-leading-with-free-market-healthcare/</link><description>By eliminating the middlemen and bureaucracy involved in billing third parties, DPC providers are able to save patients money and focus on their health while also being radically transparent with their prices – a breath of fresh air in today’s modern healthcare world.</description><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 18:26:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Understanding the One Big Beautiful Bill with Elias Tsapelas</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/economy/understanding-the-one-big-beautiful-bill-with-elias-tsapelas/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Susan Pendergrass is joined by Elias Tsapelas, director of state budget and fiscal policy at the Show-Me Institute, to break [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/economy/understanding-the-one-big-beautiful-bill-with-elias-tsapelas/"&gt;Understanding the One Big Beautiful Bill with Elias Tsapelas&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 20:57:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Congress, Not the President, Sets Taxes—Including Tariffs</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/congress-not-the-president-sets-taxes-including-tariffs/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Goldwater Institute along with the Dallas Market Center—a private business in Texas—filed a friend of the court brief today..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/congress-not-the-president-sets-taxes-including-tariffs/"&gt;Congress, Not the President, Sets Taxes—Including Tariffs&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 23:21:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] What’s in a NAEP Score?</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/performance/whats-in-a-naep-score/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The National Assessment of Educational Progress (NAEP), often called the Nation’s Report Card, is the gold standard for measuring academic [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/performance/whats-in-a-naep-score/"&gt;What’s in a NAEP Score?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 00:46:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Dr. Keri Ingraham: Industry-Specific High Schools</title><link>https://empowerms.org/dr-keri-ingraham-industry-specific-high-schools/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Dr. Keri Ingraham: Industry-Specific High Schools Join us on the Empower Podcast as we dive into the transformative world of industry-specific high schools with Dr. Keri Ingraham, whose recent policy brief at the American Enterprise Institute, “The Case for Industry-Specific High Schools,” is sparking conversation. In this episode, Dr. Ingraham explains why these specialized schools&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/dr-keri-ingraham-industry-specific-high-schools/"&gt;Dr. Keri Ingraham: Industry-Specific High Schools&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 01:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Mackinac ferry regulatory expansion is bad policy</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/mackinac-ferry-regulatory-expansion-is-bad-policy</link><description>Proposed bill repeats past transportation regulation mistakes</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] KSDE denies lowering standards despite implausible proficiency gains</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/ksde-denies-lowering-standards/</link><description>Kansas Department of Education (KSDE) staff put on a master class of political spin and deception at yesterday’s meeting of the State Board of Education. Board members were given the 2025 state assessment results based on a new test and cut scores to determine achievement levels, and were told to ignore conflicting historical results and [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 13:08:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] HB 2089 Brings Oregon into Compliance with the Supreme Court’s Tyler Ruling on Property Rights and Home Equity</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/tax-and-budget/hb-2089-brings-oregon-into-compliance-with-the-supreme-courts-tyler-ruling-on-property-rights-and-home-equity/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Kathryn Hickok With the passage of House Bill 2089 in late June,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/tax-and-budget/hb-2089-brings-oregon-into-compliance-with-the-supreme-courts-tyler-ruling-on-property-rights-and-home-equity/"&gt;HB 2089 Brings Oregon into Compliance with the Supreme Court’s Tyler Ruling on Property Rights and Home Equity&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 14:06:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Washington's Supreme Court hides the ball on state employee compensation offers</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/washington-s-supreme-court-hides-the-ball-on-state-employee-compensation-offers</link><description>In a shocking 8-1 ruling , the Washington State Supreme Court has given its official blessing to a secretive process that allows the...</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 14:39:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] NJ POLICY INSTITUTE AMICUS BRIEF ACCEPTED BY APPELLATE COURT IN SCHOOL SEGREGATION LAWSUIT</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/07/nj-policy-institute-amicus-brief-accepted-by-appellate-court-in-school-segregation-lawsuit/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 15:46:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] Tim Walz Leaves Minnesotans on the Hook for a $430,000 Legal Bill</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/tim-walz-leaves-minnesotans-on-the-hook-for-a-430000-legal-bill/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Minnesota Gov. Tim Walz already has taxpayer-funded legal counsel. Additionally, he has access to the Attorney General&amp;#8217;s office. Yet, Minnesota taxpayers are now left to foot a $430,000 legal bill from outside lawyers that Walz racked up trying to prepare for a congressional hearing where he provided testimony on his Sanctuary City illegal immigration policies. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/tim-walz-leaves-minnesotans-on-the-hook-for-a-430000-legal-bill/"&gt;Tim Walz Leaves Minnesotans on the Hook for a $430,000 Legal Bill&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 19:22:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG Poll: Wisconsin Has a New State Budget; Voters Want Specific Solutions Next</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-poll-wisconsin-has-a-new-state-budget-voters-want-specific-solutions-next/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;IRG Poll: Wisconsin Has a New State Budget; Voters Want Specific Solutions Next   High approval ratings may give politicians comfort, but won’t pay the bills  Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government (IRG) is continuing its public polling project with Napolitan News Service and Scott Rasmussen in 2025, with the focus in this poll [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-poll-wisconsin-has-a-new-state-budget-voters-want-specific-solutions-next/"&gt;IRG Poll: Wisconsin Has a New State Budget; Voters Want Specific Solutions Next&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 20:44:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] What the “One Big Beautiful Bill Act” Means for School Choice in Mississippi</title><link>https://empowerms.org/what-the-one-big-beautiful-bill-act-means-for-school-choice-in-mississippi/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;There are two aspects to the school choice provisions in the OBBB: a tax credit for contributions to organizations that provide scholarships to students in public or private schools, and rules those organizations have to follow in granting scholarships (including eligibility of scholarship students).  Tax Credit for Contributions  Starting in 2027, an individual taxpayer (not&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/what-the-one-big-beautiful-bill-act-means-for-school-choice-in-mississippi/"&gt;What the “One Big Beautiful Bill Act” Means for School Choice in Mississippi&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 21:47:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] A Tax Revolt Then—and Now</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/a-tax-revolt-then-and-now/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;How the American Revolution’s fight over taxation without representation still echoes in today’s battle against rising property taxes in Iowa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we gather each July 4th for fireworks, pool parties, cookouts, and time with family, it’s easy to forget what the holiday actually commemorates: a revolution sparked, in large part, by a tax fight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Independence Day celebrates the birth of a new nation, the catalyst for that bold break from Britain wasn’t just lofty ideas of liberty, it was taxation without representation. What began with protests in Boston soon became a widespread colonial movement. Today in Iowa, we face a different but equally pressing tax problem: one of consent, accountability, and runaway property taxes, now exceeding $7 billion in 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/a-tax-revolt-then-and-now/"&gt;A Tax Revolt Then—and Now&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 23:59:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Freedom notes U.S.A.: No unemployment benefits for strikers</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/freedom-notes-usa-no-unemployment-benefits-for-strikers</link><description>Colorado wolf program devours budget; Texas enacts pro-housing laws</description><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 09:59:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] A Closer Look at Louisiana’s 2026 Budget: Pork Projects and Missed Priorities</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/tax-budget/a-closer-look-at-louisianas-2026-budget-pork-projects-and-missed-priorities/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Last month, the 2025 Louisiana Regular Legislative Session adjourned—and much happened in the final stretch. Before final passage, major budget bills for Fiscal Year 2025-2026 were amended by the Senate Finance Committee and on the Senate Floor, with new appropriations added for favored municipalities and pet projects. Governor Landry used his line-item veto authority to...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/tax-budget/a-closer-look-at-louisianas-2026-budget-pork-projects-and-missed-priorities/"&gt;A Closer Look at Louisiana’s 2026 Budget: Pork Projects and Missed Priorities&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 13:10:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Silver Linings, Not Silver Bullets</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/silver-linings-not-silver-bullets/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;At the end of June, the Supreme Court of the United States reached its decision in Free Speech Coalition v. Paxton, ruling in favor of a Texas law that requires age verification for access to websites that host explicit content. The decision is a break from precedent and presents a heightened risk to user privacy,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/silver-linings-not-silver-bullets/"&gt;Silver Linings, Not Silver Bullets&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 13:13:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Does the Middle-Ground Still Exist? Exploring How Party-Dominance Erodes Bipartisanship</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/blog/usdatalabs/does-the-middle-ground-still-exist-exploring-how-party-dominance-erodes-bipartisanship/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A system that offers voters limited electoral choice has the potential to undermine democracy. When candidates don’t face primary opponents or general election challengers, it is harder to hold them accountable to the will of voters. The lack of political competition can have broader implications: when compromise becomes scarce, governance suffers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/blog/usdatalabs/does-the-middle-ground-still-exist-exploring-how-party-dominance-erodes-bipartisanship/"&gt;Does the Middle-Ground Still Exist? Exploring How Party-Dominance Erodes Bipartisanship&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 14:15:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] JMI Welcomes New Media Relations Manager</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/jmi-welcomes-new-media-relations-manager/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE July 10, 2025 CONTACT Logan Elizabeth Padgett 850-386-3131 JMI Welcomes New Media Relations Manager TALLAHASSEE...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/jmi-welcomes-new-media-relations-manager/"&gt;JMI Welcomes New Media Relations Manager&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] NJ SPOTLIGHT: Marathon school segregation case goes to appeals court</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/07/nj-spotlight-marathon-school-segregation-case-goes-to-appeals-court/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In this NJ Spotlight News piece, the long-running New Jersey school segregation case moves to the Appellate Division. As the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/07/nj-spotlight-marathon-school-segregation-case-goes-to-appeals-court/"&gt;NJ SPOTLIGHT: Marathon school segregation case goes to appeals court&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 15:56:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] NORTHJERSEY.COM: Appeals court to hear arguments in NJ school segregation lawsuit</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/07/northjersey-com-appeals-court-to-hear-arguments-in-nj-school-segregation-lawsuit/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In this NorthJersey.com article, the New Jersey appellate court prepares to hear arguments in the high‑profile school segregation lawsuit filed [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/07/northjersey-com-appeals-court-to-hear-arguments-in-nj-school-segregation-lawsuit/"&gt;NORTHJERSEY.COM: Appeals court to hear arguments in NJ school segregation lawsuit&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 16:00:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Allow agricultural tourism activities by-right in Maui ag districts</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/07/allow-agricultural-tourism-activities-by-right-in-maui-ag-districts/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Maui County Council on July 8, 2025._____________ July 8, 2025, 9 a.m.Kalana O Maui Building To: Maui County Council&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Alice Lee, Chair&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Yuki Lei Sugimura, Vice Chair From: Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Jonathan Helton, Policy Researcher Re: Bill 75 (2025), [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/07/allow-agricultural-tourism-activities-by-right-in-maui-ag-districts/"&gt;Allow agricultural tourism activities by-right in Maui ag districts&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 16:27:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Increase property tax exemption for homeowners under age 65</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/07/increase-property-tax-exemption-for-homeowners-under-age-65/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Honolulu City Council on July 9, 2025._____________ July 9, 2025, 10 a.m.Honolulu Hale To: Honolulu City Council       Tommy Waters, Chair       Andria Tupola, Vice Chair From: Grassroot Institute of Hawaii            Ted Kefalas, Director of Strategic Campaigns RE: Bill 50 (2025) — [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/07/increase-property-tax-exemption-for-homeowners-under-age-65/"&gt;Increase property tax exemption for homeowners under age 65&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 16:28:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Increase property tax exemption for homeowners age 65 and older</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/07/increase-property-tax-exemption-for-homeowners-age-65-and-older/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Honolulu City Council on July 9, 2025._____________ July 9, 2025, 10 a.m.Honolulu Hale To: Honolulu City Council       Tommy Waters, Chair       Andria Tupola, Vice Chair From: Grassroot Institute of Hawaii            Ted Kefalas, Director of Strategic Campaigns RE: Bill 49 (2025) — [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/07/increase-property-tax-exemption-for-homeowners-age-65-and-older/"&gt;Increase property tax exemption for homeowners age 65 and older&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 16:30:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] Congressional Republicans Call Out Walz’s ‘Wasted Taxpayer Money’</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/congressional-republicans-call-out-walzs-wasted-taxpayer-money/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Minnesota Republicans criticized the use of taxpayer funds for the legal counsel, with U.S. House Majority Whip Tom Emmer calling the governor a “scam artist” and Rep. Pete Stauber saying, “more wasted taxpayer money by the ‘knucklehead.’” It&amp;#8217;s extremely disappointing that the governor felt the need to burn nearly half a million dollars of taxpayer [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/congressional-republicans-call-out-walzs-wasted-taxpayer-money/"&gt;Congressional Republicans Call Out Walz&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8216;Wasted Taxpayer Money&amp;#8217;&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 18:39:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Is California’s Water Infrastructure Ready for Climate Whiplash?</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/is-californias-water-infrastructure-ready-for-climate-whiplash/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=is-californias-water-infrastructure-ready-for-climate-whiplash</link><description>&lt;p&gt;If there is anything that might constitute an overwhelming institutional consensus in California, it’s that we are experiencing climate change, and that one of the consequences will be more rain, less snow, and more so-called whiplash between very wet years and very dry years. In an average year these days, 30 million acre feet of water...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/is-californias-water-infrastructure-ready-for-climate-whiplash/"&gt;Is California’s Water Infrastructure Ready for Climate Whiplash?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 21:21:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Iowa Property Tax Growth Continues in FY 2026</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/iowa-property-tax-growth-continues-in-fy-2026/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Property tax collections from Iowa schools, cities (1,000+ population), and counties grew by $239.8 million—or 3.9%—from FY 2025 to FY 2026. Schools led the increase with a 4.4% rise, followed by cities at 4.2% and counties at 2.7%.&lt;br /&gt;
Over the past two years, total property tax growth across these local governments has exceeded 10%, raising concerns about long-term taxpayer impact and spending discipline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/iowa-property-tax-growth-continues-in-fy-2026/"&gt;Iowa Property Tax Growth Continues in FY 2026&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 21:33:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Plenty of time left for good policy in Wisconsin Legislature</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/plenty-of-time-left-for-good-policy-in-wisconsin-legislature/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;There are 541 days until the next Legislature’s sworn in, and there’s plenty of unfinished business&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/plenty-of-time-left-for-good-policy-in-wisconsin-legislature/"&gt;Plenty of time left for good policy in Wisconsin Legislature&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 21:37:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Antiquated Wisconsin law doesn’t allow driverless vehicles</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/antiquated-wisconsin-law-doesnt-allow-driverless-vehicles/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As self-driving taxis roll out across much of America, Wisconsinites won’t be seeing them without some changes to existing law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/antiquated-wisconsin-law-doesnt-allow-driverless-vehicles/"&gt;Antiquated Wisconsin law doesn’t allow driverless vehicles&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 21:37:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] Albuquerque Mayoral Candidate Eddie Varela completes RGF candidate survey</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/albuquerque-mayoral-candidate-eddie-varela-completes-rgf-candidate-survey/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In its ongoing efforts to ensure that voters are fully informed about the views and plans of the various candidates for Albuquerque Mayor. The latest candidate to respond is Eddie Varela. His survey can be found here. Varela&amp;#8217;s campaign website can be accessed here. You can also see images of Varela&amp;#8217;s survey answers below: &amp;#160; [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/albuquerque-mayoral-candidate-eddie-varela-completes-rgf-candidate-survey/"&gt;Albuquerque Mayoral Candidate Eddie Varela completes RGF candidate survey&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 22:32:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] ‘I couldn’t stand by’</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/podcasts/the-overton-window/sandra-hernden-and-steve-delie-tell-the-story-of-one-womans-fight-to-recover-her-first-amendment-rights</link><description>Sandra Hernden and Steve Delie tell the story of one woman’s fight to recover her first amendment rights</description><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 09:59:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Listen: Rep. Libby &amp; Maine Agree Her Lawsuit is Moot</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/listen-rep-libby-maine-agree-her-lawsuit-is-moot/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Policy analyst, Harris Van Pate, joined the WGAN Morning News to discuss the latest–and likely final–development in Rep. Laurel Libby&amp;#8217;s (R-Auburn) lawsuit against Maine regarding her censure, which resulted in her losing her voting and speaking rights on the House floor for many months until they were restored by the Supreme Court. On the last [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/listen-rep-libby-maine-agree-her-lawsuit-is-moot/"&gt;Listen: Rep. Libby &amp;amp; Maine Agree Her Lawsuit is Moot&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 12:49:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] Sec. Simon Should Hop Off the Ranked-Choice Voting Train</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/sec-simon-should-hop-off-the-ranked-choice-voting-train/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Ranked-Choice Voting must be rejected when it presents itself in Minnesota. Our republic deserves no less than our willingness to educate voters about this failed voting system and to resist misguided efforts like Sec. Simons who wants to expand this radical scheme to all Minnesota cities and counties. &amp;#8212; Secretary of State backs legislation to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/sec-simon-should-hop-off-the-ranked-choice-voting-train/"&gt;Sec. Simon Should Hop Off the Ranked-Choice Voting Train&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 13:13:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] A Tale of Two Budgets: How Maine and New Hampshire’s Latest Spending Plans Compare</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/a-tale-of-two-budgets-how-maine-and-new-hampshires-latest-spending-plans-compare/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Maine and New Hampshire share a border, but when it comes to fiscal policy, taxation, and education, they live in two totally different worlds. While Maine raises taxes and grows government to chase underwhelming outcomes, New Hampshire delivers superior services—especially in education—while maintaining no state sales or individual income taxes. That contrast has never been [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/a-tale-of-two-budgets-how-maine-and-new-hampshires-latest-spending-plans-compare/"&gt;A Tale of Two Budgets: How Maine and New Hampshire&amp;#8217;s Latest Spending Plans Compare&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 13:44:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Regional Transit in Tucson: Bigger Tax Bill, Worse Results?</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/regional-transit-in-tucson-a-bigger-tax-bill-less-results/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In 2006, voters in Pima County made a deal: an increase in the sales tax for better roads and infrastructure...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/regional-transit-in-tucson-a-bigger-tax-bill-less-results/"&gt;Regional Transit in Tucson: Bigger Tax Bill, Worse Results?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 14:41:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] In Special Session, West Hartford Democrats Set Sights on Fiscal Guardrails — Again</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/07/11/in-special-session-west-hartford-democrats-set-sights-on-fiscal-guardrails-again/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you thought Connecticut’s fiscal guardrails were safe, think again.   At a post-session town hall in West Hartford on July 8, local Democratic legislators made it abundantly clear that [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/07/11/in-special-session-west-hartford-democrats-set-sights-on-fiscal-guardrails-again/"&gt;In Special Session, West Hartford Democrats Set Sights on Fiscal Guardrails — Again &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 15:25:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Average Pay at Port Authority Surges as 11 Employees Collect $400k+</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/average-pay-at-panynj-surges-as-11-employees-collect-400k/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Eleven Port Authority of New York and New Jersey (PANYNJ) employees collected more than $400,000 each in total pay last....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/average-pay-at-panynj-surges-as-11-employees-collect-400k/"&gt;Average Pay at Port Authority Surges as 11 Employees Collect $400k+&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 15:40:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Lessons from downwinders: Why government transparency is crucial for public trust</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/lessons-from-downwinders-why-government-transparency-is-crucial-for-public-trust</link><description>Navajo George Tutt started uranium mining in 1949 as a hand mucker. Hand muckers would procure uranium waste and ore from veins in the...</description><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 16:01:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Week in Review: What Did the Supreme Court Decide?</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-what-did-the-supreme-court-decide/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Supreme Court has just concluded one of its most consequential terms in decades, handing down rulings that will reshape..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-what-did-the-supreme-court-decide/"&gt;Week in Review: What Did the Supreme Court Decide?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 16:32:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] SCOTUS asked to consider case of unions refusing to open mail from disgruntled members</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/press-release/scotus-asked-to-consider-case-of-unions-refusing-to-open-mail-from-disgruntled-members/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In all three instances, the Teamsters refused to open lawfully mailed packages from the Freedom Foundation believed to contain paperwork from public employees seeking to terminate their union membership and dues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/press-release/scotus-asked-to-consider-case-of-unions-refusing-to-open-mail-from-disgruntled-members/" rel="nofollow"&gt;SCOTUS asked to consider case of unions refusing to open mail from disgruntled members&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 16:34:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] A quiet victory: Trump rule protecting federal workers survives Biden’s presidency</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/labor/a-quiet-victory-trump-rule-protecting-federal-workers-survives-bidens-presidency/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;It took two years to find out, but it turns out the Freedom Foundation helped ensure the quiet defeat of a Biden proposal to trap federal workers in unions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/labor/a-quiet-victory-trump-rule-protecting-federal-workers-survives-bidens-presidency/" rel="nofollow"&gt;A quiet victory: Trump rule protecting federal workers survives Biden’s presidency&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 17:30:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/07/14041/</link><description>Urban Life: Shoplifting HOW ARE THINGS GOING?&amp;#160;Well, few venture out after dusk&amp;#160;on&amp;#160;our multi-million-dollar trail system;&amp;#160;there are stabbings at&amp;#160;Promenade&amp;#160;Park, if that tells you anything;&amp;#160;shootings threaten to become&amp;#160;routine&amp;#160;on the streets below our&amp;#160;majestic new downtown constructions; and there is shoplifting and theft throughout. At some point we are going to have to face a sad fact, that is,&amp;#160;there&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/07/14041/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 18:12:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Illinois ranked No. 1 for cell phone taxes – before latest hike</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/illinois-ranked-no-1-for-cell-phone-taxes-before-latest-hike/</link><description>Illinoisans paid the highest state and local taxes for wireless cell phone services in the nation in 2024 – $136 per family more than the average. An increase in Illinois’ telecommunication tax July 1 just made them even higher.</description><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 18:22:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Legislature passes 15 housing reform bills in 2025</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/07/legislature-passes-15-housing-reform-bills-in-2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Five years ago, there was little action in the Legislature to address the decades-long rising cost of housing in New Hampshire. St. Anselm College polling found in 2020 that voters hadn&amp;#8217;t yet connected surging prices to local land use regulations. Only 28.7% of voters said local governments should relax planning and zoning rules to allow [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/07/legislature-passes-15-housing-reform-bills-in-2025/"&gt;Legislature passes 15 housing reform bills in 2025&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 18:34:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] California Might Stop Making Necessary Debt Payments for 2 Years</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/california-might-stop-making-necessary-debt-payments-for-2-years/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=california-might-stop-making-necessary-debt-payments-for-2-years</link><description>&lt;p&gt;It’s July. The California State Legislature has successfully met the budget submission deadline of June 15, and it was signed by the governor. There was one small fly in the ointment: how to cut $12 billion in spending? All while trying to provide $750 million in tax credits annually to one specific industry: Hollywood. Go...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/california-might-stop-making-necessary-debt-payments-for-2-years/"&gt;California Might Stop Making Necessary Debt Payments for 2 Years&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 20:27:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] CPC releases letter in opposition to AB 84 on behalf of statewide coalition</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/ab84-coalition-letter/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=ab84-coalition-letter</link><description>&lt;p&gt;SACRAMENTO – Today, California Policy Center joined a broad coalition of education freedom advocates in submitting a letter of opposition to Assembly Bill AB 84 to the Senate Education Committee. The bill will have a hearing before the committee at 9:00am on July 16th at the Capitol. “California families need more educational choices, not fewer...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/ab84-coalition-letter/"&gt;CPC releases letter in opposition to AB 84 on behalf of statewide coalition&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 21:00:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] California: Three straight record-shattering months and counting</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/california/california-three-straight-record-shattering-months-and-counting/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Freedom Foundation’s California outreach team in June broke another record for opt-outs, with over 2,700 opt outs, making it three consecutive months of incredible growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/california/california-three-straight-record-shattering-months-and-counting/" rel="nofollow"&gt;California: Three straight record-shattering months and counting&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 21:08:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] The Answer is “Cowardice”</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/the-answer-is-cowardice/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/the-answer-is-cowardice/" rel="nofollow" title="The Answer is “Cowardice”"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Article-Headers-2025-07-10T140332.879.png" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Want to know what happens in an Idaho Freedom Foundation team meeting? Here’s a glimpse.&amp;#160; The question was asked, “If Argentina can cut its government and spending by 28% in one year, why can’t Idaho do that or more?” Without missing a beat, “The answer is ‘cowardice,’” rang out from one (unnamed) freedom fighter. And [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 21:45:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Big, Beautiful Bill heads off tax increases for Iowans</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/big-beautiful-bill-heads-off-tax-increases-for-iowans/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;With passage of the “Big, Beautiful, Bill,” Iowa taxpayers avoided a massive tax increase, but even with the positives of the measure there are still reasons for caution. Federal spending, along with the national debt, will both continue to increase and Iowa policymakers must begin to prepare for contingencies of potential cuts to federal funds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/big-beautiful-bill-heads-off-tax-increases-for-iowans/"&gt;Big, Beautiful Bill heads off tax increases for Iowans&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jul 2025 13:29:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Keep a Close Eye on Our Nation’s Credit Score</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/key-a-close-eye-on-our-nations-credit-score/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The credit score for the U.S. is not looking too hot. Our top rating was downgraded in 2011 by Standard &amp;#38; Poor’s, in 2023 by Fitch, and most recently in May 2025 by Moody’s. Moody’s cited that: Successive U.S. administrations and Congress have failed to agree on measures to reverse the trend of large annual...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/key-a-close-eye-on-our-nations-credit-score/"&gt;Keep a Close Eye on Our Nation’s Credit Score&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jul 2025 15:35:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] The James Madison Institute Releases 2025 Legislative Wrap-Up</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/the-james-madison-institute-releases-2025-legislative-wrap-up/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE July 14, 2025 CONTACT Emma Rose Graddy 850-386-3131 The James Madison Institute Releases 2025 Legislative...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/the-james-madison-institute-releases-2025-legislative-wrap-up/"&gt;The James Madison Institute Releases 2025 Legislative Wrap-Up&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 04:01:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] JMI 2025 Legislative Wrap-Up</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/jmi-2025-legislative-wrap-up/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Center for Technology and Innovation Marshall Center for Education Freedom Gibbs Center for Economic Prosperity Find the full...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/jmi-2025-legislative-wrap-up/"&gt;JMI 2025 Legislative Wrap-Up&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 04:01:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Anti-Charter School Bill Would Hurt Most Vulnerable CA Students</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/anti-charter-school-bill-would-hurt-most-vulnerable-ca-students/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Anti-Charter School Bill Would Hurt Most Vulnerable CA Students by Lance Izumi  &amp;#124;  July 14, 2025 A bill plowing through the State Legislature is using fiscal accountability as a fig-leaf issue to hide its real intentions—crippling California’s popular charter-school sector in order to bolster regular public schools that are seeing declines in both enrollment and [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/anti-charter-school-bill-would-hurt-most-vulnerable-ca-students/"&gt;Anti-Charter School Bill Would Hurt Most Vulnerable CA Students&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 09:00:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] The role of renewable energy in environmental ‘disaster’</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/the-role-of-renewable-energy-in-environmental-disaster/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;John Hinderaker writes for the Power Line blog about the latest evidence that renewable energy sources touted by politicians can cause more harm than good. Wind and solar energy, along with the batteries and transmission lines they require to function even minimally, are inherently bad for the environment. But sometimes they are even worse, as...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/the-role-of-renewable-energy-in-environmental-disaster/"&gt;The role of renewable energy in environmental ‘disaster’&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 09:39:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] SCOTUS justice writes opinions to share feelings</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/scotus-justice-writes-opinions-to-share-feelings/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Isabel Garcia writes for the Daily Wire about one U.S. Supreme Court justice’s unusual approach to her job. Justice Ketanji Brown Jackson said during her book tour last weekend that she views Supreme Court opinions as a way to voice her personal convictions. “I just feel that I have a wonderful opportunity to tell people...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/scotus-justice-writes-opinions-to-share-feelings/"&gt;SCOTUS justice writes opinions to share feelings&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 09:42:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Study Finds MBTA Operating Costs Surging Since Control Board’s Elimination</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/economic_opportunity/study-finds-mbta-operating-costs-surging-since-control-boards-elimination/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In the years since fiscal 2018, when the MBTA last balanced its budget without state contract assistance or federal funds, operating costs have been rising at an alarming rate, culminating in an increase of nearly 15 percent from FY 2023 to FY 2024 alone, according to a new policy brief published by Pioneer Institute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/economic_opportunity/study-finds-mbta-operating-costs-surging-since-control-boards-elimination/"&gt;Study Finds MBTA Operating Costs Surging Since Control Board’s Elimination&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 13:25:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Why Idaho's fiscal health remains strong</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/why-idaho-s-fiscal-health-remains-strong</link><description>Is Idaho about to fall off the fiscal cliff due to irresponsible budgeting? No. The Gem State’s current budget has a decent ending fund...</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 13:51:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Supreme Court Case Shows the Need for Donor Privacy Laws</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/supreme-court-case-shows-the-need-for-donor-privacy-laws/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The General Assembly recently passed Senate Bill (SB) 416, the “Personal Privacy Protection Act,” which contains important measures to protect the privacy of those who donate to nonprofit organizations. Gov. Josh Stein vetoed that bill, claiming the law would create “more opportunity for dark money in our politics.” That is nonsense. Senate Bill 416 is commonsense legislation...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/supreme-court-case-shows-the-need-for-donor-privacy-laws/"&gt;Supreme Court Case Shows the Need for Donor Privacy Laws&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 14:09:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] The Paradox of Justice in the Commonwealth: A Deeper Look at Massachusetts Incarceration Rates</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/blog/usdatalabs/the-paradox-of-justice-in-the-commonwealth-a-deeper-look-at-massachusetts-incarceration-rates/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;At first glance, Massachusetts appears to be a national model for criminal justice reform, boasting both the nation’s lowest incarceration rate and a low crime rate. However, a deeper look at the numbers in US DataLabs reveals a surprising paradox: Massachusetts also has one of the highest rates of life sentences in the country—and leads the nation in the percentage of life sentences without parole. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/blog/usdatalabs/the-paradox-of-justice-in-the-commonwealth-a-deeper-look-at-massachusetts-incarceration-rates/"&gt;The Paradox of Justice in the Commonwealth: A Deeper Look at Massachusetts Incarceration Rates&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 14:30:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Big Fertility Needs To Be Honest With Patients About The Consequences Of IVF</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/big-fertility-needs-to-be-honest-with-patients-about-the-consequences-of-ivf/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;‘If I believe life begins at conception, and I do, there are nine lives sitting on ice in a freezer that bear my DNA.’ When faced with infertility, Ericka Andersen turned to in-vitro fertilization (IVF) in hopes of finally having children of her own. A committed pro-life advocate, she believed IVF aligned with her values. But it...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/big-fertility-needs-to-be-honest-with-patients-about-the-consequences-of-ivf/"&gt;Big Fertility Needs To Be Honest With Patients About The Consequences Of IVF&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 14:31:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Soviets or Roman Emperors, Which Do We Get?</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/soviets-or-roman-emperors-which-do-we-get/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New York mayoral candidate—and self-proclaimed democratic socialist—Zohran Mamdani has promised to open government-run grocery stores in New York if elected. Why? Because of the high grocery prices. Let’s not kid ourselves—even though the economy is recovering under Trump and grocery prices are going down, groceries can still be obscenely expensive in New York. Mamdani’s recent...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/soviets-or-roman-emperors-which-do-we-get/"&gt;Soviets or Roman Emperors, Which Do We Get?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 15:45:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] No, Donald Trump didn’t just slash Medicaid</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/no-donald-trump-didnt-just-slash-medicaid/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Republicans’ One Big Beautiful Bill Act is now law. Democrats have wasted no time accusing the GOP of enshrining devastating “cuts” to Medicaid, the joint federal-state entitlement that provides health coverage for low-income Americans. That’s rubbish. The measure takes steps to restrain Medicaid’s rampant growth in recent years so that the program prioritizes our nation’s [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/no-donald-trump-didnt-just-slash-medicaid/"&gt;No, Donald Trump didn’t just slash Medicaid&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 15:56:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Midwest retiring the most coal capacity by 2028: EIA</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/midwest-retiring-the-most-coal-capacity-by-2028-eia/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Energy Information Administration (EIA) reports that the Midwest is planning to see the the most coal capacity retire by the end of 2028, at 10 GW of capacity. Retiring reliable baseload power will endanger the reliability of the grid and risk rolling blackouts across the region. The EIA notes that the total capacity of...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/midwest-retiring-the-most-coal-capacity-by-2028-eia/"&gt;Midwest retiring the most coal capacity by 2028: EIA&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 16:24:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Chicago mayor pushes for granny flats citywide to boost affordable housing</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/chicago-mayor-pushes-for-granny-flats-citywide-to-boost-affordable-housing/</link><description>Legalizing additional dwelling units across Chicago would expand housing options, support families and boost affordability without changing the character of single-family neighborhoods. Chicago’s mayor is ready to move on the issue.</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 16:32:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] The Culprit Impeding Drug Competition Is Not Who The Feds Expected</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/the-culprit-impeding-drug-competition-is-not-who-the-feds-expected/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Federal Trade Commission and U.S. Department of Justice recently kicked off a series of listening sessions to examine barriers to competition in the drug industry. The title of the first session—&amp;#8221;Anticompetitive Conduct by Pharmaceutical Companies&amp;#8221;—made it seem that regulators would chiefly investigate biotech firms. Yet by the end, panelists had refocused the spotlight onto [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/the-culprit-impeding-drug-competition-is-not-who-the-feds-expected/"&gt;The Culprit Impeding Drug Competition Is Not Who The Feds Expected&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 16:42:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] New transparency law a major win for Maine taxpayers</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/new-transparency-law-a-major-win-for-maine-taxpayers/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;At the end of the most recent legislative session, the Maine Legislature passed LD 857, “An Act to Increase Government Transparency in the Procurement of Goods and Services.” Gov. Janet Mills chose to allow the bill to become law without her signature.  LD 857 is a win for Maine because it increases government transparency in [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/new-transparency-law-a-major-win-for-maine-taxpayers/"&gt;New transparency law a major win for Maine taxpayers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 17:15:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Minnesota tumbles four places to 10th on CNBC’s ‘Top States for Business’ rankings</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/minnesota-tumbles-four-places-to-10th-on-cnbcs-top-states-for-business-rankings/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;That was then&amp;#8230; Back in 2023, there was much excitement among Minnesota’s political leaders and journalists when our state&amp;#160;placed fifth&amp;#160;on CNBC’s annual ranking of “America’s Top States for Business.” Some headlines read: Governor Walz was so pleased with the fact that Minnesota had ranked ahead of Texas that not only did he tweet about it...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/minnesota-tumbles-four-places-to-10th-on-cnbcs-top-states-for-business-rankings/"&gt;Minnesota tumbles four places to 10th on CNBC&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8216;Top States for Business&amp;#8217; rankings&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 17:24:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Frontierinstitute] Mike Mansfield and the Japanese</title><link>https://frontierinstitute.org/mike-mansfield-and-the-japanese/</link><description>"In 1988, on behalf of America and with Mike Mansfield’s support, President Ronald Reagan formally apologized for the internments and publicly admitted they were not justified."</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 17:43:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Mississippi’s Moment: Bold Reforms to Drive Growth</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/mississippis-moment-bold-reforms-to-drive-growth/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Mississippi is shedding its image as an economic laggard. Over the past five years, the state’s economic output has grown more than it did over the previous fifteen years combined. According to the U.S. Bureau of Economic Analysis, Mississippi posted the second-fastest per capita GDP growth and fifth-fastest personal income growth among all states in [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/mississippis-moment-bold-reforms-to-drive-growth/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi’s Moment: Bold Reforms to Drive Growth&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 17:49:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Fast Track to deportation</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/fast-track-to-deportation/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As far as I can tell from my deep dive into the illegal immigration issue here in Minnesota, the Feds really are concentrating their efforts on the worst cases. Illegal entry into the United States is a criminal act, as the name implies. But it is considered a misdemeanor, and usually prosecuted as a civil...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/fast-track-to-deportation/"&gt;Fast Track to deportation&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 18:10:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Congress gives school choice back to Illinois’ low-income students</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/congress-gives-school-choice-back-to-illinois-low-income-students/</link><description>Illinois state lawmakers listened to teachers unions and killed school choice for over 15,000 low-income students in 2023. Now Congress has restored a scholarship program for needy kids, but Illinois leaders must allow families to access the money.</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 19:22:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Is “Big” Really Bad? What Critics Miss About Big Oil, Big Tech, and Big Pharma</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/tax-budget/is-big-really-bad-what-critics-miss-about-big-oil-big-tech-and-big-pharma/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Every few months, headlines warn us about the dangers of “Big” something—Big Oil, Big Tech, Big Pharma. The narrative is familiar: powerful corporations exploit consumers, stifle innovation, and corrupt our politics. But is being big really bad? Not necessarily. In fact, in a truly free-market system, size often reflects success—earned by serving consumers well, innovating,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/tax-budget/is-big-really-bad-what-critics-miss-about-big-oil-big-tech-and-big-pharma/"&gt;Is “Big” Really Bad? What Critics Miss About Big Oil, Big Tech, and Big Pharma&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 19:41:34 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>