<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>State-Policy Think-Tank Digest</title><link>https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml</link><description>Latest posts from free-market policy institutes across the U.S.</description><atom:link href="https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 07:03:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>[Rifreedom] Center Mourns the Loss of Board Member Michael G. Riley, Civic Leader</title><link>https://rifreedom.org/2025/11/center-mourns-the-loss-of-board-member-michael-g-riley-civic-leader/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org/2025/11/center-mourns-the-loss-of-board-member-michael-g-riley-civic-leader/"&gt;Center Mourns the Loss of Board Member Michael G. Riley, Civic Leader&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://rifreedom.org"&gt;RI Center for Freedom and Prosperity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 16:51:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Trouble on the Right – Why Conservatives Need to be Wary</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/trouble-on-the-right-why-conservatives-need-to-be-wary/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I only recently learned what a “groyper” is - you may or may not be familiar with the term?&amp;#160;From what I can tell, a groyper is a hardline white nationalist.&amp;#160; Often anti-Semitic, groypers are hostile to mainstream conservatives.&amp;#160; To the extent they have a coherent agenda, groypers seem more national socialism than free-market capitalism.&amp;#160;Having been [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/trouble-on-the-right-why-conservatives-need-to-be-wary/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Trouble on the Right – Why Conservatives Need to be Wary&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 18:29:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] On Thanksgiving, remember that gratitude makes good citizens, heals divisions</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/gratitude-makes-good-citizens-and-heals-divisions/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/gratitude-makes-good-citizens-and-heals-divisions/"&gt;On Thanksgiving, remember that gratitude makes good citizens, heals divisions&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 23:00:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] The War of Visions</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/11/28/the-war-of-visions/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Across the country, Americans are no longer divided simply by policy or party but by rival moral imaginations—two incompatible visions of truth, freedom, and even human nature itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/11/28/the-war-of-visions/"&gt;The War of Visions&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 00:23:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] A Very Grateful Immigrant’s Thanksgiving</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/a-very-grateful-immigrants-thanksgiving/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Having just celebrated Thanksgiving across the United States, I’ve been reminded of what makes this holiday truly special.&amp;#160;&amp;#160;If you’re an American who’s grown up with the holiday your whole life, it’s easy to take it for granted. Speaking as an immigrant, let me tell you: there’s something genuinely magical about a country setting aside a [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/a-very-grateful-immigrants-thanksgiving/" rel="nofollow"&gt;A Very Grateful Immigrant’s Thanksgiving&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 21:11:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] New Hampshire ranked freest state in North America for 24th time</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/12/new-hampshire-ranked-freest-state-in-north-america-for-24th-time/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;New Hampshire ranks as the freest state in North America, as measured in this year’s Economic Freedom of North America report, released today by the Josiah Bartlett Center for Public Policy in conjunction with Canada’s Fraser Institute. For the 24th time, New Hampshire is the freest state among all U.S. states, having scored 8.34 out [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/12/new-hampshire-ranked-freest-state-in-north-america-for-24th-time/"&gt;New Hampshire ranked freest state in North America for 24th time&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 12:52:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] The Holiday Season Is Here — But Affordability Still Isn’t</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/the-holiday-season-is-here/</link><description>If it feels like Christmas keeps getting more expensive, that’s because it is,  and Kansans are feeling it more sharply than policymakers care to admit. The rising cost of living is no longer a blip on a chart; it’s a full-blown pocketbook problem showing up in everything from family grocery runs to holiday gift lists. [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 15:17:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG Polling: April 2025</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-polling-april-2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;April 16, 2025 NEW IRG Poll: Voters Decided Election on Abortion, Musk &amp;#38; Trump’s Agenda Despite all the emphasis on crime, voters were focused elsewhere  Delafield, Wis. –  The Institute for Reforming Government (IRG) is continuing its public polling project with Napolitan News Service and Scott Rasmussen in 2025, with the focus in this poll on Wisconsin’s [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-polling-april-2025/"&gt;IRG Polling: April 2025&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 20:28:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Book Highlights Advances in Digital Education, Policies to Unlock Its Benefits</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/book-highlights-advances-in-digital-education-policies-to-unlock-its-benefits/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;BOSTON – A new book co-edited by national digital education leader Julie Young draws on best practices and multiple studies published by Pioneer Institute to recount three decades of advances in digital education and highlights the policies necessary for students to fully...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/book-highlights-advances-in-digital-education-policies-to-unlock-its-benefits/"&gt;Book Highlights Advances in Digital Education, Policies to Unlock Its Benefits &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 12:06:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] WILL Moves to Intervene in Wisconsin Redistricting Cases on Behalf of Wisconsin Voters</title><link>https://will-law.org/will-moves-to-intervene-in-wisconsin-redistricting-cases-on-behalf-of-wisconsin-voters/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL filed motions to intervene in two lawsuits seeking to overturn Wisconsin’s Congressional Maps. Seeking again to defend those maps on behalf of a group of Wisconsin voters, WILL argues that these new lawsuits are time-barred, the three-judge panel lacks authority to overrule the Wisconsin Supreme Court, and any attempt to impose new maps in this manner would violate federal law and the U.S. Constitution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/will-moves-to-intervene-in-wisconsin-redistricting-cases-on-behalf-of-wisconsin-voters/"&gt;WILL Moves to Intervene in Wisconsin Redistricting Cases on Behalf of Wisconsin Voters&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 14:16:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] New Mexico falls to 50th among US states in latest “Index of Economic Freedom”</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/new-mexico-falls-to-50th-among-us-states-in-latest-index-of-economic-freedom/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Rio Grande Foundation has never seen &amp;#8220;eye to eye&amp;#8221; with Gov. Lujan Grisham and the leftists in Santa Fe who have failed to improve New Mexico even with the benefit of billions of dollars in oil and gas revenues. And, while these policy differences and failures may seem trivial to some, they have real [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/new-mexico-falls-to-50th-among-us-states-in-latest-index-of-economic-freedom/"&gt;New Mexico falls to 50th among US states in latest &amp;#8220;Index of Economic Freedom&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 15:40:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Nebraska Tax Reform: Why Full Expensing Is the Smart Move</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-tax-reform-why-full-expensing-is-the-smart-move/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The federal One Big Beautiful Bill (OBBB) creates the opportunity for Nebraska to adopt the most “America First” tax reform: full expensing. In an era of reshoring and friend-shoring critical supply chains, full expensing is the tax reform that properly defines “income” and incentivizes production in the U.S.A.   Full expensing is the policy of allowing...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-tax-reform-why-full-expensing-is-the-smart-move/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Nebraska Tax Reform: Why Full Expensing Is the Smart Move&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 16:55:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] Court Watch: Wisconsin Supreme Court Reverses, Consolidates Power Through New Court Management Order</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/court-watch-wisconsin-supreme-court-reverses-consolidates-power-through-new-court-management-order/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Court Watch: Wisconsin Supreme Court Reverses, Consolidates Power Through New Court Management Order Progressive majority reshapes internal court governance to cement its control of the judicial branch Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government’s Court Watch issued the following statement after the Wisconsin Supreme Court quietly issued a new court management order just days [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/court-watch-wisconsin-supreme-court-reverses-consolidates-power-through-new-court-management-order/"&gt;Court Watch: Wisconsin Supreme Court Reverses, Consolidates Power Through New Court Management Order&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 16:58:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] The Hidden Gem: Why Education Freedom is the New Economic Development</title><link>https://empowerms.org/the-hidden-gem-why-education-freedom-is-the-new-economic-development/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Forget industrial parks. The driver for economic growth in rural Mississippi is education freedom, which is the most powerful yet often overlooked tool in our economic development chest. I’ve dedicated my academic research to the topic, stemming from a comment I heard years ago at Starkville City Hall: “Education is the biggest driver of community-economic&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/the-hidden-gem-why-education-freedom-is-the-new-economic-development/"&gt;The Hidden Gem: Why Education Freedom is the New Economic Development&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 17:46:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Portland Public Schools’ Risky Real Estate Gamble</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/education/portland-public-schools-risky-real-estate-gamble/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Eric Fruits, Ph.D. On December 2, Portland Public Schools (PPS) board voted...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/education/portland-public-schools-risky-real-estate-gamble/"&gt;Portland Public Schools’ Risky Real Estate Gamble&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 01:25:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] A ‘Repeal Day’ glance at Liquor Commission revenues</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/12/a-repeal-day-glance-at-liquor-commission-revenues/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;December 5 is neither a federal nor state day of celebration, but it probably should be. On Dec. 5, 1933, Pennsylvania, Ohio and Utah became the final states to ratify the 21st Amendment to the U.S. Constitution.  The night before, toasting your Aunt Gertrude’s 92nd birthday with a glass of champagne was illegal. That evening, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/12/a-repeal-day-glance-at-liquor-commission-revenues/"&gt;A &amp;#8216;Repeal Day&amp;#8217; glance at Liquor Commission revenues&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 22:09:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Georgia candidates for governor should make welfare reform a top priority</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/georgia-candidates-for-governor-should-make-welfare-reform-a-top-priority/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/georgia-candidates-for-governor-should-make-welfare-reform-a-top-priority/"&gt;Georgia candidates for governor should make welfare reform a top priority&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 16:58:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] OPINION: New Mexico’s economic freedom is now dead last</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/opinion-new-mexicos-economic-freedom-is-now-dead-last/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following appeared in the Albuquerque Journal  on December 7, 2025. In a study published earlier this year, we highlighted the fact that New Mexico was the only state in the U.S. to have lost economic freedom since 1981. We now know that it is worse than we thought. People are more economically free when [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/opinion-new-mexicos-economic-freedom-is-now-dead-last/"&gt;OPINION: New Mexico&amp;#8217;s economic freedom is now dead last&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 17:53:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Wichita should reallocate spending rather than add a new (rushed?) 1% sales tax</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/sales-tax-proposal-rushed-wichita/</link><description>The Wichita City Council seems poised to rush a proposal to the ballot for a 1-cent sales tax to raise $850 million over seven years for several new projects. That at least implies that imposing a new tax is the only way to fund “public safety projects, property tax relief, and revitalizing Century II and [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 19:55:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Listen: Steve Robinson &amp; Matt Gagnon on WGAN</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/listen-steve-robinson-matt-gagnon-on-wgan/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Steve Robinson from the Maine Wire joins Matt Gagnon to discuss fraud and corruption by the Maine-based Gateway Community Services (GCS). According to reporting by the The Maine Wire, GCS has been found liable for nearly a million dollars worth of erroneous billing to MaineCare, the state’s Medicare agency, in an unsettling precursor to revelations [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/listen-steve-robinson-matt-gagnon-on-wgan/"&gt;Listen: Steve Robinson &amp;amp; Matt Gagnon on WGAN&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 20:37:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] Empty Schools, Empty Wallets: How ESSER Pandemic Aid Led to More School Referenda</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/empty-schools-empty-wallets-how-esser-pandemic-aid-led-to-more-school-referenda/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Empty Schools, Empty Wallets: How ESSER Pandemic Aid Led to More School Referenda New IRG analysis reveals hiring sprees and poor financial decisions as Wisconsin schools fall behind national leaders Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government released a new report on Tuesday, “Empty Schools, Empty Wallets: What Happened to $1.49 Billion in ESSER [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/empty-schools-empty-wallets-how-esser-pandemic-aid-led-to-more-school-referenda/"&gt;Empty Schools, Empty Wallets: How ESSER Pandemic Aid Led to More School Referenda&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 15:02:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Massachusetts Subsidized Housing Inventory Update Shows Record Number of Communities Exceed Critical Threshold</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/massachusetts-subsidized-housing-inventory-update-shows-record-number-of-communities-exceed-critical-threshold/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This edition of The House Call explores the 2025 update to Massachusetts&amp;#8217; Subsidized Housing Inventory, showing a spike in the number of communities that have at least 10% of their housing stocks in the Inventory. It also explains the housing-related ballot questions that could...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/massachusetts-subsidized-housing-inventory-update-shows-record-number-of-communities-exceed-critical-threshold/"&gt;Massachusetts Subsidized Housing Inventory Update Shows Record Number of Communities Exceed Critical Threshold&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 20:35:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Commissioner Andy Gipson: Family, Food Security, and Mississippi’s Future</title><link>https://empowerms.org/commissioner-andy-gipson-family-food-security-and-mississippis-future/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Commissioner Andy Gipson: Family, Food Security, and Mississippi’s Future On this episode of The Empower Podcast, host Grant Callen sits down with Commissioner Andy Gipson—Mississippi’s Commissioner of Agriculture and Commerce, former state legislator, Baptist minister, cattleman, and announced candidate for governor. Gipson shares how his journey into public service began with a desire to secure&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/commissioner-andy-gipson-family-food-security-and-mississippis-future/"&gt;Commissioner Andy Gipson: Family, Food Security, and Mississippi’s Future&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:49:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Nebraska Zoning Permitting Process: Recommended Adjustments in Nebraska</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-zoning-permitting-process-recommended-adjustments-in-nebraska/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Nebraska’s zoning and permitting process for livestock operations is inconsistent, unpredictable, and varies widely from county to county. This report examines how Nebraska’s Conditional Use Permit (CUP) system works, the origins and goals of the Livestock Siting Assessment Matrix created under LB106, and why the Matrix remains underused nearly a decade later. Drawing on survey...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/nebraska-zoning-permitting-process-recommended-adjustments-in-nebraska/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Nebraska Zoning Permitting Process: Recommended Adjustments in Nebraska&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 15:17:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] WILL Hires Associate Counsel to Grow Legal and Policy Capacity in Wisconsin and Beyond</title><link>https://will-law.org/will-hires-associate-counsel-to-grow-legal-and-policy-capacity-in-wisconsin-and-beyond/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL has announced Erin Gamble as our new Associate Counsel. Her hire reflects our organization’s commitment to fighting back against bureaucratic overreach in Wisconsin and across the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/will-hires-associate-counsel-to-grow-legal-and-policy-capacity-in-wisconsin-and-beyond/"&gt;WILL Hires Associate Counsel to Grow Legal and Policy Capacity in Wisconsin and Beyond&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 15:23:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Creating links that change lives: Georgia Center for Opportunity partners with Connect to Work GA</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/gco-partners-with-connect-to-work-ga/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This collaboration will help lift job seekers above the poverty line by providing opportunities for successful careers and upward mobility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/gco-partners-with-connect-to-work-ga/"&gt;Creating links that change lives: Georgia Center for Opportunity partners with Connect to Work GA&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 20:09:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Legislature balks as Evers demands millions for more food aid bureaucrats</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/legislature-balks-as-evers-demands-millions-for-more-food-aid-bureaucrats/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Gov. Tony Evers is pressing the Legislature for $70 million to process FoodShare applications to stave off federal penalties that could cost state taxpayers as much as $225 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/legislature-balks-as-evers-demands-millions-for-more-food-aid-bureaucrats/"&gt;Legislature balks as Evers demands millions for more food aid bureaucrats&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 21:58:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Look Up: Your Bodily Autonomy and Property Rights Are Being Attacked From the Sky</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/look-up-your-bodily-autonomy-and-property-rights-are-being-attacked-from-the-sky/</link><description>Want to have some fun at your holiday family gathering this year? Ask your fellow party-goers what they think about cloud seeding. Are those lines in the sky merely contrails, or signs of weather modification, or some sort of atmospheric experimentation? You’ll soon find a variety of answers, speculation, opinion, and theory — from genuine [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 01:40:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] “Fully Funded Schools” Are a Moving Goal Post</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/education/fully-funded-schools-are-a-moving-goal-post/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Kathryn Hickok How much money does it take to “fully fund” Oregon’s...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/education/fully-funded-schools-are-a-moving-goal-post/"&gt;“Fully Funded Schools” Are a Moving Goal Post&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 17:22:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Would you invest in Massachusetts or New Hampshire?</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/12/would-you-invest-in-massachusetts-or-new-hampshire/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;If U.S. states were companies that traded on the stock market, the only New England state with a “buy” rating would probably be New Hampshire.  Massachusetts could be called “Big Blue,” the tradition-bound leader cruising on its prior reputation, but falling behind smaller upstarts that have embraced innovation and rapid growth.  New Hampshire would be [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/12/would-you-invest-in-massachusetts-or-new-hampshire/"&gt;Would you invest in Massachusetts or New Hampshire?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 21:10:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] The Battle for Health Freedom Isn’t Over: Let’s Fight for Children</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/the-battle-for-health-freedom-isnt-over-lets-fight-for-children/</link><description>Idaho’s “Medical Freedom Act (MFA)” protects adults from employers, businesses, government agencies, or other entities imposing medical interventions on them, including vaccines. Enacted this past July, the MFA protects adults from being coerced into using medical products, devices, substances, injections, or any technology, in any form. It’s simple — bodily autonomy is a fundamental, God-given [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 02:39:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Week in Review: Medical Freedom and Informed Consent Are Fundamental</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/week-in-review-medical-freedom-and-informed-consent-are-fundamental/</link><description>Health and medical freedom, and the issues debated under this umbrella, speak directly to the overarching principles the Founders were so passionate about.&amp;#160; You have the right to access holistic healing modalities, practitioners of your choosing, and treatments to heal in the ways you choose. The state and federal governments have no place interfering in [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Arkansaspolicyfoundation] ARKANSAS GOV. SARAH HUCKABEE SANDERS &amp; STATE INCOME TAX CUTS</title><link>https://arkansaspolicyfoundation.org/arkansas-gov-sarah-huckabee-sanders-state-income-tax-cuts/</link><description>(4Q-2025) Arkansas Gov. Sarah Huckabee Sanders is the Natural State’s first female governor. Since taking office in January 2023, Sanders has also distinguished herself by advancing three separate reductions in Arkansas’ top income tax rate from 4.9 to 3.9 percent. The income tax was reduced from 7.0% to 6.9% in 2013 under Democratic Gov. Mike [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 14:33:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Empire Center Releases NYC BERS Pension Data for FY2025</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/empire-center-releases-nyc-bers-pension-data-for-fy2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Pension payments to 21,170 retirees of the New York City Board of Education Retirement System (BERS) during fiscal year 2025....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/empire-center-releases-nyc-bers-pension-data-for-fy2025/"&gt;Empire Center Releases NYC BERS Pension Data for FY2025&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 14:15:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Todd Schaible: The Importance of Career and Technical Education in Tennessee Schools</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/todd-schaible-the-importance-of-career-technical-education-in-tennessee-schools/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=todd-schaible-the-importance-of-career-technical-education-in-tennessee-schools</link><description>By elevating CTE in Tennessee schools, we can increase support for employers and improve workforce readiness for students across the state.</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 15:34:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] Albuquerque Journal editorializes in defense of free speech, Rio Grande Foundation in “hoodie-gate”</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/albuquerque-journal-editorializes-in-defense-of-free-speech-rio-grande-foundation-in-hoodie-gate/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Rio Grande Foundation has received a great deal of publicity from all corners of Albuquerque&amp;#8217;s political scene due to our involvement in reporting on the I ♥ Tim Keller &amp;#8220;hoodies for the homeless&amp;#8221; effort. As we&amp;#8217;ve discussed at length here and in other locations the Mayor&amp;#8217;s campaign has reacted to our reporting and refusal [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/albuquerque-journal-editorializes-in-defense-of-free-speech-rio-grande-foundation-in-hoodie-gate/"&gt;Albuquerque Journal editorializes in defense of free speech, Rio Grande Foundation in &amp;#8220;hoodie-gate&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 16:53:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] The Million Petty Annoyances of California’s Regulatory State</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/the-million-petty-annoyances-of-californias-regulatory-state/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=the-million-petty-annoyances-of-californias-regulatory-state</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The litany of reasons California is broken is well documented. The highest cost of living and the highest taxes. The highest percentages of homeless people and people living in poverty. Unaffordable homes and unaffordable rent. High crime and failing schools. A hostile business climate and record migration out of state as people and businesses flee....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/the-million-petty-annoyances-of-californias-regulatory-state/"&gt;The Million Petty Annoyances of California’s Regulatory State&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 17:17:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Portland Studies Inclusionary Zoning (Again) Despite Evidence</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/portland-studies-inclusionary-zoning-again-despite-evidence/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Portland is commissioning its own study on the “effects of inclusionary zoning,” as if the question was unsettled, novel, or open. It isn’t. Across the ideological spectrum, from UC Berkeley to NYU Law to George Mason and numerous think tanks, colleges, and studies across the country, the research record is remarkably consistent: inclusionary zoning reduces housing [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/portland-studies-inclusionary-zoning-again-despite-evidence/"&gt;Portland Studies Inclusionary Zoning (Again) Despite Evidence&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 17:47:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] Franke: Reapportionment</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/12/franke-reapportionment/</link><description>by Mark Franke The Indiana General Assembly’s special session appears to be over, having voted down a mid-decade congressional reapportionment proposal. The legislature is required to reapportion after each decennial census but not more often, although nothing prevents more frequent efforts other than their fiscal and political costs. Despite the heavy-handed involvement of Donald Trump&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/12/franke-reapportionment/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 17:48:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Mississippi's Free-Market Turnaround: A Model for America</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/mississippis-free-market-turnaround-a-model-for-america/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For decades, Mississippi has been the punchline in national discussions about economic performance - often ranked at the bottom in income, education, and opportunity. But something remarkable has happened in recent years: the Magnolia State is undergoing a genuine resurgence, driven not by federal handouts or gimmicks, but by principled free-market reforms. A major national [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/mississippis-free-market-turnaround-a-model-for-america/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi&amp;#039;s Free-Market Turnaround: A Model for America&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 21:13:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Florida Should Lead in Securing Healthcare Technology</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/florida-should-lead-in-securing-healthcare-technology/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Every day, millions of Americans are sustained, monitored, and diagnosed by medical technology they never think twice about....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/florida-should-lead-in-securing-healthcare-technology/"&gt;Florida Should Lead in Securing Healthcare Technology&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 21:54:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Enrollment and Employment: Is Tennessee Preparing K-12 Students for Today’s Economy?</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/enrollment-and-employment-is-tennessee-preparing-k-12-students-for-todays-economy/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=enrollment-and-employment-is-tennessee-preparing-k-12-students-for-todays-economy</link><description>Tennessee is doing well in providing Career and Technical Education (CTE) opportunities to students, but policymakers should recognize that improvements can be made.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 02:17:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] If Massachusetts Can Rein In Property Taxes, Any State Can</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/if-massachusetts-can-rein-in-property-taxes-any-state-can/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="If Massachusetts Can Rein In Property Taxes, Any State Can" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/massachusetts.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite ranking among the nation’s worst tax climates and having some of the highest income, sales, and property taxes, Massachusetts has successfully enforced a strong property tax cap through its Proposition 2½ for more than 40 years.&lt;br /&gt;
The cap limits annual levy growth to 2.5%, encourages disciplined budgeting, and includes a voter-approved override process, enabling communities to fund priorities without uncontrolled tax increases.&lt;br /&gt;
Massachusetts proves that even a high-spending state can maintain an effective property tax cap; Iowa can adopt similar limits without harming essential services or local government operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/if-massachusetts-can-rein-in-property-taxes-any-state-can/"&gt;If Massachusetts Can Rein In Property Taxes, Any State Can&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 13:52:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] A Cautionary Moment for Union Transparency as Former NJEA Leader Seeks a National Role</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/12/a-cautionary-moment-for-union-transparency-as-former-njea-leader-seeks-a-national-role/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The recent announcement that former New Jersey Education Association president Sean Spiller has launched a campaign for leadership within the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/12/a-cautionary-moment-for-union-transparency-as-former-njea-leader-seeks-a-national-role/"&gt;A Cautionary Moment for Union Transparency as Former NJEA Leader Seeks a National Role&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 14:20:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] New Jersey Policy Institute Welcomes Kristen Cobo to Its Board of Directors</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/12/new-jersey-policy-institute-welcomes-kristen-cobo-to-its-board-of-directors/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Leader in Children’s Mental Health and Parental Rights Advocacy Joins Expanding NJPI Board FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE Parsippany, N.J. — December [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/12/new-jersey-policy-institute-welcomes-kristen-cobo-to-its-board-of-directors/"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute Welcomes Kristen Cobo to Its Board of Directors&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 14:26:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Freedom Foundation CEO Aaron Withe Statement on House Bill Undermining President Trump’s Union Reform Executive Orders</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/national/freedom-foundation-ceo-aaron-withe-statement-on-house-bill-undermining-president-trumps-union-reform-executive-orders/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Freedom Foundation CEO Aaron Withe today released the following statement on the passage of the Protect America's Workforce Act by the U.S. House of Representatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/national/freedom-foundation-ceo-aaron-withe-statement-on-house-bill-undermining-president-trumps-union-reform-executive-orders/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation CEO Aaron Withe Statement on House Bill Undermining President Trump&amp;#8217;s Union Reform Executive Orders&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 15:35:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Florida Politics: Bedrock, We Have a Problem</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/florida-politics-bedrock-we-have-a-problem/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A funny thing happened in the Legislature last week. While the House was holding an “AI Week” to...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/florida-politics-bedrock-we-have-a-problem/"&gt;Florida Politics: Bedrock, We Have a Problem&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 16:05:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Introducing EPIC: A New Investment in Solution Development</title><link>https://empowerms.org/introducing-epic-a-new-investment-in-solution-development/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For more than a decade, Empower Mississippi has worked to advance opportunity-focused policy at the State Capitol. Many of you have been partners in that work — meeting with lawmakers, investing financially, and championing reforms that help Mississippians live free, work meaningfully, and learn effectively. From the beginning, our advocacy has been grounded in research&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/introducing-epic-a-new-investment-in-solution-development/"&gt;Introducing EPIC: A New Investment in Solution Development&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 16:08:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Kansas’s Revenue Mirage and the Case for a Responsible Budget in 2026</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/kansas-revenue-mirage-responsible-budget/</link><description>The Kansas State government may be collecting more money than expected, but that should make lawmakers nervous, not comfortable.  Individual income tax collections are surging, but at the same time retail sales are slowing and corporate income tax revenues are weakening. When workers get paid more while consumers and businesses pull back, the economy is [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 16:34:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Matthew Gagnon: Gov. Mills Allowing ICE Bill to Pass is “Cowardly”</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/matt-gagnon-gov-mills-allowing-ice-bill-to-pass-is-cowardly/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In an op-ed written to the Portland Press Herald, Governor Janet Mills announced that she will allow a controversial bill, LD 1971, to become law without her signature, limiting police cooperation with federal immigration authorities. Citing concerns about the bill’s broadness and President Trump’s actions, Mills argued that the times necessitate the law, despite not [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/matt-gagnon-gov-mills-allowing-ice-bill-to-pass-is-cowardly/"&gt;Matthew Gagnon: Gov. Mills Allowing ICE Bill to Pass is &amp;#8220;Cowardly&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 20:07:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Tiffany Smiley elected to MSPC Board of Directors</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/tiffany-smiley-elected-to-mspc-board-of-directors</link><description>Mountain States Policy Center's (MSPC) Board of Directors has unanimously approved the election of Tiffany Smiley to its Board of Directors, adding a nationally recognized advocate and media contributor with deep experience in service, leadership, and public policy engagement. Smiley grew up on a small farm in rural Washington, where raising 4-H animals and working the land instilled grit, responsibility, and an entrepreneurial spirit. She became the first in her family to earn a college...</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 07:56:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] Franke: Farm Subsidies — A Better Way</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/12/franke-farm-subsidies-a-better-way/</link><description>by Mark Franke One of the reasons I look forward to our monthly Socratic discussion group is the opportunity to learn something new. Regardless of what knowledge I have of the designated topic going in, two hours of rigorous discussion later and I leave knowing much more. Last month the topic was agricultural subsidies and&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/12/franke-farm-subsidies-a-better-way/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 13:30:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] The Montana Constitution’s state university quagmire</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/the-montana-constitution-s-state-university-quagmire</link><description>One reason Montanans should opt for a new state constitutional convention in 2030 is that the 1972 constitution is plagued by poorly written language. The ensuing lawsuits give lawyers and judges power that belongs to the people and their elected representatives.   Illustrative are the provisions governing the Montana University System (MUS).   The document says, “The government and control of the Montana university system is vested in a board of regents . . . which shall have full power,...</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 14:52:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Research Note: Changes in AI Regulations</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/research-note-changes-in-ai-regulations/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On Thursday, December 11, President Trump signed an executive order aimed at limiting state-level regulations on artificial intelligence (AI). The order is the latest in a series of efforts by the administration to centralize AI governance at the federal level. While it takes a distinctive approach, the order also introduces several practical and legal challenges.  ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/research-note-changes-in-ai-regulations/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Research Note: Changes in AI Regulations&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 15:29:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Pioneer New England Legal Foundation and Sullivan &amp; Worcester Sue Boston Over Retaliatory Tax Scheme</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/pioneer-legal-foundation-sullivan-worcester-sue-boston-over-retaliatory-tax-scheme/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Class action challenges city’s unlawful penalties against commercial taxpayers who exercised their right to appeal; seeks court intervention to end this retaliatory scheme in next fiscal year BOSTON, MA — Pioneer New England Legal Foundation (the Legal Foundation) and Sullivan &amp;#38; Worcester...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/pioneer-legal-foundation-sullivan-worcester-sue-boston-over-retaliatory-tax-scheme/"&gt;Pioneer New England Legal Foundation and Sullivan &amp;amp; Worcester Sue Boston Over Retaliatory Tax Scheme&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 18:43:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Will the Delta Pumps Operate at Capacity this Winter?</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/will-the-delta-pumps-operate-at-capacity-this-winter/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=will-the-delta-pumps-operate-at-capacity-this-winter</link><description>&lt;p&gt;With another series of drenching storms about to hit California, now is a good time to ask what has become a perennial question: why can’t we harvest more of this massive runoff and reserve it for our farms and cities? California must periodically cope with multi-year droughts, but these droughts are usually preceded by years...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/will-the-delta-pumps-operate-at-capacity-this-winter/"&gt;Will the Delta Pumps Operate at Capacity this Winter?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 22:46:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Florida Politics: The Ghost (Students) of Public School Future?</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/florida-politics-the-ghost-students-of-public-school-future/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;U.S. Secretary of Education Linda McMahon announced last week that her department plans to step up efforts to...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/florida-politics-the-ghost-students-of-public-school-future/"&gt;Florida Politics: The Ghost (Students) of Public School Future?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 14:49:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] A promising AI safety tool for teen accounts</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/a-promising-ai-safety-tool-for-teen-accounts</link><description>In October, Meta announced a new “teen AI safety” approach for Instagram, Facebook, and its other platforms.  The headline change is simple but important: parents will soon have a built-in “kill switch” for one-on-one chats between their teens and AI characters. Additionally, it’ll provide better insight into what their teens are doing with AI on Meta’s apps. This is exactly the type of voluntary, market-driven parental tool we highlighted in The Parental Guide to Understanding Digital Media...</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 15:14:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] We’ve Got Talent: Encouraging the Innovators and Students of Our Nation Towards Excellence</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/encouraging-the-innovators-and-students-of-our-nation-towards-excellence/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The United States is home to some of the most genius innovators and groundbreaking technologies of the modern age. Headlines in high profile news outlets frequently recount the cutthroat competition between tech companies and entrepreneurs, eager to develop products that change lives and win over the market. Excellence is the result of this competitive environment,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/encouraging-the-innovators-and-students-of-our-nation-towards-excellence/"&gt;We’ve Got Talent: Encouraging the Innovators and Students of Our Nation Towards Excellence&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 15:59:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Marquette poll finds 80 percent of Americans trust government ‘only some of the time’ or ‘never’</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/marquette-poll-finds-80-percent-of-americans-trust-government-only-some-of-the-time-or-never/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Widespread, intergenerational skepticism of government is not merely the result of America’s increasingly cutthroat politics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/marquette-poll-finds-80-percent-of-americans-trust-government-only-some-of-the-time-or-never/"&gt;Marquette poll finds 80 percent of Americans trust government ‘only some of the time’ or ‘never’&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 16:58:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Freedom Foundation Forces AFSCME to Refund Dues and Honor Minnesota Worker’s Rights</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/litigation/freedom-foundation-forces-afscme-to-refund-dues-and-honor-minnesota-workers-rights/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A simple request was met with silence. In July of 2024, John Cashman, a senior press operator with the Minnesota Department of Transportation, followed his employer’s instructions and contacted AFSCME Local 221 directly to resign his union membership and revoke his dues authorization.&amp;#160;&amp;#160; He emailed a field representative affirmatively stating his intent to opt out [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/litigation/freedom-foundation-forces-afscme-to-refund-dues-and-honor-minnesota-workers-rights/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation Forces AFSCME to Refund Dues and Honor Minnesota Worker’s Rights&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 17:09:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Lawmakers Seek Bipartisan Reform for MI Economic Development Programs</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/pressroom/2025/lawmakers-seek-bipartisan-reform-for-mi-economic-development-programs</link><description>Mackinac Center applauds bills that would base programs on fairness, accountability and measurable results</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 19:48:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Accountable, Understandable, and Comparable</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/accountability/accountable-understandable-and-comparable/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;There are so many things that go well together during the Christmas season. Faith and family, sweet potatoes and those [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/accountability/accountable-understandable-and-comparable/"&gt;Accountable, Understandable, and Comparable&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 20:50:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Extension of property tax waiver vital for rebuilding of Lahaina</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/12/extension-of-property-tax-waiver-vital-for-rebuilding-of-lahaina/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Maui County Council on Dec. 19, 2025._____________ Dec. 19, 2025, 9 a.m.Kalana O Maui Building To: Maui County Council&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Alice Lee, Chair&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Yuki Lei Sugimura, Vice Chair From: Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Jonathan Helton, Policy Analyst Re: Bill 171 (2025) [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/12/extension-of-property-tax-waiver-vital-for-rebuilding-of-lahaina/"&gt;Extension of property tax waiver vital for rebuilding of Lahaina&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 21:04:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Santa aids Freedom Foundation outreach for another holiday season</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/santa-aids-freedom-foundation-outreach-for-another-holiday-season/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;To cut through the holiday and end-of-year chaos, we took a familiar twist. As they do every year, our outreach team members suited up as Santa Claus and his helpers to spark conversations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/outreach/santa-aids-freedom-foundation-outreach-for-another-holiday-season/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Santa aids Freedom Foundation outreach for another holiday season&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 21:05:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Allow all burned Lahaina structures to be rebuilt to pre-fire heights</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/12/allow-all-burned-lahaina-structures-to-be-rebuilt-to-pre-fire-heights/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following testimony was submitted by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Maui County Council on Dec. 19, 2025._____________ Dec. 19, 2025, 9 a.m.Kalana O Maui Building To: Maui County Council&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Alice Lee, Chair&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Yuki Lei Sugimura, Vice Chair From: Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Jonathan Helton, Policy Analyst RE: Bill 183 (2025) [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/12/allow-all-burned-lahaina-structures-to-be-rebuilt-to-pre-fire-heights/"&gt;Allow all burned Lahaina structures to be rebuilt to pre-fire heights&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 21:09:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Grassroot testimonies submitted in mid-December 2025</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/12/grassroot-testimonies-submitted-in-mid-december-2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Below are testimonies submitted during mid-December 2025 by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii for consideration by the Hawai‘i and Maui county councils and the Honolulu Planning Commission. HAWAI‘I COUNTY  &amp;#62;&amp;#62;&amp;#160;Bill 103 (2025)&amp;#160;— “Limit tax hikes for senior owners as agricultural land values increase”&amp;#160; MAUI COUNTY &amp;#62;&amp;#62;&amp;#160;Bill 9 (2025)&amp;#160;— “Proposed STR phaseout is legal, economic crisis [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/12/grassroot-testimonies-submitted-in-mid-december-2025/"&gt;Grassroot testimonies submitted in mid-December 2025&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 21:27:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] One Word Could Let Missouri Students Leave Unsafe Schools</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/education/one-word-could-let-missouri-students-leave-unsafe-schools/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Under the federal Every Student Succeeds Act (ESSA), states must identify unsafe schools and notify families of students who attend [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/education/one-word-could-let-missouri-students-leave-unsafe-schools/"&gt;One Word Could Let Missouri Students Leave Unsafe Schools&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 21:30:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Albany’s School Speed Zone Camera Summer Daze</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/albanys-school-speed-zone-camera-summer-daze/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This fall, Governor Kathy Hochul signed into law bills containing the state’s permission for three cities — Mount Vernon, Schenectady....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/albanys-school-speed-zone-camera-summer-daze/"&gt;Albany’s School Speed Zone Camera Summer Daze&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 21:59:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Busting the ESA Myths with the Facts — Watch the Webinar</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/busting-the-esa-myths-with-the-facts-watch-the-webinar/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Empowerment Scholarship Accounts (ESAs) is a free government program that gives all Arizona kids the education they deserve. Today, more..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/busting-the-esa-myths-with-the-facts-watch-the-webinar/"&gt;Busting the ESA Myths with the Facts — Watch the Webinar&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 22:10:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] U.S. House defangs federal protection of gray wolves in Wisconsin</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/us-house-defangs-federal-protection-of-gray-wolves-in-wisconsin/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The U.S. House of Representatives Thursday passed a bill that would remove the state’s rapidly expanding and aggressive gray wolf population from the endangered species list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/us-house-defangs-federal-protection-of-gray-wolves-in-wisconsin/"&gt;U.S. House defangs federal protection of gray wolves in Wisconsin&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 22:32:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Ugly Math for Taxpayers</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/ugly-math-for-taxpayers/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=ugly-math-for-taxpayers</link><description>Taxpayer-funded lobbying (TFL) is nothing new in Tennessee, but it is almost universally frowned upon.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 22:52:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Senator Bill Cassidy Champions Pro-Worker Policies</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/legal-regulatory/senator-bill-cassidy-champions-pro-worker-policies/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Last month, United States Senator Bill Cassidy (R-Louisiana) and his colleagues on the Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions (HELP) Committee introduced a package of bills intended to modernize labor law, protect workers’ paychecks and privacy rights, and ensure that workers are empowered to decide whether their union is working for them. Sen. Cassidy explained...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/legal-regulatory/senator-bill-cassidy-champions-pro-worker-policies/"&gt;Senator Bill Cassidy Champions Pro-Worker Policies&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 23:00:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] The Public Purpose Program: California’s Hidden Tax Driving Up Utility Bills</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/17209-2/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=17209-2</link><description>&lt;p&gt;After several rate hikes implemented in the last few years alone, Californians are asking why their energy bills keep climbing when they use the same amount of electricity or gas. According to a 2023 report from the Transparency Foundation, residents of California pay up to 67% more for electricity and 30% more for natural gas...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/17209-2/"&gt;The Public Purpose Program: California’s Hidden Tax Driving Up Utility Bills&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 23:58:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Oregon’s “Prosperity Roadmap” Must Follow the Path of Liberty</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/economic-opportunity/oregons-prosperity-roadmap-must-follow-the-path-of-liberty/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Naomi Inman Early this December, Governor Tina Kotek’s newsroom unveiled “Oregon’s Prosperity...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/economic-opportunity/oregons-prosperity-roadmap-must-follow-the-path-of-liberty/"&gt;Oregon’s “Prosperity Roadmap” Must Follow the Path of Liberty&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 00:20:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] How tourism could help revitalize Midwest factory towns</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/how-tourism-could-help-revitalize-midwest-factory-towns</link><description>Towns should change zoning and housing policies that limit growth</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] Why the Proposed Shift in Investigatory Power Raises Serious Concerns</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/12/why-the-proposed-shift-in-investigatory-power-raises-serious-concerns/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;by Megan Whitman, NJPI Junior Economy Fellow &amp;#160; New Jersey lawmakers have been considering Bill S4924, which would significantly change [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/12/why-the-proposed-shift-in-investigatory-power-raises-serious-concerns/"&gt;Why the Proposed Shift in Investigatory Power Raises Serious Concerns&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 13:41:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Rating Agencies Applaud Iowa’s Fiscal Strength, Caution on Spending</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/rating-agencies-applaud-iowas-fiscal-strength-caution-on-spending/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Rating Agencies Applaud Iowa’s Fiscal Strength, Caution on Spending" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/capitol-009.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;S&amp;#038;P Global and Fitch Ratings have reaffirmed Iowa’s AAA credit rating, citing strong fiscal management, robust reserve levels, and prudent budgeting practices that continue to anchor the state’s financial position. Both rating agencies warned Iowa to maintain disciplined spending, noting risks tied to rising costs in education and Medicaid, economic headwinds in agriculture, and federal policy uncertainty that could pressure future budgets. As lawmakers prepare the FY 2027 budget, conservative budgeting remains key, with leaders encouraged to control spending growth to preserve Iowa’s strong reserves, credit rating, and long-term fiscal stability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/rating-agencies-applaud-iowas-fiscal-strength-caution-on-spending/"&gt;Rating Agencies Applaud Iowa’s Fiscal Strength, Caution on Spending&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 14:11:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Ninety New York Educators Receive $300k+ in Annual Pay</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/ninety-new-york-educators-receive-300k-in-annual-pay/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Ninety employees from New York’s school districts (outside New York City) received more than $300,000 during fiscal year 2025, according....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/ninety-new-york-educators-receive-300k-in-annual-pay/"&gt;Ninety New York Educators Receive $300k+ in Annual Pay&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 14:27:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Test post title</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/test-post-title-3/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Test post content&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/test-post-title-3/"&gt;Test post title&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 14:48:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Test post title</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/test-post-title-4/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Test post content&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/test-post-title-4/"&gt;Test post title&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 14:56:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] Schansberg: Tariffs on Santa Claus?</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/12/schansberg-tariffs-on-santa-claus/</link><description>by Eric Schansberg, Ph.D. Following in the footsteps of President Donald Trump, I have a modest policy proposal that is extravagant in style and would hurt the economy — a petition to eliminate competition from Santa Claus through tariffs and other trade barriers. From a Trumpian perspective, Santa’s enterprise is clearly an unfair and harmful&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/12/schansberg-tariffs-on-santa-claus/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 14:58:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Winners &amp; Losers: Best of 2025</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/winners-losers-best-of-2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Throughout 2025, I joined the Cardle &amp;#38; Woolley Show every Friday morning on Talk 1370 Radio in Austin to announce the week’s Winners &amp;#38; Losers. Starting with the inauguration of President Donald Trump’s second term and an epic session of the Texas Legislature, 2025 has been an epic year, changing the course of history in...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/winners-losers-best-of-2025/"&gt;Winners &amp; Losers: Best of 2025&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 15:00:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Private buses are back, but will government leave them alone?</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/private-buses-are-back-but-will-government-leave-them-alone/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Private buses are back, but will government leave them alone? Looking forward to attending FIFA World Cup 26? There’s “an easy and affordable way to move between host cities to see the matches.” FlixBus, the world’s largest motor coach service — it has a presence in more than 40 countries —“will connect every … host [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/private-buses-are-back-but-will-government-leave-them-alone/"&gt;Private buses are back, but will government leave them alone?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 16:50:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] The Subsidy Scheme</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/the-subsidy-scheme/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The House just took an important step toward restoring sanity to America’s health care system by voting to support the Republican health care plan. While critics will reflexively attack the vote, the reality is that the right is finally confronting the real drivers of high health care costs. It rolls back costly federal mandates, expands...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/the-subsidy-scheme/"&gt;The Subsidy Scheme&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 17:05:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Medicaid’s Wake-Up Call</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/health-care/medicaids-wake-up-call/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For years, federal audits of state Medicaid programs weren&amp;#8217;t much more than a bureaucratic annoyance. Come 2030, Missouri has something [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/health-care/medicaids-wake-up-call/"&gt;Medicaid&amp;#8217;s Wake-Up Call&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show-Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 17:21:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] She Was Preparing to Die. Right to Try Gave Her Time.</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/she-was-preparing-to-die-right-to-try-gave-her-time/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When Maya Reinhardt was born in Colorado in 2001, she arrived blue and breathless—her tiny heart failing while doctors rushed..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/she-was-preparing-to-die-right-to-try-gave-her-time/"&gt;She Was Preparing to Die. Right to Try Gave Her Time.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 18:18:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] CDC Labels Minority Neighborhoods as “Vulnerable,” Encouraging the Spread of DEI Spending Nationwide</title><link>https://will-law.org/cdc-labels-minority-neighborhoods-as-vulnerable-encouraging-the-spread-of-dei-spending-nationwide/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In new findings provided to the Trump Administration’s Health and Human Services (HHS) agency, WILL has uncovered that the Center for Disease Control (CDC) uses a race-based criteria to declare whole communities and neighborhoods as “socially vulnerable” based on the number of minorities living there. Cities and states around the country rely on the CDC’s “social vulnerability index” (SVI) to allocate taxpayer funding for parks, drinking water, and disaster assistance.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/cdc-labels-minority-neighborhoods-as-vulnerable-encouraging-the-spread-of-dei-spending-nationwide/"&gt;CDC Labels Minority Neighborhoods as “Vulnerable,” Encouraging the Spread of DEI Spending Nationwide&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 18:18:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Property taxes rob ‘Home Alone’ house of nearly $52,000</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/property-taxes-rob-home-alone-house-of-nearly-52000/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The owners of Kevin McCallister’s house from the “Home Alone” movie will pay nearly $52,000 in property taxes this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/property-taxes-rob-home-alone-house-of-nearly-52000/"&gt;Property taxes rob ‘Home Alone’ house of nearly $52,000&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 18:40:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Week in Review: The Greatest Gift</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-the-greatest-gift/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For millions of Americans, the holiday season is a time for family as well as giving and receiving gifts. But..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-the-greatest-gift/"&gt;Week in Review: The Greatest Gift &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 19:15:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] New bills would fix corporate welfare problems</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/new-bills-would-fix-corporate-welfare-problems</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 19:32:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Illinois Education Association spends little on teachers</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/illinois-education-association-spends-little-on-teachers/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Just 17% of the union’s spending in 2025 was on representing teachers. But it spent a record-breaking amount on politics and paid many staffers over $100K. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/illinois-education-association-spends-little-on-teachers/"&gt;Illinois Education Association spends little on teachers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 20:00:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] TPPF’s 2025 Year in Litigation</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/tppfs-2025-year-in-litigation/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Texas Public Policy Foundation’s Center for the American Future had a busy and successful year defending the Constitution. Below is a list of key victories, along with some new cases that launched in the last 12 months. VICTORIES  1. ATF Reverses “Zero Tolerance” Policy for Revoking Gun Store Licenses The Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/tppfs-2025-year-in-litigation/"&gt;TPPF’s 2025 Year in Litigation&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 21:50:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Louisiana’s Toxic Relationship with Lawsuit Abuse</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/legal-regulatory/lawsuit-abuse/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For years, lawsuit abuse has dragged down Louisiana’s competitiveness, acting as a hidden tax on families, consumers, and businesses across the state. Frivolous claims, inflated damage awards, and politically motivated lawsuits undermine justice and contribute to Louisiana’s long struggle with excessive and opportunistic litigation, especially against important job-creating industries like energy, manufacturing, and insurance. This...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/legal-regulatory/lawsuit-abuse/"&gt;Louisiana’s Toxic Relationship with Lawsuit Abuse&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 22:40:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Minnesota’s Economic News — W/E 12/19/25</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/minnesotas-economic-news-w-e-12-19-25/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;State and local taxes and spending Rochester Post Bulletin: 81% of Olmsted County homeowners will see their taxes go up in 2026. What are the options for relief? Pine Journal: Carlton County officials tout 3.5% tax increase Morrison County Record: Pierz raises tax levy by 5.5% for 2026 Fox News: Massive Medicaid fraud scheme puts...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/minnesotas-economic-news-w-e-12-19-25/"&gt;Minnesota’s Economic News — W/E 12/19/25&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 06:01:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Education and the Workforce</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/education-and-the-workforce/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Introduction Do North Carolinians need four-year degrees to be successful? According to projections from the U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics (BLS) and the North Carolina Department of Commerce, employment opportunities may be more plentiful for those who decide to enter the workforce without a college degree than for those who do have one. BLS analysts...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/education-and-the-workforce/"&gt;Education and the Workforce&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 09:30:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Education Facilities</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/education-facilities/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Introduction The North Carolina State Constitution requires the General Assembly to provide funding for &amp;#8220;a general and uniform system of free public schools,&amp;#8221; but it also allows the legislature to delegate additional responsibility to local governments. The legislature may “assign to units of local government such responsibility for the financial support of the free public...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/education-facilities/"&gt;Education Facilities&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 09:45:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Federal Education Policy</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/federal-education-policy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Introduction The United States Constitution does not mention education. From our nation&amp;#8217;s infancy, Congress generally adhered to the principle that the federal government had no authority to undertake functions and duties not enumerated in the Constitution. As such, the nation relied on families, communities, and state and local governments to direct the education of the...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/federal-education-policy/"&gt;Federal Education Policy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 09:56:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Taxes, Turnout, and the Power of Participation</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/taxes-turnout-and-the-power-of-participation/</link><description>&lt;div class="rss-featured-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Taxes, Turnout, and the Power of Participation" class="attachment-large size-large wp-post-image" height="336" src="https://itrfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2035/01/i-voted.jpg" width="640" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In November 2025, Iowa voters weighed in on 58 local bond proposals, which directly affect property tax bills for up to 20 years, with turnout significantly higher than in other local races. Average turnout for bond elections was 37.1%, more than double the statewide average for city and school elections, suggesting voters engage more when long-term tax impacts are clear. Higher voter participation leads to more representative outcomes in bond elections, reinforcing the importance of transparency and engagement in decisions that commit communities to long-term spending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/taxes-turnout-and-the-power-of-participation/"&gt;Taxes, Turnout, and the Power of Participation&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 14:44:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] How Labour crashed the British economy</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/how-labour-crashed-the-british-economy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In its&amp;#160;manifesto for the 2024 general election, Britain’s Labour party listed “Five Missions to Rebuild Britain,” the first being: “Kickstart economic growth.”&amp;#160; The party’s second budget since winning that election, delivered on November 26 by Chancellor of the Exchequer Rachel Reeves, suggests it has already abandoned that mission—and offers a cautionary tale to other governments...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/how-labour-crashed-the-british-economy/"&gt;How Labour crashed the British economy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] What is proof? What is evidence?</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/what-is-proof-what-is-evidence/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The debate over how much fraud has been committed against Minnesota social welfare programs has now gone national. Joe Thompson, the First Assistant U.S. Attorney and lead prosector of the fraud cases, appeared on the Fox New Laura Ingraham show last night. A clip, Meanwhile, about an hour before Thompson appeared on Fox News last...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/what-is-proof-what-is-evidence/"&gt;What is proof? What is evidence?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 15:49:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Chicago adopts $16.6B budget, adds $535M in taxes</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/chicago-adopts-16-6b-budget-adds-535m-in-taxes/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Chicago aldermen for the first time pushed through their own budget, rejecting the mayor’s effort to impose a job-killing head tax. There are other taxes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/chicago-adopts-16-6b-budget-adds-535m-in-taxes/"&gt;Chicago adopts $16.6B budget, adds $535M in taxes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org"&gt;Illinois Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 23:09:53 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>