<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>State-Policy Think-Tank Digest</title><link>https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml</link><description>Latest posts from free-market policy institutes across the U.S.</description><atom:link href="https://ndejongspn.github.io/RSS_Affiliate/rss.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 19:03:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>[Virginiainstitute] Press Release – VIPP Champions AI Moratorium, Invokes Commerce Clause</title><link>https://virginiainstitute.org/5850-2/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=5850-2</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Virginia Institute for Public Policy’s statement for memorandum highlights the urgent need for a coordinated federal approach to AI regulation, leveraging constitutional authority to avoid a fragmented and counterproductive patchwork of state laws. The proposed moratorium offers a pragmatic pathway to safeguard innovation, support small businesses, and ensure U.S. leadership in the rapidly evolving global AI landscape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org/5850-2/"&gt;Press Release – VIPP Champions AI Moratorium, Invokes Commerce Clause&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://virginiainstitute.org"&gt;Virginia Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 14:10:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cardinalinstitute] Colleges Must Educate for Freedom</title><link>https://cardinalinstitute.com/colleges-must-educate-for-freedom/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Colleges Must Educate for Freedom A great American college or university will prepare students for self-governance as both a wise human being and a prudent, productive citizen. Rightly understood, the liberal arts are the intellectual potentials shared by the leaders of a free people. That is, education policy should consider, first of all, how to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com/colleges-must-educate-for-freedom/"&gt;Colleges Must Educate for Freedom&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cardinalinstitute.com"&gt;Cardinal Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 16:31:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Arkansaspolicyfoundation] MEDICAL CARE IDEAS ADVANCE</title><link>https://arkansaspolicyfoundation.org/medical-care-ideas-advance/</link><description>(2025-2Q) The Arkansas Policy Foundation was founded by business leaders to serve the community and advance ideas to create more prosperity for Arkansans. The Policy Foundation was founded 30 years ago as a 501(c)(3) nonprofit, nonpartisan think tank that publishes credible research, hosts forums to encourage citizenship and is cited in national and state news [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 06:09:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] A better way to get welfare recipients back into the labor force</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/better-way-to-get-welfare-recipients-back-into-labor-force/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;If the One Big Beautiful Bill becomes law, states will quickly discover that their administrative systems are ill-equipped to move recipients from welfare to work. To succeed, states should adopt a more integrated approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/better-way-to-get-welfare-recipients-back-into-labor-force/"&gt;A better way to get welfare recipients back into the labor force&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 07:20:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] WATCH: Megan Martin on PCN Discussing State Budget, Mass Transit Bail-out, and More</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/07/01/watch-megan-martin-on-pcn-discussing-state-budget-mass-transit-bail-out-and-more/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Megan Martin, Commonwealth Foundation&amp;#8217;s Chief Operating Officer and General Counsel, joins PCN&amp;#8217;s Capitol Preview to talk all things state budget. From public transit to Lifeline Scholarships, Martin outlines what good looks like in this year&amp;#8217;s budget, and which proposals will damage Pennsylvania&amp;#8217;s economic future. Watch below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/07/01/watch-megan-martin-on-pcn-discussing-state-budget-mass-transit-bail-out-and-more/"&gt;WATCH: Megan Martin on PCN Discussing State Budget, Mass Transit Bail-out, and More&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 13:27:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] How both sides lost the ConVal school funding case</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/07/how-both-sides-lost-the-conval-school-funding-case/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday morning, the New Hampshire Supreme Court for the first time ordered the state to spend a minimum amount of money—$7,356.01 per pupil—to educate public school students.  The state therefore lost this landmark school funding case, Contoocook Valley School District v. State, as it had tried to avoid such a decree. But a closer [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/07/how-both-sides-lost-the-conval-school-funding-case/"&gt;How both sides lost the ConVal school funding case&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 17:57:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Closing the Gap: How Wisconsin’s Budget Continues to Close the Funding Gap Between Public &amp; Parental Choice Options</title><link>https://will-law.org/closing-the-gap-how-wisconsins-budget-continues-to-close-the-funding-gap-between-public-parental-choice-options/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Like any budget that is a result of compromise in divided government, there are positive and negative aspects.  But one definite positive to come from this year's budget agreement is the continued closing of the spending gap between private, charter, and traditional public schools.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/closing-the-gap-how-wisconsins-budget-continues-to-close-the-funding-gap-between-public-parental-choice-options/"&gt;Closing the Gap: How Wisconsin’s Budget Continues to Close the Funding Gap Between Public &amp;#038; Parental Choice Options&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 18:57:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Welfare stands in the way of the American dream</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/welfare-stands-in-the-way-of-the-american-dream/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Meaningful relationships and a strong sense of community are as much a part of the American dream as any economic measure. What’s rarely discussed is how systemic obstacles are undermining these important aspects of a flourishing life. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/welfare-stands-in-the-way-of-the-american-dream/"&gt;Welfare stands in the way of the American dream&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 18:55:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] OBBB Delivers Historic Expansion of Educational Choice, Sweeping Reforms</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/07/03/obbb-delivers-historic-expansion-of-educational-choice-sweeping-reforms/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Harrisburg, Pa., July 3, 2025 —&amp;#160;After much anticipation and debate, the One Big, Beautiful Bill (OBBB) is now passed and set to be enacted—delivering policy accomplishments that Pennsylvanians can celebrate: Protecting Taxpayers: Preventing an average $2,500 tax hike per Pennsylvania taxpayer. Nearly every Pennsylvanian has benefited from the 2017 Tax Cuts and Job Act, which [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/07/03/obbb-delivers-historic-expansion-of-educational-choice-sweeping-reforms/"&gt;OBBB Delivers Historic Expansion of Educational Choice, Sweeping Reforms&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 19:17:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Foropportunity] Are we witnessing a Baltimore Miracle in the fight against crime?</title><link>https://foropportunity.org/baltimore-miracle-in-fight-against-crime/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Baltimore has struggled with crime, especially drugs and violent crime, in both reality and in the imaginations of the American people for decades. That is, until recently. What changed and what can other high-crime cities learn from Baltimore's approach? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org/baltimore-miracle-in-fight-against-crime/"&gt;Are we witnessing a Baltimore Miracle in the fight against crime?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://foropportunity.org"&gt;Georgia Center For Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 19:33:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] A Game-Changer for School Choice in Our State!</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/a-game-changer-for-school-choice-in-our-state/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Some groundbreaking news for Mississippi!&amp;#160; With the passage of the&amp;#160;One Big Beautiful Bill, a federal tax credit is due to transform the school choice landscape in our state. &amp;#160;This new tax credit enables individual donors to fund scholarships for local Mississippi families, who will now be able to select the schools that best suit their [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/a-game-changer-for-school-choice-in-our-state/" rel="nofollow"&gt;A Game-Changer for School Choice in Our State!&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 17:57:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] 97 NYSLRS Retirees Eligible for Pensions Over $200K in FY2025</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/97-nyslrs-retirees-eligible-for-pensions-over-200k-in-fy2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A total of 97 retirees from the New York State and Local Retirement System (NYSLRS) were eligible for pensions of....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/97-nyslrs-retirees-eligible-for-pensions-over-200k-in-fy2025/"&gt;97 NYSLRS Retirees Eligible for Pensions Over $200K in FY2025&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 13:50:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Frontierinstitute] Montana Leading with Free Market Healthcare</title><link>https://frontierinstitute.org/montana-leading-with-free-market-healthcare/</link><description>By eliminating the middlemen and bureaucracy involved in billing third parties, DPC providers are able to save patients money and focus on their health while also being radically transparent with their prices – a breath of fresh air in today’s modern healthcare world.</description><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 18:26:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Dr. Keri Ingraham: Industry-Specific High Schools</title><link>https://empowerms.org/dr-keri-ingraham-industry-specific-high-schools/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Dr. Keri Ingraham: Industry-Specific High Schools Join us on the Empower Podcast as we dive into the transformative world of industry-specific high schools with Dr. Keri Ingraham, whose recent policy brief at the American Enterprise Institute, “The Case for Industry-Specific High Schools,” is sparking conversation. In this episode, Dr. Ingraham explains why these specialized schools&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/dr-keri-ingraham-industry-specific-high-schools/"&gt;Dr. Keri Ingraham: Industry-Specific High Schools&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 01:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] HB 2089 Brings Oregon into Compliance with the Supreme Court’s Tyler Ruling on Property Rights and Home Equity</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/tax-and-budget/hb-2089-brings-oregon-into-compliance-with-the-supreme-courts-tyler-ruling-on-property-rights-and-home-equity/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Kathryn Hickok With the passage of House Bill 2089 in late June,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/tax-and-budget/hb-2089-brings-oregon-into-compliance-with-the-supreme-courts-tyler-ruling-on-property-rights-and-home-equity/"&gt;HB 2089 Brings Oregon into Compliance with the Supreme Court’s Tyler Ruling on Property Rights and Home Equity&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 14:06:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] Tim Walz Leaves Minnesotans on the Hook for a $430,000 Legal Bill</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/tim-walz-leaves-minnesotans-on-the-hook-for-a-430000-legal-bill/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Minnesota Gov. Tim Walz already has taxpayer-funded legal counsel. Additionally, he has access to the Attorney General&amp;#8217;s office. Yet, Minnesota taxpayers are now left to foot a $430,000 legal bill from outside lawyers that Walz racked up trying to prepare for a congressional hearing where he provided testimony on his Sanctuary City illegal immigration policies. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/tim-walz-leaves-minnesotans-on-the-hook-for-a-430000-legal-bill/"&gt;Tim Walz Leaves Minnesotans on the Hook for a $430,000 Legal Bill&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 19:22:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] What the “One Big Beautiful Bill Act” Means for School Choice in Mississippi</title><link>https://empowerms.org/what-the-one-big-beautiful-bill-act-means-for-school-choice-in-mississippi/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;There are two aspects to the school choice provisions in the OBBB: a tax credit for contributions to organizations that provide scholarships to students in public or private schools, and rules those organizations have to follow in granting scholarships (including eligibility of scholarship students).  Tax Credit for Contributions  Starting in 2027, an individual taxpayer (not&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/what-the-one-big-beautiful-bill-act-means-for-school-choice-in-mississippi/"&gt;What the “One Big Beautiful Bill Act” Means for School Choice in Mississippi&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 21:47:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] NJ SPOTLIGHT: Marathon school segregation case goes to appeals court</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/07/nj-spotlight-marathon-school-segregation-case-goes-to-appeals-court/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In this NJ Spotlight News piece, the long-running New Jersey school segregation case moves to the Appellate Division. As the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/07/nj-spotlight-marathon-school-segregation-case-goes-to-appeals-court/"&gt;NJ SPOTLIGHT: Marathon school segregation case goes to appeals court&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 15:56:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] NORTHJERSEY.COM: Appeals court to hear arguments in NJ school segregation lawsuit</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/07/northjersey-com-appeals-court-to-hear-arguments-in-nj-school-segregation-lawsuit/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In this NorthJersey.com article, the New Jersey appellate court prepares to hear arguments in the high‑profile school segregation lawsuit filed [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/07/northjersey-com-appeals-court-to-hear-arguments-in-nj-school-segregation-lawsuit/"&gt;NORTHJERSEY.COM: Appeals court to hear arguments in NJ school segregation lawsuit&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 16:00:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] Congressional Republicans Call Out Walz’s ‘Wasted Taxpayer Money’</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/congressional-republicans-call-out-walzs-wasted-taxpayer-money/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Minnesota Republicans criticized the use of taxpayer funds for the legal counsel, with U.S. House Majority Whip Tom Emmer calling the governor a “scam artist” and Rep. Pete Stauber saying, “more wasted taxpayer money by the ‘knucklehead.’” It&amp;#8217;s extremely disappointing that the governor felt the need to burn nearly half a million dollars of taxpayer [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/congressional-republicans-call-out-walzs-wasted-taxpayer-money/"&gt;Congressional Republicans Call Out Walz&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8216;Wasted Taxpayer Money&amp;#8217;&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 18:39:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Antiquated Wisconsin law doesn’t allow driverless vehicles</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/antiquated-wisconsin-law-doesnt-allow-driverless-vehicles/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As self-driving taxis roll out across much of America, Wisconsinites won’t be seeing them without some changes to existing law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/antiquated-wisconsin-law-doesnt-allow-driverless-vehicles/"&gt;Antiquated Wisconsin law doesn’t allow driverless vehicles&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 21:37:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] Albuquerque Mayoral Candidate Eddie Varela completes RGF candidate survey</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/albuquerque-mayoral-candidate-eddie-varela-completes-rgf-candidate-survey/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In its ongoing efforts to ensure that voters are fully informed about the views and plans of the various candidates for Albuquerque Mayor. The latest candidate to respond is Eddie Varela. His survey can be found here. Varela&amp;#8217;s campaign website can be accessed here. You can also see images of Varela&amp;#8217;s survey answers below: &amp;#160; [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/albuquerque-mayoral-candidate-eddie-varela-completes-rgf-candidate-survey/"&gt;Albuquerque Mayoral Candidate Eddie Varela completes RGF candidate survey&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 22:32:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundationofminnesota] Sec. Simon Should Hop Off the Ranked-Choice Voting Train</title><link>https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/sec-simon-should-hop-off-the-ranked-choice-voting-train/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Ranked-Choice Voting must be rejected when it presents itself in Minnesota. Our republic deserves no less than our willingness to educate voters about this failed voting system and to resist misguided efforts like Sec. Simons who wants to expand this radical scheme to all Minnesota cities and counties. &amp;#8212; Secretary of State backs legislation to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM/sec-simon-should-hop-off-the-ranked-choice-voting-train/"&gt;Sec. Simon Should Hop Off the Ranked-Choice Voting Train&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://FREEDOMFOUNDATIONOFMINNESOTA.COM"&gt;Freedom Foundation of Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 13:13:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] In Special Session, West Hartford Democrats Set Sights on Fiscal Guardrails — Again</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/07/11/in-special-session-west-hartford-democrats-set-sights-on-fiscal-guardrails-again/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you thought Connecticut’s fiscal guardrails were safe, think again.   At a post-session town hall in West Hartford on July 8, local Democratic legislators made it abundantly clear that [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/07/11/in-special-session-west-hartford-democrats-set-sights-on-fiscal-guardrails-again/"&gt;In Special Session, West Hartford Democrats Set Sights on Fiscal Guardrails — Again &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 15:25:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] Average Pay at Port Authority Surges as 11 Employees Collect $400k+</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/average-pay-at-panynj-surges-as-11-employees-collect-400k/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Eleven Port Authority of New York and New Jersey (PANYNJ) employees collected more than $400,000 each in total pay last....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/average-pay-at-panynj-surges-as-11-employees-collect-400k/"&gt;Average Pay at Port Authority Surges as 11 Employees Collect $400k+&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 15:40:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/07/14041/</link><description>Urban Life: Shoplifting HOW ARE THINGS GOING?&amp;#160;Well, few venture out after dusk&amp;#160;on&amp;#160;our multi-million-dollar trail system;&amp;#160;there are stabbings at&amp;#160;Promenade&amp;#160;Park, if that tells you anything;&amp;#160;shootings threaten to become&amp;#160;routine&amp;#160;on the streets below our&amp;#160;majestic new downtown constructions; and there is shoplifting and theft throughout. At some point we are going to have to face a sad fact, that is,&amp;#160;there&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/07/14041/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 18:12:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Legislature passes 15 housing reform bills in 2025</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/07/legislature-passes-15-housing-reform-bills-in-2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Five years ago, there was little action in the Legislature to address the decades-long rising cost of housing in New Hampshire. St. Anselm College polling found in 2020 that voters hadn&amp;#8217;t yet connected surging prices to local land use regulations. Only 28.7% of voters said local governments should relax planning and zoning rules to allow [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/07/legislature-passes-15-housing-reform-bills-in-2025/"&gt;Legislature passes 15 housing reform bills in 2025&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 18:34:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Frontierinstitute] Mike Mansfield and the Japanese</title><link>https://frontierinstitute.org/mike-mansfield-and-the-japanese/</link><description>"In 1988, on behalf of America and with Mike Mansfield’s support, President Ronald Reagan formally apologized for the internments and publicly admitted they were not justified."</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 17:43:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] Mississippi’s Moment: Bold Reforms to Drive Growth</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/mississippis-moment-bold-reforms-to-drive-growth/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Mississippi is shedding its image as an economic laggard. Over the past five years, the state’s economic output has grown more than it did over the previous fifteen years combined. According to the U.S. Bureau of Economic Analysis, Mississippi posted the second-fastest per capita GDP growth and fifth-fastest personal income growth among all states in [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/mississippis-moment-bold-reforms-to-drive-growth/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi’s Moment: Bold Reforms to Drive Growth&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 17:49:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Commonwealthfoundation] PA House Democrats Pass Unbalanced, Reckless Spending Bill</title><link>https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/07/14/pa-house-democrats-pass-unbalanced-reckless-spending-bill/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Harrisburg, Pa., July 14, 2025 — Today, Pennsylvania House Democrats passed the General Appropriations Act (HB 1330), their version of a budget bill, which includes a $2.9 billion spending increase. The bill would increase general fund spending to $50.6 billion—exacerbating Pennsylvania’s structural deficit, by spending $5.3 billion more than revenue. Lawmakers would need to drain [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org/2025/07/14/pa-house-democrats-pass-unbalanced-reckless-spending-bill/"&gt;PA House Democrats Pass Unbalanced, Reckless Spending Bill&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://commonwealthfoundation.org"&gt;Commonwealth Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 21:52:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Kansas Taxpayers Still Waiting: Budget Bloat Blocks Relief Despite Strong Revenues</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/kansas-budget-bloat-despite-strong-revenues/</link><description>Kansas recently reported better-than-expected tax receipts—$248 million above projections—for the fiscal year ending June 30, 2025. Yet despite this encouraging news, Kansans won’t be seeing tax cuts anytime soon. Why? Because government spending continues to outpace sustainable levels, and the state’s new automatic tax reduction law has built-in roadblocks that delay relief even when taxpayers [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 14:00:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] The Outstater</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/07/the-outstater-278/</link><description>Islamists, Welcome? &amp;#8220;Islamism is a totalitarian ideology that seeks to impose a rigid, theocratic order, incompatible with the pluralistic values of Western civilization.” — Ayaan Hirsi Ali, Somali-born author and activist for women’s rights.&amp;#160; THE DEGRADING&amp;#160;EFFECTS&amp;#160;are&amp;#160;inarguable in&amp;#160;a half dozen U.S. cities, not to mention in the great cultural centers&amp;#160;of&amp;#160;Great Britain and Europe. So why are&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/07/the-outstater-278/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 17:10:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Newjerseypolicyinstitute] NJ ED REPORT: Is Murphy Stalling the Segregation Lawsuit? What Would His Successor Do?</title><link>https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/07/nj-ed-report-is-murphy-stalling-the-segregation-lawsuit-what-would-his-successor-do/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A new NJ Education Report article covers a high-stakes lawsuit accusing the Murphy administration of stalling efforts to fix New [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org/2025/07/nj-ed-report-is-murphy-stalling-the-segregation-lawsuit-what-would-his-successor-do/"&gt;NJ ED REPORT: Is Murphy Stalling the Segregation Lawsuit? What Would His Successor Do?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://newjerseypolicyinstitute.org"&gt;New Jersey Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 18:36:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] One Big Beautiful Bill and Nebraska’s Fiscal Response</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/one-big-beautiful-bill-and-nebraskas-fiscal-response/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The One Big Beautiful Bill introduces sweeping changes to federal fiscal policy that will have tangible impacts on the state of Nebraska. Policymakers must choose which provisions to adopt of the federal law and which to defer. These decisions will have significant budgetary and growth implications for Nebraska.   On the tax side, the OBBB makes...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/one-big-beautiful-bill-and-nebraskas-fiscal-response/" rel="nofollow"&gt;One Big Beautiful Bill and Nebraska’s Fiscal Response&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 13:58:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] TriMet’s Plan for 82nd Avenue “Road Diet” Looms in Metro Decision</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/transportation/trimets-plan-for-82nd-avenue-road-diet-looms-in-metro-decision/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Maxwell Powers TriMet has a new “road diet” planned for Portland, this...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/transportation/trimets-plan-for-82nd-avenue-road-diet-looms-in-metro-decision/"&gt;TriMet’s Plan for 82nd Avenue “Road Diet” Looms in Metro Decision&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 14:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG Announces Chief Operating Officer</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-announces-chief-operating-officer/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;THE NEWS The Institute for Reforming Government (IRG) has promoted Chris Reader to Chief Operating Officer. In this expanded role, Chris will manage the day-to-day operations of IRG, overseeing its team and project portfolio. Reader has also been named the Executive Director of IRG Action Fund, IRG’s 501(C)(4) advocacy partner.   THE QUOTE CJ Szafir, IRG, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-announces-chief-operating-officer/"&gt;IRG Announces Chief Operating Officer&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 15:54:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Massachusetts and the Energy Equation: Balancing Imports with Innovation</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/blog/usdatalabs/massachusetts-and-the-energy-equation-balancing-imports-with-innovation/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The gap between the energy Massachusetts produces and the amount it consumes results in a reliance on out-of-state energy sources, making the Commonwealth vulnerable to price volatility and supply disruptions. While consumer prices continue to rise, clean energy production provides an avenue for the state to be more energy self-sufficient. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/blog/usdatalabs/massachusetts-and-the-energy-equation-balancing-imports-with-innovation/"&gt;Massachusetts and the Energy Equation: Balancing Imports with Innovation&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 19:20:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Sophistry</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/sophistry/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/sophistry/" rel="nofollow" title="Sophistry"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Cream-Neutral-Minimalist-New-Business-Pitch-Deck-Presentation-Copy.jpg" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;NOTE: This op-ed has been edited by the author to ensure it adheres to the guidelines of our 501(c)(3) organizational status. Sophistry is the use of fallacious arguments with the intent to deceive. Critics will use sophistry to make an argument when the facts do not support their position. We see this all too often [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 21:55:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] NEW: “School Dashboard” Provides Comprehensive District Data to Wisconsin Families</title><link>https://will-law.org/new-school-dashboard-provides-comprehensive-district-data-to-wisconsin-families/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WILL released its 2025 School Scorecard Dashboard with new features and data sets to better equip parents, education stakeholders, and taxpayers with insight on how school districts across the state are performing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/new-school-dashboard-provides-comprehensive-district-data-to-wisconsin-families/"&gt;NEW: “School Dashboard” Provides Comprehensive District Data to Wisconsin Families&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 14:28:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] Trump Administration, Congress Offer Vastly Different Visions for the Future of the Housing Choice Voucher Program</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/trump-administration-congress-offer-vastly-different-visions-for-the-future-of-the-housing-choice-voucher-program/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This edition of The House Call explores a federal proposal to cut Housing and Urban Development funding by 44 percent, and how it contrasts with a more recent congressional appropriations bill. The newsletter also provides an update on compliance with Massachusetts' multifamily zoning mandate around MBTA stations after the latest deadline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/trump-administration-congress-offer-vastly-different-visions-for-the-future-of-the-housing-choice-voucher-program/"&gt;Trump Administration, Congress Offer Vastly Different Visions for the Future of the Housing Choice Voucher Program&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 15:09:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] Albuquerque Mayoral Candidate Darren White completes RGF Mayoral candidate survey</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/albuquerque-mayoral-candidate-darren-white-completes-rgf-mayoral-candidate-survey/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce that Albuquerque mayoral candidate (former Bernalillo County Sheriff and former Secretary of the New Mexico Department of Public Safety) Darren White, has completed and submitted the Rio Grande Foundation&amp;#8217;s mayoral candidate survey. You can find that survey embedded below and linked to here.  You can also find White&amp;#8217;s campaign website here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/albuquerque-mayoral-candidate-darren-white-completes-rgf-mayoral-candidate-survey/"&gt;Albuquerque Mayoral Candidate Darren White completes RGF Mayoral candidate survey&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 16:16:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Will Law] Wisconsin Bar Association Eliminates Race-Based DEI in Settlement with WILL</title><link>https://will-law.org/wisconsin-bar-association-eliminates-race-based-dei-in-settlement-with-will/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The State Bar of Wisconsin has agreed to settle a federal lawsuit and remove harmful and discriminatory “diversity, equity, and inclusion,” or DEI, from its program. The Bar also agreed to change its definition of diversity and will no longer consider race, religion, sex, or other characteristics when determining eligibility for its programs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://will-law.org/wisconsin-bar-association-eliminates-race-based-dei-in-settlement-with-will/"&gt;Wisconsin Bar Association Eliminates Race-Based DEI in Settlement with WILL&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://will-law.org"&gt;Wisconsin Institute for Law &amp;amp; Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 16:55:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empirecenter] A Warning for New York’s Energy Policy</title><link>https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/a-warning-for-new-yorks-energy-policy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On June 24th New York’s electricity grid nearly blew a fuse. That day was extremely hot, and air conditioning was....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org/publications/a-warning-for-new-yorks-energy-policy/"&gt;A Warning for New York’s Energy Policy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.empirecenter.org"&gt;Empire Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 17:50:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Robocars vs. overpriced groceries</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/robocars-vs-overpriced-groceries/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;And the real reason Wisconsin won’t join the modern world and let cars operate without drivers With automated, driverless robotaxis carrying paying passengers in at least half a dozen cities, but none of them in Wisconsin because our state law will not permit it, you may wonder why we don’t just change our law. Why [...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/robocars-vs-overpriced-groceries/"&gt;Robocars vs. overpriced groceries&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 21:37:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Badgerinstitute] Supreme Court gives governor’s bureaucrats free rein</title><link>https://www.badgerinstitute.org/supreme-court-gives-governors-bureaucrats-free-rein/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A state Supreme Court decision wresting rulemaking authority from elected state representatives has opened the door to a barrage of new regulations and fees in Wisconsin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org/supreme-court-gives-governors-bureaucrats-free-rein/"&gt;Supreme Court gives governor’s bureaucrats free rein&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.badgerinstitute.org"&gt;Badger Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 21:38:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] California May Never Get High-Speed Rail as Brightline Also Struggles</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/california-may-never-get-high-speed-rail-as-brightline-also-struggles/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=california-may-never-get-high-speed-rail-as-brightline-also-struggles</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Although Governor Newsom and Rail Authority management are in denial, President Trump’s decision to claw back $4 billion in California high-speed rail funding is likely the coup de grace for the state project. But the state’s other high-speed rail project, Brightline West’s effort to connect Rancho Cucamonga with Las Vegas, also faces headwinds and may...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/california-may-never-get-high-speed-rail-as-brightline-also-struggles/"&gt;California May Never Get High-Speed Rail as Brightline Also Struggles&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 22:36:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Job Licensing Reviews: Education Committee</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/job-licensing-reviews-education-committee/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Occupational Board Reform Act (OBRA) was passed in 2018 and became effective in 2019. It requires legislative committees of jurisdiction to review all occupational licenses in the state, roughly 20% per year, on a five-year rotation. These reviews examine whether the licensing requirements are adequate or excessive by current standards. The committees then submit...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/job-licensing-reviews-education-committee/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Job Licensing Reviews: Education Committee&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 16:59:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Alabamapolicy] Parents: Ask Your District How They Will Comply</title><link>https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/07/18/parents-ask-your-district-how-they-will-comply/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A momentous parental rights victory was handed down by the United States Supreme Court on Friday, June 27, 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org/2025/07/18/parents-ask-your-district-how-they-will-comply/"&gt;Parents: Ask Your District How They Will Comply&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://alabamapolicy.org"&gt;Alabama Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 17:45:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] Week in Review: Transparency is the Law</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-transparency-is-the-law/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;What happens when a federal agency targets a successful business, demands millions in fines, and then refuses to explain why?..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/week-in-review-transparency-is-the-law/"&gt;Week in Review: Transparency is the Law&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 18:15:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Boise’s FY26 Budget: A Betrayal of Taxpayer Trust</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/boises-fy26-budget-a-betrayal-of-taxpayer-trust/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/boises-fy26-budget-a-betrayal-of-taxpayer-trust/" rel="nofollow" title="Boise’s FY26 Budget: A Betrayal of Taxpayer Trust"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Cream-Neutral-Minimalist-New-Business-Pitch-Deck-Presentation-1.jpg" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;On July 15, 2025, the Boise City Council approved the FY26 budget, which included a 4% property tax increase — 3% allowed by law, plus a 1% foregone hike — ignoring the financial strain on residents. As one of the few voices opposing this budget, I’m dismayed by the council’s disregard for taxpayers and the [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 19:19:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] SEIU Wants Unemployment for Strikers — While Blowing Cash on Billboards</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/07/18/seiu-wants-unemployment-for-strikers-while-blowing-cash-on-billboards/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Hartford Portfolio" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="200" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/HP.jpeg" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When 1,700 unionized healthcare workers went on strike in the spring of 2023, SEIU 1199 New England had millions in reserve — including a strike fund. But instead of using [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/07/18/seiu-wants-unemployment-for-strikers-while-blowing-cash-on-billboards/"&gt;SEIU Wants Unemployment for Strikers — While Blowing Cash on Billboards&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 19:33:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jbartlett] Do advocates for total government dependency have any limiting principles?</title><link>https://jbartlett.org/2025/07/do-advocates-for-total-government-dependency-have-any-limiting-principles/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;“I find more and more that dependency from [upon] the will of others is always some diminution of human happiness, principally to a man accustom’d to follow his own will uncontrolled.”  &amp;#8211; Jan Ingenhousz to Ben Franklin, 1777 &amp;#160; During the two weeks since Americans celebrated the 249th anniversary of the Declaration of Independence, political [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org/2025/07/do-advocates-for-total-government-dependency-have-any-limiting-principles/"&gt;Do advocates for total government dependency have any limiting principles?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jbartlett.org"&gt;THE JOSIAH BARTLETT CENTER FOR PUBLIC POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 19:45:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Listen: Maine’s Housing Crisis on Inside Maine</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/listen-maines-housing-crisis-on-inside-maine/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Policy analyst, Harris Van Pate, joined Josh Filler of Inside Maine to discuss Maine Policy&amp;#8217;s recent analysis &amp;#8220;Under Construction&amp;#8221; to discuss the rising costs of living and housing across Maine, the underlying contributors, and what the state and municipalities can do to combat it. Listen to the full interview below. Newsradio WGAN · Harris Van [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/listen-maines-housing-crisis-on-inside-maine/"&gt;Listen: Maine&amp;#8217;s Housing Crisis on Inside Maine&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2025 17:01:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] High school, college students can earn $10,000, $5,000 or $1,000 from Jones Act essay contest</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/07/high-school-college-students-can-earn-10000-5000-or-1000-from-jones-act-essay-contest/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The first- and second-prize winners in each division will also have their essays published in the magazine of the Coolidge Foundation The Calvin Coolidge Presidential Foundation, based in Plymouth, Vermont, is inviting high school and college students nationwide to participate in an essay competition about whether the 1920 federal law known as the Jones Act [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/07/high-school-college-students-can-earn-10000-5000-or-1000-from-jones-act-essay-contest/"&gt;High school, college students can earn $10,000, $5,000 or $1,000 from Jones Act essay contest&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2025 21:58:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Hawaii climate policy going overboard on cruise ships</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/07/hawaii-climate-policy-going-overboard-on-cruise-ships/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Hawaii has a problem. When the only plan to accomplish certain goals is to put people out of work and damage the state’s economy, you know we have to look for a better way. My latest case in point is the new climate&amp;#160;roadmap&amp;#160;from the state Department of Transportation, which calls for reducing cruise ship visitors [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/07/hawaii-climate-policy-going-overboard-on-cruise-ships/"&gt;Hawaii climate policy going overboard on cruise ships&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2025 21:59:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Grassrootinstitute] Maui lawmakers give green light to food trucks and kitchenettes</title><link>https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/07/maui-lawmakers-give-green-light-to-food-trucks-and-kitchenettes/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Also on Maui, the Planning Commission backs a bill that would make it easier for B&amp;#38;Bs destroyed in the 2023 fires to rebuild The Maui County Council and Mayor Richard Bissen have approved measures supported by the Grassroot Institute of Hawaii that will expand economic opportunities for farmers and ranchers and make a dent in [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org/2025/07/maui-lawmakers-give-green-light-to-food-trucks-and-kitchenettes/"&gt;Maui lawmakers give green light to food trucks and kitchenettes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.grassrootinstitute.org"&gt;Grassroot Institute of Hawaii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2025 22:09:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Illinois 3X taxes on Juul, Elf Bar, ZYN products to fund more spending</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/illinois-3x-taxes-on-juul-elf-bar-zyn-products-to-fund-more-spending/</link><description>In another short-term revenue move, Illinois lawmakers July 1 turned to vape and other nicotine product tax hikes to allow ever-more spending. Taxes on vape products went from 15% to 45% of the wholesale cost.</description><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 10:00:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Beacon Takes Permit Battle to U.S. Supreme Court</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/beacon-takes-permit-battle-to-u-s-supreme-court/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=beacon-takes-permit-battle-to-u-s-supreme-court</link><description>Housing affordability is one of the biggest challenges facing Americans today. The only way out of the mess is to let builders build more housing, and that’s why it’s crucial for the Supreme Court to take this case.</description><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 13:07:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Fighting back against bureaucratic permit delays at the Supreme Court: Richmond Road v. Warrensville Heights</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/richmond-road-partners-v-city-of-warrensville-heights-fighting-back-against-bureaucratic-permit-delays-at-the-supreme-court/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=richmond-road-partners-v-city-of-warrensville-heights-fighting-back-against-bureaucratic-permit-delays-at-the-supreme-court</link><description>Beacon has petitioned the United States Supreme Court for review on an important property rights issue that affects thousands of Tennesseans.</description><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 13:18:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] New federal tax change will make our region less competitive unless state lawmakers act</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/new-federal-tax-change-will-make-our-region-less-competitive-unless-state-lawmakers-act</link><description>Note: This is a guest op-ed by the Tax Foundation. In most respects, Idaho and Montana have been enthusiastic in their pursuit of tax...</description><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 14:13:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] California’s State of Decay</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/californias-state-of-decay/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=californias-state-of-decay</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Conservative criticism of California focuses, with good reason, on the perils of progressive ideology. The dysfunction caused by progressives in power is evident in the state’s dismal system of public education, its ongoing challenges maintaining law and order, and chronic, escalating state and local government budget deficits that threaten to entirely collapse services that are...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/californias-state-of-decay/"&gt;California’s State of Decay&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 15:50:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Ed Feulner (1941-2025): A National Leader with a Virginian Heart</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/ed-feulner-1941-2025-a-national-leader-with-a-virginian-heart/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="450" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Ed-Feulner-white.jpg" width="900" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the spring of 1971, the U.S. Senate was set to debate and vote on continued government support of the supersonic transport (SST), with most conservatives opposing taxpayer funding in favor of private sector support. A few days after the vote, a well-researched study from an old-line “think tank” landed in Senators’ offices. Why hadn’t it [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/ed-feulner-1941-2025-a-national-leader-with-a-virginian-heart/"&gt;Ed Feulner (1941-2025): A National Leader with a Virginian Heart&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 16:16:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Panasonic’s EV Gamble Isn’t Capitalism—It’s Corporate Welfare</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/panasonics-ev-gamble-is-corporate-welfare/</link><description>Kansas just got played. Again. Panasonic’s $4 billion EV battery plant in De Soto—touted as the state’s biggest economic development deal ever—is now delayed. Why? Because the federal government finally decided to stop propping up the electric vehicle market with taxpayer cash. President Trump’s “Big, Beautiful Bill” kills the $7,500 new EV tax credit and [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 16:56:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mspolicy] 10 Best Things About Mississippi</title><link>https://mspolicy.org/10-best-things-about-mississippi/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Speaking to my friends at Smith County Republicans the other day, someone asked me what I most loved about moving to Mississippi from London. There are so many things I love about the Magnolia state, the more I thought about it, the longer my answer grew.&amp;#160;&amp;#160;I thought I’d list a few of my favorite things [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org/10-best-things-about-mississippi/" rel="nofollow"&gt;10 Best Things About Mississippi&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mspolicy.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mississippi Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 17:38:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Louisiana Quarterly Economic Report – Summer 2025</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/tax-budget/louisiana-quarterly-economic-report-summer-2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Download the Full Report Here&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/tax-budget/louisiana-quarterly-economic-report-summer-2025/"&gt;Louisiana Quarterly Economic Report – Summer 2025&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 19:44:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Crypto Week Recap</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/crypto-week-recap/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Before assuming office for his second term, President Trump made clear that his administration would renew a push for United States leadership in cryptocurrency. The technology is increasingly common, accessible, and beneficial for economies and users. However, in a world where emerging technologies are so heavily regulated, interested Americans have been hesitant to jump all...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/technology-innovation/crypto-week-recap/"&gt;Crypto Week Recap&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 23:46:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG Court Watch Report: Wisconsin Supreme Court Term in Review</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-court-watch-report-wisconsin-supreme-court-term-in-review/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;IRG Court Watch Report: Wisconsin Supreme Court Term in Review Court Delivers Progressive Wins in Wisconsin for the First Time in Over a Decade Delafield, Wis. – The Institute for Reforming Government’s (IRG) Court Watch released a report detailing the Wisconsin Supreme Court’s 2024-2025 term on Tuesday, analyzing the new path taken by the Court’s [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-court-watch-report-wisconsin-supreme-court-term-in-review/"&gt;IRG Court Watch Report: Wisconsin Supreme Court Term in Review&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 12:56:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Inpolicy] Franke: Hagiography or Iconoclasm?</title><link>https://inpolicy.org/2025/07/franke-hagiography-or-iconoclasm/</link><description>by Mark Franke Someone, and I wish I could remember who, said culture was the telling to ourselves stories about ourselves. OK, but what if we have conflicting stories to tell? The assumption behind all this is that the stories are at least partially true, if not in every detail then at least in the&lt;a class="moretag" href="https://inpolicy.org/2025/07/franke-hagiography-or-iconoclasm/"&gt; Read the full article...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 13:01:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] FOIA Fight: Detroit Free Press, Mackinac Center Sue Treasury Over Subsidy Secrecy</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/pressroom/2025/foia-fight-detroit-free-press-mackinac-center-sue-treasury-over-subsidy-secrecy</link><description>Lawsuit demands records detailing how tax dollars are used in Detroit redevelopment deal</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 14:38:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Beacontn] Beacon’s $1.4 Million Stormwater Settlement Receives Preliminary Court Approval</title><link>https://www.beacontn.org/settlement/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=settlement</link><description>Hundreds of property owners are now closer to receiving the refunds they deserve.</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 15:28:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Riograndefoundation] BBB Is Not The Tragedy Our Politicians Portray</title><link>https://riograndefoundation.org/bbb-is-not-the-tragedy-our-politicians-portray/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The following appeared in Eastern New Mexico News and other outlets throughout July of 2025. If you haven’t heard already, over the 4th of July weekend, President Trump signed the so-called “Big Beautiful Bill” (BBB) into law. Setting aside the merits and demerits of the legislation, you have to hand it to President Trump and Speaker Mike [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org/bbb-is-not-the-tragedy-our-politicians-portray/"&gt;BBB Is Not The Tragedy Our Politicians Portray&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://riograndefoundation.org"&gt;Rio Grande Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 17:29:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] Broadband revolution: What the new federal guidelines mean for Montana and beyond</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/broadband-revolution-what-the-new-federal-guidelines-mean-for-montana-and-beyond</link><description>Public dollars should always be spent wisely and efficiently, especially on infrastructure that touches nearly every home, school, and...</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 17:51:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Lawsuit Against United Teachers of Los Angeles Dismissed, Freedom Foundation to Appeal to Ninth Circuit</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/press-release/lawsuit-against-united-teachers-of-los-angeles-dismissed-freedom-foundation-to-appeal-to-ninth-circuit/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Today, the U.S. District Court for the Central District of California ruled against the lawsuit filed by seven Jewish teachers against United Teachers of Los Angeles (UTLA). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/press-release/lawsuit-against-united-teachers-of-los-angeles-dismissed-freedom-foundation-to-appeal-to-ninth-circuit/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Lawsuit Against United Teachers of Los Angeles Dismissed, Freedom Foundation to Appeal to Ninth Circuit&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 17:58:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] Texas can Avoid Europe’s Migration-Crime Problems</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/texas-can-avoid-europes-migration-crime-problems/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;During a recent trip to Europe for a political philosophy symposium, I was both impressed by the young leaders I met and concerned by the situations they were describing in their various home countries throughout the old continent. Young men and women, fluent in geo-politics and global current events alongside four to five different languages,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/texas-can-avoid-europes-migration-crime-problems/"&gt;Texas can Avoid Europe’s Migration-Crime Problems&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 18:17:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Statistics Shows Crime Numbers Converging for Major Missouri Cities</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/criminal-justice/statistics-shows-crime-numbers-converging-for-major-missouri-cities/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The violent crime statistics in the cities of St. Louis, Kansas City, and Springfield tell a much different story today [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/criminal-justice/statistics-shows-crime-numbers-converging-for-major-missouri-cities/"&gt;Statistics Shows Crime Numbers Converging for Major Missouri Cities&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 18:45:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] What Does Austin’s Budget Show Us About Rates and Values?</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/what-does-austins-budget-show-us-about-rates-and-values/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Ideally, an inverse relationship exists between property tax rates and property values. As one goes up, the other should come down, lest the product of those two variables—i.e., one’s tax bill—shoot up as a result. Of course, Texas’ local governments aren’t well-known for lowering rates when values rise, or vice versa. Case-in-point: the city of...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/what-does-austins-budget-show-us-about-rates-and-values/"&gt;What Does Austin’s Budget Show Us About Rates and Values?&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 18:47:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] The Spending Problem Behind Iowa’s Property Tax Crisis</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/the-spending-problem-behind-iowas-property-tax-crisis/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;No reform will work until local governments rein in their budgets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Property taxes remain a significant concern for taxpayers. In addition, they are a hindrance to economic growth. Taxpayers are demanding meaningful property tax relief, and that will only occur when legislators address the cause. Local government spending drives high property taxes, and the solution for property tax relief will only be found in limiting spending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/the-spending-problem-behind-iowas-property-tax-crisis/"&gt;The Spending Problem Behind Iowa’s Property Tax Crisis&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 19:33:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] Trump Must Shut Down Counterfeit Weight-Loss Drugs</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/trump-must-shut-down-counterfeit-weight-loss-drugs/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Americans looking to lose weight are increasingly turning to the internet. And they&amp;#8217;re being duped. Telehealth startups and fly-by-night pharmacies are peddling what look like cheap, convenient versions of blockbuster drugs like Ozempic and Wegovy. But many of these offerings are neither authentic nor safe. They&amp;#8217;re &amp;#8220;compounded&amp;#8221; copies — knockoffs often made with foreign ingredients [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/trump-must-shut-down-counterfeit-weight-loss-drugs/"&gt;Trump Must Shut Down Counterfeit Weight-Loss Drugs&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 19:54:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Platteinstitute] Research Note: Use of the Nebraska Livestock Matrix</title><link>https://platteinstitute.org/research-note-use-of-the-nebraska-livestock-matrix/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Introduced in 2015, the Nebraska Livestock Matrix is a tool designed to help counties evaluate proposed livestock operations seeking conditional use or special exception permits. Created to promote consistency across county lines in the permitting process, the committee tasked with developing the matrix faced two significant challenges in aligning its objectives. First, the tool needed...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org/research-note-use-of-the-nebraska-livestock-matrix/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Research Note: Use of the Nebraska Livestock Matrix&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://platteinstitute.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;Platte Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 19:58:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] VICTORY! Court Affirms that Public School DEI Indoctrination Isn’t a Trade Secret</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/victory-court-affirms-that-public-school-dei-indoctrination-isnt-a-trade-secret/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;A Pennsylvania mother won a major victory for parental rights and government transparency last week when her local school district..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/victory-court-affirms-that-public-school-dei-indoctrination-isnt-a-trade-secret/"&gt;VICTORY! Court Affirms that Public School DEI Indoctrination Isn’t a Trade Secret&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 20:01:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Empowerms] Former Speaker Philip Gunn: Faith, Resilience, and Leadership</title><link>https://empowerms.org/former-speaker-philip-gunn-faith-resilience-and-leadership/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;﻿ Former Speaker Philip Gunn: Faith, Resilience, and Leadership In this episode, host Grant Callen sits down with former Mississippi House Speaker Philip Gunn to trace his journey from Clinton’s small-town roots to state leadership. Gunn shares how a personal tragedy at Ole Miss Law upended his life, yet God’s faithfulness sustained him, strengthened his faith,&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org/former-speaker-philip-gunn-faith-resilience-and-leadership/"&gt;Former Speaker Philip Gunn: Faith, Resilience, and Leadership&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://empowerms.org"&gt;Empower Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 00:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pelicanpolicy] Federal School Choice Is A Double-Edged Sword for Educational Freedom</title><link>https://pelicanpolicy.org/education/federal-school-choice-is-a-double-edged-sword-for-educational-freedom/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The passage of the One Big Beautiful Bill and President Trump’s signature on the legislation represent a watershed moment for American education policy. Embedded within this massive tax reform package is the Educational Choice for Children Act, creating a first-of-its-kind, nationwide tax credit scholarship program that could fundamentally reshape how families access educational options across...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org/education/federal-school-choice-is-a-double-edged-sword-for-educational-freedom/"&gt;Federal School Choice Is A Double-Edged Sword for Educational Freedom&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pelicanpolicy.org"&gt;Pelican Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 00:27:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] ‘Goldilocks’ compromise: Reform misuse of categorical grants</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/goldilocks-compromise-reform-misuse-of-categorical-grants</link><description>House bill would return spending decisions to local school districts</description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 09:58:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] The U.S. Drug System Strikes a Reasonable Balance Between Incentivizing Innovation and Promoting Competition</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/the-u-s-drug-system-strikes-a-reasonable-balance-between-incentivizing-innovation-and-promoting-competition/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The government explicitly grants innovators temporary market exclusivity to provide an opportunity for groundbreaking pharmaceutical companies to recover the costs of capital associated with developing novel treatments. This was one of the express purposes of past federal reform legislation, such as the Hatch-Waxman Act signed in 1984 and the Biologics Price Competition and Innovation Act [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/the-u-s-drug-system-strikes-a-reasonable-balance-between-incentivizing-innovation-and-promoting-competition/"&gt;The U.S. Drug System Strikes a Reasonable Balance Between Incentivizing Innovation and Promoting Competition&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 10:00:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Union Rules: Welcome to the Hotel California</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/union-rules-welcome-to-the-hotel-california/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="630" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Unions-and-Hotel-California.jpg" width="1200" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most treasured rights in America is the right to a secret ballot – the opportunity to vote in privacy, free from harassment. It’s what separates democratic societies and is a right that filters down to even our local Rotary Clubs and Chambers of Commerce. It is a right that should be guaranteed for [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/union-rules-welcome-to-the-hotel-california/"&gt;Union Rules: Welcome to the Hotel California&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 12:45:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Cascadepolicy] Metro Should Reject the Burnside Bridge Road Diet</title><link>https://cascadepolicy.org/transportation/metro-should-reject-the-burnside-bridge-road-diet/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;By Connor Roberts The new “Earthquake Ready Burnside Bridge” lane designs, backed with...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org/transportation/metro-should-reject-the-burnside-bridge-road-diet/"&gt;Metro Should Reject the Burnside Bridge Road Diet&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://cascadepolicy.org"&gt;Cascade Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 14:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Fixing Maine’s broken budget process begins with defining ‘extraordinary occasion’</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/fixing-maines-broken-budget-process-begins-with-defining-extraordinary-occasion/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Special legislative sessions in Maine have been used to create budgets using a simple majority dating back to 2005. However, they’ve become a more apparent issue in recent sessions given that Gov. Janet Mills has declared a special session every budget cycle since 2021. With this becoming a greater problem (and occurrence) during biennial budget [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/fixing-maines-broken-budget-process-begins-with-defining-extraordinary-occasion/"&gt;Fixing Maine&amp;#8217;s broken budget process begins with defining &amp;#8216;extraordinary occasion&amp;#8217;&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 14:09:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Texaspolicy] The Energy Subsidy Trap: How the One Big Beautiful Bill Proved Subsidies Are Nearly Impossible to Remove</title><link>https://www.texaspolicy.com/the-energy-subsidy-trap-how-the-one-big-beautiful-bill-proved-subsidies-are-nearly-impossible-to-remove/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The One Big Beautiful Bill Act, signed into law on July 4, 2025, was supposed to be a decisive break from government intervention in energy markets. Instead, it became a masterclass in why energy subsidies represent one of the most persistent forms of government market intervention. When Congress first debated energy policy reform, the U.S....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com/the-energy-subsidy-trap-how-the-one-big-beautiful-bill-proved-subsidies-are-nearly-impossible-to-remove/"&gt;The Energy Subsidy Trap: How the One Big Beautiful Bill Proved Subsidies Are Nearly Impossible to Remove&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.texaspolicy.com"&gt;Texas Public Policy Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 14:40:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] The Senate Flashed a Yellow Light on AI. States Shouldn’t Run the Run</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/the-senate-flashed-a-yellow-light-on-ai-states-shouldnt-run-the-run/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;July 23,2025 By: Turner Loesel&amp;#160; In&amp;#160;the&amp;#160;predawn hours of July 1, 2025,&amp;#160;the&amp;#160;U.S.&amp;#160;Senate&amp;#160;delivered a deafening blow to America’s tech sector....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/the-senate-flashed-a-yellow-light-on-ai-states-shouldnt-run-the-run/"&gt;The Senate Flashed a Yellow Light on AI. States Shouldn&amp;#8217;t Run the Run&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 15:09:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] The U.S.’s Need for a National AI Strategy</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/the-u-s-s-need-for-a-national-ai-strategy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;July 23, 2024 By: Ian J. Parry and Turner Loesel Notably absent from the President’s One Big, Beautiful...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/the-u-s-s-need-for-a-national-ai-strategy/"&gt;The U.S.’s Need for a National AI Strategy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 15:22:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pioneerinstitute] DFI’s Jim Blew on Federal Education Tax Credit Program</title><link>https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/dfis-jim-blew-on-federal-education-tax-credit-program/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In this week’s episode of The Learning Curve, co-hosts Alisha Searcy and Dr. Cara Candal of ExcelinEd interview former assistant secretary at the U.S. Department of Education and co-founder of the Defense of Freedom Institute (DFI), Jim Blew. Mr. Blew reflects on his tenure in federal education leadership and his motivation for establishing DFI. He discusses the decades of rising federal K-12 spending through initiatives like RTTT, ESSA, and ESSER funds, instead calling for devolving federal authority out of the U.S. Department of Education, and more private school choice and charter public school innovation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org/featured/dfis-jim-blew-on-federal-education-tax-credit-program/"&gt;DFI&amp;#8217;s Jim Blew on Federal Education Tax Credit Program&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://pioneerinstitute.org"&gt;Pioneer Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 16:00:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Frontierinstitute] Written Public Comment to SFIC 7.23.25</title><link>https://frontierinstitute.org/written-public-comment-to-sfic-7-23-25/</link><description>We believe it is a constitutional and policy imperative for Montana to implement a statewide student-centered funding formula design as the primary way to fund public education.</description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 17:29:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Spending Restraint Must Take Priority in 2026</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/spending-restraint-must-take-priority-in-2026/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Iowa’s fiscal position is strong, but rising spending and short-term revenue declines from tax reforms make it critical for lawmakers to prioritize long-term budget discipline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To support this goal, policymakers could strengthen the state’s spending cap by tying budget growth to population and inflation, and adopt priority-based budgeting and independent efficiency audits to control costs and ensure spending aligns with core government functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lawmakers could also assess Iowa’s reliance on federal funds and continue streamlining state government as strategies to improve transparency, limit bureaucratic growth, and reinforce long-term fiscal sustainability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/spending-restraint-must-take-priority-in-2026/"&gt;Spending Restraint Must Take Priority in 2026&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 17:30:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] Missouri’s Squandered Opportunity</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/budget-and-spending/missouris-squandered-opportunity/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The first step toward finding a solution is admitting there’s a problem. It’s been obvious to anyone who’s been paying [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/budget-and-spending/missouris-squandered-opportunity/"&gt;Missouri’s Squandered Opportunity&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 18:20:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Goldwaterinstitute] 10/17: You’re Invited to the Goldwater Institute’s 2025 Freedom Gala</title><link>https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/2025-freedom-gala/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;You’re invited to the Goldwater Institute’s 2025 Freedom Gala on October 17 at the Arizona Biltmore. This year’s Freedom Gala..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org/2025-freedom-gala/"&gt;10/17: You&amp;#8217;re Invited to the Goldwater Institute&amp;#8217;s 2025 Freedom Gala&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.goldwaterinstitute.org"&gt;Goldwater Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 19:36:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Thomasjeffersoninst] Layoffs at Bloated Federal Agencies Versus the Impact of Private Sector Layoffs Caused by the Federal Government</title><link>https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/layoffs-at-bloated-federal-agencies-versus-the-impact-of-private-sector-layoffs-caused-by-the-federal-government/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="1080" src="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Layoffs.jpg" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Secretary of State Marco Rubio recently laid off 1,350 employees as part of a broader restructuring effort, the media response was swift and emotional. Stories of tearful farewells, union outrage, and dramatic claims of “fascism” filled the airwaves. One would think these federal employees had lifetime appointments and that accountability or right-sizing government were foreign [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org/layoffs-at-bloated-federal-agencies-versus-the-impact-of-private-sector-layoffs-caused-by-the-federal-government/"&gt;Layoffs at Bloated Federal Agencies Versus the Impact of Private Sector Layoffs Caused by the Federal Government&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.thomasjeffersoninst.org"&gt;Thomas Jefferson Institute for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 21:03:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Jamesmadison] Statement From The James Madison Institute on the Release of the Trump Administration’s AI Action Plan</title><link>https://jamesmadison.org/statement-from-the-james-madison-institute-on-the-release-of-the-trump-administrations-ai-action-plan/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE July 23, 2025 CONTACT Emma Rose Graddy 850-386-3131 Statement From The James Madison Institute on...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org/statement-from-the-james-madison-institute-on-the-release-of-the-trump-administrations-ai-action-plan/"&gt;Statement From The James Madison Institute on the Release of the Trump Administration’s AI Action Plan&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamesmadison.org"&gt;James Madison Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 21:11:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Californiapolicycenter] Public Employee Unions: The Quiet Crisis Undermining Governance</title><link>https://californiapolicycenter.org/quiet-crisis-undermining-governance/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=quiet-crisis-undermining-governance</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Unrestrained public employee union power drives up costs, erodes accountability, and holds taxpayer&amp;#8217;s hostage, especially in California. The Power Imbalance at the Heart of Governance Public employee unions consistently put their interests ahead of what serves the broader public, creating a dynamic fundamentally different from private-sector unions that must run within market constraints. These public...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org/quiet-crisis-undermining-governance/"&gt;Public Employee Unions: The Quiet Crisis Undermining Governance&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://californiapolicycenter.org"&gt;California Policy Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 21:28:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Idahofreedom] Idaho DOGE: Misses it by That Much</title><link>https://idahofreedom.org/idaho-doge-misses-it-by-that-much/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://idahofreedom.org/idaho-doge-misses-it-by-that-much/" rel="nofollow" title="Idaho DOGE: Misses it by That Much"&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image" height="1396" src="https://idahofreedom.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Gemini_Generated_Image_ku2awsku2awsku2a-scaled.jpg" style="display: block; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 10px;" width="2560" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Ask any good conservative in Idaho politics, and they’ll tell you Idaho’s budgets and government growth are out of control. They’re right. Now, throw in the biggest buzzword in politics for the last six months (the start of President Trump’s return to power), “DOGE.” Of course, that’s shorthand for the Department of Government Efficiency (headed [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 22:28:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mountainstatespolicy] MSPC launches the Bill &amp;#38; Milly Kay Baldwin Center for Education</title><link>https://www.mountainstatespolicy.org/mspc-launches-the-bill-milly-kay-baldwin-center-for-education</link><description>Mountain States Policy Center (MSPC) is proud to announce the official launch of the Bill &amp;#38; Milly Kay Baldwin Center for Education, a new research and advocacy hub focused on expanding educational opportunity and defending student-centered policy reforms throughout the Mountain West.</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 07:15:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Holder’s group promotes redistricting double standard</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/holders-group-promotes-redistricting-double-standard/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Collin Anderson writes for the Washington Free Beacon about the latest example of Eric Holder’s hypocrisy. As Texas Republicans approached a special legislative session aimed at redrawing the state&amp;#8217;s congressional map to carve out additional districts likely to elect Republicans, the New York Times published an account of their plans. It cited former attorney general...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/holders-group-promotes-redistricting-double-standard/"&gt;Holder’s group promotes redistricting double standard&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 09:36:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Docs reveal WaPo’s key role in Russia election hoax</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/docs-reveal-wapos-key-role-in-russia-election-hoax/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Hans Mahncke writes for the Federalist about a legacy media outlet’s major role in spreading misinformation. Newly released documents from Director of National Intelligence (DNI) Tulsi Gabbard have shattered the official narrative surrounding Russian interference in the 2016 election. A previously classified draft of the Presidential Daily Briefing (PDB), prepared for President Barack Obama on...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/docs-reveal-wapos-key-role-in-russia-election-hoax/"&gt;Docs reveal WaPo’s key role in Russia election hoax&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 09:39:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Johnlocke] Major media outlets ignore Gabbard’s ‘bombshell’</title><link>https://www.johnlocke.org/major-media-outlets-ignore-gabbards-bombshell/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Brian Flood and Joseph Wulfsohn write for FoxNews.com about major media outlets’ apparent disinterest in the latest news emerging from the nation’s top intelligence official. Director of National Intelligence Tulsi Gabbard suggested last week that intelligence was &amp;#8220;manufactured and politicized&amp;#8221; by the most powerful people in the Obama administration in 2016 and Americans will finally...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org/major-media-outlets-ignore-gabbards-bombshell/"&gt;Major media outlets ignore Gabbard’s ‘bombshell’&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.johnlocke.org"&gt;John Locke Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 09:42:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mackinac] Will Whitmer’s legacy include fixing the roads?</title><link>https://www.mackinac.org/blog/2025/will-whitmers-legacy-include-fixing-the-roads</link><description>Talk and tax-hike requests don’t fill potholes</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 09:59:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Pacificresearch] California’s obsession with density limits housing growth</title><link>https://www.pacificresearch.org/californias-obsession-with-density-limits-housing-growth/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Morphing from a once-reasonable requirement that building permit applicants report on the “significant environmental impact” of their construction project and how they intend to mitigate that impact, CEQA is now a process-heavy, bureaucratic beast that delays projects for years and costs developers millions. Of all the ways California’s Legislature and state agencies are trying to [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org/californias-obsession-with-density-limits-housing-growth/"&gt;California’s obsession with density limits housing growth&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.pacificresearch.org"&gt;Pacific Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 10:00:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Itrfoundation] Taxpayer Protections Are Just as Important as Pro-Growth Tax Policy</title><link>https://itrfoundation.org/taxpayer-protections-are-just-as-important-as-pro-growth-tax-policy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Iowa lawmakers are considering two constitutional amendments—one to require a two-thirds supermajority to raise income taxes and another to protect the state’s flat tax rate—to safeguard taxpayers and limit government growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additional reforms, including constitutional spending limits and protections for the Taxpayer Relief Fund, would reinforce Iowa’s commitment to fiscal conservatism and protect taxpayers from future tax-and-spend cycles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without constitutional protections, future legislatures could reverse recent tax reforms by reintroducing progressive tax structures or misusing surplus funds, underscoring the need for permanent safeguards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org/taxpayer-protections-are-just-as-important-as-pro-growth-tax-policy/"&gt;Taxpayer Protections Are Just as Important as Pro-Growth Tax Policy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://itrfoundation.org"&gt;ITR Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 13:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Fitzgerald, Lummis Introduce STUDENT Act to Curb Out-of-Control NEA</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/labor/fitzgerald-lummis-introduce-student-act-to-curb-out-of-control-nea/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This week, U.S. Rep. Scott Fitzgerald (R-WI) and U.S. Sen. Cynthia Lummis (R-WY) introduced legislation to overhaul the federal charter of the National Education Association (NEA), the largest teachers union in the country, to make it more accountable and less partisan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/labor/fitzgerald-lummis-introduce-student-act-to-curb-out-of-control-nea/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Fitzgerald, Lummis Introduce STUDENT Act to Curb Out-of-Control NEA&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Yankeeinstitute] Unveiling Financial Transparency Failures in Labor Organizations</title><link>https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/07/24/unveiling-financial-transparency-failures-in-labor-organizations/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full wp-post-image" height="1709" src="https://yankeeinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/shutterstock_2463875405-scaled.jpg" width="2560" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*Editor&amp;#8217;s Note: This article was originally testimony submitted, on July 16, to the U.S. House Committee on Education and the Workforce, regarding a &amp;#8216;Comprehensive Case for Strengthening LM2 Reporting and [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org/2025/07/24/unveiling-financial-transparency-failures-in-labor-organizations/"&gt;Unveiling Financial Transparency Failures in Labor Organizations&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://yankeeinstitute.org"&gt;Yankee Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 13:30:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Kansaspolicy] Over 150,000 Kansas students may be functionally illiterate, yet the adults in charge won’t take action</title><link>https://kansaspolicy.org/150k-kansas-students-functionally-illiterate/</link><description>The 2024 state assessment indicates that more than 150,000 Kansas students suffer from what is officially described as having a “limited ability to understand and use English language arts skills and knowledge to be academically successful for postsecondary success.”  This closely aligns with what is commonly referred to as being ‘functionally illiterate’, which  Dictionary.com defines [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 14:08:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Oak Park natural gas ban faces legal challenge</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/oak-park-natural-gas-ban-faces-legal-challenge/</link><description>In 2024, Oak Park, Illinois, went where Mayor Brandon Johnson tried to take Chicago – banning all natural gas connections in new building projects. The high cost of this inconsequential, feel-good move is getting legal pushback.</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 15:25:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Illinoispolicy] Chicago Teachers Union president fails to pay her bills… again</title><link>https://www.illinoispolicy.org/chicago-teachers-union-president-fails-to-pay-her-bills-again/</link><description>Despite Chicago Teachers Union President Stacy Davis Gates’ constant demands for “wealthy” taxpayers to pay their “fair share,” she is behind on her city water, sewer and trash bills once again. She makes $265,150 a year.</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 15:28:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Reforminggovernment] IRG Announces New Leadership</title><link>https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-announces-new-leadership/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;IRG Announces New Leadership Alison Prange to serve as the next Chair of the Board of Directors  THE NEWS The Board of Directors for the Institute for Reforming Government has elected Alison Prange to serve as the next Chair of the Board. Alison Prange was appointed to IRG’s Board in 2022. THE QUOTES Alison Prange, IRG [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org/irg-announces-new-leadership/"&gt;IRG Announces New Leadership&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://reforminggovernment.org"&gt;Institute for Reforming Government&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 15:54:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] PJM electricity prices hit record due to AI</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/pjm-electricity-prices-hit-record-due-to-ai/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday was a big day for the biggest U.S. power auction, held by the grid operator PJM Interconnection. Prices to supply electricity between June 2026 and May 2027 exceeded last year&amp;#8217;s all-time high by 22 percent thanks to demand from artificial intelligence. Reuters reports: A recent surge in U.S. power consumption driven by Big Tech&amp;#8217;s...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/pjm-electricity-prices-hit-record-due-to-ai/"&gt;PJM electricity prices hit record due to AI&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 16:04:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Showmeinstitute] “Just Let Me Write the Definitions”</title><link>https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/state-and-local-government/just-let-me-write-the-definitions/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In The Power Broker, Robert Caro’s legendary biography of Robert Moses, Caro describes how Moses was fully capable of getting [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org/blog/state-and-local-government/just-let-me-write-the-definitions/"&gt;“Just Let Me Write the Definitions”&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://showmeinstitute.org"&gt;Show Me Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 17:06:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] Feeding Our Future: 49th conviction</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/feeding-our-future-49th-conviction/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Mahad Ibrahim pled guilty to two felony counts this morning at the Federal Courthouse in downtown Minneapolis. Your correspondent was there. Ibrahim is facing years in federal prison and the forfeiture of millions of dollars. Ibrahim, age 49, was defendant No. 17 in the case, overall (out of 72) and entered guilty plea No. 42...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/feeding-our-future-49th-conviction/"&gt;Feeding Our Future: 49th conviction&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 17:09:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Mainepolicy] Maine Must Act to Lift Students Under New Federal Education Tax Credit Program</title><link>https://mainepolicy.org/maine-must-act-to-lift-students-under-new-federal-education-tax-credit-program/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In 2025, Congress enacted the first-ever federal 1-to-1 tax credit for donations to K–12 education scholarships. While championed by President Trump, the program reflects a broader bipartisan vision: empowering families, driving educational innovation, and keeping funding decisions closer to home. But unless Maine lawmakers act swiftly, Maine families and students will miss out on the [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org/maine-must-act-to-lift-students-under-new-federal-education-tax-credit-program/"&gt;Maine Must Act to Lift Students Under New Federal Education Tax Credit Program&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://mainepolicy.org"&gt;Maine Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 17:20:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Freedomfoundation] Teacher Freedom Summit brings together educators anxious to cut ties with their union</title><link>https://www.freedomfoundation.com/teacher-conference/teacher-freedom-summit-brings-together-educators-anxious-to-cut-ties-with-their-union/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Despite the shocking news headlines from big unions like the American Federation of Teachers (AFT) and the National Education Association (NEA), 2025 has been a year of success and hope for America’s education system and educators alike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com/teacher-conference/teacher-freedom-summit-brings-together-educators-anxious-to-cut-ties-with-their-union/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Teacher Freedom Summit brings together educators anxious to cut ties with their union&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.freedomfoundation.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Freedom Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 18:16:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>[Americanexperiment] A tenth deportation</title><link>https://www.americanexperiment.org/a-tenth-deportation/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Roberto Trinidad De La Rosa (a/k/a Jaime) is facing his 10th deportation from the United States after pleading guilty this morning at the Federal Courthouse in downtown St. Paul. He pled guilty to a felony charge of illegal re-entry by a previously deported alien. Previous deportations were recorded in 2001, 2003, 2004, 2005 (twice), 2007,...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org/a-tenth-deportation/"&gt;A tenth deportation&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.americanexperiment.org"&gt;American Experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 18:46:57 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>